<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Basilica of Saint Mary Major Rome">

<photo  date_taken="2011-08-08 13:00:26" description="" id="6053583435" latitude="41.897198" license="1" longitude="12.499126" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="rome roma basilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicadisantamariamaggiore church basilica facade" title="rome - papal basilica of saint mary major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6204/6053583435_1bfa9694d8_b.jpg" username="drencrome" views="60" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-08 12:57:23" description="" id="6053580971" latitude="41.898356" license="1" longitude="12.497999" nbComments="0" rank="2" tags="rome roma basilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicadisantamariamaggiore church basilica romancatholic" title="rome - papal basilica of saint mary major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6069/6053580971_a5b681fd90_b.jpg" username="drencrome" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-08 13:00:17" description="" id="6054132082" latitude="41.897305" license="1" longitude="12.499254" nbComments="0" rank="3" tags="rome roma basilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicadisantamariamaggiore church basilica romancatholic belltower campanile" title="rome - papal basilica of saint mary major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6186/6054132082_003898ee14_b.jpg" username="drencrome" views="39" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-12 17:00:50" description="This basilica of Santa Maria Maggiore on the Esquiline Hill in Rome was built shortly after the Council by Pope Liberius (352-366) and was called after him &amp;quot;Basilica Liberii&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Liberiana&amp;quot;. Later legends tell that on 5 August in 352, during the night, snow fell on the summit of the Esquiline Hill and, in obedience to a vision which Pope Liberius III had that same night, he built a basilica, in honour of Our Lady on the spot which was covered with snow. For this reason, today used to be named after Our Lady of the Snow. In 431 the Council of Ephesus affirmed that Our Lady is 'Theotokos', or God-bearer. This doctrine was set in place to teach the divinity of Christ, and to this day, a proper understanding of Mary and her role in the history of salvation helps us to understand Christ rightly. For this reason, the Mother of God is the Vanquisher of all Heresies. The Liberian basilica was restored by Pope Sixtus III (432-440) and dedicated to Our Lady after the Council of Ephesus. It is thus said to be the oldest church in the West that is dedicated to Our Lady, hence it is called St Mary Major (or the Greater). From the 7th century it was known also as &amp;quot;Maria ad Præsepe&amp;quot; because the relics of the manger of Christ are kept here. Today, we celebrate 5th August as the feast of the Dedication of St Mary Major." id="6011007106" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="4" tags="rome santamariamaggiore basilica tower facade" title="Basilica of Saint Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6021/6011007106_4b61d25630_b.jpg" username="Lawrence OP" views="316" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-07 02:40:47" description="The Sistine Chapel Rome, Saint Mary Major The altar in the center of the Chapel is beautiful: four gold leafed bronze angels in life size, an opera by Sebastiano Torregiani." id="1320763206" latitude="41.897533" license="4" longitude="12.498761" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="basilicadisantamariamaggiore santamariamaggiore saintmarymajor" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1059/1320763206_f813a474bd_b.jpg" username="rjhuttondfw" views="140" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-03-11 18:40:02" description="The Basilica Papale di Santa Maria Maggiore in Rome, Italy, viewed from the Piazza dell'Esquilino. From my architecture series at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wildretina.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.wildretina.com&lt;/a&gt;" id="6974093371" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="basilica santa maria maggiore saint mary major church cathedral rome italy architecture building sacred old" title="Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7186/6974093371_52a9c91ec3_b.jpg" username="wildretina" views="34" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-10 04:12:20" description="The Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major (Italian: Basilica Papale di Santa Maria Maggiore, Latin: Basilica Sanctae Mariae Majoris ad Nives, is an ancient Roman Catholic basilica of Rome. It is one of the four major or four papal basilicas, which, together with St. Lawrence outside the Walls, were formerly referred to as the five &amp;quot;patriarchal basilicas&amp;quot; of Rome, associated with the five ancient patriarchal sees of Christendom (see Pentarchy). The other three papal or major basilicas are St. John Lateran, St. Peter and St. Paul outside the Walls. The Liberian Basilica (another title for the church) is one of the tituli, presided over by a patron—in this case Pope Liberius—that housed the major congregations of early Christians in Rome. Santa Maria Maggiore is the only Roman basilica that retained the core of its original structure, left intact despite several additional construction projects and damage from the earthquake of 1348. The name of the church reflects two ideas of greatness (&amp;quot;major&amp;quot;), that of a major (or papal) basilica and that of the largest (major) church in Rome dedicated to the Blessed Virgin Mary. After the Avignon papacy formally ended and the Papacy returned to Rome, the Basilica became a temporary Palace of the Popes due to the deteriorated state of the Lateran Palace. The papal residence was later moved to the Palace of the Vatican in what is now Vatican City. From: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Maggiore&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Maggiore&lt;/a&gt;" id="3388800967" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="rome italy" title="The Patriarchal Basilica of St. Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3427/3388800967_455333b4c4_b.jpg" username="Northfielder" views="443" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-28 12:51:05" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Maggiore&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Santa Maria Maggiore&lt;/a&gt;" id="4127723902" latitude="41.897894" license="4" longitude="12.498192" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="basilicadisantamariamaggiore basilica santamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore basilicasanctaemariaemajorisadnives interior rome gold roma italy italia" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2698/4127723902_f8777edac3_b.jpg" username="The Wolf" views="299" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-07 02:40:47" description="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore, Rome The Sistine Chapel The altar in the center of the Chapel by Sebastiano Torregiani" id="1319879935" latitude="41.897533" license="4" longitude="12.498761" nbComments="0" rank="9" tags="basilicadisantamariamaggiore santamariamaggiore saintmarymajor sebastianotorregiani" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1213/1319879935_ad5b189082_b.jpg" username="rjhuttondfw" views="187" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-26 17:18:32" description="&lt;i&gt;Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore&lt;/i&gt; Wikipedia:&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Maggiore&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore&lt;/a&gt;" id="4622650889" latitude="41.897561" license="3" longitude="12.49843" nbComments="0" rank="10" tags="ancientrome basilicadisantamariamaggiore church rome italy roma italia travel 1755 40d canon canoneos40d canonefs1755mmf28isusm tomfs geotag geotagged geodata amodagl3080gpsdatalogger gpicsync" title="The Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4033/4622650889_62c98f3fcf_b.jpg" username="tomfs" views="172" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-12 01:45:59" description="Gilded ceiling designed by Leon Battista Alberti and completed by Antonio da Sangallo" id="3607725978" latitude="41.897587" license="3" longitude="12.498541" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="rome roma italy europe basilicadisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore church basilica santamariamaggiore worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite interior gilded sangallo alberti ceiling columns" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3643/3607725978_9fa9b74e49_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="159" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:44:55" description="" id="6565836359" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="12" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7029/6565836359_f9b186c8ed_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-15 14:58:03" description="The Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major (Italian: Basilica Papale di Santa Maria Maggiore, Latin: Basilica Sanctae Mariae Majoris ad Nives), is an ancient Roman Catholic Marian basilica of Rome. It is one of the four major or four papal basilicas, which, together with St. Lawrence outside the Walls, were formerly referred to as the five &amp;quot;patriarchal basilicas&amp;quot; of Rome, associated with the five ancient patriarchal sees of Christendom." id="5735334780" latitude="41.897581" license="3" longitude="12.498396" nbComments="3" rank="13" tags="roma rome italia italy europa europe canoneos7d eos7d javiercorbo corbo cityscape arquitectura arte art architecture romanico building edificio plazadeespaña coliseo piazzanavona sanpedro vaticano santangelo castillo castle church iglesia sangiovanilaterano sanjuandeletran satjohnlateran basilicadesanclemente sanclemente santamarialamayor basilica santamariamaggiore catholic catolico catolicismo jesus christ viajar viajes travel dzoom xatakafoto canonistas flickr favorita favorites favoritas blackwhitephotos" title="Basilica de Santa Maria la Mayor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5268/5735334780_09e728caa8_b.jpg" username="Javier Corbo" views="426" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-28 12:49:20" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Maggiore&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Santa Maria Maggiore&lt;/a&gt;" id="4127724026" latitude="41.897894" license="4" longitude="12.498192" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="basilicadisantamariamaggiore basilica santamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore basilicasanctaemariaemajorisadnives hdr altar interior church rome symmetry symmetrical gold candles marble praying religion roma italy italia" title="Prayers in Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2687/4127724026_63cfd6f3a1_b.jpg" username="The Wolf" views="401" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-22 10:14:16" description="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore - The Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major (Italian: Basilica Papale di Santa Maria Maggiore, Latin: Basilica Sanctae Mariae Maioris), known also by other names, is the largest Roman Catholic Marian church in Rome, Italy. There are other churches in Rome dedicated to Mary, such as Santa Maria in Trastevere, Santa Maria in Aracoeli, Santa Maria sopra Minerva, but the greater size of the Basilica of Saint Mary Major justifies the adjective by which it is distinguished from the other 25. It is agreed that the present church was built under Pope Sixtus III (432-440). The dedicatory inscription on the triumphal arch, Sixtus Episcopus plebi Dei, (Sixtus the bishop to the people of God) is an indication of that Pope's role in the construction. As well as this church on the summit of the Esquiline Hill, Pope Sixtus III is said to have commissioned extensive building projects throughout the city, which were continued by his successor Pope Leo I, the great. The church retains the core of its original structure, despite several additional construction projects and damage by the earthquake of 1348. Church building in Rome in this period, as exemplified in Saint Mary Major, was inspired by the idea of Rome being not just the centre of the world of the Roman Empire, as it was seen in the classical period, but the centre of the Christian world. Santa Maria Maggiore, one of the first churches built in honour of the Virgin Mary, was erected in the immediate aftermath of the Council of Ephesus of 431, which proclaimed Mary Mother of God. Pope Sixtus III built it to commemorate this decision. Richard Krautheimer attributes the magnificence of the work also to the abundant revenue accruing to the papacy at the time from land holdings acquired by the Church during the 4th and 5th centuries on the Italian peninsula: &amp;quot;Some of these holdings were locally controlled; the majority as early as the end of the 5th century were administered directly from Rome with great efficiency: a central accounting system was involved in the papal chancery; and a budget was apparently prepared, one part of the income going to the papal administration, another to the needs of the clergy, a third to the maintenance of church buildings, a fourth to charity. These fines enabled the papacy to carry out through the 5th century an ambitious building program, including Santa Maria Maggiore.&amp;quot; Miri Rubin believes that the building of the basilica was influenced also by seeing Mary as a one who could represent the imperial ideals of classical Rome, bringing together the old Rome and the new Christian Rome: &amp;quot;In Rome, the city of martyrs, if no longer of emperors, Mary was a figure that could credibly carry imperial memories and representations.&amp;quot; When the popes returned to Rome after the period of the Avignon papacy, the buildings of the basilica became a temporary Palace of the Popes due to the deteriorated state of the Lateran Palace. The papal residence was later moved to the Palace of the Vatican in what is now Vatican City. The basilica was restored, redecorated and extended by various popes, including Eugene III (1145–1153), Nicholas IV (1288–92), Clement X (1670–76), and Benedict XIV (1740–58), who in the 1740s commissioned Ferdinando Fuga to build the present façade and to modify the interior. The interior of the Santa Maria Maggiore underwent a broad renovation encompassing all of its altars between the years 1575 and 1630. The church is also called Our Lady of the Snow, or of the Snows, a name given to it in the Roman Missal from 1568 to 1969 in connection with the liturgical feast of the anniversary of its dedication on 5 August, a feast that was then denominated Dedicatio Sanctae Mariae ad Nives (Dedication of Saint Mary of the Snows). This name for the basilica had become popular in the 14th century in connection with a legend that the 1911 Catholic Encyclopedia reports thus: &amp;quot;During the pontificate of Liberius, the Roman patrician John and his wife, who were without heirs, made a vow to donate their possessions to the Virgin Mary. They prayed that she might make known to them how they were to dispose of their property in her honour. On 5 August, at the height of the Roman summer, snow fell during the night on the summit of the Esquiline Hill. In obedience to a vision of the Virgin Mary which they had the same night, the couple built a basilica in honour of Mary on the very spot which was covered with snow. From the fact that no mention whatever is made of this alleged miracle until a few hundred years later, not even by Sixtus III in his eight-line dedicatory inscription ... it would seem that the legend has no historical basis.&amp;quot; The legend is first reported only after the year 1000. It may be implied in what the Liber Pontificalis, of the early 13th century, says of Pope Liberius: &amp;quot;He built the basilica of his own name (i.e. the Liberian Basilica) near the Macellum of Livia&amp;quot;. It's prevalence in the 15th century is shown in the painting or the Miracle of the Snow by Masaccio and Masolino da Panicale. The feast was originally called Dedicatio Sanctae Mariae (Dedication of Saint Mary's), and was celebrated only in Rome until inserted for the first time into the General Roman Calendar , with ad Nives added to its name, in 1568. A congregation appointed by Pope Benedict XIV in 1741 proposed that the reading of the legend be struck from the Office and that the feast be given its original name. No action was taken on the proposal until 1969, when the reading of the legend was removed and the feast was called In dedicatione Basilicae S. Mariae (Dedication of the Basilica of Saint Mary). The legend is still commemorated by dropping white rose petals from the dome during the celebration of the Mass and Second Vespers of the feast. Another name is the Liberian Basilica or Santa Maria Liberiana, after Pope Liberius (352-366). This name may have originated from the same legend, which recounts that, like John and his wife, Pope Liberius was told in a dream of the forthcoming summer snowfall, went in procession to where it did occur and there marked out the area on which the church was to be built. On the other hand, the name &amp;quot;Liberian Basilica&amp;quot; may be independent of the legend, since, according to Pius Parsch, Pope Liberius transformed a palace of the Sicinini family into a church, which was for that reason called the Sicinini Basilica. This building was then replaced under Pope Sixtus III (432-440) by the present structure dedicated to Mary. However, some sources say that the adaptation as a church of a pre-existing building on the site of the present basilica was done in the 420s under Pope Celestine I, the immediate predecessor of Sixtus III. Long before the earliest traces of the story of the miraculous snow, the church now known as Saint Mary Major was called Saint Mary of the Crib (Sancta Maria ad Praesepe), a name it was given because of its relic of the crib or manger of the Nativity of Jesus Christ, four boards of sycamore wood believed to have been brought to the church, together with a fifth, in the time of Pope Theodore (640-649). This name appears in the Tridentine editions of the Roman Missal as the place for the Pope's Mass (the station Mass) on Christmas Night, while the name &amp;quot;Mary Major&amp;quot; appears for the church of the station Mass on Christmas Day. According to the 1929 Lateran Treaty, the basilica, located in Italian territory, is owned by the Holy See and enjoys extraterritorial status similar to that of foreign embassies. The building is patrolled internally by police agents of Vatican City State, not by Italian police." id="6261639883" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="15" tags="" title="Rome" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6235/6261639883_ca7d83ef5c_b.jpg" username="Oggie Dog" views="144" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-03-10 23:24:30" description="The Cathedral of Saint Mary of the See (Spanish: Catedral de Santa María de la Sede), better known as Seville Cathedral, is a Roman Catholic cathedral in Seville (Andalusia, Spain). It is the largest Gothic cathedral and the third-largest church in the world. The total area covers 11,520 square meters. After its completion in the early 16th century, Seville Cathedral supplanted Hagia Sophia,Istanbl as the largest cathedral in the world, a title the Byzantine church had held for nearly a thousand years. The cathedral also serves as the burial site of Christopher Columbus. The cathedral was built to demonstrate Seville's wealth, as it had become a major trading center in the years after the Reconquista in 1248. In July 1401 it was decided to build a new temple, as the ancient Muslim mosque was in bad shape after a 1356 earthquake. According to the oral tradition of Seville, the decision of members of the chapter was: &amp;quot;Let a church so beautiful and so great that those who see it built will think we were mad&amp;quot;. According to the minutes of that day, the new church should be: &amp;quot;a work such as good, which like no other.&amp;quot; Construction began in 1402; it continued until 1506. Seville Cathedral was built on the same large, rectangular base-plan of the grand Almohad Mosque it replaced, but the Christian architects added the extra dimension of height. The result is an astonishingly large building that breaks several size records. Measured by area, Seville Cathedral is the third largest in Europe after after St. Paul's Cathedral in London and St. Peter's Basilica in Rome, but measured by volume, it surpasses them both. The builders used some columns and elements from the mosque, and most famously the Giralda, a minaret converted into a bell tower( bell tower or giralda not in the picture as it is on the other side). : Two parts of the mosque were thankfully preserved in the cathedral: the Moorish entrance court (Patio de los Naranjos); and the Giralda, originally a minaret, converted into a bell tower.The Giralda is the city's most famous symbol. Its square base is 13.61 metres and a height of 105 metres. It was built as a minaret of the old mosque, although the bell tower and spire top, is Renaissance. The huge interior of the cathedral, with a central nave and four side aisles, is lavishly decorated. Gold is everywhere. But at the same time, there is a sense of overall simplicity and restraint in decoration, for the grand monuments are confined to the side aisles and the huge nave is left mostly empty. The supreme masterpiece of the cathedral was the life's work of a single craftsman, Fleming Pieter Dancart. Composed of 45 carved scenes from the life of Christ, it is carved in wood and covered with staggering amounts of gold. It is the largest and richest altarpiece in the world. Other notable works of art in the cathedral include 15th-century stained-glass windows and the iron screens (rejas) closing off the chapels. During Corpus Christi and Immaculate Conception observances, altar boys with castanets dance in front of the high altar." id="6971388215" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="58" rank="16" tags="cathedral seville saint mary stmary cathedralseville de sants maria roman catholic largest gothic spain andalusia chirstopher columbus tomb gothicarchitecture architecture chapels ancient almohad mohads muslim mosque reconquista columns elements giralda minaret belltower spainvisit spaintrip february12 nikon d90 rejik" title="Cathedral of Saint Mary of the See, Seville, Spain" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7186/6971388215_61be4b780e_b.jpg" username="-RejiK" views="250" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-21 21:26:40" description="The Basilica of St Paul Outside the Walls or St Paul-without-the-Walls (Italian: Basilica di San Paolo fuori le Mura) is one of four churches considered to be the great ancient basilicas of Rome. The Roman Catholic Church counts among them St. John Lateran, St. Mary Major, and St. Peter's. Cardinal Andrea Cordero Lanza di Montezemolo, named in 2005, is the current archpriest of this basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_of_Saint_Paul_Outside_the_Walls&quot;&gt;Read the article on wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;" id="2960612702" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="4" rank="17" tags="basilica san paolo roma fuori le mura" title="Basilica of Saint Paul Outside the Walls" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3196/2960612702_7e6199aab9_b.jpg" username="sgatto" views="268" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-10 02:06:50" description="The Basilica of St Paul Outside the Walls or St Paul-without-the-Walls (Italian: Basilica di San Paolo fuori le Mura) is one of four churches considered to be the great ancient basilicas of Rome. As well as St Paul's, the Roman Catholic Church counts among them St. John Lateran, St. Mary Major, and St. Peter's. The basilica was founded by the Roman Emperor Constantine I over the burial place of Saint Paul, where it was said that, after the Apostle's execution, his followers erected a memorial, called a cella memoriae, over his grave. This first edifice was expanded under Valentinian I. In 386, Emperor Theodosius I began the erection of a much larger and more beautiful basilica with a nave and four aisles with a transept; the work including the mosaics was not completed till the pontificate of Leo I. In the 5th century it was even larger than the Old St. Peter's Basilica. The Christian poet Prudentius, who saw it at the time of emperor Honorius, describes the splendours of the monument in a few, expressive lines. As it was dedicated also to Saints Taurinus and Herculanus, martyrs of Ostia in the 5th century, it was called the basilica trium Dominorum (&amp;quot;basilica of Three Lords&amp;quot;). Under Gregory the Great (590-604) the basilica was again extensively modified: the pavement was raised, in order to place the altar directly over Paul's tomb. A confession permitted the access to the Apostle's sepulcher. In that period there were two monasteries near the basilica: St. Aristus's for men and St. Stefano's for women. Masses were carried out by a special body of clerics instituted by Pope Simplicius. In the course of time the monasteries and the clergy of the basilica declined; Pope Saint Gregory II restored the former and entrusted the monks with the care of the basilica. As it lay outside the Aurelian Walls, the basilica was damaged during the Saracen invasions in the 9th century. In consequence of this Pope John VIII fortified the basilica, the monastery, and the dwellings of the peasantry, forming the town of Joannispolis (Italian: Giovannipoli: it existed until 1348 when an earthquake totally destroyed it. In 937, when Saint Odo of Cluny came to Rome, Alberic II of Spoleto, Patrician of Rome, entrusted the monastery and basilica to his congregation and Odo placed Balduino of Monte Cassino in charge. Pope Gregory VII was abbot of the monastery and in his time Pantaleone of Amalfi presented the bronze doors of the basilica maior, which were executed by Constantinopolitan artists. Pope Martin V entrusted it to the monks of the Congregation of Monte Cassino. It was then made an abbey nullius. The jurisdiction of the abbot extended over the districts of Civitella San Paolo, Leprignano and Nazzano, all of which formed parishes; the parish of San Paolo in Rome, however, is under the jurisdiction of the cardinal vicar. The graceful cloister of the monastery was erected between 1220 and 1241. From 1215 until 1964 it was the seat of the Latin Patriarch of Alexandria. From: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Paul_outside_the_Walls&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Paul_outside_the_Walls&lt;/a&gt;" id="3388821339" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="rome st paul outside walls" title="The Basilica of St Paul Outside the Walls" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3620/3388821339_cf15b78a20_b.jpg" username="Northfielder" views="577" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-10 04:29:56" description="Arnolfo di Cambio's &amp;quot;Crib&amp;quot; The spiritual and sentimental image of the reconstruction of the &amp;quot;Crib&amp;quot; in remembrance of the venerated event of Christ's birth, originated in 432 when Pope Sixtus III (432-440) created, within the primitive Basilica, a &amp;quot;cave of the Nativity&amp;quot; similar to that in Bethlehem. Numerous pilgrims returning to Rome from the Holy Land, brought back precious fragments of the Holy Crib (cunambulum), which are now kept in the golden Confessional shrine. During the following centuries several popes took care of Sixtus III's Holy Cave, until Pope Nicolò IV in 1288 commissioned a sculpture of the &amp;quot;Nativity&amp;quot; by Arnolfo di Cambio. Many changes and reconstructions took place in the basilica. When Pope Sixtus V (1585-1590) wished to erect the large Chapel of the Blessed Sacrament or Sistina in the right nave, he ordered the architect Domenico Fontana to transfer, without dismantling, the ancient &amp;quot;cave of the Nativity&amp;quot; with its surviving elements of Arnolfo di Cambio's sculpture. The three Magi, dressed in elegant vestments and shoes in a rough gothic style, and Saint Joseph admire with a sense of wonder and reverence the miracle of the Baby in the Virgin Mary's arms (of P. Olivieri) warmed by the ox and the donkey. From: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vatican.va/various/basiliche/sm_maggiore/en/storia/interno.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.vatican.va/various/basiliche/sm_maggiore/en/storia/in...&lt;/a&gt;" id="3388802301" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="rome italy" title="Arnolfo di Cambio's &quot;Crib&quot; Inside the Patriarchal Basilica of St. Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3212/3388802301_65f6465852_b.jpg" username="Northfielder" views="133" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-10 04:22:23" description="Arnolfo di Cambio's &amp;quot;Crib&amp;quot; The spiritual and sentimental image of the reconstruction of the &amp;quot;Crib&amp;quot; in remembrance of the venerated event of Christ's birth, originated in 432 when Pope Sixtus III (432-440) created, within the primitive Basilica, a &amp;quot;cave of the Nativity&amp;quot; similar to that in Bethlehem. Numerous pilgrims returning to Rome from the Holy Land, brought back precious fragments of the Holy Crib (cunambulum), which are now kept in the golden Confessional shrine. During the following centuries several popes took care of Sixtus III's Holy Cave, until Pope Nicolò IV in 1288 commissioned a sculpture of the &amp;quot;Nativity&amp;quot; by Arnolfo di Cambio. Many changes and reconstructions took place in the basilica. When Pope Sixtus V (1585-1590) wished to erect the large Chapel of the Blessed Sacrament or Sistina in the right nave, he ordered the architect Domenico Fontana to transfer, without dismantling, the ancient &amp;quot;cave of the Nativity&amp;quot; with its surviving elements of Arnolfo di Cambio's sculpture. The three Magi, dressed in elegant vestments and shoes in a rough gothic style, and Saint Joseph admire with a sense of wonder and reverence the miracle of the Baby in the Virgin Mary's arms (of P. Olivieri) warmed by the ox and the donkey. From: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vatican.va/various/basiliche/sm_maggiore/en/storia/interno.htm&quot;&gt;www.vatican.va/various/basiliche/sm_maggiore/en/storia/in...&lt;/a&gt;" id="3388802073" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="rome italy" title="Arnolfo di Cambio's &quot;Crib&quot; Inside the Patriarchal Basilica of St. Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3457/3388802073_e317a03c5b_b.jpg" username="Northfielder" views="346" />
<photo  date_taken="2013-03-06 10:35:45" description="The Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major (Italian: Basilica Papale di Santa Maria Maggiore, Latin: Basilica Sanctae Mariae Maioris),[2][3][4] known also by other names, is the largest Roman Catholic Marian church in Rome, Italy. There are other churches in Rome dedicated to Mary, such as Santa Maria in Trastevere, Santa Maria in Aracoeli, Santa Maria sopra Minerva, but the greater size of the Basilica of Saint Mary Major justifies the adjective by which it is distinguished from the other 25. According to the 1929 Lateran Treaty, the basilica, located in Italian territory, is owned by the Holy See and enjoys extraterritorial status similar to that of foreign embassies.[Notes 2] The building is patrolled internally by police agents of Vatican City State, not by Italian police. It is located on Piazza del Esquilino, number 34, some five blocks Southwest of the Stazione Termini. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_of_Saint_Mary_Major&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basilica_of_Saint_Mary_Major&lt;/a&gt;" id="8549215225" latitude="41.897925" license="4" longitude="12.497997" nbComments="1" rank="21" tags="piazza rome santamariamaggiore church roma lazio italy" title="Santa Maria Maggiore - ND0_4598.CR2" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8100/8549215225_af280cbedc_b.jpg" username="Nicola since 1972" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-28 15:29:51" description="Today, ,8 August, is St Dominic's day! The inscription in the book held by St Dominic reads: &amp;quot;Draw me after you&amp;quot;, a quotation from the Song of Songs. In this altarpiece in one of the side chapels in St Mary Major, the saint is shown pointing to Our Lady. On his right is St Philip Neri." id="1049327661" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="santamariamaggiore stmarymajor rome stdominic liberian basilica" title="Trahe me post te" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1396/1049327661_ef27c624b8_b.jpg" username="Lawrence OP" views="799" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-12 17:03:24" description="Rarely seen because they are largely hidden from view by a facade added in 1743 to the front of the basilica of Sta Maria Maggiore in Rome, these medieval mosaics once adorned the former 12th-century facade of the church. St Paul is shown between another apostle (possibly St James) and the Virgin Mary with the eagle of St John the Evangelist overhead. In his hand he holds the sword of his martyrdom and a scroll of his writings, which reads: &amp;quot;For me to live is Christ&amp;quot; (Philippians 1:21)." id="6759200423" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="rome santamariamaggiore stpaul virginmary eagle stjohn mosaic facade saint apostle" title="St Paul at St Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7147/6759200423_3583732277_b.jpg" username="Lawrence OP" views="238" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-23 18:06:07" description="Antonio Ghislieri was born in 1504 in Bosco, Italy. At the age of fourteen he received the habit of the Friars Preachers (Dominicans), taking the name Michael. He was ordained in 1528 and became a lector, taught sacred theology and was prior of several communities, being known for the integrity and austerity of his life. In 1551 he was appointed Commissary General of the Roman Inquisition, afterwards become bishop of Nepi and Sutri. In 1557 he was named cardinal by Paul IV and in 1560 he was given the Piedmontese diocese of Mondovi by Pius IV. On 7 January 1566 he was elected to the highest pastoral office, taking the name Pius. Supported by St Charles Borromeo, he dedicated himself to the salvation of the souls and the reform of the Church. He strenuously defended the Catholic faith against the Reformers, concerned himself with the propagation of that faith, and put into effect the decrees of the Council of Trent. He radically reformed the Roman curia; he published the Roman Catechism (1566); he promoted as a solid formation for seminarians the Summa Theologiae of St Thomas Aquinas, whom he named the fifth ‘angelic’ Latin Doctor of the Church in 1567; he efficaciously promoted the unity and renewal of the liturgy, promulgating new editions of the Roman Breviary (1568) and Missal (1570); he upheld the unity of the dogmatic traditions of East and West, honouring four major doctors of each. He stood against those who opposed the faith with all his power, notably in the naval expedition against the Turks at Lepanto (1571), attributing the victory to the intercession of Our Lady of the Rosary, in whose honour he instituted a feast in 1572. He had a most holy death in Rome on 1 May 1572, was beatified one-hundred years later by Clement X, and was canonized by Clement XI on 22 May 1712. His body is venerated at the basilica of St Mary Major, Rome. Today, 30 April, is his feast day, and this statue of the saint is in the Dominican priory church of San Pablo in Valladolid." id="6981419904" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="24" tags="piusv pope dominican friar sanpablo valladolid" title="Pope St Pius V" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8163/6981419904_b7675d2c8f_b.jpg" username="Lawrence OP" views="404" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-02 15:04:48" description="LUKE WADDING OFM Historian and theologian, born at Waterford, Ireland, 16 October, 1588; died at Rome, 18 November, 1657. He was the son of Walter Wadding, a citizen of eminence, and Anastasia Lombard, a near relation of Peter Lombard, Archbishop of Armagh. He was the eleventh of fourteen children and was baptized on the feast of St. Luke. Many members of his family distinguished themselves in their various careers. His brother Ambrose, the Jesuit, taught philosophy with applause at Dillingen, Bavaria, where he died in the flower of his age. His cousins Richard Wadding, the Augustinian, and Peter and Michael Wadding, Jesuits, shed lustre on their respective orders. He was brought up piously by his excellent parents, who, Harold tells us, required all their children, boys and girls, when able to read, to recite daily the Little Office of the Blessed Virgin, and, at stated times, the Penitential psalms with the litanies and orations, the Office of the Dead, and other prayers contained in the so-called minor breviary of Pius V, then much in use among Catholics in Ireland. At the age of thirteen he had already acquired a good knowledge of the Classics, and had learned to write Latin, prose and verse, with facility. The excellence of his early classic training shows out through all his writings. He lost both parents at the age of fourteen, but his brother Matthew took charge of his education and put him to study philosophy. He read logic and part of physics in Ireland, and then entered the Irish seminary at Lisbon, prosecuting his studies under the Jesuits. After six months he left the seminary to enter the novitiate of the Friars Minor in the Convent of the Immaculate Conception at Matozinhos, near Oporto. Having made solemn profession and received minor orders in 1605, his superiors sent him to Leyria, the house of studies, to specialize in Scotistic philosophy for two years. Richard Synott, of Wexford, companion of Wadding's novitiate and studies, and afterwards Guardian of S. Isidore's, Rome, died a martyr in Ireland at the hands of the soldiers of Cromwell. Wadding read theology at Lisbon, and then for three years at Coimbra, hearing in this latter place Didacus Limadensis, O.F.M., at the College of S. Bonaventure, and Francisco Suárez and Ægidius a Praesentatione, O.S.A., at the university. The Benedictine monk Leo a S. Thomas bears witness to the great talents he displayed (see Harold, &amp;quot;Vita&amp;quot;, c.v.). Ordained priest in 1613 and commissioned to preach, he showed himself a perfect master not only of rhetorical art but of the Portuguese and Castilian languages. He commenced in 1613 to draw up a sylva or commonplace-book of quotations from the Scripture, the Fathers, the lives of the saints, etc., which is still preserved in two large volumes of manuscript in the archives in the order at Merchant's Quay, Dublin. After a brilliant academic display at Lisbon during a provincial chapter, Antony a Trejo, the vicar-general of the order, sent him to Salamanca for fuller opportunities. Here he mastered Hebrew, composed his work on the origin and excellence of that tongue, and was assigned the chair of theology in the College of St. Francis. He filled the office of professor till 1618, when, though only in his thirtieth year, he was chosen by Philip III for the office of theologian in the embassy which Philip was then sending to Paul V to promote the doctrine of the Immaculate Conception. Antony a Trejo, Bishop of Cartagena, who, as vicar-general of the order, had been Wadding's patron and admirer, was the legate-extraordinary appointed for the purpose. Leaving the Court of the Catholic King on 1 October, 1618, the embassy reached Rome on 17 Dec. In search of materials for the work entrusted to him, as well as for his other studies. Wadding spent whole days in the libraries of Rome. In May, 1620, the legate returned to his diocese in Spain, but Wadding was ordered to remain in Rome to assist the new chargé d'affaires. While the commission lasted he was its accredited theological adviseR. When he arrived at Rome in 1618 he found the name of Ireland partly ignominiously ignored, partly (owing to the wiles of her traditional enemies) disparaged and reviled. But he lost no opportunity of rectifying matters, and soon succeeded in making Ireland known and respected. Wadding was not only the official representative and indefatigable agent in the Roman Curia of the archbishops and bishops of Ireland, but the Holy See took no measure of importance concerning that country without consulting him. The Supreme Council of the Confederates, by letters patent of 6 December, 1642, nominated their agent and procurator in Rome and the whole of Italy. It was at his suggestion that Father Scarampi, the Oratorian, was sent in 1643 as papal envoy to Ireland, with supplies of arms, and ammunition, and money. Wadding had sent similar supplies in the preceding year, as well as Irish officers trained in the armies of France and the Netherlands. He procured letters from the Holy See to the Catholic powers of Europe to enlist their sympathies and secure their aid in favour of the Irish war. In 1645 he prevailed on the new pope, Innocent X, to send another envoy to Ireland, with the powers and dignity of an Apostolic nuncio, Archbishop Rinuccini being sent. On his departure from Rome the nuncio received from Wadding the sum of 26,000 scudi towards the Irish cause. Wadding sent him a similar sum the year after through Dean Massari, to mention only some of his contributions. Great was the interest now evinced in Irish affairs at the Roman Court. The tidings of O'Neill's victory at Benburb (5 June, 1646) caused much rejoicing; a solemn Te Deum was sung in the Basilica of St. Mary Major, and the standards taken in the battle, being sent out by the nuncio, were hung as trophies in the cupola of St. Peter's. Innocent X, through Wadding, sent is blessing to Owen Roe O'Neill and with it the sword of the great Earl of Tyrone. But jealousy and disunion among the Confederate chiefs ruined all, and no one felt the blow so much as Wadding. The Catholic Encyclopaedia" id="3858730164" latitude="52.260514" license="1" longitude="-7.106781" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="statues sculpture ireland irish art ruinsinireland irishruins ruinsofireland normanruins normanchurches antiquitiesofireland irishantiquities limestone drystone" title="Luke Wadding OFM in Waterford" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2518/3858730164_61de95a712_b.jpg" username="Fergal Mac Eoinin" views="627" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-21 03:39:59" description="Vatican Museums - Pinacoteca - Pietro Perugino : Saint Flavia (1495-1498) Pietro Perugino (ca.1446/1450–1523), born Pietro Vannucci, was an Italian Renaissance painter of the Umbrian school, who developed some of the qualities that found classic expression in the High Renaissance. Raphael was his most famous pupil. He was born in Città della Pieve, Umbria, the son of Cristoforo Vannucci; his nickname characterizes him as from Perugia, the chief city of Umbria. Despite what stated by his biographer Giorgio Vasari, the Vannucci were one of the richest in the town. His exact date of birth is not known, although, basing on his age at the death mentioned by Vasari and Giovanni Santi, it has been dated between 1446 and 1452. He most likely began to study painting in Perugia, in local workshops such as those of Bartolomeo Caporali or Fiorenzo di Lorenzo. The date of this first Florentine sojourn is unknown; some make it as early as 1466/1470, others push the date to 1479. According to Vasari, he apprenticed in the workshop of Andrea del Verrocchio alongside Leonardo da Vinci, Domenico Ghirlandaio, Lorenzo di Credi, Filippino Lippi and others. He may have learned perspective from Piero della Francesca. In 1472 he must have completed his apprenticeship, for he was enrolled as a painter in the confraternity of St Luke. Perugino was one of the earliest Italian practitioners of oil painting. Some of his early works were extensive frescoes for the convent of the Ingessati fathers, destroyed during the siege of Florence; he produced for them also many cartoons, which they executed with brilliant effect in stained glass. A good specimen of his early style in tempera is the tondo (circular picture) in the Musée du Louvre of the Virgin and Child Enthroned between Saints. Perugino returned from Florence to Perugia, where his Florentine training showed in the Adoration of the Magi for the church of Santa Maria dei Servi of Perugia (c. 1476). In about 1480, he was called to Rome to fresco panels for the Sistine Chapel walls by Sixtus IV including Moses and Zipporah (often attributed to Luca Signorelli), the Baptism of Christ, and Delivery of the Keys. Pinturicchio accompanied Perugino to Rome, and was made his partner, receiving a third of the profits. He may have done some of the Zipporah subject. The Sistine frescoes were the major high Renaissance commission in Rome. The altar wall was also painted with the Assumption, the Nativity, and Moses in the Bulrushes. These works were later destroyed to make a space for Michelangelo's Last Judgement, The Delivery of the Keys fresco, 1481–1482, Sistine Chapel, Rome. Perugino, aged forty, left Rome after completion of the Sistine Chapel work in 1486, and by autumn was in Florence. Here he figured in a criminal court case. In July 1487 he and another Perugian painter named Aulista di Angelo were convicted, on their own confession, of having in December waylaid with staves someone (the name does not appear) in the streets near Pietro Maggiore. Perugino merely intended assault and battery, but Aulista meant to commit murder. The more illustrious culprit, guilty of the lesser offence, was fined ten gold florins, and the other was exiled for life. Between 1486 and 1499 Perugino worked chiefly in Florence, making one journey to Rome and several to Perugia, where he may have maintained a second studio. He had an established studio in Florence, and received a great number of commissions. His Pietà (1483–1493) in the Uffizi is an uncharacteristically stark work that avoids Perugino's sometimes too easy sentimental piety. In 1499 the guild of the cambio (money-changers or bankers) of Perugia asked him to decorate their audience-hall, the Sala delle Udienze del Collegio del Cambio. The humanist Francesco Maturanzio acted as his consultant. This extensive scheme, which may have been finished by 1500, comprised the painting of the vault with the seven planets and the signs of the zodiac (Perugino being responsible for the designs and his pupils most probably for the execution) and the representation on the walls of two sacred subjects: the Nativity and Transfiguration; in addition, the Eternal Father, the cardinal virtues of Justice, Prudence, Temperance and Fortitude, Cato as the emblem of wisdom, and numerous life-sized figures of classic worthies, prophets and sibyls figured in the program. On the mid-pilaster of the hall Perugino placed his own portrait in bust-form. It is probable that Raphael, who in boyhood, towards 1496, had been placed by his uncles under the tuition of Perugino, bore a hand in the work of the vaulting. Perugino was made one of the priors of Perugia in 1501. On one occasion Michelangelo told Perugino to his face that he was a bungler in art (goffo nell arte): Vannucci brought an action for defamation of character, unsuccessfully. Put on his mettle by this mortifying transaction, he produced the masterpiece of the Madonna and Saints for the Certosa of Pavia, now disassembled and scattered among museums: the only portion in the Certosa is God the Father with cherubim. An Annunciation has disappeared; three panels, the Virgin adoring the infant Christ, St. Michael and St. Raphael with Tobias are among the treasures of the National Gallery, London. This was succeeded in 1504-1507 by the Annunziata Altarpiece for the high altar of the Basilica dell'Annunziata in Florence, in which he replaced Filippino Lippi. The work was a failure, being accused of lack of innovation. Perugino lost his students; and towards 1506 he once more and finally abandoned Florence, going to Perugia, and thence in a year or two to Rome. Pope Julius II had summoned Perugino to paint the Stanza of the Incendio del Borgo in the Vatican City; but he soon preferred a younger competitor, Raphael, who had been trained by Perugino; and Vannucci, after painting the ceiling with figures of God the Father in different glories, in five medallion-subjects, retired from Rome to Perugia from 1512. Among his latest works, many of which decline into repetitious studio routine, one of the best is the extensive altarpiece (painted between 1512 and 1517) of the church of San Agostino in Perugia, also now dispersed. Perugino's last frescoes were painted for the church of the Madonna delle Lacrime in Trevi (1521, signed and dated), the monastery of Sant'Agnese in Perugia, and in 1522 for the church of Castello di Fortignano. Both series have disappeared from their places, the second being now in the Victoria and Albert Museum. He was still at Fontignano in 1523 when he died of the plague. Like other plague victims, he was hastily buried in an unconsecrated field, the precise spot now unknown. Vasari is the main source stating that Perugino had very little religion, and openly doubted the soul's immortality. Perugino in 1494 painted his own portrait, now in the Uffizi Gallery, and into this he introduced a scroll lettered Timete Deum. That an open disbeliever should inscribe himself with Timete Deum seems odd. The portrait in question shows a plump face, with small dark eyes, a short but well-cut nose, and sensuous lips; the neck is thick, the hair bushy and frizzled, and the general air imposing. The later portrait in the Cambio of Perugia shows the same face with traces of added years. Perugino died possessed of considerable property, leaving three sons. Gonfalone with Pietà, c. 1472. In 1495 he signed and dated a Deposition for the Florentine convent of Santa Chiara (Palazzo Pitti). Towards 1496 he frescoed a Crucifixion, commissioned in 1493 for Maria Maddalena de' Pazzi, Florence (the Pazzi Crucifixion). The attribution to him of the picture of the marriage of Joseph and the Virgin Mary (the Sposalizio) now in the museum of Caen, which indisputably served as the original, to a great extent, of the still more famous Sposalizio painted by Raphael in 1504 (Accademia di Brera, Milan), is now questioned, and it is assigned to Lo Spagna. A vastly finer work of Perugino's was the polyptych of the Ascension of Christ painted ca 1496–98 for the church of S. Pietro of Perugia, (Municipal Museum, Lyon); the other portions of the same altarpiece are dispersed in other galleries. In the chapel of the Disciplinati of Città della Pieve is an Adoration of the Magi, a square of 6.5 m containing about thirty life-sized figures; this was executed, with scarcely credible celerity, from the 1st to 25 March (or thereabouts) in 1505, and must no doubt be in great part the work of Vannucci's pupils. In 1507, when the master's work had for years been in a course of decline and his performances were generally weak, he produced. nevertheless, one of his best; pictures — the Virgin between Saint Jerome and Saint Francis, how in the Palazzo Penna. In the church of S. Onofrio in Florence is a much lauded and much debated fresco of the Last Supper, a careful and blandly correct but uninspired work; it has been ascribed to Perugino by some connoisseurs, by others to Raphael; it may more probably be by some different pupil of the Umbrian master. Among his pupils were Raphael, upon whose early work Perugino's influence is most noticeable, and Giovanni di Pietro (lo Spagna)." id="6226679061" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="" title="Stato della Città del Vaticano" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6158/6226679061_3794150d6f_b.jpg" username="Oggie Dog" views="310" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-08 12:57:21" description="" id="6053579943" latitude="41.89816" license="1" longitude="12.497624" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="rome roma basilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicadisantamariamaggiore church romancatholic" title="rome - papal basilica of saint mary major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6190/6053579943_c86c425c38_b.jpg" username="drencrome" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-29 13:50:35" description="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" id="4281645727" latitude="41.89611" license="1" longitude="12.499166" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="building church religion christian infocus highquality italy roma rome unesco romancatholic basilicadisantamariamaggiore basilica basilicasanctaemariaemajorisadnives basilicaofsaintmarymajor catholic patriarchalbasilicas papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor majorbasilica" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2691/4281645727_b54106091a_b.jpg" username="CyberMacs" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-29 13:50:43" description="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" id="4281653431" latitude="41.896389" license="1" longitude="12.499166" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="building church religion christian infocus highcontrast highquality italy roma rome unesco romancatholic basilicadisantamariamaggiore basilica basilicasanctaemariaemajorisadnives basilicaofsaintmarymajor catholic patriarchalbasilicas papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor majorbasilica" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2501/4281653431_042faec0e5_b.jpg" username="CyberMacs" views="53" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-29 13:50:26" description="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" id="4282381418" latitude="41.89611" license="1" longitude="12.499166" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="building church religion christian infocus highcontrast highquality italy roma rome unesco romancatholic basilicadisantamariamaggiore basilica basilicasanctaemariaemajorisadnives basilicaofsaintmarymajor catholic patriarchalbasilicas papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor majorbasilica" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2724/4282381418_f7bc5ebf48_b.jpg" username="CyberMacs" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-12 01:43:27" description="Tallest campanile in Rome, rebuilt 1370-1378 with the top added in the 16th century. The church dates from the 5th centry, though it has been remodeled several times." id="3607726106" latitude="41.89702" license="3" longitude="12.499002" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="rome roma italy europe basilicadisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore church basilica santamariamaggiore worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite campanile" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3605/3607726106_778c0832b0_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="120" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-03-25 11:36:23" description="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore, Rome The Piazza dell'Esquilino with the apse area of Santa Maria Maggiore." id="1320765588" latitude="41.897533" license="4" longitude="12.498761" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="basilicadisantamariamaggiore santamariamaggiore saintmarymajor" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1218/1320765588_1d38bda760_b.jpg" username="rjhuttondfw" views="275" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-12 01:44:26" description="The façade by Ferdinando Fuga is from the 18th century." id="3606906815" latitude="41.897268" license="3" longitude="12.49911" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="rome roma italy europe basilicadisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore church basilica santamariamaggiore worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite chiaroscuro" title="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2475/3606906815_e941c6b723_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="98" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-17 21:53:45" description="" id="3928839235" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore italy papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor rome" title="_DSC0452" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3441/3928839235_cf758687b2_b.jpg" username="Peter Lundgren" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:43:01" description="" id="6565834863" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7171/6565834863_6475f025fb_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:39:36" description="" id="6565779863" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7158/6565779863_cacff6b649_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:39:41" description="" id="6565833677" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7007/6565833677_b986612ba9_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:39:47" description="" id="6565833877" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7148/6565833877_de3eea9d7c_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:38:37" description="" id="6565779705" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7025/6565779705_d3eedd7990_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:43:50" description="" id="6565835817" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7035/6565835817_2623b91e55_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:43:05" description="" id="6565835257" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7023/6565835257_ec1c3e8ba6_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:42:12" description="" id="6565834385" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7161/6565834385_1d95ec4b56_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:35:17" description="" id="6565754129" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7172/6565754129_f0759ba246_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:33:40" description="" id="6565753977" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7024/6565753977_584f714740_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:46:39" description="" id="6565836645" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7165/6565836645_d980834c63_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:43:25" description="" id="6565835501" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="46" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7161/6565835501_d539983f11_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:36:42" description="" id="6565775201" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7003/6565775201_a179a591e6_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:32:04" description="" id="6565753765" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7141/6565753765_0cb40d06d8_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:43:53" description="" id="6565836211" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7008/6565836211_2f91f41cc1_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:36:08" description="" id="6565774637" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7012/6565774637_dc74db2bd1_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:35:32" description="" id="6565774411" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7032/6565774411_f2c1cd9005_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:41:59" description="" id="6565834111" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7158/6565834111_d6a753867d_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:48:42" description="" id="6565838289" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7017/6565838289_e736e2a436_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:42:56" description="" id="6565834575" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7147/6565834575_b0c9d824fa_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:48:32" description="" id="6565837533" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7169/6565837533_84bd65195d_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:47:05" description="" id="6565836959" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7174/6565836959_79b8d88af4_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:36:27" description="" id="6565774827" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7034/6565774827_bd27faf9e4_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:49:56" description="" id="6565837861" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7172/6565837861_43e4aa2b2e_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:38:09" description="" id="6565775581" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7033/6565775581_e5ea91a851_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-10-09 09:47:39" description="" id="6565837305" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="basilicapapaledisantamariamaggiore papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor roma rome italy" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7141/6565837305_115b9c908a_b.jpg" username="Heather F" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-03-10 09:42:55" description="Built over the pagan temple of Cybele, Santa Maria Maggiore is the only Roman basilica that retained the core of its original structure, left intact despite several additional construction projects and damage from the earthquake of 1348. This is the largest and most important place of prayer dedicated to the Blessed Virgin Mary. If you want you can see my most interesting photos in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://interestingby.isaias.com.mx/pm.php?id=70961014@N00&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;" id="416249653" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="juanillooo rome roma italia italy lazio church iglesia basilica hdr santamariamaggiore saintmarymajorbasilica liberianbasilica basilicaliberiana altar juansalmoral" title="Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/149/416249653_43dd86d933_b.jpg" username="J.Salmoral" views="2075" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-12 17:51:59" description="Rome: Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major- Detail-" id="5488772065" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="12" rank="62" tags="rome" title="PICT0172" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5091/5488772065_4969e70308_b.jpg" username="Vincenzo Spina" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-12 17:51:47" description="Rome: Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major- Obelisque-" id="5224098866" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="4" rank="63" tags="rome" title="PICT0171" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4125/5224098866_a9d62f4f98_b.jpg" username="Vincenzo Spina" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-12 17:47:17" description="Rome: Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major -Detail-" id="5537674098" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="6" rank="64" tags="rome" title="PICT0169" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5298/5537674098_d51b6c0076_b.jpg" username="Vincenzo Spina" views="18" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-12 18:53:33" description="Rome: Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major- Detail -" id="5488772071" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="8" rank="65" tags="rome" title="PICT0174" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5174/5488772071_eb30e3fc51_b.jpg" username="Vincenzo Spina" views="30" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-23 05:00:38" description="Rome: Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major at Night" id="5226876350" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="66" tags="rome" title="PICT0160" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5045/5226876350_e56e26f891_b.jpg" username="Vincenzo Spina" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-12 17:43:02" description="Rome: Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major- Tower Bell-" id="5224098880" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="67" tags="rome" title="PICT0168" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5005/5224098880_5cf005f357_b.jpg" username="Vincenzo Spina" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-12 18:47:31" description="Rome: Papal Basilica of Saint Mary Major - Facade 's Detail -" id="5224125880" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="68" tags="rome" title="PICT0170" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5281/5224125880_61bbf09a76_b.jpg" username="Vincenzo Spina" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-07 02:57:52" description="Basilica di Santa Maria Maggiore, Rome The Sistine Chapel The altar in the center of the Chapel by Sebastiano Torregiani" id="1320764228" latitude="41.897533" license="4" longitude="12.498761" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="basilicadisantamariamaggiore santamariamaggiore saintmarymajor" title="The Borghese (or Pauline) Chapel" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1138/1320764228_069eecbd2f_b.jpg" username="rjhuttondfw" views="58" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-29 13:50:49" description="The statue of Sixtus V" id="4282403210" latitude="41.896389" license="1" longitude="12.498888" nbComments="0" rank="70" tags="blurred highquality italy roma rome unesco basilicadisantamariamaggiore basilicasanctaemariaemajorisadnives basilicaofsaintmarymajor patriarchalbasilicas papalbasilicaofsaintmarymajor majorbasilica obelisks obelischi obeliskos ses obeliszk dikilitas obélisque obelisk ὀβελίσκοσ dikilitaş" title="The statue of Sixtus V" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4046/4282403210_d1bf51f4a8_b.jpg" username="CyberMacs" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-10 04:12:36" description="The façade is the magnificent work of Ferdinand Fuga (1741), and faces east, opening in a portico of five arcades on the lower story and three arches in the upper loggia, which covers the thirteenth-century mosaics of the previous façade. Like precious gems set into the façade, the mosaics illustrate the origin of the Basilica. In the first scene, the Blessed Virgin appears to Pope Liberius and the Roman Patrician John in the dream that will inspire the location of the new basilica. An exceptional event would confirm the divine will - on August 5, 358, a snowfall covered the Esquiline Hill and in this snow, the Pope traced the perimeter of the future basilica. Filippo Rusuti's majestic mosaics welcome visitors, arousing sentiments which draw man closer to the greatness of God. These precious remnants can only be visited through a special guided tour that gratifies the interest of those who contemplate these works of art. Both in the loggia and in the façade, Fuga's Baroque tastes and vivid sense of space are amply demonstrated by his architecture. The lower five arches form the portico and support the triple arch of the loggia. This play of open space lightens the heaviness of the columns and their decorative capitals, entablatures, cornices, garlands and cherubs. The statues accentuating the outline of the façade represent saintly Popes, as well as Saint Charles Borromeo and the Blessed Nicholas Albergati. Crowning the ensemble, as if hovering over from Heaven above, are the Madonna and Child. The façade seems almost like a tabernacle, allowing glimpses of the shimmering, polychrome mosaic concealed behind it. The foundation stone for this façade was laid on March 4, 1741 by Pope Benedict XIV. Many eighteenth-century sculptors contributed to this remarkable project. The works both within and outside of the Basilica were completed just in time for the Jubilee Year 1750. One hundred and fifty years separate the construction of the two palaces flanking the façade. Flaminio Ponzio built the structure on the right in 1605, while the second building was designed by Ferdinando Fuga in 1743 to give an overall uniformity to the site. Two graceful allegorical statues surmount the central entrance - Virginity by Giovanni Battista Maini, and Humility, carved by Pietro Bracci, who is also known for his sculptures at the Trevi Fountain. From: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vatican.va/various/basiliche/sm_maggiore/en/storia/facciata.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.vatican.va/various/basiliche/sm_maggiore/en/storia/fa...&lt;/a&gt;" id="3389612526" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="71" tags="rome italy" title="The Patriarchal Basilica of St. Mary Major" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3448/3389612526_3c5aede6be_b.jpg" username="Northfielder" views="161" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-01 09:46:40" description="The Dominican pope, St Pius V, is buried in the Sistine chapel in St Mary Major's; not to be confused with the Sistine chapel in the Vatican palace! This pope reformed and codified the Roman Missal, excommunicated Queen Elizabeth I and defeated the Turks at the Battle of Lepanto (thus saving Christian Europe). His body is on view in this chapel for the veneration of the faithful. It is said that the pope now wears white because this pope refused to shed the white habit of the Order of Preachers. The awful colour of the shrine is due to the lighting used to illuminate the saint's body - no amount of tweaking created a satisfactory effect..." id="1020638219" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="72" tags="stmarymajor mariamaggiore rome basilica liberian" title="The shrine and relic of Pope St Pius V" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1276/1020638219_6bfbb3ae31_b.jpg" username="Lawrence OP" views="1108" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-02-13 10:32:18" description="Basilica Papale di Santa Maria Maggiore | Basilica of Saint Mary Major #0590" id="4368094928" latitude="41.897669" license="3" longitude="12.498321" nbComments="1" rank="73" tags="basilica santa maria maggiore papal rome roma italia italy roman catholic church esquiline ceiling canon 500d canoneos500d efs1855mmf3556" title="Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2761/4368094928_c57b26b477_b.jpg" username="p_valdivieso" views="128" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-02-13 10:44:10" description="Basilica Papale di Santa Maria Maggiore | Basilica of Saint Mary Major #0591" id="4368097348" latitude="41.897345" license="3" longitude="12.49889" nbComments="0" rank="74" tags="basilica santa maria maggiore papal rome roma italia italy roman catholic church esquiline canon 500d canoneos500d efs1855mmf3556" title="Santa Maria Maggiore" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2776/4368097348_0929a819c3_b.jpg" username="p_valdivieso" views="80" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-01 16:09:36" description="One Dominican saint follows another... Tomorrow, 30 April, is the feast of St Pius V, who was pope from 1566-72. Born Antonio Ghisleri in 1504, he entered the Order of Preachers at the age of 16 and took the religious name Michele. He was ordained in 1528 and became was noted for his austerity and integrity of life. In 1551 he was named Commissary General of the Roman Inquisition and afterwards became bishop of Nepi and Sutri. In 1557 he was named cardinal by Paul IV and in 1560 he was given the Piedmontese diocese of Mondovi by Pius IV. On 7 January 1566 he was elected to the highest pastoral office, taking the name Pius. Supported by St Charles Borromeo, he devoted himself to the salvation of souls and the reform of the Church. He strenuously defended the Church against the Protestant reformers, concerned himself with the propagation of the faith and put into effect the decrees of the Council of Trent. He radically reformed the Roman Curia, published the Catechism of Trent (1566) and promoted the solid formation of seminarians, holding up St Thomas Aquinas as a teacher of the Catholic church and naming him the fifth 'angelic' doctor of the Church in 1567. He efficaciously promoted the unity and renewal of the liturgy, promulgating new editions of the Roman Breviary (1568) and Roman Missal (1570). he upheld the unity of the dogmatic traditions of East and West, honouring four major doctors of each. He stood against all those who opposed the faith with all his power, notably in the naval expedition against the Turks at Lepanto (1571), attributing the victory to the intercession of our Lady of the Rosary, in whose honourhe instituted a feast in 1572. He had a most holy death in Rome on 1 May 1572 and was beatified a hundred years later by Clement X and was canonised by Clement XI on 22 May 1712. His body is venerated at the basilica of St Mary Major in Rome. This window is part of the west window at the Dominican priory church of Hawkesyard." id="2452839698" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="75" tags="piusv saint pope dominican stained glass hawkesyard" title="Pope St Pius V" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2213/2452839698_94308c0dfc_b.jpg" username="Lawrence OP" views="857" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-01 09:47:56" description="As the inscription says, this is &amp;quot;The Body of Saint Pius V, Pontifex Maximus, from the Order of friars Preachers.&amp;quot; Today, 30 April, is his feast day. &amp;quot;The Second Vatican Council recalls that 'the Saints have been traditionally honoured in the Church, and their authentic relics and images held in veneration'. The term 'relics of the Saints' principally signifies the bodies - or notable parts of the bodies - of the Saints who, as distinguished members of Christ's mystical Body and as Temples of the Holy Spirit (cf. 1 Cor 3, 16; 6, 19; 2 Cor 6, 16) in virtue of their heroic sanctity, now dwell in Heaven, but who once lived on earth. Objects which belonged to the Saints, such as personal objects, clothes and manuscripts are also considered relics, as are objects which have touched their bodies or tombs such as oils, cloths, and images.&amp;quot; - Directory on Popular Piety and the Liturgy. St Pius V's shrine is in a side chapel of the basilica of St Mary Major, and I had to convert the photo to black &amp;amp; white because the body was illuminated by a ghastly fluorescent tube that gave the photo a most unnatural light." id="2453444819" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="76" tags="stpiusv pope dominican relics body shrine rome stamariasopraminerva liberian basilica tomb" title="Relics of Pope St Pius V" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2255/2453444819_b06d023646_b.jpg" username="Lawrence OP" views="1976" />
</photos>
