<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Booker T. Washington National Monument Virginia">

<photo  date_taken="2010-08-27 14:26:44" description="Taken from VA Hw 122 of part of the lands included in Booker T Washington National Monument." id="4946190435" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="virginia bookertwashington nationalmonument birthplace franklincounty" title="Booker T Washington Birthplace" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4084/4946190435_141157765b_b.jpg" username="jimmywayne" views="76" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-27 14:24:10" description="The national monument consists of the plantation lands where Washington was born. It is located along VA Hwy 122 near the Burnt Chimney community in Franklin County." id="4946749112" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="2" tags="virginia franklincounty burntchimney bookertwashington natioinalmonument birthplace" title="Booker T Washington National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4123/4946749112_689f59fbe8_b.jpg" username="jimmywayne" views="124" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 14:11:45" description="This is a reconstructed slave cabin at the Booker T. Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. This building had two floors with one room on each. The fireplace and kitchen were on the bottom floor. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4761960220&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Please view large&lt;/a&gt; or on the light box. :D" id="4761960220" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="1" rank="3" tags="buildings bookertwashingtonnationalmonument national monument slave cabin hdr fujifilm hs10" title="Reconstructed Slave Cabin" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4077/4761960220_e9be25ab42_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="143" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-18 11:49:16" description="This is my friend Bubba who I met at the Harvest Festival a few weeks ago at the Booker T Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. He's not much of a conversationalist but he dresses well. ;D &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=5073268879&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View On Black&lt;/a&gt;" id="5073268879" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="11" rank="4" tags="bookertwashingtonnationalmonument scarecrow hdr finepix hs10" title="Scarecrow Fence" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4129/5073268879_c1336258e8_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="85" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-27 14:26:35" description="Located on VA Hwy 122 near the Booker T Washington National Monument." id="4946190425" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="virginia franklincounty historic marker bookertwashington birthplace" title="Booker T Washington Birthplace Historic Marker" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4086/4946190425_8f12e53baa_b.jpg" username="jimmywayne" views="173" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-21 12:25:24" description="Booker Taliaferro Washington (April 5, 1856 – November 15, 1915) was an African American political leader, educator and author. He was one of the dominant figures in African American history from 1890 to 1915. He was born into slavery at the community of Hale's Ford in Franklin County, Virginia. As a young man he made his way east from West Virginia to obtain schooling at Hampton in eastern Virginia at a school established to train teachers. In his later years, Dr. Washington became a leading educator and was a prominent and popular spokesperson for African American citizens of the United States in the late 19th and early 20th century. Although labeled by some activists as an &amp;quot;accommodator&amp;quot;, his work cooperating with white people and enlisting the support of wealthy philanthropists helped raise funds to establish and operate dozens of small community schools and institutions of higher education for the betterment of black persons throughout the south. Within the context of the times he did much to improve the friendship and working relationship between the races. I will let no man drag me down so low as to make me hate him. During Reconstruction, after he was freed by the Emancipation Proclamation, Washington worked with his mother Jane as a salt-packer in a West Virginia facility, and, when he could, attended school. At 16, Washington worked odd jobs to make his way across Virginia to reach Elizabeth City County near Hampton Roads where he enrolled at the Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute (now Hampton University), in Hampton, Virginia. It was a school founded for the purpose of training black teachers and had been funded by individuals such as William Jackson Palmer, a Quaker, among others. From 1878 to 1879 he attended Wayland Seminary in Washington, D.C. In 1881 Booker T. Washington founded and became the first principal of the Normal School in Tuskegee, Alabama. It later developed into the Tuskegee Institute and Tuskegee University. Still an important center for African-American learning, the Institute was created to embody and enable the goals of self-reliance. He wed Olivia A. Davidson, his second wife, in 1885. She was a Hampton graduate and the assistant principal of Tuskegee. They had two sons, Booker T. Washington Jr. and Ernest Davidson Washington before she died in 1889. His third marriage took place in 1893 to Margaret James Murray who died in 1925. Active in politics, Booker T. Washington was routinely consulted by Congressmen and Presidents about the appointment of African Americans to political positions. He worked and socialized with many white politicians and notables. He argued that self-reliance was the key to improved conditions for African Americans in the United States and that they could not expect too much having only just been granted emancipation. His 1895 &amp;quot;Separate as the fingers&amp;quot; speech given at the Cotton States and International Exposition, Atlanta, Georgia sparked a controversy wherein he was cast as an accommodationist among those who heeded Frederick Douglass' call to &amp;quot;Agitate, Agitate, Agitate&amp;quot; for social change. A public debate soon began between those such as Washington, who valued the so-called &amp;quot;industrial&amp;quot; education and those who, like W. E. B. DuBois, supported the idea of a &amp;quot;classical&amp;quot; education among African Americans. Both sides sought to define the best means to improve the conditions of the post-antebellum African American community. Washington's advice to African Americans to &amp;quot;compromise&amp;quot; and accept segregation, incensed other activists of the time, such as DuBois, who labeled him &amp;quot;The Great Accommodator&amp;quot;. It should be noted, however, that despite not condemning Jim Crow laws and the inhumanity of lynching publicly, Washington privately contributed funds for legal challenges against segregation and disfranchisement (see Giles v. Harris (1903)). Although early in DuBois' career the two were friends and respected each other considerably, their political views diverged to the extent that after Washington's death, DuBois stated &amp;quot;In stern justice, we must lay on the soul of this man a heavy responsibility for the consummation of Negro disfranchisement, the decline of the Negro college and public school, and the firmer establishment of color caste in this land.&amp;quot; Henry H. Rogers 1840-1909Around 1894, Dr. Washington developed a friendship with millionaire industrialist and financier Henry Huttleston Rogers. The latter had attended one of his speeches in New York City, and had been surprised that no one had &amp;quot;passed the hat&amp;quot; afterwards. Rogers had risen from a working-class family in a small town to become a partner of John D. Rockefeller's Standard Oil Trust. With additional interests in natural gas, copper, mining, and railroads, Rogers was one of the wealthiest men in the world. Despite his great wealth, and widespread reputation for tough business dealings, Rogers was apparently both a modest and generous man. Dr. Washington became a frequent visitor to Rogers' office, to his family's 85-room mansion in Fairhaven, Massachusetts, and was an honored guest aboard Rogers' yacht Kanawha. Their friendship extended over a period of 15 years, during which time Rogers quietly financially supported and encouraged Washington in his work. Handbill from 1909 Tour of southern Virginia and West VirginiaAmong many other enterprises, Rogers was the builder of the Virginian Railway, completed in 1909. Although Rogers had died suddenly a few weeks earlier, Dr. Washington went on a previously arranged speaking tour in June, 1909 along the route of the new railroad which was built to transport bituminous coal from the mountains of West Virginia to port at Sewell's Point on Hampton Roads. Dr. Washington rode in Rogers' personal rail car, &amp;quot;Dixie&amp;quot;, making speeches at many locations over a 7-day period. He told his audiences that his recently departed friend, Henry Rogers, who was held in their esteem for having financed the railroad from his personal fortune, had urged him to make the trip and see what could be done to improve relations between the races and economic conditions for African Americans along the route of the new railway, which touched many previously isolated communities in the southern portions of Virginia and West Virginia. Some of the places where Dr. Washington spoke on the tour were (in order of the tour stops), Newport News, Norfolk, Suffolk, Lawrenceville, Kenbridge, Victoria, Charlotte Courthouse, Roanoke, Salem, and Christiansburg in Virginia, and Princeton, Mullens, Page and Deepwater in West Virginia. One of his trip companions reported that they had received a strong and favorable welcome from both white and African American citizens all along the tour route. It was only after the multi-millionaire's death that Dr. Washington said he felt compelled to reveal publicly some of the extent of Henry Rogers' contributions for his causes. The funds, he said, were at that very time, paying for the operation of at least 65 small country schools for the education and betterment of African Americans in Virginia and other portions of the South, all unknown to the recipients. Known only to a few trustees, Rogers had also generously provided support to institutions of higher education. Dr. Washington later wrote that Henry Rogers had encouraged projects with at least partial matching funds, as that way, two ends were accomplished: 1. The gifts would help fund even greater work. 2. Recipients would have a stake in knowing that they were helping themselves through their own hard work and sacrifice. In an effort to inspire the &amp;quot;commercial, agricultural, educational, and industrial advancement&amp;quot; of African Americans, Booker T. Washington founded the National Negro Business League (NNBL) in 1900. Booker T. Washington's coffin was being carried to grave site when his autobiography, Up From Slavery, was published in 1901, it became a bestseller and was one of the major influences to Marcus Garvey in the founding of the UNIA in Jamaica. He was also the first African-American ever invited to the White House as the guest of a President – which led to a scandal for the inviting President, Theodore Roosevelt. &amp;quot;Think about it: We went into slavery pagans; we came out Christians. We went into slavery pieces of property; we came out American citizens. We went into slavery with chains clanking about our wrists; we came out with the American ballot in our hands... Notwithstanding the cruelty and moral wrong of slavery, we are in a stronger and more hopeful condition, materially, intellectually, morally, and religiously, than is true of an equal number of black people in any other portion of the globe.&amp;quot; – from Up From Slavery Washington finally collapsed in Tuskegee, Alabama due to a lifetime of overwork and died soon after in a hospital, on November 14, 1915. For his contributions to American society, Dr. Washington was granted honorary degrees from Harvard University in 1896 and Dartmouth College. On April 5, 1956, the house where he was born in Hardy, Virginia was designated a United States National Monument. Additionally, the first coin to feature an African-American was the Booker T. Washington Memorial Half Dollar that was minted by the United States Mint from 1946 to 1951. On April 7, 1940, Dr. Washington became the first African American to be depicted on a United States postage stamp. Numerous schools across the country are named for him, including the Dallas Independent School District's Booker T. Washington High School for the Performing and Visual Arts and Booker T. Washington Magnet High School in Montgomery, Alabama where the choir there is outstanding." id="89685629" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="6" tags="" title="Booker T Washington" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/15/89685629_a7482d95a7_b.jpg" username="dbking" views="17123" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-22 12:30:22" description="Harvest Day, Booker T. Washington National Monument - September 2012 Check the detail &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=8024693442&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;large on black&lt;/a&gt; or in the light box. :D" id="8024693442" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="31" rank="7" tags="pottery wheel hands spin elderly arthritis art canon 60d artist virginia twtmeiconoftheday" title="Potter's Hands" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8181/8024693442_08c43b14dd_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="275" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-05-24 12:16:26" description="African-American Civil War Memorial 10th and U Streets NW Sculptor : Ed Hamilton Date: 1997 Medium: Bronze ---late May 1865, weeks after the surrender of the Conferderacy at Appomattox, the Grand Review of the Union troops galvanized the nation. During the Grand Review of troops some 200,000 Union soldiers marched in wide, even rows down Pennsylvania Ave from the Capitol to the White House. The Grand Review was incomplete, not one of the 166 regiments of the United States Colored Troops (U.S.C.T) regiments made up of African-Americans had been invited to participate. Their absence went unnoticed by most, but not all. A reporter for The Philadelphia Inquirer wrote: “their time will come” ---Long overdue, recognition of black soldiers and sailors of the Civil War has come. The most recent of the Civil War related monuments in the city is to honor the African-American troop who fought not only for a abstract concept of freedom to preserve the Union but literally for their own liberation. ---few realize how many blacks fought nor the extent of their involvement. 178,000 African-American troops from eight northern states, seven southern states and the District of Columbia fought in more than four hundred engagements, of which thirty nine were major battles in every theatre from 1863 to 1865, except Sherman’s March to the Sea. About 37,000 African-American members of the military died in the war. Sixteen black soldiers and seven black sailors received the Medal of Honor for bravery. ---African Americans volunteered to fight for the Union almost as soon as the Confederate cannons fired on Fort Sumter. Federal law prohibited the from serving in state militias and they had little success getting into the Union army. The navy did not exclude blacks, and more than 19,000 served as sailors during the war. As the war went on, abolitionist, such as Frederick Douglas, mounted pressure to allow African Americans into the army where they could fight to destroy slavery ---In September 1862 after the major Union victory at Antietam, Lincoln issued a preliminary emancipation proclamation paving the way for African American enlistment. In 1863 when the emancipation proclamation was made law, African Americans enlisted in droves. ---Many northerners doubted the ability of the former slaves to fight effectively, but from the first major battle in which they did (two regiments of Louisiana’s Corps d’Afrique took part on an assault on Port Hudson, LA, May 27, 1863) the doubters were proven wrong. After two regiments of newly recruited freedmen beat back a Confederate attack on Milliken’s Bend a Union outpost on the Mississippi River in June 1863 did it begin to change minds. Further helping to change minds was the now famous 54th Massachusetts regiment with the charge on Fort Wagner outside of Charleston, SC under the command of the young Boston abolitionist, Colonel Robert Gould Shaw. The Massachuesetts 54th Regiment was immortalized in the movie Glory as well as by a statue on Boston’s CommonGarden commemorating that charge which claimed the lives of nearly half of the men in the regiment, including Shaw. ---District of Columbia Councilman Frank Smith, empowered by the film Glory, himself a veteran of the 1960’s civil rights movement, became even more aware of the need for a memorial to honor the valor of those African Americans who took up arms and fought for their freedom. ---1991, Frank Smiths resolution proposed the monument and was quickly approved by the city council. President George H W Bush signed into law an act officially establishing the African American Civil War Memorial. Incorporated in 1992, the African American Civil War Memorial Freedom Foundation working with the National Park Service, the National Archives, Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, The Commission of Fine Arts, The National Capital Planning Commission, and The National Capital Memorial Commission began planning the new monument. ---Frank Smith envisioned this memorial in an inner city neighborhood with strong ties to the capital’s black community. The site at 10th and U Streets is doubly appropriate. Not only is the site in the middle of one of the most historic and vibrant black communities in Washington, but one that long ago was named for Colonel Robert Gould Shaw. The Shaw community’s main street (U St) is often referred to as the “Black Broadway”. This neighborhood predates Harlem as a center of African American history. ---Collaborative efforts by Deverouax and Purnell Architects and Ed Dunson and Associated resulted in a design concept for the site that was approved by all of the arts agencies. ---a wide stone plaza whose centerpiece is a sculpture partially enclosed within a long low semicircular wall. Affixed to the stone wall are steel panels inscribed with the names of the more than 178,000 African American solders and sailors who fought in the Civil War as well as the 7000 white officers who let the Colored Troops. ---over twenty designs were put forth during the open competition by artists of African American descent for the sculpture that would be the centerpiece. Ed Hamilton of Louisville, KY whose works include: …Boxer Joe Louis in Detroit, Michigan …Booker T. Washington for Hampton Institute in Hampton, Virginia …Amistead Memorial in New Haven, Connecticut ---the statue: 3 black infantrymen and a sailor guardedly look out in high relief from the convex side of a 12’ high wall. On the concave side, An African-American man bound for war is bid farewell by his wife, their you children and his elderly parents. Above all of them hovers the hooded Spirit of Freedom. ---The commission of Fine Arts wrote that Hamlton’s sculpture conveyed “the sense that they were fighting for the protection of their families from the slave trade…and for equal protection under the law” ---Hamilton’s sculpture makes tangible the sentiments of African American soldiers like Samuel Cabble, who escaped from a slavemaster in Missouri and made his way to Massachusetts where he joined the 54th Massachusetts Colored Infantry and then marched off to fight in North Carolina. Cabble’s letter made it clear what he was fighting for, he wrote: fighting for his wife, still enslaved in Missouri, and, as he wrote her, “against that very curse that has separated you and me” ---names of soldiers and information relative to them is now being compiled and placed on the web as a project call the Civil War Soldiers and Sailors System. ---September 1996, some 300 African American Civil War re-enactors clad in Union blue uniforms strode down Pennsylvania Avenue to martial tunes like “Marching Thru Georgia” the same tune to which the white troops had marched to in the Grand Review 131 years earlier. Several direct descendants of soldiers from the Colored Troops marched that day including Kevin Douglass Green, the great-great-grandson of Frederick Douglass, and great grandson of Charles Douglass who had volunteered with the 54th Massachusetts ---This long overdue parade acknowledged the African Americans who fought for freedom, and it opened a five day celebration organized by the African-American Civil War Memorial Foundation which culminated in the dedication of the site of the first national memorial honoring these troops. As the Philadelphia Inquirer reporter had predicted, indeed their time has come at last!" id="16069825" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="8" rank="8" tags="" title="African American Civil War Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/13/16069825_a1a713c6ea_b.jpg" username="dbking" views="19057" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-18 11:40:40" description="This was at the recent harvest festival at the Booker T. Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. These costumed volunteers were walking to an outdoor fire where they were preparing soap. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=5016308104&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View On Black&lt;/a&gt;" id="5016308104" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="9" rank="9" tags="bookertwashingtonnationalmonument harvestfestival virginia finepix hs10" title="Afternoon Walk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4088/5016308104_0e33d6849b_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="87" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 14:07:13" description="I don't know what kind of flower this is. It was poking through the fence at the foot of the scarecrow at Booker T Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4780416559&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View On Black&lt;/a&gt;" id="4780416559" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="5" rank="10" tags="flower macro bookertwashingtonnationalmonument" title="Flame" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4080/4780416559_870dec8ab5_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="72" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 14:50:26" description="This is tobacco curing inside a building at the Booker T. Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4780165558&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View On Black&lt;/a&gt;" id="4780165558" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="4" rank="11" tags="bookertwashingtonnationalmonument tobacco farm finepix hs10 barn monochrome" title="Curing Tobacco" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4120/4780165558_ffdfa72ea5_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="86" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 15:28:31" description="There is a small creek on the property where several ducks were swimming and generally cooling off. This is at the Booker T. Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4781171658&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View Large&lt;/a&gt;" id="4781171658" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="9" rank="12" tags="duck pond bookertwashingtonnationalmonument hdr summer quack finepix hs10" title="Quack" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4093/4781171658_14eb29f949_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="98" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 14:14:44" description="Inside the kitchen at Booker T Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4759170854&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Please view large&lt;/a&gt; or in the light box. :D" id="4759170854" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="7" rank="13" tags="buildings bookertwashingtonnationalmonument kitchen garlic table wood cabin window fujifilm hs10 hdr" title="Garlic" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4082/4759170854_08f10f5fb2_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="86" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 14:02:00" description="This was at the Booker T Washington National Monument close to Hardy, Virginia. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4758222861&amp;amp;size=large&amp;amp;bg=white&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Please view large&lt;/a&gt; or in the light box. :D" id="4758222861" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="2" rank="14" tags="bookertwashingtonnationalmonument scarecrow blackandwhite infrared fujifilm hs10 hdr" title="Scarecrow" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4093/4758222861_9cd33a6701_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="62" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 14:14:44" description="Inside the kitchen at Booker T Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4758560657&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Please view large&lt;/a&gt; or in the light box. :D" id="4758560657" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="2" rank="15" tags="buildings bookertwashingtonnationalmonument kitchen cabin log garlic window table wood history hdr fujifilm hs10" title="Garlic BW" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4093/4758560657_2e3f84dc04_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="83" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-01 14:17:42" description="Inside the bottom floor of the slave quarters at the Booker T Washington National Monument in Hardy, Virginia &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/onblack.php?id=4780455701&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View On Black&lt;/a&gt;" id="4780455701" latitude="37.118335" license="1" longitude="-79.730939" nbComments="3" rank="16" tags="buildings bookertwashingtonnationalmonument slave quarters table butterchurn garlic window shelf cabin finepix hs10" title="Table and Churn" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4079/4780455701_5e7b191b42_b.jpg" username="dbnunley" views="79" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:10:45" description="at the Booker T Washington National Monument" id="3416109209" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Horse" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3357/3416109209_11631c2963_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:19:16" description="at the Booker T Washington National Monument" id="3416115199" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Rooster and chickens" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3355/3416115199_af697f0b6c_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="30" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:23:18" description="at the Booker T Washington National Monument, Hardy VA" id="3416135925" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Slave house" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3322/3416135925_0e4144eaa1_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="65" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:35:03" description="" id="3416145435" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Booker T. Washington Farm" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3325/3416145435_75e8e3cdf3_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="79" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:21:11" description="" id="3416925152" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Houses" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3653/3416925152_4f60ed5f0b_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:14:52" description="" id="3416113769" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Cock-a-doodle doo" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3596/3416113769_0505dd0ac4_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:21:18" description="" id="3416929050" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Site of a house" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3559/3416929050_5e10c295d7_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:33:32" description="" id="3416952350" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Goose? Swan?" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3412/3416952350_dba9aa3c65_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="37" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:23:04" description="" id="3416944200" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="From the house" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3539/3416944200_7904221223_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="34" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:13:18" description="" id="3416110711" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="More clucks" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3345/3416110711_31ba65d1f8_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:13:33" description="" id="3416112235" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Cluck" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3365/3416112235_c584b7843c_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:24:14" description="" id="3416946018" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Farm building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3331/3416946018_89d0fd583e_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:32:17" description="" id="3416140951" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Honk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3320/3416140951_2c73f35b55_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:30:37" description="" id="3416948194" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Fence" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3327/3416948194_68db449ae1_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:32:25" description="on the farm" id="3416950928" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service" title="Ducks" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3411/3416950928_3f756a76e7_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="38" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:28:00" description="" id="3416137771" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service tobacco" title="Tobaccy" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3324/3416137771_0af740f27d_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="24" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:34:20" description="" id="3416143903" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="booker t washington national monument farm hardy smith mountain lake virginia park service turkey" title="Turkey" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3368/3416143903_b3ea6155e7_b.jpg" username="aawiseman" views="31" />
</photos>
