<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="European Watershed">

<photo  date_taken="2009-08-29 14:34:21" description="The North Sea is bounded by the Orkney Islands and east coasts of England and Scotland to the west and the northern and central European mainland to the east and south, including Norway, Denmark, Germany, the Netherlands, Belgium, and France. In the southwest, beyond the Straits of Dover, the North Sea becomes the English Channel connecting to the Atlantic Ocean. In the east, it connects to the Baltic Sea via the Skagerrak and Kattegat, narrow straits that separate Denmark from Norway and Sweden respectively. In the north it is bordered by the Shetland Islands, and connects with the Norwegian Sea, which lies in the very north-eastern part of the Atlantic. It is more than 970 kilometres (600 mi) long and 580 kilometres (360 mi) wide, with an area of 750,000 square kilometres (290,000 sq mi) and a volume of 94,000 cubic kilometres (23,000 cu mi).[4] Around the edges of the North Sea are sizeable islands and archipelagos, including Shetland, Orkney, and the Frisian Islands. The North Sea receives freshwater from a number of European continental watersheds, as well as the British Isles island watersheds. A large part of the European drainage basin empties into the North Sea including water from the Baltic Sea. The largest and most important affecting the North Sea are the Elbe river and the Rhine - Meuse watershed. The Elbe watershed drains an area of 149,000 square kilometres (58,000 sq mi) which includes 18 cities and their effluence. The Rhine-Meuse delta receives water discharge from a land area of 199,000 square kilometres (77,000 sq mi), including its 68 cities. Around 184 million people live in the catchment area of the rivers that flow into the North Sea. This area contains dense concentrations of industry." id="3874843156" latitude="56.002076" license="6" longitude="8.118038" nbComments="33" rank="1" tags="thenorthseaisboundedbytheorkneyislandsandeastcoastsofenglandandscotlandtothewestandthenorthernandcentraleuropeanmainlandtotheeastandsouth includingnorway denmark germany thenetherlands belgium andfranceinthesouthwest beyondthestraitsofdover thenorthseabecomestheenglishchannelconnectingtotheatlanticoceanintheeast itconnectstothebalticseaviatheskagerrakandkattegat narrowstraitsthatseparatedenmarkfromnorwayandswedenrespectivelyinthenorthitisborderedbytheshetlandislands andconnectswiththenorwegiansea whichliesintheverynortheasternpartoftheatlantic niels jørn buus madsen holstebro danmark hdr photography tvis canon 5dii" title="The North Sea in bad weather" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2646/3874843156_eb0301b893_b.jpg" username="Niels J. Buus Madsen" views="837" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-27 12:59:00" description="From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nyc.gov/html/dep/pdf/newtown_creek_nature_walk_flyer.pdf&quot;&gt;Newtown Creek Nature Walk Flyer&lt;/a&gt; (PDF): &amp;quot;Centered between two Weeping Willow trees near the eastern edge of the granite steps is a large, 1400 lb. granite table in the shape of an enormous shipping bollard, the cylindrical posts used to secure ships in port. Atop the table is an etching of Newtown Creek’s original watershed, before the first Europeans came to inhabit the land. The etching has a slight gradient, so falling rain drops will replicate the journey of the Creek’s own, original waters, albeit on a much smaller scale. A small, brass pin on the shore indicates your position on the watershed map. &amp;quot;" id="2141799878" latitude="40.736823" license="1" longitude="-73.946624" nbComments="0" rank="2" tags="greenpoint park sculpture geography brookln art cameraphone newtowncreek newtowncreeknaturewalk bollard marble nyc geocaching gc16ax2 newyorkcity newyork" title="Watershed Bollard" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2110/2141799878_07f553aea9_b.jpg" username="iandavid" views="118" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-27 11:15:43" description="The €110 billion financial bail out of Greece to meet its obligations could mark a watershed in the crisis. A Parliamentary delegation of MEPs has just returned from Athens to see for themselves the state of the Greek economy. In particular they focused on the accuracy of Greek statistical data over which there has been some controversy concerning its veracity. We spoke to the Chair of the delegation, Italian MEP Luigi de Magistris who chairs the Budgetary Control Committee. Read more: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/public/story_page/042-73858-120-04-18-907-20100430STO73836-2010-30-04-2010/default_en.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.europarl.europa.eu/news/public/story_page/042-73858-1...&lt;/a&gt; ©European Parliament/Pietro Naj-Oleari" id="4577757983" latitude="50.838521" license="3" longitude="4.37597" nbComments="0" rank="3" tags="luigi de magistris budget greece crisis 2010 belgium brussels bruxelles france strasbourg citizen citizens citoyen communication democracy election elections ep eu plenary session political group president rights euroepan euroopaparlament europa parlamentet europas parlaments europe european parliament union europejski europeu parlamentul europos parlamentas europský parlament europäisches eurostudio európai ewropeweuropees flag politic leader parlaimintnaheorpa euroopan parlamentevropski parlamentil parlamento europeo parlamentti parlement européen" title="&quot;It's simply right that Athens has to provide adequate guarantees&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4042/4577757983_052d162b25_b.jpg" username="European Parliament" views="130" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-19 11:24:40" description="Less a movement than a set of crucially new ideas about the nature of artistic practice, minimalism has profoundly influenced the most important art of the last four decades. Donald Judd was minimalism's philosopher, defining its principles through his work and writing, while disparaging the term. In recent years the National Gallery has made key acquisitions of work by other minimalist artists, such as Dan Flavin, but there has been no major work by Judd in the Gallery's collection to provide a center point for these holdings. The recently acquired Untitled, 1963, adds to the collection a major early work by Judd of exceptional historic significance. For Judd, 1963 was a watershed year, concluding with a solo exhibition at the Green Gallery in New York in December. Now widely considered a landmark for the definition of minimalism, the exhibition showcased a transformation in the artist's work, from painting to the creation of large, simplified three-dimensional objects. Among the works shown were two floor boxes—one of which was Untitled, 1963—that sat on the ground without pedestals, directly in the space of the viewer, brutally unframed in a way that almost no previous sculpture had been. With these two works Judd took aim at what he saw as the continuing illusionism of European modernism, pursuing instead a purely lucid form that would exist simply as an object. The floor boxes defined, as Judd wrote soon afterward, &amp;quot;the top, the whole shape, and the interior volume at once.&amp;quot; From this point on, the box—either mounted on the wall or placed directly on the floor—became Judd's principal form. Untitled offered a cubic structure that was generated by geometrical logic rather than by appealing to the language of expression: bisected across the diagonal, one half was double the height of the other, creating a step formation. Judd's pursuit of literal rather than apparent space emerges in Untitled as a challenge to the terms of traditional perspective in painting; the rising volume makes it nearly impossible to see the work as a cubic form with orthogonals receding in space. All objects shown at the Green Gallery exhibition were made of plywood painted a matte cadmium red; this serial use of color imposed uniformity on the objects and denied surface variation. Judd explained the choice on optical grounds, saying that it allowed him to create a sharply perceptible form. &amp;quot;Other than a gray of that value,&amp;quot; he wrote, &amp;quot;[red] seems to be the only color that makes an object sharp and defines its contours and angles.&amp;quot; It also marked the artist's sense of debt to Barnett Newman, who used such a red in paintings like Vir Heroicus Sublimis, 1950–1951, and whom Judd saw as breaking importantly with artistic tradition, his famous &amp;quot;zips&amp;quot; suspending the traditional opposition of figure and ground. Color was particularly central to Judd's thinking with Untitled: the purple panel bisecting the work is the first use of Plexiglas in the artist's career. He later described his interest in the industrial resin as a way of incorporating color that was integral to the material and not merely applied, and it subsequently became a signature material for Judd. The ideas developed in creating the objects for the 1963 Green Gallery exhibition facilitated what followed and were articulated in a key text the next year, &amp;quot;Specific Objects,&amp;quot; which became a minimalist credo. In it, Judd defines a new type of work, neither painting nor sculpture in the traditional sense, that would jettison both the vestiges of representation and traditional notions of composition—&amp;quot;the relics of European art&amp;quot;—with a driving sense of ethical imperative. &amp;quot;Three dimensions are real space,&amp;quot; he wrote. &amp;quot;That gets rid of illusionism and of literal space, space in and around marks and colors.&amp;quot; These volumes would be nonadditive, nondivisible entities that challenged the &amp;quot;part to part&amp;quot; organization of European modernism. Though modern sculpture conventionally was unpainted, exposing the material and marks of its manufacture, Judd's own specific objects would be intensely so, always with nonnatural hues that made no claim to representation. No work better represents these principles than Untitled—in both its manifesto-like clarity and its historic role in the Green Gallery exhibition, it stands at the conceptual origins of minimalism. Acquired soon after its making in an exchange of work between Judd and his friend and fellow minimalist Dan Flavin, Untitled remained in Flavin's possession during his lifetime, a testament to the relationship between the two artists." id="3144756936" latitude="38.891442" license="4" longitude="-77.016479" nbComments="5" rank="4" tags="americanart americanartmuseum art artgallery artmuseum artist dc district districtofcolumbia eastbuilding exhibit gallery museum national nationalartgallery nationalgallery nationalgalleryofart painting portrait portraitgallery sculpture smithsonian washington washingtondc donaldjudd judd untitled" title="Untitled, 1963, oil on wood with Plexiglas by Donald Judd" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3289/3144756936_bbda31d1bf_b.jpg" username="cliff1066™" views="3494" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-15 23:43:53" description="The Mississippi River is the chief river of the largest river system in North America. Flowing entirely in the United States (though its drainage basin reaches into Canada), it rises in northern Minnesota and meanders slowly southwards for 2,530 miles (4,070 km) to the Mississippi River Delta at the Gulf of Mexico. With its many tributaries, the Mississippi's watershed drains all or parts of 31 US states between the Rocky and Appalachian Mountains and even reaches into southern Canada. The Mississippi ranks as the fourth longest and tenth largest river in the world. The river either borders or cuts through the states of Minnesota, Wisconsin, Iowa, Illinois, Missouri, Kentucky, Tennessee, Arkansas, Mississippi, and Louisiana. Native Americans lived along the Mississippi and its tributaries. Most were hunter-gatherers or herders, but some, such as the Mound builders, formed prolific agricultural societies. The arrival of Europeans in the 1500s changed the native way of life as first explorers, then settlers, ventured into the basin in increasing numbers. The river served first as barrier – forming borders for New Spain, New France, and the early United States – then as vital transportation artery and communications link. In the 19th century, during the height of Manifest Destiny, the Mississippi and several western tributaries, most notably the Missouri, formed pathways for pioneers partaking in the western expansion of the United States. Formed from thick layers of this river's silt deposits, the Mississippi River Valley is one of the most fertile agricultural regions of the country, which resulted in the river's storied steamboat era. During the American Civil War, the Mississippi's capture by Union forces marked a turning point towards victory because of this very importance as a route of trade and travel, not least to the Confederacy. Because of substantial growth of cities and the larger ships and barges that have supplanted riverboats, the decades following the 1900s saw massive engineering works applied to the river system, such as the often in-combination construction of levees, locks and dams. Since modern development of the basin began, the Mississippi has also seen its share of pollution and environmental problems – most notably large volumes of agricultural runoff, which has led to the Gulf of Mexico dead zone off the Delta. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7235187106" latitude="40.391158" license="5" longitude="-91.376917" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="newjerseyday1" title="Mississippi River, Illinois-Missouri-Iowa Border" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8027/7235187106_2e34aa9486_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="37" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-15 23:41:51" description="The Mississippi River is the chief river of the largest river system in North America. Flowing entirely in the United States (though its drainage basin reaches into Canada), it rises in northern Minnesota and meanders slowly southwards for 2,530 miles (4,070 km) to the Mississippi River Delta at the Gulf of Mexico. With its many tributaries, the Mississippi's watershed drains all or parts of 31 US states between the Rocky and Appalachian Mountains and even reaches into southern Canada. The Mississippi ranks as the fourth longest and tenth largest river in the world. The river either borders or cuts through the states of Minnesota, Wisconsin, Iowa, Illinois, Missouri, Kentucky, Tennessee, Arkansas, Mississippi, and Louisiana. Native Americans lived along the Mississippi and its tributaries. Most were hunter-gatherers or herders, but some, such as the Mound builders, formed prolific agricultural societies. The arrival of Europeans in the 1500s changed the native way of life as first explorers, then settlers, ventured into the basin in increasing numbers. The river served first as barrier – forming borders for New Spain, New France, and the early United States – then as vital transportation artery and communications link. In the 19th century, during the height of Manifest Destiny, the Mississippi and several western tributaries, most notably the Missouri, formed pathways for pioneers partaking in the western expansion of the United States. Formed from thick layers of this river's silt deposits, the Mississippi River Valley is one of the most fertile agricultural regions of the country, which resulted in the river's storied steamboat era. During the American Civil War, the Mississippi's capture by Union forces marked a turning point towards victory because of this very importance as a route of trade and travel, not least to the Confederacy. Because of substantial growth of cities and the larger ships and barges that have supplanted riverboats, the decades following the 1900s saw massive engineering works applied to the river system, such as the often in-combination construction of levees, locks and dams. Since modern development of the basin began, the Mississippi has also seen its share of pollution and environmental problems – most notably large volumes of agricultural runoff, which has led to the Gulf of Mexico dead zone off the Delta. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7235180094" latitude="40.042786" license="5" longitude="-91.494258" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="newjerseyday1" title="Mississippi River Plain at Missouri-Illinois Border" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7097/7235180094_db55a73810_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-15 23:42:33" description="The Mississippi River is the chief river of the largest river system in North America. Flowing entirely in the United States (though its drainage basin reaches into Canada), it rises in northern Minnesota and meanders slowly southwards for 2,530 miles (4,070 km) to the Mississippi River Delta at the Gulf of Mexico. With its many tributaries, the Mississippi's watershed drains all or parts of 31 US states between the Rocky and Appalachian Mountains and even reaches into southern Canada. The Mississippi ranks as the fourth longest and tenth largest river in the world. The river either borders or cuts through the states of Minnesota, Wisconsin, Iowa, Illinois, Missouri, Kentucky, Tennessee, Arkansas, Mississippi, and Louisiana. Native Americans lived along the Mississippi and its tributaries. Most were hunter-gatherers or herders, but some, such as the Mound builders, formed prolific agricultural societies. The arrival of Europeans in the 1500s changed the native way of life as first explorers, then settlers, ventured into the basin in increasing numbers. The river served first as barrier – forming borders for New Spain, New France, and the early United States – then as vital transportation artery and communications link. In the 19th century, during the height of Manifest Destiny, the Mississippi and several western tributaries, most notably the Missouri, formed pathways for pioneers partaking in the western expansion of the United States. Formed from thick layers of this river's silt deposits, the Mississippi River Valley is one of the most fertile agricultural regions of the country, which resulted in the river's storied steamboat era. During the American Civil War, the Mississippi's capture by Union forces marked a turning point towards victory because of this very importance as a route of trade and travel, not least to the Confederacy. Because of substantial growth of cities and the larger ships and barges that have supplanted riverboats, the decades following the 1900s saw massive engineering works applied to the river system, such as the often in-combination construction of levees, locks and dams. Since modern development of the basin began, the Mississippi has also seen its share of pollution and environmental problems – most notably large volumes of agricultural runoff, which has led to the Gulf of Mexico dead zone off the Delta. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7235184474" latitude="40.042786" license="5" longitude="-91.494258" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="newjerseyday1" title="Mississippi River Plain at Missouri-Illinois Border" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5035/7235184474_76a15eea1f_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="32" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-15 23:43:27" description="The Mississippi River is the chief river of the largest river system in North America. Flowing entirely in the United States (though its drainage basin reaches into Canada), it rises in northern Minnesota and meanders slowly southwards for 2,530 miles (4,070 km) to the Mississippi River Delta at the Gulf of Mexico. With its many tributaries, the Mississippi's watershed drains all or parts of 31 US states between the Rocky and Appalachian Mountains and even reaches into southern Canada. The Mississippi ranks as the fourth longest and tenth largest river in the world. The river either borders or cuts through the states of Minnesota, Wisconsin, Iowa, Illinois, Missouri, Kentucky, Tennessee, Arkansas, Mississippi, and Louisiana. Native Americans lived along the Mississippi and its tributaries. Most were hunter-gatherers or herders, but some, such as the Mound builders, formed prolific agricultural societies. The arrival of Europeans in the 1500s changed the native way of life as first explorers, then settlers, ventured into the basin in increasing numbers. The river served first as barrier – forming borders for New Spain, New France, and the early United States – then as vital transportation artery and communications link. In the 19th century, during the height of Manifest Destiny, the Mississippi and several western tributaries, most notably the Missouri, formed pathways for pioneers partaking in the western expansion of the United States. Formed from thick layers of this river's silt deposits, the Mississippi River Valley is one of the most fertile agricultural regions of the country, which resulted in the river's storied steamboat era. During the American Civil War, the Mississippi's capture by Union forces marked a turning point towards victory because of this very importance as a route of trade and travel, not least to the Confederacy. Because of substantial growth of cities and the larger ships and barges that have supplanted riverboats, the decades following the 1900s saw massive engineering works applied to the river system, such as the often in-combination construction of levees, locks and dams. Since modern development of the basin began, the Mississippi has also seen its share of pollution and environmental problems – most notably large volumes of agricultural runoff, which has led to the Gulf of Mexico dead zone off the Delta. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_River&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7235186204" latitude="40.237101" license="5" longitude="-91.492906" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="newjerseyday1" title="Mississippi River Plain at Missouri-Illinois Border" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7105/7235186204_07e4149434_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="100" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-30 13:09:18" description="The Teddy Boys grew out of the 1950's when anything and everything had to do with America. America was viewed as the nation to be. The cars were big and opulent and the austerity by which the English had previously led their lives was something the teenagers of the time were rebelling against. Rising prosperity meant teenagers in work had more money to spend. The 50s saw the first youth cult, the Teddy Boys. Their outlandish style of dress combined with acts of violence shocked British society. The 50s was also the decade of American Rock’n'Roll. Young people in the latest fashions danced to music despised by their parents. American influence on European teenagers was huge. Rock and Roll idols including Elvis Presley, Bill Hayley, Jerry Lee Lewis and film stars James Dean and Marlon Brando set fashions almost unwittingly. The main looks for teenagers were greasers and preppies. Teddy Boys, quiffs, Brylcreem, poodle skirts and blue suede shoes. Greasers followed the standard black leather and denim jeans look set by Marlon Brando in &amp;quot;The Wild One&amp;quot; (1953) and later emulated in the 1978 film called &amp;quot;Grease&amp;quot;. They raced about town on motorbikes and were consider outrageous. Preppie qualities were neatness, tidiness and grooming. Teen girls wore full dirndl or circular skirts with large appliqués on their clothing. Neat pleated skirts were also popular. The pleated skirts were made from a then new fabric called TERYLENE (polyester) which helped maintain razor sharp sunray pleating. The skirts were supported by bouffant paper nylon or net petticoats. On top, teens wore scoop neck blouses, back to front cardigans, tight polo necks or three quarter sleeve white fitting shirts often with a scarf knotted cowboy fashion at the side neck. These teen clothing fashions that originated in America, filtered to Britain in watered down fashion. The Teddyboy emerged in the 1950s as Britain was coming to the end of post-war austerity and represented the first face of British youth culture. The consumer boom of the 1950s America did not reach Britain until the 1960s but nevertheless working class teenagers could for the first time afford good clothes, a bicycle or motorcycle and entertainment. The clothing that the Teddyboys wore was designed to shock their parents' generation. It consisted of an Edwardian style drape jacket, much too 'camp' for a working class man, suede Gibson shoes with thick crepe soles, narrow 'drainpipe' trousers, a smart shirt and a loud tie - usually of the 'Slim Jim' or bootlace type. The trademark drape jacket was not as impractical as it seems. Not only did it act as a badge of recognition but, as it was made of woollen cloth with lots of pockets, its kept it's owner warm as he hung around in the street and was also good at concealing weapons and alcohol. Some carrying coshes, bicycle chains, razors and flick-knives beneath their fine Edwardian style clothes. The Teddygirls adopted American fashions such as toreador pants and circle skirts, although they tended to wear low cut tops to make themselves look less prissy. Girls wore ponytails and the boys tried a number of experimental hairstyles, the most favourite being the overblown quiff with a DA (ducks arse) at the back. The British Teddy Boy subculture is typified by young men wearing clothes that were partly inspired by the styles worn by dandies in the Edwardian period, styles which Savile Row tailors had attempted to re-introduce in Britain after World War II. The subculture got its name from a 1953 newspaper headline which shortened Edward to Teddy and coined the term Teddy Boy (also known as Ted). The subculture started in London in the 1950s, and rapidly spread across the UK, soon becoming strongly associated with American rock and roll music of the period. Although there had been youth groups with their own dress codes called &amp;quot;Scuttlers&amp;quot; in 19th century Manchester and Liverpool, Teddy Boys were the first youth group in England to differentiate themselves as teenagers, helping create a youth market. The US film Blackboard Jungle marked a watershed in the United Kingdom. When shown in Elephant and Castle, south London, in 1956 the teenage Teddy boy audience began to riot, tearing up seats and dancing in the cinema's aisles. After that, riots took place around the country wherever the film was shown. Some Teds formed gangs and gained notoriety following violent clashes with rival gangs which were often exaggerated by the popular press. The most notable was the 1958 Notting Hill race riots, in which Teddy Boys were present in large numbers and were implicated in attacks on the West Indian community. The violent lifestyle was also sensationalised in the pulp novel Teddy Boy by Ernest Ryman. The bound edition was first published in England in 1958, by Michael Joseph Limited, London, WC1 © 1958 by Ernest Ryman. The first Ace Books edition (H399) was printed 1960. During the 1970s, rockabilly music enjoyed a renewed period of popularity and saw a resurgence of interest in Teddy Boy fashions; the look was taken up by Vivienne Westwood and Malcolm McLaren through their shop Let it Rock on London's King's Road. This new generation of Teds adopted some aspects of the 1950s but with a large glam rock influence, including louder colours for drape jackets, brothel creepers and socks. Additionally, rather than grease to style their hair, they were more likely to use hairspray. In the later 1970s, the new generation became the enemies of the Westwood and Sex Pistol-inspired punk rockers. The early 1990s saw a revival of original Teddy Boy style by a group known as The Edwardian Drape Society (T.E.D.S). Based in the Tottenham area of north London, they were concerned with reclaiming the style they felt had become bastardised by pop/glam bands such as Showaddywaddy and Mud in the 1970s. They were the subject of a short film, The Teddy Boys, by Bruce Weber, at the Cambridge Film Festival in July 2006. &lt;b&gt;Were you a Teddy Boy? Do you have any stories from that era?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;See My Other Youth Culture Links Below&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/4082458089/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/4082458089/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130733677/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130733677/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130851019/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130851019/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5131064113/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5131064113/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Teddy Boys on Video&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uji9wdkydxo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uji9wdkydxo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uBdbwnfRmsM&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=uBdbwnfRmsM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dx4EyJbS9J4&amp;amp;feature=related&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=dx4EyJbS9J4&amp;amp;feature=related&lt;/a&gt;" id="5130851019" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="9" tags="youthculture teddyboys britishyouth 1950s teds rebelling teenagers youthcult americanrock’nroll elvispresley billhayley jerryleelewis jamesdean marlonbrando teddyboyquiffs brylcreem poodleskirts bluesuedeshoes terylene pleatedskirts bouffant cowboyfashion postwar edwardianstyledrapejacket drainpipetrousers bootlacetie slimjim razors flickknives toreadorpants circleskirts ponytails overblownquiff da ducksarse firstyouthcultureinengland elephantandcastle blackboardjungle gangs brothelcreepers drapejackets tottenham showaddywaddy mud theteddyboysbybruceweber bristol uk 19461960 america" title="Youth Culture - Teddy Boys 1950s" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1127/5130851019_bee3b8b61a_b.jpg" username="brizzle born and bred" views="19070" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:59:53" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3932617632" latitude="31.635844" license="5" longitude="-91.247956" nbComments="0" rank="10" tags="natcheztrace jefferson mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (20)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2426/3932617632_bf87fd8739_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="272" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:25:21" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931091195" latitude="31.614321" license="5" longitude="-91.258589" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (3)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2612/3931091195_185be37ed9_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="303" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:50:42" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931115563" latitude="31.635844" license="5" longitude="-91.247956" nbComments="0" rank="12" tags="adams natcheztrace mississippi lamsday1" title="Emerald Mound, Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (17)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3459/3931115563_50bd3080ea_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="473" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:41:08" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931886318" latitude="31.624626" license="5" longitude="-91.249201" nbComments="0" rank="13" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (12)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2529/3931886318_7dbc53a1ab_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="248" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:33:24" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931878442" latitude="31.624626" license="5" longitude="-91.249201" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (7)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2514/3931878442_7dd3410fa8_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="343" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:25:30" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931092283" latitude="31.614321" license="5" longitude="-91.258589" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (4)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3491/3931092283_48956f645a_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="339" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:31:39" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931094397" latitude="31.624626" license="5" longitude="-91.249201" nbComments="0" rank="16" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (6)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3473/3931094397_984b05e958_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="478" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 17:33:02" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931848567" latitude="31.928622" license="5" longitude="-90.9982" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="claiborne mississippi natcheztrace lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (24)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3443/3931848567_6582c99913_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="203" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:49:25" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931109407" latitude="31.635844" license="5" longitude="-91.247956" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Emerald Mound, Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (15)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2480/3931109407_3462a2d9dd_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="400" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:51:17" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931112171" latitude="31.635844" license="5" longitude="-91.247956" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Emerald Mound, Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (18)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2669/3931112171_197d33ec72_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="292" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:26:23" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931093205" latitude="31.616061" license="5" longitude="-91.255863" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (5)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3431/3931093205_25f3998269_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="608" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:33:33" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931879958" latitude="31.624626" license="5" longitude="-91.249201" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (8)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3508/3931879958_8eb0340035_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="297" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:25:01" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931090149" latitude="31.614321" license="5" longitude="-91.258589" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (2)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3470/3931090149_c7ddf9907b_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="307" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:49:48" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931893102" latitude="31.635844" license="5" longitude="-91.247956" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Emerald Mound, Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (16)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2473/3931893102_3784219cca_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="295" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:40:39" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931102399" latitude="31.624626" license="5" longitude="-91.249201" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (11)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2468/3931102399_a9f84dc1dc_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="422" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:46:01" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931890368" latitude="31.633634" license="5" longitude="-91.24315" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Road to Emerald Mound, Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (14)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2508/3931890368_94f4c9c041_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="384" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 17:00:10" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931839187" latitude="31.646695" license="5" longitude="-91.209504" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="natcheztrace jefferson mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (21)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2650/3931839187_d4640fc191_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="315" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:24:46" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931088623" latitude="31.614321" license="5" longitude="-91.258589" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2568/3931088623_6cbf13c5f8_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="359" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-09 16:35:23" description="The Natchez Trace Parkway is a 444 mile (715 km) long parkway, in the form of a limited-access two-lane road, in the southeastern United States. The southern end of the route is in Natchez, Mississippi, at an intersection with Liberty Road; the northern end is northeast of Fairview, Tennessee, in the suburban community of Pasquo, Tennessee, at an intersection with Tennessee 100. The road links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi, and Nashville, Tennessee, via Jackson and Tupelo, Mississippi, and Florence in northwestern Alabama. Construction was begun by the federal government in the 1930s. The final two segments, between Interstate 55 and Interstate 20 (in Ridgeland and Clinton, Mississippi, respectively); and between Liberty Road in the city of Natchez, Mississippi and U.S. Highway 61 near Washington, Mississippi, opened to the public on May 21, 2005. The road is maintained by the National Park Service, and has been designated an All-American Road. The purpose of the road is to commemorate the original route of the Natchez Trace. The gentle sloping and curving alignment of the route is due to the fact that it follows an ancient salt-lick-to-grazing pasture migratory route of the American Bison and other game, who moved between grazing the pastures of central and western Mississippi and the salt and other mineral surface deposits of the Cumberland Plateau. The route generally traverses upon the tops of the low hills and ridges of the watershed divides from northeast to southwest. Native Americans, following the &amp;quot;traces&amp;quot; of Bison and other game, further improved this &amp;quot;walking trail&amp;quot; for foot-borne commerce between major villages located in middle Mississippi and central Tennessee. The route is locally circuitous. However, by traversing this route the Bison, and later humans, avoided the endless, energy-taxing climbing and descending of the many hills along the way. Also avoided was the danger to a herd (or groups of human travelers) of being caught en-masse at the bottom of a hollow or valley if attacked by predators. The nature of the route, to this day, affords good all-around visibility for those who travel it. Though the modern traveler by car or foot will only appreciate the beauty of the scenery afforded by the topography of the alignment. By the time of European exploration and settlement the route was well known and established as the fastest means of communication between the Cumberland Plateau, the Mississippi River, and the Gulf of Mexico settlements of, Pensacola, Mobile, and New Orleans. In the early Post Revolutionary War period of America's (south) westward expansion, the Trace was the return route for American flat-boat commerce between the territories of the upper &amp;amp; lower Ohio, Tennessee, and Cumberland River valleys. The Americans would construct flat-boats, load their commerce upon them, and drift upon the said same rivers, one-way south-southwestward all the way to New Orleans. They would sell their goods (including the salvageable logs of the flat-boats), and return home via the Trace (for the middle section of their return trip), to as far away as Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Improved communications (steam boats, stagecoach lines, and railroads) and the development of river cites along the rivers named above, (e.g., Natchez, Memphis, Tennessee, Paducah, Kentucky, Nashville, Tennessee, and Louisville, Kentucky) made the route obsolete as a means of passenger and freight commerce. As a result no major population centers were born or developed along the Trace, because of the Trace's alignment, between its termini Nashville and Natchez. The two cities of note, near or on the Trace's alignment (Jackson, Mississippi and Tupelo, Mississippi), developed as a result of their alignment along axis of communication different from the Trace. To this day has there has not been constructed a dedicated rail alignment between Natchez and Nashville. Thus the Trace and its alignment come down to us today almost completely undeveloped and unspoiled along its whole route. Many sections of the original foot path are visible today within the Parkway right-of-way to observe and for hiking. The road was one of the many projects of the Civilian Conservation Corps during the Great Depression. The road was the proposal of U.S. Congressman Thomas Jefferson Busby of Mississippi, who proposed it as a way to give tribute to the original Natchez Trace. Inspired by the proposal, the Daughters of the American Revolution began planting markers and monuments along the Trace. In 1934, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt administration ordered a survey. President Roosevelt signed the legislation to create the parkway on May 18, 1938.[2] Construction on the Parkway began in 1939, to be overseen by the National Park Service. Its length includes more than 45,000 acres (182 km²) and the towering Natchez Trace Parkway Bridge in Williamson County, Tennessee, completed in 1994 and one of only two post-tensioned, segmental concrete arch bridges in the world. (See the Federal Highway Administration's photo.) There are numerous historical sites on the Parkway, including the Meriwether Lewis Museum, the refurbished Mount Locust stand, and the Ridgeland Crafts Center in Ridgeland, Mississippi, which focuses on promoting Mississippi's native art. Nestléd between the Parkway and Old Port Gibson Road is the ghost town of Rocky Springs that thrived in the late 1800s. Today the old Rocky Springs Methodist Church, the cemetery and several building sites still exist and are accessible from the Parkway. Scenic Cypress Swamp is located at Mile Post 122. There are also several cascading waterfalls to view, some require a little hike from the parkway to view. In addition, parts of the original trail are still accessible. The history of the Parkway and that of the entire Trace is summarized at the Natchez Trace Visitor Center in Tupelo, Mississippi. Commercial traffic is prohibited along the entire route, and the speed limit is 50 miles per hour (80 km/h). Emergency Appropriations Act of June 19, 1934, allocated initial construction funds; established as parkway under National Park Service by act of May 18, 1938. Ackia Battleground National Monument (established August 27, 1935, and now called Chickasaw Village) and Meriwether Lewis Park (proclaimed as Meriwether Lewis National Monument February 6, 1925 and transferred from the War Department August 10, 1933) were added to the parkway by act of August 10, 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natchez_Trace_Parkway&lt;/a&gt;" id="3931099225" latitude="31.624626" license="5" longitude="-91.249201" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="natcheztraceparkway natcheztrace adams mississippi lamsday1" title="Natchez Trace Parkway, Mississippi (9)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3473/3931099225_70843d20bb_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="442" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-07-24 12:08:25" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Licking_River_(Kentucky)&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Licking_River_(Kentucky)&lt;/a&gt; The Licking River is a tributary of the Ohio River, approximately 320 mi (515 km) long in northeastern Kentucky in the United States. The Native Americans called the river Nepernine, but when Dr. Thomas Walker discovered it in 1750, he called it Frederick's River. One earlier name, Great Salt Lick Creek, makes reference to the many saline springs near the river that attracted animals to its salt licks. The origin of the present name is unclear, though possibly related to this previous name. Numerous aboriginal peoples inhabited the watershed for at least part of the year for several thousand years, but no tribal lands are recognized to have been displaced by European settlement. The Melungeons— a mysterious, pale Native American group— occupied points on the southern end of the river, as well as Shawnee and Cherokee tribes. Other, older settlements of unnamed groups in Bath County on Slate Creek can also be found in the region. The river served as an important transportation route for Native Americans and early European pioneers. In the 19th century, it was an important trade route. In 1780, during the American Revolutionary War, a group of American frontiersmen under George Rogers Clark gathered at the river's mouth for their march up the valley of the Little Miami River. In 1782 the river was the site of the Battle of Blue Licks. The Newport Barracks in Newport guarded its mouth from 1803 to 1894. It joins the Ohio opposite Cincinnati, Ohio, where it separates the cities of Covington and Newport. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.org/wherewework/northamerica/states/kentucky/preserves/art10920.html&quot;&gt;www.nature.org/wherewework/northamerica/states/kentucky/p...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nkyviews.com/campbell/newport_licking_scenes.htm&quot;&gt;www.nkyviews.com/campbell/newport_licking_scenes.htm&lt;/a&gt;" id="2806149466" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="29" tags="acqua agua dwr eau het vand vanduo vatten voda wasser water woda νερό нещоjuly2008 sky cincinnati ohio summer verano 夏天 xiàtiān sommer 夏 natsu été صيف haf zomer קיץ ग्रीष्म sumar musimpanas تابستان лето simmer หน้าร้อน zumer" title="Mouth of the Licking River" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3125/2806149466_31f60d508c_b.jpg" username="elycefeliz" views="221" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-08 19:06:24" description="The Platte River ( /plæt/) (Pawnee: Kíckatusʾ)[6] is a major river in the state of Nebraska and is about 310 mi (500 km) long. Measured to its farthest source via its tributary the North Platte River, it flows for over 1,050 miles (1,690 km). The Platte River is a tributary of the Missouri River, which in turn is a tributary of the Mississippi River which flows to the Gulf of Mexico. The Platte over most of its length is a muddy, broad, shallow, meandering stream with a swampy bottom and many islands—a braided stream. These characteristics made it too difficult for canoe travel, and it was never used as a major transportation route by European-American trappers or explorers. The Platte is one of the most significant tributary systems in the watershed of the Missouri, draining a large portion of the central Great Plains in Nebraska and the eastern Rocky Mountains in Colorado and Wyoming. The river valley played an important role in the westward expansion of the United States, providing the route for several major emigrant trails, including the Oregon, California, Mormon and Bozeman trails. The first Europeans to see the Platte were French explorers and fur trappers about 1714; they first called it the Nebraskier (Nebraska), a transliteration of the name given by the Otoe people, meaning &amp;quot;flat water&amp;quot;. Source: Wikipedia" id="2250887463" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="bogdanmigulski migulskicom photo foto photography art artistic interesting interestingness flickr photograph image pic picture shot capture digital artistry design graphic craft creative imagination display exhibit camera" title="Denver-Platte-River" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2340/2250887463_5a59e24a3f_b.jpg" username="Bogdan Migulski" views="40" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-11-24 13:07:02" description="&amp;quot;Peachtree Burning&amp;quot; Documentary Filmakers Site Regarding the Winecoff Hotel Fire &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.winecoffhotelfire.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.winecoffhotelfire.com&lt;/a&gt;. Dawn Fields: Producer/Director/Editor Dawn Fields has worked in production, post-production, development and acquisitions for several Los Angeles based production/distribution companies and has aquired many producer, production coordinator, assistant director and editor credits on features, shorts, and documentaries. Ms. Fields has written, produced and directed her own projects including dramatic shorts, award-winning music videos, feature films, documentaries and regional Lottery commercials. She self-published a trade magazine for filmmakers, teaches filmmaking seminars and has several features and documentaries in various stages of production See Ms. Field's text below: The Winecoff Hotel's Origins Built in 1913 by renowned architect, William Lee Stoddard, the Winecoff Hotel was Atlanta's tallest and most luxurious hotel. Standing fifteen stories tall with an open-air terrace dining room, coffee shop and lounge, the hotel was strategically located in the heart of Atlanta's retail district. According to their stationery, the hotel was advertised as being absolutely fireproof, even though it was designed without fire alarms, fire escapes or a sprinkler system. The Night of The Fire On December 7, 1946, the hotel was filled to capacity with over two hundred and eighty guests including shoppers, travelers, World War II soldiers eager to rebuild their lives, and forty of Georgia's most promising high school students who had come to attend a mock legislation. And even though the five year anniversary of Pearl Harbor Day was somberly approaching, Christmas was just around the corner and there was a sense of hope and excitement in the winter air. Around three o'clock in the morning, the elevator operator, descending from the top floor, noticed the smell of smoke around the fifth floor. Panicked, she stumbled out of the elevator upon reaching the lobby and began screaming, &amp;quot;Fire! Fire!&amp;quot; Unbeknownst to her, the fire had already completely engulfed floors three, four and five. For employees of the hotel and the guests who were awake, realization and reaction would come quickly. But for the guests who were asleep, survival would come at a much higher price. Before dawn, a total of one hundred and nineteen lives would be lost. The Tragedy of The Hotel's Design One of the most critical factors contributing to this staggering loss of life was the design of the building itself. Based on &amp;quot;European&amp;quot; design, the hotel was a perfect square with the stairwell and elevator shafts running straight through the middle. Thin wooden doors leading to the stairwells had been left open on several floors as well as many transoms above guest rooms allowing smoke and flames to be pulled upward like a giant chimney. When the only means of egress became impassable, guests were forced to the windows of their rooms, where they were met with precious few choices. Many fashioned sheet ropes, while others doused their rooms and themselves with toilet and bath water. Others simply awaited their fates in hopeless silence. Firefighting Efforts By the time fire trucks arrived, many guests were already on the verge of jumping and many lept to their deaths moments before ladders reached their windows. Fear had reached such a fevered pitch that panic-strickened guests became desperate, and nothing short of a human rain shower ensued. Several firefighters fell to their deaths or were injured after being knocked off their ladders by falling bodies. Mothers hurled their babies from windows only to follow them to their deaths. Rescue efforts were further hindered by the geographic location of the building. The Mortgage Guarantee Building sat opposite the hotel with only about six feet of alley between them. This prevented any kind of rescue from the firetrucks. But perhaps the most unfortunate limitation came from the trucks themselves. Back then, fire trucks were outfitted with ladders that could only reach as high as the seventh floor. Eighty percent of the fatalities were guests who were staying above the eighth floor and on the back side of the building. It was reported that thirty-six people died from falling or jumping, thirty-two burned and forty-one suffocated from smoke and fumes. Perhaps the most tragic of these victims were the thirty teenage children who lost their lives and the elderly Winecoffs, who had resided in the hotel since its inception. The Investigation: Accident or Arson? By the time Mayor Hartsfield arrived at the location, nothing remained but smoldering embers and the smell of burnt flesh. The brick exterior was still intact, but the hollow shell of its inside told a different and tragic story. According to a report filed by the National Board of Underwriters, a partially burned mattress found in a hallway on the third floor gave rise to the conclusion that a careless and possibly intoxicated guest dropped a cigarette onto it, thus starting the fire. Pressured by public outcry for culpability, and anxious to prove himself as &amp;quot;the mayor who cares&amp;quot;, Hartsfield invited fire experts from across the country to conduct their own investigations. Many of these experts were convinced that due to the massive devastation, the intensity of the fire's heat and the speed at which it accelerated, a smoldering mattress could not possibly have been the cause. Several arson theories emerged including an illegal poker game on the third floor that spun out of control. But the press and the public in general were more concerned about why an &amp;quot;absolutely fireproof&amp;quot; hotel lacked fire escapes, a sprinkler system and fire alarms and less concerned with theories of arson. They demanded answers from the hotel's owners and operators. Families and Survivors File Suit In 1948, the first of over one hundred and fifty lawsuits came to trial against the Winecoff Hotel Company. The plaintiffs' lawyers hoped to prove that the hotel owner and the hotel operators were negligent in not providing adequate fire safety devices. The defendants' attorneys were charged with proving arson, thereby absolving their clients of liability and relieving their insurance companies of paying the huge claim. In the end, however, no arson theory could be substantiated, and only the hotel operators, not it's owner were found to be liable. Although the plaintiffs were awarded over $3.5 million in damages, the hotel operators were only insured for $350,000 and most of the families received less than $1,000 each. The Fire's Effect On Fire Safety Codes Because the building had a brick exterior, the owners were able, under certain insurance provisions, to classify the hotel as &amp;quot;fireproof&amp;quot; even though it was not fitted with fire escapes, fire sprinklers nor an alarm system. Indeed, the exterior did not burn in the fire, but the contents did. The furniture, carpet, hallways, wainscoting and painted walls were highly flammable. Even the stairwells were constructed of wood and became impassible when the fire chose this as its main route of destruction. Up until the time of the Winecoff fire, no national codes had been required and decisions about fire safety were left to the discretion of local city officials, . Mayor Hartsfield had once argued that Atlanta property owners should be spared the hassle of retrofitting existing buildings in order to bring them up to code due to the enormous expense involved. He reasoned, &amp;quot;Why should we make it safe in Atlanta when Atlantans going to other towns would be in the same danger?&amp;quot; His position was quite popular with the property owners. As a result of the Winecoff disaster, many fire officials became enraged and cried, &amp;quot;Never again!&amp;quot; It was determined that local officials could not be relied upon to make responsible decisions about fire safety, and national safety codes were established and strictly enforced. The response to this tragedy was so intense that officials in several southern cities ordered all existing buildings be retrofitted and brought up to code within seven days or be shut down. It is a testament to the effectiveness of these newly enforced codes that in this country there has never been a hotel fire since in which so many lost their lives. The Winecoff After The Fire In April of 1951, the hotel reopened as the Peachtree on Peachtree Hotel, complete with fire alarms and fire escapes. But competing hotels were cropping up all around Atlanta's retail district and by 1967, with no buyers in sight, the hotel was donated to the Georgia Baptist Convention who used it as housing for the elderly. In 1981, the hotel was sold to a real estate conglomerate and would pass through the hands of no less a dozen more buyers over the next twenty five years. Each had high hopes but no solid deal to resurrect the hotel ever materialized. Today, in 2005, the hotel remains an eyesore and a thorn in the side of a city whose officials would have demolished it decades ago if it did not reside above the city's railway system, preventing it from being imploded. To this day, the building stands as a hollowed-out shell reminding us of the tragedy that occurred there. The curse of the Winecoff Hotel solidly remains and many local merchants claim that the building is haunted, having seen ghosts puttering about on more than on occasion. The Winecoff Hotel Fire of 1946 held the unenviable honor of being known as the deadliest hotel fire in the world and maintained that title until 1971 when one hundred and sixty-two people lost their lives in a hotel fire in Seoul, South Korea. The Winecoff remains, to this day, the worst hotel fire in American history. The fate of this once glamorous and celebrated hotel is unclear, but one thing is certain, it must never be forgotten. -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- Arnold Hardy was a 26-year-old graduate student at Georgia Tech the night he heard the sirens roaring downtown from all directions. It was 1946, and he was living upstairs in a rooming house at West Peachtree and North Avenue, within walking distance of Tech, where he was working in both the research lab and physics department. Hardy was still up at 4 o'clock on the morning of Dec. 7. After taking his date home in Buckhead, he had waited an hour for a trolley back to town. He had just taken his shoes off when he heard the sirens. An amateur photographer, he hurriedly called the fire department. &amp;quot;Press photographer. Where's the fire?&amp;quot; he asked &amp;quot;Winecoff Hotel.&amp;quot; Hardy called a taxi. The cab picked him up and raced toward the corner of Peachtree and Ellis. With his prized Speed Graphic camera and five flashbulbs in his pocket, Hardy sprinted the final blocks. He was the first photographer there. The windows of the 15-story Winecoff Hotel were backlit by orange flames. Guests--jumping out of panic or falling from makeshift ropes of bedsheets as they tried to escape the terrible smoke--were landing and dying on Peachtree Street. Amid the pandemonium and a cacophony of sirens, Hardy went to work. He took a shot that spanned the front of the building and the faces of the doomed in the windows--the mutely pleading, hopeless faces. When he was down to his final flashbulb--one had exploded in the cold night air--Hardy decided to try for a picture of a falling or jumping guest. When his viewfinder found a dark-haired woman falling midair at the third floor, her skirt billowing, he snapped the shutter open for 1/400th of a second. With his photography completed, Hardy heard a fireman and policeman at a drugstore across the street discussing calling the store owner so they could obtain medical supplies. He told them to break the door open. When they said they wouldn't he kicked it open himself. He was quickly arrested. As the Red Cross moved into the store to set up a first-aid station and make sandwiches and coffee for the firemen, Hardy was led off to jail. Upon being released on his own recognizance, he headed for the darkroom at the Tech research search lab. He developed his film and struck out for the Associated Press office downtown. The AP offered him $150 for exclusive rights to his pictures. He said he wanted $300--and got it. His final photograph--the one of the jumping woman--would be reprinted around the world the following day, and be on magazine covers for weeks. The fire had killed 119 people and drawn international coverage as the worst hotel fire in the history of the world. A few months later, Hardy became the first amateur photographer to win the Pulitzer Prize. The AP gave Hardy a $200 bonus the day after the fire, but he has never received another cent for its frequent use. With the 47th anniversary of the Winecoff fire approaching, Hardy's famous photograph is back in the spotlight. It appears on the cover of The Winecoff Fire: The Untold Story of America 's Deadliest Hotel Fire. The book reports for the first time that the fire was set by an arsonist. It also identifies the &amp;quot;jumping lady&amp;quot; for the first time. She was Daisy McCumber, a 41-year-old Atlanta secretary who--contrary to countless captions--survived the 11-story jump. She broke both legs, her back, and her pelvis. She underwent seven operations in 10 years and lost a leg, but then worked until retirement. She died last year in Jacksonville Fla., having never admitted even to family that she was the woman in Hardy's photo. Hardy's Photo: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apug.org/forums/blogs/two40/91-week-5-pulitzer-1946-winecoff-hotel-fire-arnold-hardy.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.apug.org/forums/blogs/two40/91-week-5-pulitzer-1946-w...&lt;/a&gt; The book also tells the dramatic story of James D. &amp;quot;Jimmy&amp;quot; Cahill, IM '48, who became one of the fire's heroes. Cahill, now retired from an academic career in Charlotte, N.C., had returned from the service and was staying at the hotel while applying to re-enter Georgia Tech. After escaping from the front side of the hotel, he raced around to the back to rescue his mother. Cahill entered an adjacent building and stretched a board across a 10-foot alley to his mother's sixth-floor room. He crawled across the board and brought his mother to safety. Firemen quickly followed his lead and, with Cahill's help, rescued many guests who had no other escape from the backside of the hotel. Hardy, a mechanical engineer, retired earlier this year, and sold Hardy Manufacturing Co. of Decatur, builder of medical X-ray equipment to his son. He retired from amateur photography decades earlier, shortly after realizing his photos would always be measured against his Pulitzer Prize winner. Hardy's goal that night had been to capture the futility of the whole scene before him. &amp;quot;It upset me so much that of all those trucks--there there were about 18 in the front of the building--I saw only two nets,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;I thought to myself, 'I'd love to take a picture that would just stir up the public to where they would do something about this and equip every truck in the city with a net.'&amp;quot; Hardy's horrifying photo accomplished much more. The Winecoff did not have fire escapes, fire doors, or sprinklers, yet had called itself fireproof. Quickly, fire codes changed nationwide. The Winecoff became a watershed event in the history of fire safety. The 119 did not die in vain--their deaths made hotels safer for Americans then and now. And the work Hardy did one night as a 26-year-old graduate student was one of the main reasons. ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ Arnold Hardy, Dies at age 85 Arnold Hardy, 85, took Pulitzer-winning photo By KAY POWELL The Atlanta Journal-Constitution Published on: 12/07/07 Arnold Hardy, the first amateur photographer to win the Pulitzer Prize, was a reluctant celebrity. His photograph of a woman plunging from a window of the burning Winecoff Hotel on Dec. 7, 1946, is the defining image of the nation's deadliest hotel fire. Arnold Hardy's photo prompted improvements in fire codes. Hardy's Pulitzer-winning photo of a woman falling from an upper floor of the hotel. The woman survived and was identified in photos as Daisy McCumber. For Mr. Hardy, then a 24-year-old Georgia Tech graduate student and lab assistant, the photograph, the publicity and the Pulitzer Prize were bittersweet, said his son Glen Hardy of Decatur. &amp;quot;He stood on the sidewalk and watched people plummet to their deaths,&amp;quot; his son said. &amp;quot;He had almost a post-traumatic response to that. &amp;quot;It wasn't just a lucky snapshot,&amp;quot; his son said. &amp;quot;It was technically a very complicated photograph to take. He had to consider lighting, temperature. He was working hard to get that photograph, to capture a moving object in pitch black darkness. He tweaked his camera to its limits.&amp;quot; Not long after, Mr. Hardy turned down a job from the Associated Press, married and founded a business that designs and manufactures X-ray equipment. &amp;quot;The only pictures I've taken since then,&amp;quot; Mr. Hardy said in a 2000 Atlanta Journal-Constitution article, &amp;quot;have been family and vacations.&amp;quot; Mr. Hardy, 85, of Stone Mountain died at Emory University Hospital Wednesday of complications following hip surgery. The funeral is at 2 p.m. today &amp;amp;madah;the anniversary of the fire— at A.S. Turner &amp;amp; Sons. Mr. Hardy had earned his degree in physics, and photography was his hobby. He bought a $200 Speed Graphic that folded into a box carrying case. To pay for it, he thought he could earn freelance money shooting Tech athletic events. On that fateful Saturday, he returned to his Midtown rooming house about 3 a.m. after a date. He heard sirens screaming, called the fire department to get the location, grabbed his camera and headed to the Peachtree Street hotel where 280 guests were registered. He had five flashbulbs, four after one of them burst from the cold. He took three pictures. Then, with his final flash bulb, he trained his lens on the mezzanine where bodies were bouncing on the awning and striking the marquee. He noticed a woman who was trying to climb down a rope and lost her grip, the article said. Mr. Hardy captured her fall, her dress flying above her head and her white underpants stark against the hotel. He developed his film at Tech, and it was about 6 a.m. when he saw the image of the woman in free fall. He called AP and sold the picture for $300. Mr. Hardy continued his freelance photography until an industrial fire led him to retire his press card. &amp;quot;I went out there and hung around a while; there wasn't anything worth shooting,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;But the next day my picture appeared in the paper with some caption about the Winecoff photographer looking for another prize.&amp;quot; Mr. Hardy did not want people to think of him as some kind of ambulance-chaser. He used the Speed Graphic only for personal photographs until the camera was stolen in the 1970s, his son said. After that, &amp;quot;he would find some old camera at a garage sale for $3 and take it apart and fix it and take a few pictures with it, then get another one.&amp;quot; Mr. Hardy was a perfectionist, and that influenced his career making X-Ray equipment. He spent so much time perfecting his designs and equipment, he had to sell to high-end businesses such as medical equipment suppliers or airlines, said his son, who bought Hardy Manufacturing Co. in Decatur from his father. &amp;quot;He always was designing or building some piece of medical equipment or a treehouse for me,&amp;quot; he said. After retiring in 1987, Mr. Hardy, who enjoyed sailing, designed and began building a mini-houseboat but never launched it. &amp;quot;One thing he took great pride in,&amp;quot; his son said, &amp;quot;is that after his photograph was published worldwide, fire codes were changed all over the country and maybe the world.&amp;quot; Survivors include his wife, Lorraine Hardy; a daughter, Nancy Cooper of Stockbridge; three stepsons, John F. Weber III of Stockbridge, Warren D. Weber of Seattle and Keith D. Weber of Austin, Texas; five grandchildren and six great-grandchildren." id="2073140320" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="31" tags="" title="The Winecoff Hotel (and fire)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2261/2073140320_4cbc63ca27_b.jpg" username="dbking" views="18796" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 14:20:33" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269986476" latitude="42.884807" license="3" longitude="-122.235572" nbComments="7" rank="32" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage_01" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5241/5269986476_7d664fe405_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="113" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 14:13:35" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269377201" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5082/5269377201_28353d48f3_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 13:58:01" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269376699" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5203/5269376699_6eb011a4b3_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 13:48:47" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269985378" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5043/5269985378_c63ae0ee33_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="31" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 14:23:35" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269377669" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5042/5269377669_ebeda54449_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="37" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-30 15:37:58" description="Rupert, Count Palatine of the Rhine, Duke of Bavaria (German: Ruprecht Pfalzgraf bei Rhein, Herzog von Bayern), commonly called Prince Rupert of the Rhine, (17 December 1619 – 29 November 1682), soldier, inventor and amateur artist in mezzotint, was a younger son of Frederick V, Elector Palatine and Elizabeth Stuart, and the nephew of King Charles I of England, who created him Duke of Cumberland and Earl of Holderness. Prince Rupert had a very varied career. He was a soldier from a young age, fighting against Spain in the Netherlands (during the Eighty Years' War) and the Holy Roman Empire in Germany (during the Thirty Years' War). Aged 23, he was appointed commander of the Royalist cavalry during the English Civil War. He surrendered after the Battle of Naseby and was banished from England[2]. He spent some time in Royalist forces in exile, first on land then at sea. He then became a buccaneer in the Caribbean. Following the Restoration, Rupert returned to England, becoming a naval commander, inventor, artist, and first Governor of the Hudson's Bay Company. Prince Rupert died in England in 1682, aged 62. Rupert was born in Prague in 1619 at the time of the Thirty Years' War. Soon after his birth, the family fled from Bohemia to the Netherlands where Rupert spent his childhood. He was almost left behind until a court member, thinking the swaddled prince was a bundle of household goods, tossed him onto a carriage. His mother, Elizabeth Stuart, sometimes known as the &amp;quot;Winter Queen&amp;quot; (due to her reign as Queen of Bohemia lasting a single winter in 1619), was a daughter of King James I of England and sister of King Charles I of England. Consequently, Rupert and his brother Maurice supported their uncle Charles when the English Civil War began in 1642. He took to soldiering early. At the age of fourteen he fought alongside the Protestant Frederick Henry, Prince of Orange at the siege of Rheinberg in 1633, and against Spain at Breda in 1638 in the Eighty Years' War in the Netherlands. As a child he was at times badly behaved and earned himself the nickname &amp;quot;Rupert The Devil&amp;quot;. His childhood was not easy; the family had little money after leaving Prague, and he was still a teenager when his elder brother and his father died. Nevertheless Rupert was an exceptional student, becoming fluent in several European languages and excelling in art and mathematics. By the time he was 18 he stood about 6 ft 4 in tall and had become a dashing young prince. In the Thirty Years' War, aged 19, Rupert fought for the alliance of Protestants and France at the Battle of Vlotho (17 October 1638) during the invasion of Westphalia. The forces of the Imperial General Hatzfeld captured him, imprisoning him in Linz, where he studied military textbooks. He was released on parole in 1641, on the condition that he never bear arms against the Holy Roman Emperor again. Following the Restoration of the monarchy under Charles II, Rupert returned to the service of England, accepting an annuity and becoming a member of the privy council. He never again fought on land, but, turning admiral like Blake and Monk, he played a brilliant part in the Second Anglo-Dutch War as actual supreme commander of the British fleet from June 1666, gaining a victory in the St James's Day Battle. His efforts in the Third Anglo-Dutch War met with humiliating failure at the Battles of Schooneveld and the Battle of Texel. At some point Rupert, a talented amateur artist, had learned of the printmaking process of mezzotint invented in 1642 by Ludwig von Siegen, a German Lieutenant-Colonel who was also an amateur artist. Whether the two ever met is a subject of scholarly controversy, but Siegen had worked as chamberlain, and probably part-tutor, to Rupert's young cousin William VI, Landgrave of Hesse-Kassel (or Hesse-Cassel), with whom Rupert discussed the technique in letters from 1654. Rupert produced a few stylish prints in the technique, mostly copies of paintings, and introduced it to England after the Restoration. John Evelyn wrongly credited him as its inventor in 1662; apparently though Rupert invented, or perfected, the &amp;quot;rocker&amp;quot;, a key tool in the process. It was Wallerant Vaillant, Rupert's artistic assistant or tutor, who first popularized the process and exploited it commercially. In 1670, Rupert became the first Governor of the Hudson's Bay Company (HBC), after having sponsored an expedition of Radisson and des Groseilliers into Hudson Bay. Rupert's HBC secretary was Sir James Hayes (Radisson named the Hayes River, Manitoba in his honour). The HBC was granted a trading monopoly in the whole Hudson Bay watershed area, an immense territory named Rupert's Land. In 1869, control of this territory reverted to the British and Canadian governments.[3] After his retirement from the active military in around 1674, he engaged in scientific research. He is usually credited with the invention of a form of gunpowder and an alloy named &amp;quot;Prince's metal&amp;quot; in his honour. He is also credited with the invention of Prince Rupert's Drops, glass teardrops which explode when the tail is cracked. He also erected a water-mill on Hackney Marshes for a revolutionary method of boring guns, however his secret died with him, and the enterprise failed.[4] In retirement, he continued to hold important governmental posts; from 1673, when he was 54, to 1679, he served as England's Lord High Admiral. Prince Rupert died at his house in Spring Gardens, Westminster, on 29 November 1682, and was buried in Westminster Abbey. Prince Rupert, British Columbia and the Rupert River in Quebec are named after him." id="3969914826" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="" title="Prince Rupert of the Rhine, nephew of King Charles I, grandson of James I, great-grandson of Mary, Queen of Scots" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2645/3969914826_0755aaf1e8_b.jpg" username="lisby1" views="1453" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-02-02 16:20:29" description="MEPs on Thursday expressed solidarity with the protests that are &amp;quot;enabling the Tunisian people to regain their freedom and bring down the regime&amp;quot; of former President Ben Ali. At the same time, they criticised the European Union for being &amp;quot;unable to develop a genuine foreign policy that is consistent and effective vis-à-vis its partners.&amp;quot; After Wednesday's debate with EU High Representative Catherine Ashton on the Jasmine Revolution in Tunisia and the situation in Egypt, the House today approved a resolution expressing its &amp;quot;solidarity with the Tunisian people,&amp;quot; whose protests against the government have &amp;quot;brought their country to a political watershed.&amp;quot; Parliament condemned the repressive measures and disproportionate force used by the security forces, while supporting all measures that are creating the conditions for the holding of elections. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/public/focus_page/008-112869-031-01-06-901-20110131FCS12843-31-01-2011-2011/default_p001c006_en.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.europarl.europa.eu/news/public/focus_page/008-112869-...&lt;/a&gt; © European Union 2011 PE-EP/Pietro Naj-Oleari" id="5412983161" latitude="50.838521" license="3" longitude="4.37597" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="§ brussels be 2011 belgium bruxelles france strasbourg citizen citizens citoyen communication democracy election elections ep eu plenary session political group president rights euroepan euroopaparlament europa parlamentet europas parlaments europe european parliament union europejski europeu parlamentul europos parlamentas europský parlament europäisches eurostudio európai ewropeweuropees flag politic leader parlaimintn aheorpa euroopan parlamente vropski parlamentil parlamento europeo parlamentti parlement européen" title="MEPs offer solidarity with Tunisian protesters but question EU foreign policy" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5173/5412983161_f5d4528fc7_b.jpg" username="European Parliament" views="136" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-03 04:48:28" description="Base is native ash, top is European. May 3, 2009" id="3498922037" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="toronto janeswalk yellowcreek donwatershed torontoravines" title="Grafted Tree" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3304/3498922037_44ac985c65_b.jpg" username="jbcurio" views="95" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 21:56:56" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (Photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt)" id="7304153888" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="Early morning at LCD" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7091/7304153888_f44bcde041_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-29 16:49:12" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (Photo M. Leaver)" id="7304155026" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="Couros 'tanning area' panorama" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7087/7304155026_ccb0c7c60b_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 21:56:49" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (Photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt)" id="7304153186" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="Early morning at LCD" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7217/7304153186_2df758f4d5_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="56" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 21:56:35" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (Photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt)" id="7304151822" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="The first maps coming in" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7095/7304151822_bd504ae5d0_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 21:56:23" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (Photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt)" id="7304150718" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="Paper mapping" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8163/7304150718_a1806d250e_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="50" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 22:03:20" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo João Sousa)" id="7304187656" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="Walking papers" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8143/7304187656_bf9fb7bb1c_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="52" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 22:03:27" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo João Sousa)" id="7304188380" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="46" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="The complex tanning pools in Couros" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7078/7304188380_47481dc091_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="59" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 21:57:03" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (Photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt)" id="7304154574" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="Early morning at LCD" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7216/7304154574_c58d83131b_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-30 22:03:17" description="'Walking the Streets' mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo João Sousa)" id="7304187362" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="2012 capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeancapitalofculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="James Bridle" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7079/7304187362_85597b6aa8_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:54" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609764238" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="Walking the sky advert in Porto" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8434/7609764238_3fe76d09b4_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="30" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:40" description="'Grassroots mapping in Guimarães 'James Bridle talk for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609763002" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="talk1" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8011/7609763002_e0249a9217_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="27" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:17" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609761052" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="Creating a camera capsule" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8013/7609761052_e3c3f8dfec_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:03" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609759790" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="From the top floor of CAAA" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8282/7609759790_ac26a3d538_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:03:52" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609769226" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="Eclipse" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8150/7609769226_dc99244fd7_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:21" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609761422" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="Balloon outside CAAA" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7121/7609761422_23b28ce46f_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:25" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609761748" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="Day 1 giving birth to balloon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8142/7609761748_f05d23d859_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:12" description="'Grassroots mapping in Guimarães 'James Bridle talk for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609760676" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8162/7609760676_873e7ddb3e_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="18" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:36" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609762744" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="Day 1 full house" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8028/7609762744_1bf24a0792_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="24" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:09" description="'Grassroots mapping in Guimarães 'James Bridle talk for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609760368" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8003/7609760368_9ed67c2dd8_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:02:42" description="'Grassroots mapping in Guimarães 'James Bridle talk for Guimarães 2012 (photo Vanessa Bellaar Spruijt" id="7609763228" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="2012x view photos from you or everyone capital culturaxgmr12xguimarãesxguimarães 2012xtufazespartejames bridle watershed european culture mapping open street maps" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8141/7609763228_0709feda5c_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:15:16" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012" id="7609826672" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeanculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="balloon portrait" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8147/7609826672_66e8bb5671_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-20 16:15:11" description="'Walking the Sky' aerial mapping workshop for Guimarães 2012" id="7609826322" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="capitalcultura gmr12 guimarães guimarães2012 tufazesparte jamesbridle watershed europeanculture mapping openstreetmaps" title="Centro Cultural Vila Flor aerial shot from balloon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7127/7609826322_1037189833_b.jpg" username="Open City Guimarães" views="38" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-05-14 10:35:00" description="&amp;quot;Potomac&amp;quot; is a European spelling of an Algonquian name for a tribe subject to the Powhatan confederacy, that inhabited the upper reaches of the Northern Neck in the vicinity of Fredericksburg. Some accounts say the name means &amp;quot;place where people trade&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;the place to which tribute is brought&amp;quot;. The natives called the river above the falls Cohongarooton, translated as &amp;quot;river of geese&amp;quot;, and that area was renowned in early years for an abundance of both geese and swans. The spelling of the name has been simplified over the years from &amp;quot;Patawomeke&amp;quot; (as on Captain John Smith's map) to &amp;quot;Patowmack&amp;quot; in the 18th century and now &amp;quot;Potomac&amp;quot;. Some scholars have also suggested its a rooted in the ancient Greek for river, &amp;quot;potamos&amp;quot;, blended with the Powhatan name &amp;quot;Patawomeke&amp;quot;. The river's name was officially decided upon as Potomac by the Board on Geographic Names in 1931. The Potomac River brings together a variety of cultures throughout the watershed from the coal miners of upstream West Virginia to the urban residents of the nation's capital and, along the lower Potomac, the watermen of Virginia's Northern Neck. Being situated in an area rich in American history and American heritage has led to the Potomac being nicknamed &amp;quot;the Nation's River.&amp;quot; George Washington, the first President of the United States, was born in, surveyed, and spent most of his life within the Potomac basin. All of Washington, D.C., the nation's capital city, also lies within the watershed. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potomac_River&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potomac_River&lt;/a&gt;" id="2522006493" latitude="38.185522" license="5" longitude="-76.916302" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="westmoreland virginia georgewashingtonbirthplace georgewashington" title="George Washington Birthplace National Monument, Virginia" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3050/2522006493_9c9016c1ee_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="276" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 13:47:23" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269376003" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5123/5269376003_51d8bd53ea_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="21" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 13:47:55" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269376189" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5088/5269376189_7259904e4c_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 14:22:02" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269377519" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5205/5269377519_3c850d839d_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="200" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 13:50:57" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269985580" latitude="42.884807" license="3" longitude="-122.235572" nbComments="1" rank="66" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5049/5269985580_f3602ffcf6_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="30" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 13:38:10" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269375857" latitude="42.884807" license="3" longitude="-122.235572" nbComments="1" rank="67" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5249/5269375857_561a985931_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 13:58:56" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269985990" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="68" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5246/5269985990_c93080e75f_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 14:11:42" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269377053" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5285/5269377053_516300cbac_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 11:25:32" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269984730" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="70" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5202/5269984730_955d1ccfa5_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="38" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-24 11:24:17" description="Oregon Route 62 is an Oregon state highway that runs between the city of Medford, and U.S. Route 97 between Chiloquin and Klamath Falls. The highway approaches Crater Lake National Park from the south, and is known as the Crater Lake Highway. The Rogue River in southwestern Oregon in the United States flows about 215 miles (346 km) in a generally westward direction from the Cascade Range to the Pacific Ocean. Known for its salmon runs, whitewater rafting, and rugged scenery, it was one of the original eight rivers named in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968. Beginning near Crater Lake, which occupies the caldera left by the explosive volcanic eruption of Mount Mazama, the river flows through the geologically young High Cascades and the older Western Cascades, another volcanic province. Further west, the river passes through multiple exotic terranes of the more ancient Klamath Mountains. In the Kalmiopsis Wilderness section of the Rogue basin are some of the world's best examples of rocks that form the Earth's mantle. Near the mouth of the river, the only dinosaur fragments ever discovered in Oregon were found in the Otter Point Formation, along the coast of Curry County. People have lived along the Rogue River and its tributaries for at least 8,500 years. European explorers made first contact with Native Americans (Indians) toward the end of the 18th century and began beaver trapping and other activities in the region. Clashes, sometimes deadly, occurred between the natives and the trappers and later between the natives and European-American miners and settlers. These struggles culminated with the Rogue River Wars of 1855–56 and removal of most of the natives to reservations outside the basin. After the war, settlers expanded into remote areas of the watershed and established small farms along the river between Grave Creek and the mouth of the Illinois River. They were relatively isolated from the outside world until 1895, when the Post Office Department added mail-boat service along the lower Rogue. As of 2010, the Rogue has one of the two remaining rural mail-boat routes in the United States." id="5269375547" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="71" tags="fall foliage craterlake craterlakehighway oregon craterlakegorge" title="Crater Lake Highway Fall Foliage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5005/5269375547_e65a75d7f7_b.jpg" username="John Bruckman" views="75" />
</photos>
