<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Fontaine de l'Observatoire Paris">

<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 20:46:37" description="" id="5022076493" latitude="48.841135" license="1" longitude="2.336719" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="paris france europe travel jardinmarcopolo fontainedelobservatoire" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4113/5022076493_550727b118_b.jpg" username="Aurorion" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:01:05" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455881204/&quot;&gt;centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight dolphins, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455882268/&quot;&gt;tortoises&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455012581/&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt;. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455880210" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="1" rank="2" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld sculpture emmanuelfrémiet emmanuelfremiet dolphin fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1172/1455880210_5c24274ffe_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1177" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-06 11:46:20" description="Jean Baptiste Carpeaux's &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere), was executed from 1868 to 1872 for la fontaine de l'Observatoire (Observatory fountain) in Jardin du Luxembourg (Luxembourg Gardens). This original half-size plaster model was exhibited in Salon de 1872. Baron Haussmann, the prefect of Paris who gave the city the face we know today, commissioned Carpeaux to design the fountain in 1867. The sculptor chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wantefd to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. His passionate nature was quite the contrary of Neoclassic serenity. It was not until 1874, a year before Carpeaux died, that the bronze fountain was set up on the designated site. The tangle of legs displeased the public of the time. Two of the busts exist as separate works. Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. The Musée d'Orsay (The Orsay Museum), housed in the former railway station, the Gare d'Orsay, holds mainly French art dating from 1848 to 1914, including paintings, sculptures, furniture, and photography, and is probably best known for its extensive collection of impressionist masterpieces by popular painters such as Monet and Renoir. Many of these works were held at the Galerie nationale du Jeu de Paume prior to the museum's opening in 1986." id="1391379671" latitude="48.859844" license="3" longitude="2.326596" nbComments="0" rank="3" tags="france europe muséedorsay orsaymuseum museum musée art sculpture statue jeanbaptistecarpeaux lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutnantlasphérecéleste lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutnantlasphereceleste fourpartsoftheworldholdingacelestialsphere fontainedelobservatoire observatoryfountain carpeaux museedorsay dorsay orsay paris" title="Paris - Musée d'Orsay: Jean Baptiste Carpeaux's Les Quatre Parties du monde soutnant la sphére céleste" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1198/1391379671_6c036e95be_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="5001" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-06 11:47:29" description="Jean Baptiste Carpeaux's &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere), was executed from 1868 to 1872 for la fontaine de l'Observatoire (Observatory fountain) in Jardin du Luxembourg (Luxembourg Gardens). This original half-size plaster model was exhibited in Salon de 1872. Baron Haussmann, the prefect of Paris who gave the city the face we know today, commissioned Carpeaux to design the fountain in 1867. The sculptor chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wantefd to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. His passionate nature was quite the contrary of Neoclassic serenity. It was not until 1874, a year before Carpeaux died, that the bronze fountain was set up on the designated site. The tangle of legs displeased the public of the time. Two of the busts exist as separate works. Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. The Musée d'Orsay (The Orsay Museum), housed in the former railway station, the Gare d'Orsay, holds mainly French art dating from 1848 to 1914, including paintings, sculptures, furniture, and photography, and is probably best known for its extensive collection of impressionist masterpieces by popular painters such as Monet and Renoir. Many of these works were held at the Galerie nationale du Jeu de Paume prior to the museum's opening in 1986." id="1392272590" latitude="48.859844" license="3" longitude="2.326596" nbComments="1" rank="4" tags="france europe muséedorsay orsaymuseum museum musée art sculpture statue jeanbaptistecarpeaux lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutnantlasphérecéleste lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutnantlasphereceleste fourpartsoftheworldholdingacelestialsphere fontainedelobservatoire observatoryfountain carpeaux museedorsay dorsay orsay paris" title="Paris - Musée d'Orsay: Jean Baptiste Carpeaux's Les Quatre Parties du monde soutnant la sphére céleste" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1337/1392272590_d61bbafe87_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="7519" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:02:47" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455881204/&quot;&gt;centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455880210/&quot;&gt;dolphins&lt;/a&gt;, tortoisesand &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455012581/&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt;. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455882268" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld sculpture emmanuelfrémiet emmanuelfremiet tortoise horse fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1385/1455882268_d7669a30b3_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1079" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:00:54" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455881204/&quot;&gt;centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455880210/&quot;&gt;dolphins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455882268/&quot;&gt;tortoises&lt;/a&gt; and horses. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455012581" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="1" rank="6" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france sculpture emmanuelfrémiet emmanuelfremiet horse horses matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1326/1455012581_4f88ad03c4_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1279" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:02:01" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455881204/&quot;&gt;centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wantefd to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. The tangle of legs displeased the public of the time. Two of the busts exist as separate works. Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455880210/&quot;&gt;dolphins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455882268/&quot;&gt;tortoises&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455012581/&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt;.. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455019345" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlasphérecéleste fourpartsoftheworldholdingacelestialsphere lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlaspherecéleste jeanbaptistecarpeaux pierrelegrain sphere fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1107/1455019345_e57ce0509e_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1842" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:01:23" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wanted to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. The tangle of legs displeased the public of the time. Two of the busts exist as separate works. Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight dolphins&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455880210/&quot;&gt;dolphins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455882268/&quot;&gt;tortoises&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455012581/&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt;. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455881204" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="1" rank="8" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlasphérecéleste fourpartsoftheworldholdingacelestialsphere lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlaspherecéleste jeanbaptistecarpeaux pierrelegrain sphere fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1402/1455881204_4f544f9fe2_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="6380" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:00:21" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455881204/&quot;&gt;centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wantefd to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. The tangle of legs displeased the public of the time. Two of the busts exist as separate works. Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455880210/&quot;&gt;dolphins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455882268/&quot;&gt;tortoises&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455012581/&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt;.. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455885524" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="1" rank="9" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlasphérecéleste fourpartsoftheworldholdingacelestialsphere lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlaspherecéleste jeanbaptistecarpeaux pierrelegrain sphere fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1388/1455885524_dcd868ce62_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1610" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:02:23" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455881204/&quot;&gt;centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wantefd to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. The tangle of legs displeased the public of the time. Two of the busts exist as separate works. Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455880210/&quot;&gt;dolphins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455882268/&quot;&gt;tortoises&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455012581/&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt;.. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455017361" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="0" rank="10" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlasphérecéleste fourpartsoftheworldholdingacelestialsphere lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlaspherecéleste jeanbaptistecarpeaux pierrelegrain sphere fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1011/1455017361_0fb479ec31_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1024" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 12:00:35" description="At the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian, sits the celebrated &lt;i&gt;Fontaine des Quatre Parties du Monde&lt;/i&gt; (Fountain of the Four Parts of the World). Designed and supervised by Gabriel Davioud, it was built between 1867 and 1874, leveraging the collaborative efforts of several artists. The centerpiece sculpture, &lt;i&gt;Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste&lt;/i&gt; (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1391379671/&quot;&gt;half-size plaster model at Musée d'Orsay&lt;/a&gt;), was executed by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux. Baron Haussmann commissioned Carpeaux, who chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere, which was carved with decorated signs of the zodiac by Perre Legrain. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usially found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wanted to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. The tangle of legs displeased the public of the time. Two of the busts exist as separate works. Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1389103550/&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Frémiet&lt;/a&gt; was responsible for the base, adorned with eight dolphins&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455880210/&quot;&gt;dolphins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455882268/&quot;&gt;tortoises&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455012581/&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt;. The garlands were created by Pierre Legrain. And the sculpture itself, was foundried by Matifat. Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire. Along with Jardin Robert Cavelier de la Salle, the garden is one of two parks created in 1867 between the Jardin du Luxembourg and the Observatoire de Paris. Named after the great explorer, Marco Polo, is is laid with lawns and planted with four rows of chestnut trees, which are sharply trimmed in the classic French-style." id="1455883526" latitude="48.840917" license="3" longitude="2.336783" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinmarcopolo marcopologarden jardin garden europe france matifate fountain fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fontainecarpeaux placecamillejullian fountainofthefourpartsoftheworld lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlasphérecéleste fourpartsoftheworldholdingacelestialsphere lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlaspherecéleste jeanbaptistecarpeaux pierrelegrain sphere fontainedel’observatoire jardinsdelobservatoire paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin Marco Polo - Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1037/1455883526_98138cb093_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1610" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-10 20:12:29" description="Fontaine des Quatre parties du monde." id="2580179539" latitude="48.84122" license="3" longitude="2.336654" nbComments="5" rank="12" tags="paris jeanbaptistecarpeaux emmanuelfremiet pierrelegrain louisvuillemot gabrieldavioud lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlasphèrecéleste fountain fontaine wysiwyg thechallengefactory" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2185/2580179539_e67ec412d7_b.jpg" username="Istvan" views="318" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-08-26 17:01:42" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capture-the-world.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Website&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loic80l&quot;&gt;My Flickr&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/loiclagardephoto&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Facebook&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/108023614454861008041/posts&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Google+&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://Loic80l.500px.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My 500px&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://loiclagarde.darqroom.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Darqroom&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinterest.com/loic80l/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;" id="7865464516" latitude="48.841102" license="3" longitude="2.336813" nbComments="3" rank="13" tags="canonef1635mmf28liiusm canoneos5dmarkiii fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde gabrieldavioud jeanbaptistecarpeaux paris expositionlongue fontain fontaine fontainecarpeaux fontainedel’observatoire jardinduluxembourg longexposure placecamillejullian" title="Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8421/7865464516_358dfd16fd_b.jpg" username="loic80l" views="143" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-08-26 16:56:41" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capture-the-world.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Website&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loic80l&quot;&gt;My Flickr&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/loiclagardephoto&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Facebook&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/108023614454861008041/posts&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Google+&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://Loic80l.500px.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My 500px&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://loiclagarde.darqroom.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Darqroom&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinterest.com/loic80l/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;My Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;" id="7865460474" latitude="48.841102" license="3" longitude="2.336813" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="canonef1635mmf28liiusm canoneos5dmarkiii fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde gabrieldavioud jeanbaptistecarpeaux paris expositionlongue fontain fontaine fontainecarpeaux fontainedel’observatoire jardinduluxembourg longexposure placecamillejullian" title="Fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8152/7865460474_3e6d058f3d_b.jpg" username="loic80l" views="94" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 10:51:32" description="In his 1885 &lt;i&gt;Le Triomphe de Silène&lt;/i&gt; (The Procession of Silenus) a pyramidal tangle of human forms, Aimé Jules Dalou represents Silène (Sleinus) stripped, drunk and staggering on his ass. The Silenoi were followers of Dionysus. They were drunks, and were usually bald and fat with thick lips and squat noses, and had the legs of a human. Later, the plural &amp;quot;silenoi&amp;quot; went out of use and the only references were to one individual named Silenus, the teacher and faithful companion of the wine-god Dionysus. A notorious consumer of wine, he was usually drunk and had to be supported by satyrs or carried by a donkey. Silenus was described as the oldest, wisest and most drunken of the followers of Dionysus, and was said in Orphic hymns to be the young god's tutor. When intoxicated, Silenus was said to possess special knowledge and the power of prophecy. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1450180045" latitude="48.847511" license="3" longitude="2.333253" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardin garden europe luco letriomphedesilène letriomphedesilene processionofsilenus silenus silene silène statue sculpture aiméjulesdalou aimejulesdalou julesdalou jardinduluxembourg france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Le Triomphe De Silène" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1174/1450180045_2b9395c173_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1627" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:25:00" description="La Fontaine de Médicis (Fountain of Medicis), originally known as La grotte du Luxembourg (The cave of Luxembourg), was commissioned in 1624 by the Marie de Médicis (Marie de' Medici), the second wife and widow of King Henri IV, and mother of King Louis XIII, who wanted to emulate la grotte de Buontalenti in jardins de Boboli in her hometown Florence. Designed by engineer Florentin Thomas Francine, it comprised of three niches and a pediment with coats of arms of France and Médicis, backed by la fontaine de Léda. The fountain was moved and refitted in 1861. Alphonse de Gisors restored the arms, and created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451159248/&quot;&gt;50 meter water alley&lt;/a&gt; lined with trees. The new basin was filled with the The centerpiece sculpture, added in 1866 by Auguste Louis Ottin, depicts the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450304863/&quot;&gt;cyclops, Polyphème&lt;/a&gt;, waiting to crush &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450305677/&quot;&gt;Galatée, who is holding Acis&lt;/a&gt;, with a boulder, and Pan faune and Diane chasseresse (Diana the Huntress) watching from each side. Acis et Galatée (Acis and Galatea) tells the story of a love triangle between the three main characters of Acis, a mortal shepherd, Galatea, a semi-divine nymph, and Poliphème. Poliphème murders Acis out of jealousy, as depicted in this work, but he is revived and turned into a fountain (or river by Neptune, depending on the telling). The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1451160602" latitude="48.848154" license="3" longitude="2.338929" nbComments="1" rank="16" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco fontainedemédicis fontainedemedicis france fountain fontaine medicis sculpture statue polyphème cyclops alphonsedegisors augustelouisottin galatéedansdesbrasdacisleberger galatée acis florentinthomasfrancine acisetgalatée acisandgalatea galatea luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Fontaine de Médicis" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1221/1451160602_baeb35f2c8_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="3339" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:25:30" description="La Fontaine de Médicis (Fountain of Medicis), originally known as La grotte du Luxembourg (The cave of Luxembourg), was commissioned in 1624 by the Marie de Médicis (Marie de' Medici), the second wife and widow of King Henri IV, and mother of King Louis XIII, who wanted to emulate la grotte de Buontalenti in jardins de Boboli in her hometown Florence. Designed by engineer Florentin Thomas Francine, it comprised of three niches and a pediment with coats of arms of France and Médicis, backed by la fontaine de Léda. The fountain was moved and refitted in 1861. Alphonse de Gisors restored the arms, and created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451159248/&quot;&gt;50 meter water alley&lt;/a&gt; lined with trees. The new basin was filled with the The centerpiece sculpture, added in 1866 by Auguste Louis Ottin, depicts the cyclops, Polyphème, waiting to crush &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450305677/&quot;&gt;Galatée, who is holding Acis&lt;/a&gt;, with a boulder, and Pan faune and Diane chasseresse (Diana the Huntress) watching from each side. Acis et Galatée (Acis and Galatea) tells the story of a love triangle between the three main characters of Acis, a mortal shepherd, Galatea, a semi-divine nymph, and Poliphème. Poliphème murders Acis out of jealousy, as depicted in this work, but he is revived and turned into a fountain (or river by Neptune, depending on the telling). The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1450304863" latitude="48.848154" license="3" longitude="2.338929" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco fontainedemédicis fontainedemedicis france fountain fontaine medicis sculpture statue augustelouisottin alphonsedegisors polyphème cyclops jeunefaune florentinthomasfrancine acisetgalatée acisandgalatea luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Fontaine de Médicis - Polyphème" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1412/1450304863_e2cfb8f262_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="2062" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:25:19" description="La Fontaine de Médicis (Fountain of Medicis), originally known as La grotte du Luxembourg (The cave of Luxembourg), was commissioned in 1624 by the Marie de Médicis (Marie de' Medici), the second wife and widow of King Henri IV, and mother of King Louis XIII, who wanted to emulate la grotte de Buontalenti in jardins de Boboli in her hometown Florence. Designed by engineer Florentin Thomas Francine, it comprised of three niches and a pediment with coats of arms of France and Médicis, backed by la fontaine de Léda. The fountain was moved and refitted in 1861. Alphonse de Gisors restored the arms, and created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451159248/&quot;&gt;50 meter water alley&lt;/a&gt; lined with trees. The new basin was filled with the The centerpiece sculpture, added in 1866 by Auguste Louis Ottin, depicts the cyclops, Polyphème, waiting to crush &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450305677/&quot;&gt;Galatée, who is holding Acis&lt;/a&gt;, with a boulder, and Pan faune and Diane chasseresse (Diana the Huntress) watching from each side. Acis et Galatée (Acis and Galatea) tells the story of a love triangle between the three main characters of Acis, a mortal shepherd, Galatea, a semi-divine nymph, and Poliphème. Poliphème murders Acis out of jealousy, as depicted in this work, but he is revived and turned into a fountain (or river by Neptune, depending on the telling). The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1450301387" latitude="48.848154" license="3" longitude="2.338929" nbComments="1" rank="18" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco fontainedemédicis fontainedemedicis france fountain fontaine medicis sculpture statue flower augustelouisottin alphonsedegisors polyphème cyclops florentinthomasfrancine acisetgalatée acisandgalatea luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Fontaine de Médicis - Polyphème" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1229/1450301387_5e52e8fa0c_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1005" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:25:36" description="La Fontaine de Médicis (Fountain of Medicis), originally known as La grotte du Luxembourg (The cave of Luxembourg), was commissioned in 1624 by the Marie de Médicis (Marie de' Medici), the second wife and widow of King Henri IV, and mother of King Louis XIII, who wanted to emulate la grotte de Buontalenti in jardins de Boboli in her hometown Florence. Designed by engineer Florentin Thomas Francine, it comprised of three niches and a pediment with coats of arms of France and Médicis, backed by la fontaine de Léda. The fountain was moved and refitted in 1861. Alphonse de Gisors restored the arms, and created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451159248/&quot;&gt;50 meter water alley&lt;/a&gt; lined with trees. The new basin was filled with the The centerpiece sculpture, added in 1866 by Auguste Louis Ottin, depicts the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450304863/&quot;&gt;cyclops, Polyphème&lt;/a&gt;, waiting to crush Galatée, who is holding Acis, with a boulder, and Pan faune and Diane chasseresse (Diana the Huntress) watching from each side. Acis et Galatée (Acis and Galatea) tells the story of a love triangle between the three main characters of Acis, a mortal shepherd, Galatea, a semi-divine nymph, and Poliphème. Poliphème murders Acis out of jealousy, as depicted in this work, but he is revived and turned into a fountain (or river by Neptune, depending on the telling). The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1450305677" latitude="48.848154" license="3" longitude="2.338929" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco fontainedemédicis fontainedemedicis france fountain fontaine medicis sculpture statue galatéedansdesbrasdacisleberger augustelouisottin alphonsedegisors galatée acis florentinthomasfrancine acisetgalatée acisandgalatea galatea luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Fontaine de Médicis - Galatée dans des bras d'Acis le berger" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1309/1450305677_e77492e9cc_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="11244" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:22:20" description="The Palais du Luxembourg, now home to the French Senate, was built for Marie de de Médicis, widow of Henri IV mother of king Louis XIII of France, to remind her of her native Florence. In 1612, she bought and old hôtel particulier owned by François, duc de Luxembourg and the surrounding property and commissioned architect Salomon de Brosse to built, in the style of the Pitti Palace in Florence, what she called Palais Médicis. She installed her household in 1625, while work on interiors continued. Construction was finished in 1631, but the Queen Mother was forced from court the same year, following the Day of the Dupes. In 1624, she bequeathed the palace to her second son, Gaston d'Orléans, the king's younger brother, who passed it to his widow and daughter, Anne, Duchess of Montpensier, who made it her residence. Her daughter, the duchesse de Guise, inherited it in 1660 and gave it to Louis XIV in 1694. The palace was not used again until it was owned by Louis XVI, who gave it in 1778 to his brother, the Comte de Provence. During the French Revolution, it was briefly a prison, then the center of the French Directory and later the first residence of Napoleon Bonaparte, as First Consul of France. It has continued its senatorial role, with brief interruptions, ever since. During the German occupation of Paris (1940-1944), Hermann Göring took over the Palais as the headquarters of the Luftwaffe in France, taking for himself a sumptuous suite of rooms to accommodate his visits to the French capital. His subordinate, Luftwaffe Field Marshal Hugo Sperrle, also took an apartment and spent most of the war enjoying the luxurious surroundings. The Palais was a designated &amp;quot;strong point&amp;quot; for German forces defending the city in August 1944, but thanks to the decision of commanding Gen. Dietrich von Choltitz to surrender the city rather than fight, it was only minimally damaged and later used for the peace conference of 1946. The Palace sits within the Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco, a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountains--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1455381636" latitude="48.847836" license="3" longitude="2.337309" nbComments="1" rank="20" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco france palaisduluxembourg luxembourgpalace luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris palace palais salomondebrosse palaismédecis palaismédicis frenchsenate" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Palais du Luxembourg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1021/1455381636_b4bcc6d627_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1301" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:16:57" description="The Palais du Luxembourg, now home to the French Senate, was built for Marie de de Médicis, widow of Henri IV mother of king Louis XIII of France, to remind her of her native Florence. In 1612, she bought and old hôtel particulier owned by François, duc de Luxembourg and the surrounding property and commissioned architect Salomon de Brosse to built, in the style of the Pitti Palace in Florence, what she called Palais Médicis. She installed her household in 1625, while work on interiors continued. Construction was finished in 1631, but the Queen Mother was forced from court the same year, following the Day of the Dupes. In 1624, she bequeathed the palace to her second son, Gaston d'Orléans, the king's younger brother, who passed it to his widow and daughter, Anne, Duchess of Montpensier, who made it her residence. Her daughter, the duchesse de Guise, inherited it in 1660 and gave it to Louis XIV in 1694. The palace was not used again until it was owned by Louis XVI, who gave it in 1778 to his brother, the Comte de Provence. During the French Revolution, it was briefly a prison, then the center of the French Directory and later the first residence of Napoleon Bonaparte, as First Consul of France. It has continued its senatorial role, with brief interruptions, ever since. During the German occupation of Paris (1940-1944), Hermann Göring took over the Palais as the headquarters of the Luftwaffe in France, taking for himself a sumptuous suite of rooms to accommodate his visits to the French capital. His subordinate, Luftwaffe Field Marshal Hugo Sperrle, also took an apartment and spent most of the war enjoying the luxurious surroundings. The Palais was a designated &amp;quot;strong point&amp;quot; for German forces defending the city in August 1944, but thanks to the decision of commanding Gen. Dietrich von Choltitz to surrender the city rather than fight, it was only minimally damaged and later used for the peace conference of 1946. The Palace sits within the Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco, a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountains--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1454512485" latitude="48.847307" license="3" longitude="2.337244" nbComments="1" rank="21" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco france palaisduluxembourg luxembourgpalace luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris palace palais salomondebrosse palaismédecis palaismédicis frenchsenate" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Palais du Luxembourg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1034/1454512485_05337809fb_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="2577" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:15:52" description="The Palais du Luxembourg, now home to the French Senate, was built for Marie de de Médicis, widow of Henri IV mother of king Louis XIII of France, to remind her of her native Florence. In 1612, she bought and old hôtel particulier owned by François, duc de Luxembourg and the surrounding property and commissioned architect Salomon de Brosse to built, in the style of the Pitti Palace in Florence, what she called Palais Médicis. She installed her household in 1625, while work on interiors continued. Construction was finished in 1631, but the Queen Mother was forced from court the same year, following the Day of the Dupes. In 1624, she bequeathed the palace to her second son, Gaston d'Orléans, the king's younger brother, who passed it to his widow and daughter, Anne, Duchess of Montpensier, who made it her residence. Her daughter, the duchesse de Guise, inherited it in 1660 and gave it to Louis XIV in 1694. The palace was not used again until it was owned by Louis XVI, who gave it in 1778 to his brother, the Comte de Provence. During the French Revolution, it was briefly a prison, then the center of the French Directory and later the first residence of Napoleon Bonaparte, as First Consul of France. It has continued its senatorial role, with brief interruptions, ever since. During the German occupation of Paris (1940-1944), Hermann Göring took over the Palais as the headquarters of the Luftwaffe in France, taking for himself a sumptuous suite of rooms to accommodate his visits to the French capital. His subordinate, Luftwaffe Field Marshal Hugo Sperrle, also took an apartment and spent most of the war enjoying the luxurious surroundings. The Palais was a designated &amp;quot;strong point&amp;quot; for German forces defending the city in August 1944, but thanks to the decision of commanding Gen. Dietrich von Choltitz to surrender the city rather than fight, it was only minimally damaged and later used for the peace conference of 1946. The Palace sits within the Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco, a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountains--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1454511107" latitude="48.847836" license="3" longitude="2.337309" nbComments="1" rank="22" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco france palaisduluxembourg luxembourgpalace luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris palace palais salomondebrosse palaismédecis palaismédicis frenchsenate" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Palais du Luxembourg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1053/1454511107_207b0ea1b1_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1111" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:49:44" description="The Palais du Luxembourg, now home to the French Senate, was built for Marie de de Médicis, widow of Henri IV mother of king Louis XIII of France, to remind her of her native Florence. In 1612, she bought and old hôtel particulier owned by François, duc de Luxembourg and the surrounding property and commissioned architect Salomon de Brosse to built, in the style of the Pitti Palace in Florence, what she called Palais Médicis. She installed her household in 1625, while work on interiors continued. Construction was finished in 1631, but the Queen Mother was forced from court the same year, following the Day of the Dupes. In 1624, she bequeathed the palace to her second son, Gaston d'Orléans, the king's younger brother, who passed it to his widow and daughter, Anne, Duchess of Montpensier, who made it her residence. Her daughter, the duchesse de Guise, inherited it in 1660 and gave it to Louis XIV in 1694. The palace was not used again until it was owned by Louis XVI, who gave it in 1778 to his brother, the Comte de Provence. During the French Revolution, it was briefly a prison, then the center of the French Directory and later the first residence of Napoleon Bonaparte, as First Consul of France. It has continued its senatorial role, with brief interruptions, ever since. During the German occupation of Paris (1940-1944), Hermann Göring took over the Palais as the headquarters of the Luftwaffe in France, taking for himself a sumptuous suite of rooms to accommodate his visits to the French capital. His subordinate, Luftwaffe Field Marshal Hugo Sperrle, also took an apartment and spent most of the war enjoying the luxurious surroundings. The Palais was a designated &amp;quot;strong point&amp;quot; for German forces defending the city in August 1944, but thanks to the decision of commanding Gen. Dietrich von Choltitz to surrender the city rather than fight, it was only minimally damaged and later used for the peace conference of 1946. The Palace sits within the Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco, a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountains--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1455382908" latitude="48.846064" license="3" longitude="2.337094" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco france palaisduluxembourg luxembourgpalace luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris palace palais salomondebrosse palaismédecis palaismédicis frenchsenate" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Palais du Luxembourg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1048/1455382908_66b5a51570_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1832" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:49:04" description="The Palais du Luxembourg, now home to the French Senate, was built for Marie de de Médicis, widow of Henri IV mother of king Louis XIII of France, to remind her of her native Florence. In 1612, she bought and old hôtel particulier owned by François, duc de Luxembourg and the surrounding property and commissioned architect Salomon de Brosse to built, in the style of the Pitti Palace in Florence, what she called Palais Médicis. She installed her household in 1625, while work on interiors continued. Construction was finished in 1631, but the Queen Mother was forced from court the same year, following the Day of the Dupes. In 1624, she bequeathed the palace to her second son, Gaston d'Orléans, the king's younger brother, who passed it to his widow and daughter, Anne, Duchess of Montpensier, who made it her residence. Her daughter, the duchesse de Guise, inherited it in 1660 and gave it to Louis XIV in 1694. The palace was not used again until it was owned by Louis XVI, who gave it in 1778 to his brother, the Comte de Provence. During the French Revolution, it was briefly a prison, then the center of the French Directory and later the first residence of Napoleon Bonaparte, as First Consul of France. It has continued its senatorial role, with brief interruptions, ever since. During the German occupation of Paris (1940-1944), Hermann Göring took over the Palais as the headquarters of the Luftwaffe in France, taking for himself a sumptuous suite of rooms to accommodate his visits to the French capital. His subordinate, Luftwaffe Field Marshal Hugo Sperrle, also took an apartment and spent most of the war enjoying the luxurious surroundings. The Palais was a designated &amp;quot;strong point&amp;quot; for German forces defending the city in August 1944, but thanks to the decision of commanding Gen. Dietrich von Choltitz to surrender the city rather than fight, it was only minimally damaged and later used for the peace conference of 1946. The Palace sits within the Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco, a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountains--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1454516781" latitude="48.845767" license="3" longitude="2.337416" nbComments="1" rank="24" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris lion statue sculpture palaisduluxembourg luxembourgpalace palace palais salomondebrosse palaismédecis palaismédicis frenchsenate" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Palais du Luxembourg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1225/1454516781_61f6b50439_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1216" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:43:42" description="Michel-Louis Victor's statue pays homage to Sainte Geneviéve, the patron saint of Paris. Saint Geneviève (c. 419/422 - 512) was a wealthy 5th-century Gallo Roman landowner. When Paris was invaded by the Huns in 451, she passed through Childeric's seige in a boat to Troyes, bringing grain to a starving city, and successfully pled for the welfare of prisoners of war leading to their liberation. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1455388062" latitude="48.846544" license="3" longitude="2.337791" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco statue sculpture france saintegeneviéve saintegenevieve saintgeneviéve saintgenevieve michellouisvictor luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Statue de Sainte Geneviéve" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1078/1455388062_69fc74174b_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1536" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:44:50" description="This statue of Marie Stuart, reine de France et d'Ecosse sits in Jardin du Luxembourg. Mary I (popularly known as Mary, Queen of Scots) was Queen of Scots (the monarch of the Kingdom of Scotland) from 1542 to 1567, and the queen consort of France from 1559 to 1560. Mary was born in Linlithgow Palace in 1542 as the only legitimate child of James V of Scotland and Mary of Guise. James who died six days after her birth leaving her as the infant queen. Through her grandmother, Margaret Tudor, she had the strongest claim to the throne of England after the children of Henry VIII. This claim, and her Roman Catholicism, made Mary a threat to Elizabeth I of England, who finally had her executed. However, Mary's son, James VI of Scotland, succeeded Elizabeth to the English throne as James I. Mary's reported beauty and charm and her undoubted courage have made her a particularly romantic figure in history. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1455387008" latitude="48.846544" license="3" longitude="2.337791" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco mariestuart maryqueenofscots maryi statue sculpture france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Statue de Marie Stuart" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1131/1455387008_3620acf436_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1998" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:48:21" description="This statue of Marguerite d'Anjou, reine d'Angleterre, bears the base inscription: &amp;quot;Si vous ne respectez pas une Reine proscrite, respectez une mère malheureuse&amp;quot; (If you do not respect a proscribed Queen, respect an unhappy mother). Margaret of Anjou was the Queen Consort of Henry VI of England from 1445 to 1471, and led the Lancastrian contingent, in the Wars of the Roses. She was born in the Lorraine, an Imperial fief east of France ruled by the cadet branch of the French kings, the house of Anjou, to Rene I of Naples, Duke of Anjou, King of Naples and Sicily and Isabella, Duchess of Lorraine. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1455386010" latitude="48.846544" license="3" longitude="2.337791" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco margueritedanjou maragretofanjou statue sculpture france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Statue de Marguerite d'Anjou" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1137/1455386010_10aa36aa32_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1471" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:47:24" description="This statue of Anne Marie Louise d'Orléans, duchesse de Montpensier sits in Jardin du Luxembourg. Anne, Duchess of of Montpensier was a French princess, known as &amp;quot;la Grande Mademoiselle&amp;quot;, remembered for her voluminous memoirs of the reign of Louis XIV. She was born at the Louvre in 1627 to Jean-Baptiste Gaston, duc d'Orléans, &amp;quot;Monsieur,&amp;quot; the brother of Louis XIII and Marie de Bourbon, heiress of the Duke of Montpensier, who died during birth. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1454517921" latitude="48.846544" license="3" longitude="2.337791" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco annemarielouisedorleans statue sculpture france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Statue de Anne Marie Louise D'Orleans" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1429/1454517921_e1eaf22655_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1616" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-11 22:25:14" description="The Fountain &amp;quot;of the four parts of the world&amp;quot;, in the square de l'Observatoire, in Paris, three exposures photomatixed." id="387079299" latitude="48.8411" license="3" longitude="2.336837" nbComments="2" rank="29" tags="aldor paris photomatix hdr observatoire squaredelobservatoire fountain fontaine jardinmarcopolo" title="La fontaine des quatre parties du monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/188/387079299_369dccffc3_b.jpg" username="Aldor" views="398" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 10:49:37" description="Pierre Roche's L'Effort depicts one of the Twelve Labours of Heracles (Hercules), the cleaning of the Augian stables in one day. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1451030964" latitude="48.848422" license="3" longitude="2.333403" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardin garden europe luco jardinduluxembourg france leffort pierreroche hercules heracles statue sculpture luxembourggarden luxembourggardens twelvelabours twelvelabors paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - L'Effort" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1407/1451030964_60dd15a0bc_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1111" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 10:48:58" description="Pierre Roche's L'Effort depicts one of the Twelve Labours of Heracles (Hercules), the cleaning of the Augian stables in one day. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1450171483" latitude="48.848422" license="3" longitude="2.333403" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardin garden europe luco pierreroche leffort sculpture statue twelvelabours twelvelabors heracles hercules jardinduluxembourg france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - L'Effort" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1213/1450171483_06f0508f5a_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1816" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:39:23" description="Arthur Bourgeois' bronze sculpture, &lt;i&gt;L'Acteur Grec&lt;/i&gt; (The Greek Actor), was inspired by Greek theater. It depicts a young actor, manuscript in hand, and mask on his face. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1455375552" latitude="48.847875" license="3" longitude="2.338639" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco lacteurgrec greekactor arthurbourgeois statue sculpture france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - L'Acteur Grec" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1342/1455375552_d52b9c58a1_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1305" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:01:27" description="Jules Dalou's Monument to Delacroix, inaugurated in 1890, is often seen as defining by the monumental form. It is one of the earliest of its kind where the subject is represented only by a bust, while allegorical figures are grouped around it to carry out the artist's conception. Ferdinand Victor Eugène Delacroix (1798 – 1863) was a prominent French Romantic painter, whose use of expressive brush strokes and study of the optical effects of color profoundly shaped the work of the Impressionists, and whose passion for the exotic inspired the artists of the Symbolist movement. A fine lithographer, Delacroix illustrated various works of William Shakespeare, the Scottish writer Sir Walter Scott, and the German writer Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1450182507" latitude="48.848415" license="3" longitude="2.335549" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardin garden europe luco monumentaudelacroix monumenttodelacroix statue sculpture delacroix julesdalou aimejulesdalou aiméjulesdalou jardinduluxembourg france eugènedelacroix eugenedelacroix monument luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - monument au Delacroix" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1345/1450182507_a9432ca4a8_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1194" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:01:19" description="Jules Dalou's Monument to Delacroix, inaugurated in 1890, is often seen as defining by the monumental form. It is one of the earliest of its kind where the subject is represented only by a bust, while allegorical figures are grouped around it to carry out the artist's conception. Ferdinand Victor Eugène Delacroix (1798 – 1863) was a prominent French Romantic painter, whose use of expressive brush strokes and study of the optical effects of color profoundly shaped the work of the Impressionists, and whose passion for the exotic inspired the artists of the Symbolist movement. A fine lithographer, Delacroix illustrated various works of William Shakespeare, the Scottish writer Sir Walter Scott, and the German writer Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1450181223" latitude="48.848415" license="3" longitude="2.335549" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardin garden europe luco statue sculpture monumentaudelacroix monumenttodelacroix delacroix julesdalou aimejulesdalou aiméjulesdalou jardinduluxembourg france eugènedelacroix eugenedelacroix monument luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - monument au Delacroix" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1429/1450181223_48f0b89b8a_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="2523" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:17:13" description="Dominating the Jardin du Luxembourg is an octagonal pond, known as the Grand Bassin, often filled with RV boats. The bassin is surrounded by formal terraces flanked with sunbathers on a warm day. Jules Dalou's Monument to Delacroix, inaugurated in 1890, is often seen as defining by the monumental form. It is one of the earliest of its kind where the subject is represented only by a bust, while allegorical figures are grouped around it to carry out the artist's conception. Ferdinand Victor Eugène Delacroix (1798 – 1863) was a prominent French Romantic painter, whose use of expressive brush strokes and study of the optical effects of color profoundly shaped the work of the Impressionists, and whose passion for the exotic inspired the artists of the Symbolist movement. A fine lithographer, Delacroix illustrated various works of William Shakespeare, the Scottish writer Sir Walter Scott, and the German writer Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1454510145" latitude="48.846929" license="3" longitude="2.337137" nbComments="2" rank="35" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco france octagonallake pond lake grandbasin boat sailboat grandbassin luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Grand Bassin" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1375/1454510145_454397ba10_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1521" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-06 03:44:56" description="Les Quatre Parties du Monde by Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux For his last major commission, Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux, the greatest and best-known sculptor of Second Empire France, created the figural grouping of the four continents for the Fountain of the Observatory in the Luxembourg Gardens. Jean Baptiste Carpeaux's Les Quatre Parties du monde soutenant la sphére céleste (Four Parts of the World Holding a Celestial Sphere), was executed from 1868 to 1872 for la fontaine de l'Observatoire (Observatory fountain) in Jardin du Luxembourg (Luxembourg Gardens). This original half-size plaster model was exhibited in Salon de 1872. Baron Haussmann, the prefect of Paris who gave the city the face we know today, commissioned Carpeaux to design the fountain in 1867. The sculptor chose the theme of the four parts of the world turning around the celestial sphere. Not only are the four allegories dancing in a ring, but they are also revolving on the spot, rejecting the static pose usually found in this type of representation Europe scarcely touches the ground, Asia, with her long pigtail, is seen almost from the back, Africa is in a three-quarter view and America, wearing a feather headdress, is facing the spectator but her body is turned to the side. This taste for movement is one of the features of Carpeaux's art. Carpeaux originally wanted to give the figures a patina to match the skin color of the different races, but this was ruled out. It was not until 1874, a year before Carpeaux died, that the bronze fountain was set up on the designated site.Carpeaux turned the Chinese woman into a man and reproduced the statue in several different materials. The figure of Africa gave rise to a bust that Carpeaux exhibited with the inscription Why be born a slave? This reference to the abolition of slavery is also visible in the statue: America is standing on the broken chain of slavery wrapped around Africa's ankle. The first version enhanced by the play of a water fountain can be found at the southern end of the Garden Marco Polo, near the Place Camille-Jullian Jardin Marco Polo, also known as le Jardin de l'Observatoire (the Garden of the Observatory), occupies the southern half of l'avenue de l'Observatoire &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfmission.com/cgi-bin/gallery/imageFolio.cgi?direct=France/Art_and_History/Artists/Jean-Baptiste_Carpeaux&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.sfmission.com/cgi-bin/gallery/imageFolio.cgi?direct=F...&lt;/a&gt; Posing the Question of how the future will judge Art at the zeitgeist of the 21st century &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aforum/collections&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/aforum/collections&lt;/a&gt; /72157625299189937/" id="5218148030" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="musée dorsay sculpture paris france museum" title="Four parts of the World supporting the Sphere by JB Carpeaux" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5005/5218148030_3259cc5ba8_b.jpg" username="sfmission.com" views="553" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-29 18:23:45" description="" id="3153392733" latitude="48.840994" license="5" longitude="2.336397" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="paris fontainedelobservatoire france" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3079/3153392733_f89f9d85f4_b.jpg" username="myahya" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-29 09:47:03" description="" id="3777958887" latitude="48.841097" license="1" longitude="2.33673" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="paris france travel fontainedelobservatoire" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3556/3777958887_7a11a9396b_b.jpg" username="denovich" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-29 09:43:31" description="" id="3778750800" latitude="48.841097" license="1" longitude="2.33673" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="paris france travel fontainedelobservatoire mark" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2505/3778750800_2e96cc49c9_b.jpg" username="denovich" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-29 09:44:44" description="" id="3777952649" latitude="48.841097" license="1" longitude="2.33673" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="paris france travel fontainedelobservatoire mark baguette" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3548/3777952649_8f743a44d3_b.jpg" username="denovich" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-18 04:48:29" description="Taken during a run through Paris." id="4151720035" latitude="48.841026" license="5" longitude="2.336847" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="fontainedelobservatoire fountain france iphoto paris" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2719/4151720035_f85e9e0676_b.jpg" username="vitamindave" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-29 09:47:12" description="" id="3777966109" latitude="48.841097" license="1" longitude="2.33673" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="paris france travel fontainedelobservatoire" title="Mer Horses of the Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2644/3777966109_ebb9f089bf_b.jpg" username="denovich" views="33" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-03 20:33:42" description="" id="6781544463" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="jamie letsbook france paris fontainedelobservatoire fountain statues jardinduluxembourg" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7167/6781544463_8bd47b20f6_b.jpg" username="lets.book" views="38" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-04 13:41:24" description="Fontaine de l'Observatoire (1873) by Gabriel Davioud, Paris" id="768725977" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="france 6e 1870s fountain architecture architect 19thcentury c19 nineteenthcentury paris french" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1057/768725977_c23131a48b_b.jpg" username="stevecadman" views="199" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 20:47:26" description="" id="5022077447" latitude="48.841135" license="1" longitude="2.336719" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="paris france europe travel jardinmarcopolo fontainedelobservatoire" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4148/5022077447_107a1d6b09_b.jpg" username="Aurorion" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 20:50:11" description="" id="5022078315" latitude="48.841135" license="1" longitude="2.336719" nbComments="0" rank="46" tags="paris france europe travel jardinmarcopolo fontainedelobservatoire" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4105/5022078315_69cf69dd3d_b.jpg" username="Aurorion" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-20 17:43:08" description="fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde/fontaine de l’Observatoire/fontaine Carpeaux" id="3415449652" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="paris parigi fontaine carpeaux travel viaggio trip fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontainedel’observatoire" title="fontaine des Quatre-Parties-du-Monde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3569/3415449652_4d4129149d_b.jpg" username="cioccithebest" views="40" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-28 11:28:18" description="28 jul 2008 passeando por Paris" id="3744237770" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="paris" title="La Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2470/3744237770_d3379e9e40_b.jpg" username="suzzinha" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-28 11:34:30" description="28 jul 2008 passeando por Paris" id="3744241948" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="paris" title="La Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2496/3744241948_6fd97cedbe_b.jpg" username="suzzinha" views="33" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-28 11:43:19" description="28 jul 2008 passeando por Paris" id="3743450647" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="paris" title="La Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2603/3743450647_c5e269f38f_b.jpg" username="suzzinha" views="32" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-11-17 15:23:17" description="the fountain is turned off because of the cold... &amp;quot;Designed by Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet in 1873. The fountain includes a statue of a globe supported by four women, each representing a continent. To maintain symmetry, Oceania was left out.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aviewoncities.com/paris/jardinduluxembourg.htm&quot;&gt;www.aviewoncities.com/paris/jardinduluxembourg.htm&lt;/a&gt;" id="2041189926" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="jardinduluxembourg paris winter sun fountain" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2256/2041189926_d735583b18_b.jpg" username="jerseysam" views="86" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-05-18 15:47:26" description="" id="2537416304" latitude="48.841107" license="3" longitude="2.336697" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="paris france water horse sculpture fountain" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2341/2537416304_af2968f5f7_b.jpg" username="Dmitry Shakin" views="55" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-05-18 15:45:07" description="" id="2534212927" latitude="48.841107" license="3" longitude="2.336697" nbComments="8" rank="53" tags="paris france fountain horse water sculpture" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3062/2534212927_6e9c3a5a0c_b.jpg" username="Dmitry Shakin" views="169" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-05-18 15:46:34" description="" id="2536596359" latitude="48.841107" license="3" longitude="2.336697" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="paris france water horse sculpture fountain" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3151/2536596359_d055bc6d03_b.jpg" username="Dmitry Shakin" views="70" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-05-18 15:47:05" description="" id="2536597663" latitude="48.841107" license="3" longitude="2.336697" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="paris france water horse sculpture fountain" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2024/2536597663_7687656f5d_b.jpg" username="Dmitry Shakin" views="46" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-05-18 15:46:49" description="" id="2537414982" latitude="48.841107" license="3" longitude="2.336697" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="paris france water horse sculpture fountain" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2240/2537414982_e554d2b22e_b.jpg" username="Dmitry Shakin" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-10 20:12:48" description="This is for DinyarG's request." id="2581040570" latitude="48.84122" license="3" longitude="2.336654" nbComments="6" rank="57" tags="paris fontainedesquatrepartiesdumonde fontaine fountain lesquatrepartiesdumondesoutenantlasphèrecéleste wysiwyg" title="Detail of Fontaine de l'Observatoire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3157/2581040570_c89340746c_b.jpg" username="Istvan" views="129" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-29 09:45:46" description="" id="3777953699" latitude="48.841097" license="1" longitude="2.33673" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="paris france travel fontainedelobservatoire wildlife duck" title="Sleepy duck and duckling" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3153/3777953699_1fb25ca4bc_b.jpg" username="denovich" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:46:35" description="Zacharie Astruc's 1883 bronze statue, &lt;i&gt;Le Marchand de Masques&lt;/i&gt; (The Merchant of the Masks), presents the masks of Hugo, Gambetta, Dumas, Delacroix, Carpeaux, Corot, Berlioz, Faure, Balzac, and Barbey d' Aurevilly around its base. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1454509427" latitude="48.847758" license="3" longitude="2.338918" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco lemarchanddemasque themerchantofthemasks zacharieastruc statue sculpture france luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Le Marchand de Masque" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1007/1454509427_7e8b0667bb_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1405" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-10 11:28:55" description="Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?t=k&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=48.841062,2.336800&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=48.841081,2.3368&amp;amp;spn=0.000817,0.002661&amp;amp;om=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see where this photo was taken." id="211912090" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="observatoire carpaux frémiet bronze chevaux paris geotagged geo:lat=48841062 geo:lon=2336800 panorama ptassembler smartblend hdr fontaine fountain france étiennecazin etiennecazin" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire - 26-05-2006 - 14h22" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/72/211912090_1d08655b15_b.jpg" username="Panoramas" views="443" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-10 11:28:53" description="Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?t=k&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=48.841062,2.336800&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=48.841081,2.3368&amp;amp;spn=0.000817,0.002661&amp;amp;om=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see where this photo was taken." id="211912066" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="observatoire carpaux frémiet bronze chevaux paris geotagged geo:lat=48841062 geo:lon=2336800 panorama ptassembler smartblend hdr fontaine fountain france étiennecazin etiennecazin" title="Fontaine de l'Observatoire - 26-05-2006 - 14h17" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/66/211912066_502484e669_b.jpg" username="Panoramas" views="423" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 11:23:45" description="La Fontaine de Médicis (Fountain of Medicis), originally known as La grotte du Luxembourg (The cave of Luxembourg), was commissioned in 1624 by the Marie de Médicis (Marie de' Medici), the second wife and widow of King Henri IV, and mother of King Louis XIII, who wanted to emulate la grotte de Buontalenti in jardins de Boboli in her hometown Florence. Designed by engineer Florentin Thomas Francine, it comprised of three niches and a pediment with coats of arms of France and Médicis, backed by la fontaine de Léda. The fountain was moved and refitted in 1861. Alphonse de Gisors restored the arms, and created a 50 meter water alley lined with trees. The new basin was filled with the The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450304863/&quot;&gt;centerpiece sculpture&lt;/a&gt;, added in 1866 by Auguste Louis Ottin, depicts the cyclops, Polyphème, waiting to crush &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450305677/&quot;&gt;Galatée, who is holding Acis&lt;/a&gt;, with a boulder, and Pan faune and Diane chasseresse (Diana the Huntress) watching from each side. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1451159248" latitude="48.848154" license="3" longitude="2.338929" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardinduluxembourg jardin garden europe luco fontainedemédicis fontainedemedicis france fountain fontaine medicis sculpture statue augustelouisottin alphonsedegisors florentinthomasfrancine luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Fontaine de Médicis" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1412/1451159248_bd449547e8_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="2800" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-03 20:38:40" description="" id="6781548383" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="jamie letsbook france paris fontainedelobservatoire fountain statues jardinduluxembourg globe" title="Atlas" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7015/6781548383_7eeccfa2c6_b.jpg" username="lets.book" views="36" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-03 20:44:22" description="" id="6781556169" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="jamie letsbook france paris fontainedelobservatoire fountain statues jardinduluxembourg blackandwhite" title="Statues And Trees" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7155/6781556169_eba93a6479_b.jpg" username="lets.book" views="49" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 16:10:25" description="La fontaine, située place Camille Jullian au milieu de l'avenue de l'Observatoire près du boulevard st Michel, a été terminée en 1874. Elle est composée d'un socle flanqué de chevaux marins, oeuvre d'Emmanuel Frémiet, supportant un groupe sculpté de Jean Baptiste Carpeaux. Le Globe, orné des signes du Zodiaque, a été sculpté par Legrain." id="5018189014" latitude="48.841369" license="4" longitude="2.336745" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="jardin explorateurs fontaine manifestations greves defile cortege sudptt syndicats sud sudposte retraites solidaires paris iledefrance capitale 75 france frankreich 6emearrondissement" title="JARDIN DES GRANDS EXPLORATEURS" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4148/5018189014_011f061261_b.jpg" username="marsupilami92" views="49" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 10:49:48" description="This large bust of Stefan Zweig by Félix Schivo was inauguarated in le Jardin du Luxembourg on December 9, 2003. Stefan Zweig (1881 – 1942) was an Austrian novelist, playwright, journalist and biographer. The Jardin du Luxembourg, referred to by locals as Luco. is a 224,500 m² public park--the largest in the city--designed in the French style in 1612. The park is centered around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455381636/&quot;&gt;Palais du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;, constructed between 1615 and 1627 for Marie de Medicis, mother of Louis XIII, and currently the home of the French Senate. The Jardin features two noteworthy fountas--the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1451160602/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de Medicis&lt;/a&gt;, a baroque fountain designed in 1624; and at the southern end, in an extension known as Jardins de l'Observatoire, Davioud, Carpaux and Frémiet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1455883526/&quot;&gt;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&lt;/a&gt;, erected in 1873." id="1451027240" latitude="48.848422" license="3" longitude="2.333403" nbComments="0" rank="66" tags="luxembourgquarter quartierluxembourg jardin garden europe luco bust statue sculpture stefanzweig jardinduluxembourg france félixschivo felixschivo luxembourggarden luxembourggardens paris" title="Paris - Luxembourg Quarter: Jardin du Luxembourg - Bust of Stefan Zweig" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1362/1451027240_0679f264cc_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="929" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-13 07:14:26" description="Paris, place Camille Jullian, fontaine de l'observatoire (fontaine &amp;quot;des quatre parties du monde&amp;quot;)" id="145559646" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="67" tags="paris statue fish" title="Poisson de pierre" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/50/145559646_cdd198e63c_b.jpg" username="kurto" views="118" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-13 05:36:58" description="Read about this French officer and explorer here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Francis_Garnier&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Francis_Garnier&lt;/a&gt; The plaque says that his ashes are interred within the monument that honors him. The monument is located near the &amp;quot;Fontaine de l'Observatoire&amp;quot;, on the Blvd. Saint-Michel. The monument was sculpted by Denys Puech. It is located at the Place Camille Julian, near the Fontaine de l'Observatoire, Paris 6th arr." id="8218780178" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="68" tags="francisgarnier grave plaque monument paris 6tharr placecamillejulian openplaques:id=11849" title="Francis Garnier plaque - his ashes buried here" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8204/8218780178_e9abdb939b_b.jpg" username="Monceau" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-01-03 10:09:48" description="Fontaine des jardins de l'Observatoire à Paris" id="3163927691" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="ice cold froid chevaux horses" title="Le gel s'accentue" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3076/3163927691_78b1f9c78a_b.jpg" username="john-aïves-1946" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-04-11 03:31:38" description="Fontaine de l'observatoire, near Luxembourg Gardens  Paris, France" id="455896795" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="4" rank="70" tags="france fountain water horse" title="Wet and Wild" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/197/455896795_364b1e7827_b.jpg" username="Telstar Logistics" views="183" />
</photos>
