<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="July Column Paris">

<photo  date_taken="2010-01-28 13:42:04" description="This working group had at least one interest : a nice photowalk during the lunchbreak :) &lt;i&gt;The Port de l'Arsenal&lt;/i&gt; is a boat basin in Paris. It links the Canal Saint-Martin, which begins at the Place de la Bastille, to the Seine, at the Quai de la Rapée (source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bassin_de_l'Arsenal&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;)." id="4312685182" latitude="48.849248" license="3" longitude="2.36706" nbComments="6" rank="1" tags="2010 samyras paris 75012 portdelarsenal julycolumn bastille france iledefrance europe reflection clouds boats project365 project36528 365 day28 pentax k200d twtme shuttercal freefr urban cityscape aphotoaday samyraserin samyra008 fpdf2013" title="Port de l'Arsenal, Paris 28-365" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4068/4312685182_13c35369cf_b.jpg" username="Samyra Serin" views="137" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-01 12:35:51" description="Built in 1831, this column commemorates the July Revolution of 1830, when King Charles X of the House of Bourbon was overthrown and replaced by King Louis-Phillipe the more liberal House of Orleans, which was also the shift from France's absolute monarchy to a constitutional monarchy. Cast in bronze drums, this 74m tall Corinthian column is topped by a gilded globe and Auguste Dumont's Spirit of Liberty. Inscribed on the monument are the names of the 615 dead of the July Revolution, who are buried in a columbarium in the column's foundations. Another 200 victims of the Revolution of 1848, which overthrew the July Monarchy, are also buried there. Perhaps unsurprisingly, the two other great revolts also have left their mark here at the Place de la Bastille. This was the site of &lt;a href=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4e/Prise_de_la_Bastille.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the infamous Bastille prison that was stormed in 1789&lt;/a&gt; , initiating the French Revolution that led to the collapse of the Ancien Régime. In 1871, this square was the location of one of the last centers of resistance during the Paris Commune of 1871. This traditionally restive eastern portion of Paris would also be the setting for Victor Hugo's barricades in Les Miserables (which references the small, failed 1832 June Uprising). Place de la Bastille, Paris, France Colonne de Juillet, Place de la Bastille, Paris, France" id="5712036164" latitude="48.853027" license="1" longitude="2.368319" nbComments="0" rank="2" tags="july column paris ile de france place la bastille monarchy arrondissement" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3329/5712036164_6c2b236f04_b.jpg" username="www78" views="57" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-01-29 13:05:47" description="" id="4315020544" latitude="48.8515" license="3" longitude="2.368733" nbComments="2" rank="3" tags="2010 samyras paris 75012 portdelarsenal julycolumn bastille france iledefrance europe clouds boats project365 project36529 365 day29 pentax k200d shuttercal urban cityscape aphotoaday samyraserin samyra008" title="July Column &amp; Port de l'Arsenal 29-365" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2761/4315020544_79334558c5_b.jpg" username="Samyra Serin" views="62" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 11:20:15" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8207518417" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="4" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8488/8207518417_b3aa41cd44_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-16 22:00:01" description="(@ Paris, France) We stop for a short while our entertainment program about nature and beaches and stuff to bring some proximity journalism..." id="3828803313" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="5" rank="5" tags="paris france riotasasport bbq" title="Paris will always be Paris #1" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3508/3828803313_333bdc8cbd_b.jpg" username="hern42" views="107" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-27 00:00:02" description="ITA Colonna di luglio situata sulla piazza della Bastiglia. Sormontata dalla statua del &amp;quot;Genio della Libertà&amp;quot;, questa colonna in bronzo raggiunge i 51,5 m di altezza. Il monumento ricorda le vittime dei moti del luglio 1830 che determinarono il rovesciamento della monarchia. La cripta custodisce le spoglie di 504 vittime di quegli scontri e di altri caduti nella rivoluzione del 1848 ENG Column of July located in front of the Bastille. Topped by the statue of the &amp;quot;Genius of Liberty&amp;quot;, this column bronze reaches 51.5 m in height. The monument remembers the victims of the battles in July 1830 that led to the end of the monarchy. The crypt houses the remains of 504 victims of those battles and other soldiers killed in the revolution of 1848" id="3155211335" latitude="48.862456" license="6" longitude="2.336654" nbComments="1" rank="6" tags="paris parigi francia france colonnedejuillet colonna column geniodellalibertà geniusofliberty géniedelaliberté placedelabastille piazzadellabastiglia squareofbastille ericborda" title="Paris (Francia)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3284/3155211335_332c810c11_b.jpg" username="Eric Borda" views="183" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 08:56:10" description="Le Panthéon, atop Montagne Sainte-Geneviève at Place du Panthéon, was originally built by King Louis XIV between 1757-1790 as Église Sainte-Geneviève, dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève, the patron saint of Paris. Designed by Jacques-Germain Soufflot, it is considered one of the earliest and most prominent works of Neoclassicism. After many changes over the year, the Panthéon now combines liturgical functions with its role as burial place for famous French heroes. When Louis suffered from a mysterious illness in 1744 he vowed to build a church dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève if he would survive. After he recovered, he entrusted the Marquis of Marigny with the task of replacing the ruined 6th century basilica, Abbey Sainte-Geneviève. Foundations were laid in 1758, but due to financial difficulties, it wasn't completed until 1789-after Soufflot's death, by his pupil Jean-Baptiste Rondelet. In the midst of the French Revolution, the Constituent Assembly of the Revolution decided by decree to transform the church into a mausoleum to accommodate the remains of the great men of France and building was adapted by architect Quatremère de Quincy. In 1806, the building was turned into a church again, but since 1885 it has served civically as a &amp;quot;Temple of Fame.&amp;quot; In 1851 physicist Léon Foucault famously demonstrated the rotation of the Earth by constructing the 67-meter&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444819885&quot;&gt;Foucault's pendulum&lt;/a&gt; beneath the central dome. The Panthéon is designed in a Greek-cross plan, 110-meters long and 85-meters wide, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445222374&quot;&gt;massive portico of Corinthian columns&lt;/a&gt;, modeled on the Pantehon in Rome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445221640&quot;&gt;surmounted by a small dome&lt;/a&gt; that reaches a height of 83-meters. The dome features three superimposed shells, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/305228615/&quot;&gt;St. Paul's Cathedral in London&lt;/a&gt;. The low relief on the pediment The Panthéon, &lt;i&gt;la Patrie, entre la Liberté et l'Histoire, distribue des couronnes aux grands hommes (Patria (The Nation) Distributing Crowns Handed to Her by Liberty to Great Men, Civil and Military, While History Inscribes Their Name)&lt;/i&gt;, by David d’Angers is an allegory to the glory of great men. Added to the pediment in 1837, it sits atop an inscription--Aux grands hommes la patrie reconnaissante (A Grateful nation honours its great men)--which was added originally in 1791 and taken off at the time of the Restoration only to be restored under the July Monarchy. To the left, on the side where Liberty is depicted, the following civil personages are presented to the Nation: Malesherbes, Mirabeau, Monge, Fenélon, Manuel, Carnot, Berthollet, Laplace, David, Cuvier, La Fayette, Voltaire and Rousseau, seated side by side, with Chigat expiring amongst the faculty students. To the right, on the side of History, stands the military figures: General Bonaparte, the drummer of Arcola, soldiers from each branch of service, personifying military valour, and finally, the students of the École Polytechnique. The vast crypt covers the whole surface of the building, Among those buried in its necropolis are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449685355&quot;&gt;Voltaire&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449684795&quot;&gt;Rousseau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450546508&quot;&gt;Victor Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450540512&quot;&gt;Alexandre Dumas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449682245&quot;&gt;Louis Braile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450545930&quot;&gt;Jean Jaurès&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444594509&quot;&gt;Marie Curie&lt;/a&gt;, Emile Zola, and Soufflot." id="1444361609" latitude="48.846413" license="3" longitude="2.34521" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="france europe panthéon pantheon pantheondeparis panthéondeparis latinquarter quartierlatin pediment lefronton sculpture dome l’édifice greekrevival paris jeanbaptisterondelet montagnesaintegeneviève montagnesaintegenevieve peristyle davidd’angers relief lowrelief basrelief patria auxgrandshommeslapatriereconnaissante lapatrieentrelalibertéetlhistoiredistribuedescouronnesauxgrandshommes" title="Paris - Latin Quarter: Panthéon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1338/1444361609_57c9fdb82f_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="618" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 08:00:11" description="Le Panthéon, atop Montagne Sainte-Geneviève at Place du Panthéon, was originally built by King Louis XIV between 1757-1790 as Église Sainte-Geneviève, dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève, the patron saint of Paris. Designed by Jacques-Germain Soufflot, it is considered one of the earliest and most prominent works of Neoclassicism. After many changes over the year, the Panthéon now combines liturgical functions with its role as burial place for famous French heroes. When Louis suffered from a mysterious illness in 1744 he vowed to build a church dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève if he would survive. After he recovered, he entrusted the Marquis of Marigny with the task of replacing the ruined 6th century basilica, Abbey Sainte-Geneviève. Foundations were laid in 1758, but due to financial difficulties, it wasn't completed until 1789-after Soufflot's death, by his pupil Jean-Baptiste Rondelet. In the midst of the French Revolution, the Constituent Assembly of the Revolution decided by decree to transform the church into a mausoleum to accommodate the remains of the great men of France and building was adapted by architect Quatremère de Quincy. In 1806, the building was turned into a church again, but since 1885 it has served civically as a &amp;quot;Temple of Fame.&amp;quot; In 1851 physicist Léon Foucault famously demonstrated the rotation of the Earth by constructing the 67-meter&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444819885&quot;&gt;Foucault's pendulum&lt;/a&gt; beneath the central dome. The Panthéon is designed in a Greek-cross plan, 110-meters long and 85-meters wide, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445222374&quot;&gt;massive portico of Corinthian columns&lt;/a&gt;, modeled on the Pantehon in Rome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445221640&quot;&gt;surmounted by a small dome&lt;/a&gt; that reaches a height of 83-meters. The dome features three superimposed shells, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/305228615/&quot;&gt;St. Paul's Cathedral in London&lt;/a&gt;. The low relief on the pediment The Panthéon, &lt;i&gt;la Patrie, entre la Liberté et l'Histoire, distribue des couronnes aux grands hommes (Patria (The Nation) Distributing Crowns Handed to Her by Liberty to Great Men, Civil and Military, While History Inscribes Their Name)&lt;/i&gt;, by David d’Angers is an allegory to the glory of great men. Added to the pediment in 1837, it sits atop an inscription--Aux grands hommes la patrie reconnaissante (A Grateful nation honours its great men)--which was added originally in 1791 and taken off at the time of the Restoration only to be restored under the July Monarchy. To the left, on the side where Liberty is depicted, the following civil personages are presented to the Nation: Malesherbes, Mirabeau, Monge, Fenélon, Manuel, Carnot, Berthollet, Laplace, David, Cuvier, La Fayette, Voltaire and Rousseau, seated side by side, with Chigat expiring amongst the faculty students. To the right, on the side of History, stands the military figures: General Bonaparte, the drummer of Arcola, soldiers from each branch of service, personifying military valour, and finally, the students of the École Polytechnique. The vast crypt covers the whole surface of the building, Among those buried in its necropolis are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449685355&quot;&gt;Voltaire&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449684795&quot;&gt;Rousseau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450546508&quot;&gt;Victor Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450540512&quot;&gt;Alexandre Dumas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449682245&quot;&gt;Louis Braile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450545930&quot;&gt;Jean Jaurès&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444594509&quot;&gt;Marie Curie&lt;/a&gt;, Emile Zola, and Soufflot." id="1445220028" latitude="48.846413" license="3" longitude="2.34521" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="france europe panthéon pantheon pantheondeparis panthéondeparis latinquarter quartierlatin greekrevival l’édifice lefronton paris jeanbaptisterondelet montagnesaintegeneviève montagnesaintegenevieve pediment peristyle davidd’angers relief lowrelief basrelief sculpture patria auxgrandshommeslapatriereconnaissante lapatrieentrelalibertéetlhistoiredistribuedescouronnesauxgrandshommes" title="Paris - Latin Quarter: Panthéon - L’édifice et le fronton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1199/1445220028_3571c600f4_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="666" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 08:30:24" description="François-Marie Arouet, better known by the pen name Voltaire, was a French Enlightenment writer, essayist, and philosopher known for his wit and his defence of civil liberties, including both freedom of religion and free trade. A prolific writer, he produced works in almost every literary form including plays, poetry, novels, essays, historical and scientific works, more than 20,000 letters and more than 2,000 books and pamphlets. An outspoken supporter of social reform and satirical polemicist, he frequently made use of his works to criticize Catholic Church dogma and the French institutions of his day. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1387671984&quot;&gt;Voltaire died&lt;/a&gt; at the age of 83 on May 28, 1778 while back in Paris for the first time in 20 years to see the opening of his latest tragedy, Irene. Refusing to retract his criticism of the church on his deathbed, he was denied a proper Christian burial, but friends managed to bury his body secretly at the abbey of Scellières in Champagne. In July 1791, the National Assembly, which regarded him as a forerunner of the French revolution, had his remains brought back to the Panthéon. There was an elaborate ceremony, complete with an orchestra, and the music included a piece that André Grétry composed specially for the event. A widely-repeated story that the remains of Voltaire were stolen by religious fanatics in 1814 or 1821 during the Pantheon restoration and thrown into a garbage heap is false. Such rumours resulted in the coffin being opened in 1897, which confirmed that his remains were still present. Le Panthéon, atop Montagne Sainte-Geneviève at Place du Panthéon, was originally built by King Louis XIV between 1757-1790 as Église Sainte-Geneviève, dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève, the patron saint of Paris. Designed by Jacques-Germain Soufflot, it is considered one of the earliest and most prominent works of Neoclassicism. After many changes over the year, the Panthéon now combines liturgical functions with its role as burial place for famous French heroes. When Louis suffered from a mysterious illness in 1744 he vowed to build a church dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève if he would survive. After he recovered, he entrusted the Marquis of Marigny with the task of replacing the ruined 6th century basilica, Abbey Sainte-Geneviève. Foundations were laid in 1758, but due to financial difficulties, it wasn't completed until 1789-after Soufflot's death, by his pupil Jean-Baptiste Rondelet. In the midst of the French Revolution, the Constituent Assembly of the Revolution decided by decree to transform the church into a mausoleum to accommodate the remains of the great men of France and building was adapted by architect Quatremère de Quincy. In 1806, the building was turned into a church again, but since 1885 it has served civically as a &amp;quot;Temple of Fame.&amp;quot; In 1851 physicist Léon Foucault famously demonstrated the rotation of the Earth by constructing the 67-meter &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444819885&quot;&gt;Foucault's pendulum&lt;/a&gt; beneath the central dome. The Panthéon is designed in a Greek-cross plan, 110-meters long and 85-meters wide, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445222374&quot;&gt;massive portico of Corinthian columns&lt;/a&gt;, modeled on the Pantehon in Rome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445221640&quot;&gt;surmounted by a small dome&lt;/a&gt; that reaches a height of 83-meters. The dome features three superimposed shells, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/305228615/&quot;&gt;St. Paul's Cathedral in London&lt;/a&gt;. The vast crypt covers the whole surface of the building, Among the others buried in its necropolis are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449684795&quot;&gt;Rousseau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450546508&quot;&gt;Victor Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450540512&quot;&gt;Alexandre Dumas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449682245&quot;&gt;Louis Braile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450545930&quot;&gt;Jean Jaurès&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444594509&quot;&gt;Marie Curie&lt;/a&gt;, Emile Zola, and Soufflot." id="1450545258" latitude="48.846212" license="3" longitude="2.346262" nbComments="0" rank="9" tags="france europe panthéon pantheon pantheondeparis panthéondeparis latinquarter quartierlatin lacryptegalerieest lacrypte crypte crypt tomb toumbeau voltaire paris montagnesaintegeneviève montagnesaintegenevieve necropolis mausoleum" title="Paris - Latin Quarter: Panthéon - La crypte galerie est - le tombeau de Voltaire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1016/1450545258_9ee5df9a69_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1258" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 08:55:32" description="The low relief on the pediment The Panthéon, &lt;i&gt;la Patrie, entre la Liberté et l'Histoire, distribue des couronnes aux grands hommes (Patria (The Nation) Distributing Crowns Handed to Her by Liberty to Great Men, Civil and Military, While History Inscribes Their Name)&lt;/i&gt;, by David d’Angers is an allegory to the glory of great men. Added to the pediment in 1837, it sits atop an inscription--Aux grands hommes la patrie reconnaissante (A Grateful nation honours its great men)--which was added originally in 1791 and taken off at the time of the Restoration only to be restored under the July Monarchy. To the left, on the side where Liberty is depicted, the following civil personages are presented to the Nation: Malesherbes, Mirabeau, Monge, Fenélon, Manuel, Carnot, Berthollet, Laplace, David, Cuvier, La Fayette, Voltaire and Rousseau, seated side by side, with Chigat expiring amongst the faculty students. To the right, on the side of History, stands the military figures: General Bonaparte, the drummer of Arcola, soldiers from each branch of service, personifying military valour, and finally, the students of the École Polytechnique. Le Panthéon, atop Montagne Sainte-Geneviève at Place du Panthéon, was originally built by King Louis XIV between 1757-1790 as Église Sainte-Geneviève, dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève, the patron saint of Paris. Designed by Jacques-Germain Soufflot, it is considered one of the earliest and most prominent works of Neoclassicism. After many changes over the year, the Panthéon now combines liturgical functions with its role as burial place for famous French heroes. When Louis suffered from a mysterious illness in 1744 he vowed to build a church dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève if he would survive. After he recovered, he entrusted the Marquis of Marigny with the task of replacing the ruined 6th century basilica, Abbey Sainte-Geneviève. Foundations were laid in 1758, but due to financial difficulties, it wasn't completed until 1789-after Soufflot's death, by his pupil Jean-Baptiste Rondelet. In the midst of the French Revolution, the Constituent Assembly of the Revolution decided by decree to transform the church into a mausoleum to accommodate the remains of the great men of France and building was adapted by architect Quatremère de Quincy. In 1806, the building was turned into a church again, but since 1885 it has served civically as a &amp;quot;Temple of Fame.&amp;quot; In 1851 physicist Léon Foucault famously demonstrated the rotation of the Earth by constructing the 67-meter&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444819885&quot;&gt;Foucault's pendulum&lt;/a&gt; beneath the central dome. The Panthéon is designed in a Greek-cross plan, 110-meters long and 85-meters wide, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445222374&quot;&gt;massive portico of Corinthian columns&lt;/a&gt;, modeled on the Pantehon in Rome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445221640&quot;&gt;surmounted by a small dome&lt;/a&gt; that reaches a height of 83-meters. The dome features three superimposed shells, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/305228615/&quot;&gt;St. Paul's Cathedral in London&lt;/a&gt;. The vast crypt covers the whole surface of the building, Among those buried in its necropolis are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449685355&quot;&gt;Voltaire&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449684795&quot;&gt;Rousseau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450546508&quot;&gt;Victor Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450540512&quot;&gt;Alexandre Dumas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449682245&quot;&gt;Louis Braile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450545930&quot;&gt;Jean Jaurès&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444594509&quot;&gt;Marie Curie&lt;/a&gt;, Emile Zola, and Soufflot." id="1445215444" latitude="48.846413" license="3" longitude="2.34521" nbComments="1" rank="10" tags="france europe panthéon pantheon pantheondeparis panthéondeparis latinquarter quartierlatin pediment lefronton sculpture greekrevival paris jeanbaptisterondelet montagnesaintegeneviève montagnesaintegenevieve peristyle davidd’angers relief lowrelief basrelief patria auxgrandshommeslapatriereconnaissante lapatrieentrelalibertéetlhistoiredistribuedescouronnesauxgrandshommes" title="Paris - Latin Quarter: Panthéon - la Patrie, entre la Liberté et l'Histoire, distribue des couronnes aux grands hommes" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1433/1445215444_71e89ef372_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1339" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 08:32:40" description="François-Marie Arouet, better known by the pen name Voltaire, was a French Enlightenment writer, essayist, and philosopher known for his wit and his defence of civil liberties, including both freedom of religion and free trade. A prolific writer, he produced works in almost every literary form including plays, poetry, novels, essays, historical and scientific works, more than 20,000 letters and more than 2,000 books and pamphlets. An outspoken supporter of social reform and satirical polemicist, he frequently made use of his works to criticize Catholic Church dogma and the French institutions of his day. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1387671984&quot;&gt;Voltaire died&lt;/a&gt; at the age of 83 on May 28, 1778 while back in Paris for the first time in 20 years to see the opening of his latest tragedy, Irene. Refusing to retract his criticism of the church on his deathbed, he was denied a proper Christian burial, but friends managed to bury his body secretly at the abbey of Scellières in Champagne. In July 1791, the National Assembly, which regarded him as a forerunner of the French revolution, had his remains brought back to the Panthéon. There was an elaborate ceremony, complete with an orchestra, and the music included a piece that André Grétry composed specially for the event. A widely-repeated story that the remains of Voltaire were stolen by religious fanatics in 1814 or 1821 during the Pantheon restoration and thrown into a garbage heap is false. Such rumours resulted in the coffin being opened in 1897, which confirmed that his remains were still present. Le Panthéon, atop Montagne Sainte-Geneviève at Place du Panthéon, was originally built by King Louis XIV between 1757-1790 as Église Sainte-Geneviève, dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève, the patron saint of Paris. Designed by Jacques-Germain Soufflot, it is considered one of the earliest and most prominent works of Neoclassicism. After many changes over the year, the Panthéon now combines liturgical functions with its role as burial place for famous French heroes. When Louis suffered from a mysterious illness in 1744 he vowed to build a church dedicated to Sainte-Geneviève if he would survive. After he recovered, he entrusted the Marquis of Marigny with the task of replacing the ruined 6th century basilica, Abbey Sainte-Geneviève. Foundations were laid in 1758, but due to financial difficulties, it wasn't completed until 1789-after Soufflot's death, by his pupil Jean-Baptiste Rondelet. In the midst of the French Revolution, the Constituent Assembly of the Revolution decided by decree to transform the church into a mausoleum to accommodate the remains of the great men of France and building was adapted by architect Quatremère de Quincy. In 1806, the building was turned into a church again, but since 1885 it has served civically as a &amp;quot;Temple of Fame.&amp;quot; In 1851 physicist Léon Foucault famously demonstrated the rotation of the Earth by constructing the 67-meter &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444819885&quot;&gt;Foucault's pendulum&lt;/a&gt; beneath the central dome. The Panthéon is designed in a Greek-cross plan, 110-meters long and 85-meters wide, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445222374&quot;&gt;massive portico of Corinthian columns&lt;/a&gt;, modeled on the Pantehon in Rome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1445221640&quot;&gt;surmounted by a small dome&lt;/a&gt; that reaches a height of 83-meters. The dome features three superimposed shells, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/305228615/&quot;&gt;St. Paul's Cathedral in London&lt;/a&gt;. The vast crypt covers the whole surface of the building, Among the others buried in its necropolis are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449684795&quot;&gt;Rousseau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450546508&quot;&gt;Victor Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450540512&quot;&gt;Alexandre Dumas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1449682245&quot;&gt;Louis Braile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1450545930&quot;&gt;Jean Jaurès&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1444594509&quot;&gt;Marie Curie&lt;/a&gt;, Emile Zola, and Soufflot." id="1449685355" latitude="48.846212" license="3" longitude="2.346262" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="france europe panthéon pantheon pantheondeparis panthéondeparis latinquarter quartierlatin lacryptegalerieest lacrypte crypte crypt tomb toumbeau voltaire statue sculpture paris montagnesaintegeneviève montagnesaintegenevieve necropolis mausoleum" title="Paris - Latin Quarter: Panthéon - La crypte galerie est - le tombeau de Voltaire" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1072/1449685355_5644dc1074_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1527" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-06 11:54:49" description="Thomas Couture's &lt;i&gt;Romains de la décadence&lt;/i&gt; (Romans during the Decadence) took three years to complete, finally finishing in time for Salon de 1847. Couture wanted to give fresh impetus to French painting and to do so referred, rather conventionally, to the masters of ancient Greece, the Renaissance and the Flemish school. The work is a history painting, regarded as the noblest genre during the 19th century: it therefore had to represent human behaviour and convey a moral message. This was explained by Couture himself, who quoted two lines from the Roman poet Juvenal, in the catalogue for the Salon: &amp;quot;Crueller than war, vice fell upon Rome and avenged the conquered world&amp;quot;. In the centre of the painting, Couture has placed a group of debauched revellers, exhausted and disillusioned or still drinking and dancing. In the foreground are three men who are not taking part in the drunken revels: on the left, a melancholic boy sitting on a column and on the right two foreign visitors casting a disapproving eye over the scene. The antique statues looming above the group also seem to be condemning the orgy. Apart from illustrating an ancient text, Couture was alluding to French society of his time. A Jacobin, Republican and anticlerical, he criticised the moral decadence of France under the July monarchy, the ruling class of which had been discredited by a series of scandals. This painting is therefore a &amp;quot;realist allegory&amp;quot;, and the art critics of 1847 were quick to see in these Romans &amp;quot;The French of the Decadence&amp;quot;. The Musée d'Orsay (The Orsay Museum), housed in the former railway station, the Gare d'Orsay, holds mainly French art dating from 1848 to 1914, including paintings, sculptures, furniture, and photography, and is probably best known for its extensive collection of impressionist masterpieces by popular painters such as Monet and Renoir. Many of these works were held at the Galerie nationale du Jeu de Paume prior to the museum's opening in 1986." id="1392588734" latitude="48.859844" license="3" longitude="2.326596" nbComments="2" rank="12" tags="france europe muséedorsay orsaymuseum museum musée art painting romainsdeladecadence romansduringthedecadence museedorsay dorsay orsay paris" title="Paris - Musée d'Orsay: Thomas Couture's Romains de la décadence" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1129/1392588734_b32711ca0b_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="7394" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-06 11:54:19" description="Thomas Couture's &lt;i&gt;Romains de la décadence&lt;/i&gt; (Romans during the Decadence) took three years to complete, finally finishing in time for Salon de 1847. Couture wanted to give fresh impetus to French painting and to do so referred, rather conventionally, to the masters of ancient Greece, the Renaissance and the Flemish school. The work is a history painting, regarded as the noblest genre during the 19th century: it therefore had to represent human behaviour and convey a moral message. This was explained by Couture himself, who quoted two lines from the Roman poet Juvenal, in the catalogue for the Salon: &amp;quot;Crueller than war, vice fell upon Rome and avenged the conquered world&amp;quot;. In the centre of the painting, Couture has placed a group of debauched revellers, exhausted and disillusioned or still drinking and dancing. In the foreground are three men who are not taking part in the drunken revels: on the left, a melancholic boy sitting on a column and on the right two foreign visitors casting a disapproving eye over the scene. The antique statues looming above the group also seem to be condemning the orgy. Apart from illustrating an ancient text, Couture was alluding to French society of his time. A Jacobin, Republican and anticlerical, he criticised the moral decadence of France under the July monarchy, the ruling class of which had been discredited by a series of scandals. This painting is therefore a &amp;quot;realist allegory&amp;quot;, and the art critics of 1847 were quick to see in these Romans &amp;quot;The French of the Decadence&amp;quot;. The Musée d'Orsay (The Orsay Museum), housed in the former railway station, the Gare d'Orsay, holds mainly French art dating from 1848 to 1914, including paintings, sculptures, furniture, and photography, and is probably best known for its extensive collection of impressionist masterpieces by popular painters such as Monet and Renoir. Many of these works were held at the Galerie nationale du Jeu de Paume prior to the museum's opening in 1986." id="1392587812" latitude="48.859844" license="3" longitude="2.326596" nbComments="0" rank="13" tags="france europe muséedorsay orsaymuseum museum musée art painting thomascouture romainsdeladécadence romainsdeladecadence romansduringthedecadence museedorsay dorsay orsay paris" title="Paris - Musée d'Orsay: Thomas Couture's Romains de la décadence" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1435/1392587812_13bb92107a_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="4432" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 15:12:59" description="The neoclassical Panthéon was originally built as a church to St Genevieve, to fulfill a vow made by Louis XV on recovery from an illness. The architect was Jacques-Gabriel Soufflot (July 22, 1713-80). Construction on the building began 1758, but was hampered by the economic situation; it was finally completed in 1790. In 1791 the National Constituent Assembly declared that the church should be a mausoleum &amp;quot;&amp;quot;To the great men, the grateful homeland&amp;quot;&amp;quot;. Taken in the 5ieme Arrondissement" id="8207542799" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="200912 paris thepanthéon neoclassicalarchitecture stgenevieve jacquesgabrielsoufflot nationalconstituentassembly 5iemearrondissement" title="Waiting by the Columns" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8480/8207542799_1a49b84548_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-07-12 03:54:04" description="A lucky girl am I married to the king of all BBQs. Dov can make a mean steak; he’s methodical about choosing the right cut, marinating them and cooking them to perfect medium-rare temperature. Dov will make a BBQ warm weather or in a blizzard; nothing can come between a man and his steak. Our once-a-week home BBQ has taught me a great deal about meat and its complexities. . .........***** All images are copyrighted by their respective authors ........ . header message for item 2)... What better way to end summer with a flourish than to serve hot dogs and hamburgers with bunches and bunches of yummy toppings so that everyone can build their own mega meal…and sit back and enjoy a last day of culinary freedom? . ............................................................................................................................................................................................ . .....item 1).... aish.com ... &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aish.com/f/r&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.aish.com/f/r&lt;/a&gt; ... HOME FAMILY COOKING CORNER ... BBQ Done Right .... Fool-proof summer BBQ recipes that will wow your taste buds. . .................................... img code photo ... BBQ Done Right &lt;a href=&quot;http://media.aish.com/images/BBQDoneRight230x150-EN.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;media.aish.com/images/BBQDoneRight230x150-EN.jpg&lt;/a&gt; .................................... . July 14, 2011 / 12 Tammuz 5771 by Sarah Lasry &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aish.com/f/r/BBQ_Done_Right.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.aish.com/f/r/BBQ_Done_Right.html&lt;/a&gt; School is out and the summer season has officially started. That means long leisurely fun-filled days that usually end in a delicious BBQ suppers. But for some, BBQ means the unfortunate task of eating burnt hamburgers and dried steak with the occasional charred hot dog. Here are some fool-proof summer BBQ recipes that will wow your taste buds and make you wish summer grilling was an all year round option! For more great BBQ recipes and summer supper ideas go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosherstreet.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.kosherstreet.com&lt;/a&gt; . . --- The Ultimate BBQ Steak ............................................ imge code photo.....The Ultimate BBQ Steak &lt;a href=&quot;http://media.aish.com/images/bbq-steak.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;media.aish.com/images/bbq-steak.jpg&lt;/a&gt; ............................................ A lucky girl am I married to the king of all BBQs. Dov can make a mean steak; he’s methodical about choosing the right cut, marinating them and cooking them to perfect medium-rare temperature. Dov will make a BBQ warm weather or in a blizzard; nothing can come between a man and his steak. Our once-a-week home BBQ has taught me a great deal about meat and its complexities. For the Marinade: 2 steaks, rinsed &amp;amp; patted dry 3 Tbsp. steak seasoning mix (mesquite flavoring) Kosher salt &amp;amp; black pepper ½ cup teriyaki sauce 2 Tbsp. honey 1 tsp. ginger ½ cup hickory BBQ sauce (your favorite brand) For the Glaze: ½ cup teriyaki sauce 2 Tbsp. honey 1 tsp. ginger ½ cup hickory BBQ sauce 2 tsp. spicy Dijon mustard (optional) Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Or place on grill that has been already preheated and is very hot and has been coated lightly with cooking spray. (If gas grill keep it on med heat) Take a fork and punch small holes into the meat of your steak. Combine the steak seasoning with the Kosher salt and pepper and rub into the top and bottom of your steak. In a small bowl combine all the remaining marinade ingredients, mix well. Put the steaks into a Ziploc bag and then pour in your marinade. Refrigerate for up to 4 hours or at least 30 minutes before grilling. Heat your grill. Remove steaks from marinade and wipe off excess with paper towels. Grill off both sides of your steak for about 2 minutes each side. While the steaks are grilling combine your glaze ingredients in a small bowl. Remove steaks from grill and place into aluminum pan. Brush both side of steaks with your glaze using a pastry brush and finish cooking in the oven until your steaks reach 130 degrees for medium rare, (about 8-10 minutes). . . --- Mustard BBQ Chicken Wings .......................................... img code photo....Mustard BBQ Chicken Wings &lt;a href=&quot;http://media.aish.com/images/bbq-wings.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;media.aish.com/images/bbq-wings.jpg&lt;/a&gt; .......................................... Late one night when in my eighth month of pregnancy, my husband and I saw a piece about an all night restaurant that serves chicken wings and waffles. I can’t even describe the cravings that report elicited, so much so, that I made my poor husband go out and beg our local chicken take out place to stay open 10 minutes longer to satisfy my hunger. I have since had my daughter, but still have cravings for these chicken wings. 12-16 chicken wings, rinsed and patted dry ¼ cup orange juice ¼ cup honey ¼ cup spicy Dijon mustard ¼ cup hickory BBQ sauce (favorite brand) For the Mustard Glaze: ¾ cup mayonnaise ¼ cup sweet teriyaki sauce 3 Tbsp. spicy Dijon mustard 1 tsp. ground ginger powder 1 tsp. garlic powder 1 tsp. soy sauce Extra ginger powder for sprinkling Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Or keep on the med-high side of your grill and cover with hood for 6-8 minutes on each side. Place the chicken wings in a heavy duty Ziploc bag. Mix all the remaining ingredients in a small bowl blending well. Pour mixture into Ziploc bag and gently shake, coating all wings as best as you can. Place into refrigerator and let marinate for at least 30 minutes or ideally up to 4 hours or more. In another small bowl, mix together all the glaze ingredients, combining well. Set aside. Drain and remove wings from marinade and pat dry with paper towel. Place the wings in a large baking tray. Sprinkle with ginger powder over the top of the wings, then using a pastry brush coat each wing thoroughly with the glaze mixture that you made. Place into oven and bake about 20-25 minutes. Remove and pile up onto a plate and dig in. . . --- Pareve Ranch Dipping Sauce ¼ cup mayonnaise 1 cup Tofutti non-dairy sour cream ½ tsp. dried chives ½ tsp. dried parsley ½ tsp. dried dill weed ¼ tsp. garlic powder ¼ tsp. onion powder 1/8 tsp. salt 1/8 tsp. ground black pepper Mix together all the ingredients in a small bowl, blending well. Cover and refrigerate for 30 minutes before serving. . . --- BBQ FRUIT SALAD This salad is super easy to make and does not need a lot of your time. As I prep for my BBQ, I cut the cherries and throw them together in the bowl with my whole blueberries. I make the dressing and set it aside. I then start to BBQ the fruit only after all the meat is finished cooking on the BBQ and while everyone else is enjoying the burgers and steaks the fruit cooks. I then quickly cut and toss all the rest together with the dressing and serve with some Pareve Ice Cream or Whip Cream! 1 whole pineapple, cut into 1/2 inch rounds 6 peaches or nectarines, halved with pit removes 1 cup pitted cherries, diced 1 pint whole blueberries for dressing: 3 tbsp. apricot or peach preserve 2 tsp. apple cider vinegar 1 tsp. garlic powder 1/2 tsp ground ginger On your hot BBQ, grill the pineapple and peaches for about 4 minutes each side. When finished cut them into bite size pieces and toss into a big bowl with the cut cherries and whole blueberries. Mix all the ingredients for the dressing in a separate small bowl, and then pour over the cut fruit. Mix well and serve. For more kosher recipes visit kosherstreet.com . . ........................................................................................................................................................................................... . .....item 2).... ORTHODOX UNION ... &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ou.org/life/food&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.ou.org/life/food&lt;/a&gt; ... Enhancing Jewish Life Your Last and Most Delicious Summer Barbecue By Eileen Goltz | Aug 30th, 2012 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ou.org/life/food/recipes/your-last-most-delicious-summer-barbecue-eileen-goltz/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.ou.org/life/food/recipes/your-last-most-delicious-sum...&lt;/a&gt; Please note: Eileen Goltz is a freelance kosher food writer. The Orthodox Union makes no endorsements or representations regarding kashrut certification of various products/vendors referred to in her articles, blog or web site. In the good ol’ days when dinosaurs roamed the earth and fire was the only form of instant messaging, school didn’t start until AFTER Labor Day. Vacations and pool parties were planned right up until the day when we all trudged 10 miles (uphill both ways) to the non-air conditioned halls of education. But now that schools start earlier and Labor Day is the first “get out of jail free” day, I find that a celebratory barbeque is called for. What better way to end summer with a flourish than to serve hot dogs and hamburgers with bunches and bunches of yummy toppings so that everyone can build their own mega meal…and sit back and enjoy a last day of culinary freedom? . ............................... img code photo ... American hotdog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ou.org/life/files/iStock_000012454273XSmall-300x200.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.ou.org/life/files/iStock_000012454273XSmall-300x200.jpg&lt;/a&gt; ............................... . Keep the basics topping for your burgers and dawgs but tweak them: Relish, mustards of all kinds, ketchup, sauerkraut, and onions are always appreciated but add a kick by caramelizing the onions and adding jalapeno or horseradish to your ketchup. Try serving salsa, guacamole, chili, BBQ or pizza sauce. Chopped olives, cooked salami, and these simple recipes for some savory toppings help make this last official summer meal one of the best ever. . . ----- SWEET HERBED PEPPERS (pareve) Ingredients: 1 tablespoon olive oil 3 red and/or yellow bell peppers, sliced thin 1 to 2 tablespoons minced garlic 2 teaspoons sugar 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1 teaspoon dried basil 1 teaspoon dried thyme salt and pepper to taste Directions: In a skillet saute the peppers, sugar and garlic in the olive oil. When they start to soften slightly, add the oregano, basil and thyme. Cook for 1 to 2 minutes and then remove from the heat. Season with salt and pepper. My files, source unknown. . . ----- BALSAMIC GLAZED ONIONS (pareve) Ingredients: 2 to 3 large sweet onions, sliced thin 2 tablespoons olive oil 1 tablespoon brown sugar 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 to 2 teaspoons balsamic vinegar Servings: In a skillet, heat the olive oil and add the onions and brown sugar. Cook until the onions are soft. Add the salt. Cook until the onions are really soft, then add the balsamic vinegar. Remove to cool. Serve hot or cold. My files, source unknown. . . ----- CRAZY HOT CUCUMBER SAUCE (pareve) Servings: 3 cups Ingredients: 2 large cucumbers, diced 1 red bell peppers, diced 1 onion, finely diced 3 celery stalks, diced 2 to 3 jalapeno peppers, minced 3 tablespoons salt 2 cups sugar 1 cup white vinegar 1/2 tablespoon celery seed 1 tablespoon dill seed Directions: In a bowl combine the cucumbers, peppers, onions, celery, and jalapeno peppers. Sprinkle the salt over the top and then cover the vegetables with cold water and ice cubes. Let vegetables soak for 2 to 3 hours. Then drain in a colander but don’t rinse. In a saucepan combine the sugar, vinegar, celery seeds and dill. Bring the mixture to a boil and then simmer for 4 to 5 minutes. Pour the sauce over the vegetables, mix to coat and let set until the mixture is room temperature. Cover and refrigerate until cold and serve with hotdogs or burgers. Modified from a recipe from epicurean.com. . . ----- GARLIC AND PEPPER KETCHUP (pareve) Servings: 1 1/2 cups Ingredients: 2 tablespoon minced garlic 1 tablespoon minced onion 1 tablespoon olive oil 1 1/2 cup ketchup hot sauce to taste Directions: In a skillet saute the garlic and onion in the olive oil. Cool and whisk in the ketchup and hot sauce. Makes My files, source unknown. . . ----- CHILI FOR BURGERS AND HOT DOGS (meat) Servings: 3 cups Ingredients: 2 lbs ground beef or turkey 2 8 oz cans tomato paste with garlic 2 cups water, plus extra if needed 1 tablespoon cumin 1 to 2 tablespoons chili powder 1/2 tablespoon paprika 3/4 teaspoon onion powder 1/2 teaspoon garlic salt 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon pepper 6 oz hickory barbeque sauce 2 tablespoons honey mustard 1 teaspoon soy sauce 1 cup minced onion Directions: In a skillet brown the ground beef and drain the excess grease. Return to the heat and add the tomato paste and water; mix to combine. Add the remaining ingredients and simmer for 45 minutes. You can add a little water if it starts to get dry. Submitted by Carlie Yong of Chicago, IL. . . ----- MIXED MUSHROOM TOPPING (pareve) Servings: 2 – 3 cups, depending on the amount of mushrooms you use Ingredients: 1 tablespoon olive oil 1 large onion, diced 2 lbs sliced mushrooms, 2 to 3 kinds (mixed) 1 tablespoon white wine 1/2 teaspoon salt 2 teaspoons balsamic vinegar 1 1/2 tablespoons paprika Directions: In a skillet, saute the mushrooms and onions in the olive oil and wine. When they are soft and there is almost no liquid left in the pan, add the paprika and balsamic vinegar. Season with salt and pepper to taste. Are you sure you’re not eating bugs? Certain produce requires inspection. For clear guidelines, check out the newly released OU Manual for Checking Fruits and Vegetables. If your order from OU Press is over $100, you’ll get a FREE manual + FREE shipping. Eileen Goltz is a freelance kosher food writer. She graduated from Indiana University and the Cordon Bleu Cooking School in Paris. She lectures on various food-related topics across the U.S. and Canada and writes weekly columns for the Chicago Jewish News, kosher.com and OU Life. She is the author of the Perfectly Pareve Cookbook (Feldheim) and is a contributing writer for several publications. You can visit Eileen’s blog by clicking Cuisine by Eileen. SHARE . . ........................................................................................................................................................................................... . ." id="5929928566" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="explaintomeagain whyineedaman aishcom bbqdoneright july14201112tammuz5771 foolproofsummerbbqrecipes thatwillwowyourtastebuds bysarahlasry schoolisout andthesummerseasonhasofficiallystarted thatmeanslongleisurelyfunfilleddays thatusuallyendinadeliciousbbqsuppers theultimatebbqsteak mustardbbqchickenwings pareveranchdippingsauce bbqfruitsalad formorekosherrecipes visitkosherstreetcom orthodoxunion enhancingjewishlife yourlastandmostdelicioussummerbarbecue byeileengoltz aug30th2012 pleasenoteeileengoltzisafreelancekosherfoodwriter theorthodoxunionmakesnoendorsements orrepresentationsregardingkashrutcertification ofvariousproductsvendors referredtoinherarticlesblogorwebsite whatbetterwaytoendsummerwithaflourish thantoservehotdogsandhamburgers withbunchesandbunchesofyummytoppings sothateveryonecanbuildtheirownmegameal …andsitbackandenjoyalastdayofculinaryfreedom sweetherbedpepperspareve balsamicglazedonionspareve crazyhotcucumbersaucepareve garlicandpepperketchuppareve chiliforburgersandhotdogsmeat mixedmushroomtoppingpareve areyousureyou’renoteatingbugs certainproducerequiresinspection forclearguidelinescheckoutthenewlyreleased oumanualforcheckingfruitsandvegetables eileengoltzisafreelancekosherfoodwriter sheistheauthoroftheperfectlyparevecookbookfeldheim andisacontributingwriterforseveralpublications youcanvisiteileen’sblogbyclickingcuisinebyeileen" title="Explain to me again ... BBQ Done Right (July 14, 2011 / 12 Tammuz 5771) ...item 2.. Your Last and Most Delicious Summer Barbecue (Aug 30th, 2012) ..." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6021/5929928566_79e72cae34_b.jpg" username="marsmet541" views="452" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-07 00:18:37" description="'The Place de la Bastille is a square in Paris, where the Bastille prison stood until the 'Storming of the Bastille' and its subsequent physical destruction between 14 July 1789 and 14 July 1790 during the French Revolution; no vestige of it remains. The July Column (Colonne de Juillet) which commemorates the events of the July Revolution (1830) stands at the center of the square. The monument, in an elaboration of a Corinthian column, was designed by the architect Jean-Antoine Alavoine, following a commission from Louis-Philippe. The Colonne de Juillet is composed of twenty-one cast bronze drums, weighing over 163,000 pounds (74,000 kg); it is 154 feet (47 m) high, containing an interior spiral staircase, and rests on a base of white marble ornamented with bronze bas-reliefs, of which the lion by Antoine-Louis Barye is the most noted. The French cockerels at the corners are also by Barye. The column is engraved in gold with the names of Parisians who died during the revolution. Over the Corinthian capital is a gallery 16 feet (4.9 m) wide, surmounted with a gilded globe, on which stands a colossal gilded figure, Auguste Dumont's Génie de la Liberté (the &amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;). Perched on one foot in the manner of Giambologna's Mercury, the star-crowned nude brandishes the torch of civilisation and the remains of his broken chains. Formerly the figure also appeared on French ten-franc coins.' (Wikipedia)" id="7966385054" latitude="48.856918" license="3" longitude="2.341209" nbComments="14" rank="16" tags="" title="Place de la Bastille, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8321/7966385054_d1772d7bde_b.jpg" username="CameliaTWU" views="91" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-07-14 00:16:14" description="On the morning of Bastille Day, 2011" id="6078399910" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="paris france placedelabastillebastillesign july column naturallight" title="Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6076/6078399910_03f6dbeeb2_b.jpg" username="Veg A" views="18" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-17 14:10:10" description="&lt;i&gt;Les Demoiselles d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;, Paris, June-July 1907 Oil on canvas, 8' x 7' 8&amp;quot; Pablo Picasso (Spanish, 1881-1973) &lt;i&gt;Les Demoiselles d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;, one of Pablo Picasso's most famous works, was painted in France and completed in the summer of 1907. A seminal work in the development of Cubism, Picasso's eye-catching depiction of five prostitutes in a brothel revolutionized the art world. Picasso created over one hundred sketches and studies in preparation for this work, drawing on sources as diverse as Iberian sculpture, African tribal masks, and El Greco &lt;i&gt;Opening of the Fifth Seal&lt;/i&gt; and Cezanne's &lt;i&gt;Les Grandes Baigneuses&lt;/i&gt; to make this startling composition. Its monumental size underscored the shocking incoherence resulting from the outright sabotage of conventional representation. Picasso drew each of the figures differently. The woman pulling the curtain on the far right has heavy paint application throughout. Her head is the most cubist of all five, featuring sharp geometric shapes. The cubist head of the crouching figure underwent at least two revisions from an Iberian figure to its current state. Much of the critical debate over Les Demoiselles attempts to account for the multiplicity of styles. Alfred Barr, the first director of MoMA, interpreted it as evidence of an artist in transition--an effort to connect his earlier work to his new Cubist style. In 1974, however, critic Leo Steinberg claimed in was a deliberate attempt to capture the attention of the viewer. He notes that the five women all seem eerily disconnected, wholly unaware of each other and instead focusing their intense gaze on the viewer. In 1994, William Rubin suggests that some of the figure's faces symbolize the disfigurements of syphilis, and that the painting was created following a series of brothel visits by Picasso, who was then temporarily separated from his mistress Fernande Olivier. Preparatory studies featured two men inside the brothel--one a sailor and the other a medical student. Picasso, wanting no anecdotal detail to interfere with the sheer impact of the work, decided to eliminate it in the final painting. The only remaining allusion to the brothel lies in the title: Avignon was a street in Barcelona famed for its brothel. A trace of the male presence remains--the jutting edge of a table near the bottom of the canvas. Steinberg argues that the viewer has ocme to replace the men. In July 2007, Newsweek published a two-page, four-column article about Les Demoiselles d'Avignon describing it as the &amp;quot;most influential work of art of the last 100 years&amp;quot;. Acquired through the Lillie P. Bliss Bequestt * The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/sets/72157600384973772/&quot;&gt;Museum of Modern Art (MoMA)&lt;/a&gt; was founded in 1929 and is often recognized as the most influential museum of modern art in the world. Over the course of the next ten years, the Museum moved three times into progressively larger temporary quarters, and in 1939 finally opened the doors of its midtown home, located on 53rd Street between Fifth and Sixth Avenues in midtown. MoMA's holdings include more than 150,000 paintings, sculptures, drawings, prints, photographs, architectural models and drawings, and design objects. Highlights of the collection inlcude Vincent Van Gogh's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562372044/&quot;&gt;The Starry Night&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Salvador Dali's &lt;i&gt;The Persisence of Memory&lt;/i&gt;, Pablo Picasso's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/563353753/&quot;&gt;Les Demoiseels d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/563994968/&quot;&gt;Three Musicians&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Claude Monet's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562778789/&quot;&gt;Water Lilies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Piet Mondrian's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562979024/&quot;&gt;Broadway Boogie Woogie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Paul Gauguin's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562834748/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Seed of the Areoi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Henri Matisse's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/564480519/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dance&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Marc Chagall's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562546594/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I and the Village&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Paul Cezanne's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562211624/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Bather&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Jackson Pollack's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/564040776/&quot;&gt;Number 31, 1950&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, and Andy Warhol's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562288842/&quot;&gt;Campbell's Soup Cans&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. MoMA also owns approximately 22,000 films and four million film stills, and MoMA's Library and Archives, the premier research facilities of their kind in the world, hold over 300,000 books, artist books, and periodicals, and extensive individual files on more than 70,000 artists." id="563354141" latitude="40.761174" license="3" longitude="-73.977019" nbComments="5" rank="18" tags="newyorkcity nyc gothamist manhattan moma museumofmodernart art aia150 museum painting theyoungladiesofavignon youngladiesofavignon cubist cubism newyork ny picasso lesdemoiseelsdavignon lebordel pablopicasso" title="NYC - MoMA: Pablo Picasso's Les Demoiselles d'Avignon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1305/563354141_dea564001f_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="82276" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-17 14:09:50" description="&lt;i&gt;Les Demoiselles d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;, Paris, June-July 1907 Oil on canvas, 8' x 7' 8&amp;quot; Pablo Picasso (Spanish, 1881-1973) &lt;i&gt;Les Demoiselles d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;, one of Pablo Picasso's most famous works, was painted in France and completed in the summer of 1907. A seminal work in the development of Cubism, Picasso's eye-catching depiction of five prostitutes in a brothel revolutionized the art world. Picasso created over one hundred sketches and studies in preparation for this work, drawing on sources as diverse as Iberian sculpture, African tribal masks, and El Greco &lt;i&gt;Opening of the Fifth Seal&lt;/i&gt; and Cezanne's &lt;i&gt;Les Grandes Baigneuses&lt;/i&gt; to make this startling composition. Its monumental size underscored the shocking incoherence resulting from the outright sabotage of conventional representation. Picasso drew each of the figures differently. The woman pulling the curtain on the far right has heavy paint application throughout. Her head is the most cubist of all five, featuring sharp geometric shapes. The cubist head of the crouching figure underwent at least two revisions from an Iberian figure to its current state. Much of the critical debate over Les Demoiselles attempts to account for the multiplicity of styles. Alfred Barr, the first director of MoMA, interpreted it as evidence of an artist in transition--an effort to connect his earlier work to his new Cubist style. In 1974, however, critic Leo Steinberg claimed in was a deliberate attempt to capture the attention of the viewer. He notes that the five women all seem eerily disconnected, wholly unaware of each other and instead focusing their intense gaze on the viewer. In 1994, William Rubin suggests that some of the figure's faces symbolize the disfigurements of syphilis, and that the painting was created following a series of brothel visits by Picasso, who was then temporarily separated from his mistress Fernande Olivier. Preparatory studies featured two men inside the brothel--one a sailor and the other a medical student. Picasso, wanting no anecdotal detail to interfere with the sheer impact of the work, decided to eliminate it in the final painting. The only remaining allusion to the brothel lies in the title: Avignon was a street in Barcelona famed for its brothel. A trace of the male presence remains--the jutting edge of a table near the bottom of the canvas. Steinberg argues that the viewer has ocme to replace the men. In July 2007, Newsweek published a two-page, four-column article about Les Demoiselles d'Avignon describing it as the &amp;quot;most influential work of art of the last 100 years&amp;quot;. Acquired through the Lillie P. Bliss Bequestt * The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/sets/72157600384973772/&quot;&gt;Museum of Modern Art (MoMA)&lt;/a&gt; was founded in 1929 and is often recognized as the most influential museum of modern art in the world. Over the course of the next ten years, the Museum moved three times into progressively larger temporary quarters, and in 1939 finally opened the doors of its midtown home, located on 53rd Street between Fifth and Sixth Avenues in midtown. MoMA's holdings include more than 150,000 paintings, sculptures, drawings, prints, photographs, architectural models and drawings, and design objects. Highlights of the collection inlcude Vincent Van Gogh's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562372044/&quot;&gt;The Starry Night&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Salvador Dali's &lt;i&gt;The Persisence of Memory&lt;/i&gt;, Pablo Picasso's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/563353753/&quot;&gt;Les Demoiseels d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/563994968/&quot;&gt;Three Musicians&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Claude Monet's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562778789/&quot;&gt;Water Lilies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Piet Mondrian's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562979024/&quot;&gt;Broadway Boogie Woogie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Paul Gauguin's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562834748/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Seed of the Areoi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Henri Matisse's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/564480519/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dance&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Marc Chagall's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562546594/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I and the Village&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Paul Cezanne's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562211624/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Bather&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Jackson Pollack's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/564040776/&quot;&gt;Number 31, 1950&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, and Andy Warhol's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562288842/&quot;&gt;Campbell's Soup Cans&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. MoMA also owns approximately 22,000 films and four million film stills, and MoMA's Library and Archives, the premier research facilities of their kind in the world, hold over 300,000 books, artist books, and periodicals, and extensive individual files on more than 70,000 artists." id="563353753" latitude="40.761174" license="3" longitude="-73.977019" nbComments="2" rank="19" tags="newyorkcity nyc gothamist manhattan moma museumofmodernart art aia150 museum painting theyoungladiesofavignon youngladiesofavignon cubist cubism newyork ny picasso lesdemoiseelsdavignon lebordel pablopicasso" title="NYC - MoMA: Pablo Picasso's Les Demoiselles d'Avignon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1050/563353753_c1bda1bedc_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="12478" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-17 14:10:30" description="&lt;i&gt;Les Demoiselles d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;, Paris, June-July 1907 Oil on canvas, 8' x 7' 8&amp;quot; Pablo Picasso (Spanish, 1881-1973) &lt;i&gt;Les Demoiselles d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;, one of Pablo Picasso's most famous works, was painted in France and completed in the summer of 1907. A seminal work in the development of Cubism, Picasso's eye-catching depiction of five prostitutes in a brothel revolutionized the art world. Picasso created over one hundred sketches and studies in preparation for this work, drawing on sources as diverse as Iberian sculpture, African tribal masks, and El Greco &lt;i&gt;Opening of the Fifth Seal&lt;/i&gt; and Cezanne's &lt;i&gt;Les Grandes Baigneuses&lt;/i&gt; to make this startling composition. Its monumental size underscored the shocking incoherence resulting from the outright sabotage of conventional representation. Picasso drew each of the figures differently. The woman pulling the curtain on the far right has heavy paint application throughout. Her head is the most cubist of all five, featuring sharp geometric shapes. The cubist head of the crouching figure underwent at least two revisions from an Iberian figure to its current state. Much of the critical debate over Les Demoiselles attempts to account for the multiplicity of styles. Alfred Barr, the first director of MoMA, interpreted it as evidence of an artist in transition--an effort to connect his earlier work to his new Cubist style. In 1974, however, critic Leo Steinberg claimed in was a deliberate attempt to capture the attention of the viewer. He notes that the five women all seem eerily disconnected, wholly unaware of each other and instead focusing their intense gaze on the viewer. In 1994, William Rubin suggests that some of the figure's faces symbolize the disfigurements of syphilis, and that the painting was created following a series of brothel visits by Picasso, who was then temporarily separated from his mistress Fernande Olivier. Preparatory studies featured two men inside the brothel--one a sailor and the other a medical student. Picasso, wanting no anecdotal detail to interfere with the sheer impact of the work, decided to eliminate it in the final painting. The only remaining allusion to the brothel lies in the title: Avignon was a street in Barcelona famed for its brothel. A trace of the male presence remains--the jutting edge of a table near the bottom of the canvas. Steinberg argues that the viewer has ocme to replace the men. In July 2007, Newsweek published a two-page, four-column article about Les Demoiselles d'Avignon describing it as the &amp;quot;most influential work of art of the last 100 years&amp;quot;. Acquired through the Lillie P. Bliss Bequestt * The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/sets/72157600384973772/&quot;&gt;Museum of Modern Art (MoMA)&lt;/a&gt; was founded in 1929 and is often recognized as the most influential museum of modern art in the world. Over the course of the next ten years, the Museum moved three times into progressively larger temporary quarters, and in 1939 finally opened the doors of its midtown home, located on 53rd Street between Fifth and Sixth Avenues in midtown. MoMA's holdings include more than 150,000 paintings, sculptures, drawings, prints, photographs, architectural models and drawings, and design objects. Highlights of the collection inlcude Vincent Van Gogh's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562372044/&quot;&gt;The Starry Night&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Salvador Dali's &lt;i&gt;The Persisence of Memory&lt;/i&gt;, Pablo Picasso's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/563353753/&quot;&gt;Les Demoiseels d'Avignon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/563994968/&quot;&gt;Three Musicians&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Claude Monet's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562778789/&quot;&gt;Water Lilies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Piet Mondrian's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562979024/&quot;&gt;Broadway Boogie Woogie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Paul Gauguin's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562834748/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Seed of the Areoi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Henri Matisse's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/564480519/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dance&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Marc Chagall's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562546594/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I and the Village&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Paul Cezanne's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562211624/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Bather&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Jackson Pollack's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/564040776/&quot;&gt;Number 31, 1950&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, and Andy Warhol's &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/562288842/&quot;&gt;Campbell's Soup Cans&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. MoMA also owns approximately 22,000 films and four million film stills, and MoMA's Library and Archives, the premier research facilities of their kind in the world, hold over 300,000 books, artist books, and periodicals, and extensive individual files on more than 70,000 artists." id="563354865" latitude="40.761174" license="3" longitude="-73.977019" nbComments="1" rank="20" tags="newyorkcity nyc gothamist manhattan moma museumofmodernart art aia150 museum painting theyoungladiesofavignon youngladiesofavignon cubist cubism newyork ny picasso lesdemoiseelsdavignon lebordel pablopicasso" title="NYC - MoMA: Pablo Picasso's Les Demoiseels d'Avignon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1117/563354865_0e2eea4a91_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="8949" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-07 21:31:50" description="&lt;b&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.de/search?q=quadriga+brandenburg+gate&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;tbs=tl:1&amp;amp;tbo=u&amp;amp;ei=7_V3Sp7OLZiO_Aac0bWRBg&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=timeline_result&amp;amp;ct=title&amp;amp;resnum=11&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;quadriga atop the Brandenburg Gate&lt;/a&gt; —restored since 1991— is shining in pale-verdigris against a black backdrop of a gloomy night. In 1793, — when the so called &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_Revolutionary_Wars&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;'French Revolutionary Wars'&lt;/a&gt; all over Europe were to begin —, Schadow installed in an anxious &amp;amp; defiant gesture towards the revolutionary Paris a peace-goddess (PAX) holding up a coronal of olive leaves behind a roman, triumphal carriage. - Under those political circumstances that build-up was obviously meant as an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apotropaic_magic&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;apotropaic allegory&lt;/a&gt; against the upcoming, second wave of the Great Revolution which was looming from the other side of the Rhine ... In 1806 that sculpture was of course dislodged and travelled to the Louvre by the victorious Napoléon Bonaparte but already eight years later — in 1814— the booty was tracked down and re-confiscated by the prussian General Blücher. Back in Berlin the restituted trophy was overhauled and revised by Schinkel in 1815: The once pre-reactionary Fräulein PAX (roman peace-goddess) was still turning its back against the Madame France in the West but this time she was classified into a full-blown reactionary NIKE (hellenic victory-goddess). Supporting that lurking tendency he supplemented as some new &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piping_and_plumbing_fittings&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;fittings&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.travel-images.com/photo-germany183.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;erect shaft in between the pairs of horses&lt;/a&gt; (“Pferdeherme”), the harness for the four domesticated mammals and the coronet of oak leaves for the goddess, and he set up the “perch”, i.e. the banner-like standard with the iron cross inside a wreath of oak leaves &amp;amp; acorns from which an eagle coronated by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hazboy/3587272271/&quot;&gt;christian cross atop a prussian crown&lt;/a&gt; holds lookout. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eisernes_Kreuz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;iron cross&lt;/a&gt; on the Brandenburg was posted in 1815 and contains &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hazboy/3587272271/&quot;&gt;the initials 'FW' and the figure '1813'&lt;/a&gt; in remembrance of its endowment as the prussian war decoration by &lt;a href=&quot;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedrich_Wilhelm_III._(Preu%c3%9fen)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Friedrich Wilhelm III.&lt;/a&gt; in the year 1813 which marks the beginning of the first restoration—the second such reanimation was instigated by the Hitlerists in 1933 under the pompous title “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nazi_Germany&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Third Reich&lt;/a&gt;”—of the 1806 passed away cadaver of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Roman_Empire&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Holy Roman Empire of German Nation&lt;/a&gt; by 'freedom wars' (&lt;a href=&quot;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Befreiungskriege&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;'Befreiungskriege'&lt;/a&gt;) that were the prussian tribute to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_of_the_Sixth_Coalition&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;'the wars of the 6th coalition'&lt;/a&gt; (1812-1814) for breaking Napoleon's hegemony over Europe. On 18th Oktober 1913, i.e. at the eve of WWI, all around the victory goddess of the Brandenburg triumphal arch a wilhelmine state act was held by the german emperor; like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.berlinonline.de/berliner-zeitung/archiv/.bin/dump.fcgi/1998/1201/lokales/0162/index.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;everywhere in the suburbs of the Berlin&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_Reich&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;German Reich&lt;/a&gt; it was celebrated the centenary of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Leipzig&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Battle of Leipzig&lt;/a&gt; ... Originally an emblematic build-up to the Restoration epoch (1815-1848) the “horses'—herma” was rededicated in 1991 and refurbished 2000/02 by private businessmen and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stiftung-denkmalschutz-berlin.de/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Berlin Monument Conservation Foundation&lt;/a&gt; that were sponsored to indulge their “faible” for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.germaniainternational.com/kjewelry2.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“imperial prussian flair”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt; The &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brandenburg_Gate&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Brandenburg Gate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; in 1945 was one of the few structures still standing on the Pariser Platz but the relics of the copper quadriga atop it had to be melted down; only the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/42311564@N00/2736722440/sizes/m/&quot;&gt;head of one of the four horses&lt;/a&gt; was preserved and can be visited in the Märkisches Museum. In 1958 a replica of bronze was built up to replace the copper quadriga. Vehicles and pedestrians could travel freely through the thouroughfare until 13th August 1961; then the wall with its death strip ran just behind it. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.berlin.de/rubrik/hauptstadt/geschichte/kennedyrede.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;On 26th of June 1963&lt;/a&gt;, — two years after the put-up of the Wall —, U.S. President John F. Kennedy officially visited West-Berlin and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pingnews/482209249/&quot;&gt;the Wall at the Brandenburg Gate&lt;/a&gt;, where he himself and the West-Berlin mayor wanted him to deliver his prepared speech but the west-german chancellor which was demonstratively all the time accompanying him agreed with the western allies that the venue near the soviet sector would have been much too provocative. So he could not hold his oratio in sight of the contended cold-war-focus-point but had to shift to another location: That was the square in front of the office-building of the then ruling mayor &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Willy_Brandt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Willy Brandt&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike Ronald Reagan who could easily overtake the venue twenty four years later—only protected by transparent bullet-proof glass to prevent potential snipers from behind the wall and two decades of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D%c3%a9tente&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;détente&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ostpolitik&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Ostpolitik”&lt;/a&gt;) followed up by &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glasnost&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;glasnost&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perestroika&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;perestroika&lt;/a&gt;. «&lt;i&gt;Two thousand years ago the proudest boast was “civis romanus sum” {translation lat-engl: “I'm a roman citizen”}. Today, in the world of freedom, the proudest boast is „Ich bin ein Berliner“. {translation ger-engl: “I'm a Berliner”, after these four words interpreter Lochner is heard whispering instructions to him on how to pronounce the four german words more correctly, and he's answering insinuatingly into the open microphone: “I appreciate my interpreter translating my German!”} {JFK continues:} There are many people in the world who really don't understand, or say they don't, what is the great issue between the free world and the Communist world. Let them come to Berlin. There are some who say that communism is the wave of the future. Let them come to Berlin. And there are some who say in Europe and elsewhere we can work with the Communists. Let them come to Berlin. And there are even a few who say that it is true that communism is an evil system, but it permits us to make economic progress. &lt;b&gt;„Lass' sie nach Berlin kommen!&lt;/b&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thekennedys.de/blog/2009/05/zwei-kennedys-an-einem-tag/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lust z nach Bearlen comen&lt;/a&gt;]“ Let them come to Berlin. - KA: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jfklibrary.org/Asset+Tree/Asset+Viewers/Audio+Video+Asset+Viewer.htm?guid={73860A23-DDA6-4604-8B3B-8A0F8E7E754A}&amp;amp;type=Audio&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;„Aber lass auch Sie nach Berlin kommen!“&lt;/a&gt; {heckled the standing-by Bundeskanzler &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Konrad_Adenauer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Konrad Adenauer&lt;/a&gt; who obviously had'nt quite understood the english words of the speech} {JFK continues:} Freedom has many difficulties and democracy is not perfect, but we have never had to put a wall up to keep our people in, to prevent them from leaving us. ... While the wall is the most obvious and vivid demonstration of the failures of the Communist system, for all the world to see, we take no satisfaction in it, ... ... All free men, wherever they may live, are citizens of Berlin, and, therefore, as a free man, I take pride in the words &lt;b&gt;„Ich bin ein Berliner!“&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;» (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Ich_bin_ein_Berliner&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;speech by President John F. Kennedy on 26 June 1963 at 'Rathaus Schöneberg' in West-Berlin&lt;/a&gt; When he tried to take sight of the Brandenburg Gate on that sultry summerday climbing on the tourists' platform on the then Hindenburg-Platz &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pingnews/482209249/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; he was 'welcomed' by large red curtains that were hung into the five doorways of the arch to prevent the VIP from speaking and spying to the East ... In the 1980s, decrying the existence of two German states, the then West Berlin mayor Richard von Weizsäcker said: “&lt;i&gt;The German question will remain open as long as the Brandenburg Gate is closed&lt;/i&gt;.” On June 12, 1987, U.S. President &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/james_h_leblanc/3833035163/&quot;&gt;Ronald Reagan spoke to the West Berlin populace at the Brandenburg Gate&lt;/a&gt;: “&lt;i&gt;To those listening in East Berlin, a special word: Although I cannot be with you, I address my remarks to you just as surely as to those standing here before me. For I join you, as I join your fellow countrymen in the West, in this firm, this unalterable belief: &lt;b&gt;Es gibt nur ein Berlin.&lt;/b&gt; ... we believe that freedom and security go together, that the advance of human liberty can only strengthen the cause of world peace ...Perhaps this gets to the root of the matter, to the most fundamental distinction of all between East and West. The totalitarian world produces backwardness because it does such violence to the spirit, thwarting the human impulse to create, to enjoy, to worship. The totalitarian world finds even symbols of love and of worship an affront. Years ago, before the East Germans began rebuilding their churches, they erected a secular structure: the television tower at Alexander Platz. Virtually ever since, the authorities have been working to correct what they view as the tower's one major flaw, treating the glass sphere at the top with paints and chemicals of every kind. Yet even today when the sun strikes that sphere -- that sphere that towers over all Berlin the light makes the sign of the cross.&lt;/i&gt;” Demanding the razing of the Berlin Wall and addressing the then General Secretary of the Communist Party of the USSR &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mikhail_Gorbachev&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mikhail Gorbachev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ronald_Reagan&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ronald Reagan&lt;/a&gt; said: “&lt;i&gt;And I invite Mr. Gorbachev: Let us work to bring the Eastern and Western parts of the city closer together, so that all the inhabitants of all Berlin can enjoy the benefits that come with life in one of the great cities of the world. To open Berlin still further to all Europe, East and West, let us expand the vital air access to this city, finding ways of making commercial air service to Berlin more convenient, more comfortable, and more economical. We look to the day when West Berlin can become one of the chief aviation hubs in all central Europe. ... There is one sign the Soviets can make that would be unmistakable, that would advance dramatically the cause of freedom and peace. General Secretary Gorbachev, if you seek peace, if you seek prosperity for the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, if you seek liberalization: Come here to this gate! Mr. Gorbachev, open this gate! Mr. Gorbachev, tear down this wall! ... &lt;b&gt;The wall cannot withstand freedom.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;” On July 12, 1994, U.S. President Bill Clinton spoke at the Gate about peace in post-Cold War Europe. On December 21, 2000, the Brandenburg Gate was privately refurbished at a 6 million $ cost. Depiction of German euro coinage: On the obverse sides of the 1 € and 2 € coins, there are stylized prussian eagles; on the the 50¢, 20¢ and 10¢ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knowledgerush.com/kr/encyclopedia/German_euro_coins/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;coins&lt;/a&gt; there are the Brandenburg Gates; on the 5¢, 2¢ and 1¢ coins there are twigs with five oak leaves and two acorns. &lt;b&gt;The Brandenburg Gate &amp;amp; The Wall&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Berlin, it is worth remembering, came of age as a garrison town. Though Friedrich Wilhelm I was not interested in beautifying the city, he did seek to promote its growth. Needing more space to quarter soldiers and more artisans to supply their needs, he gave away hundreds of lots and compelled the recipients to build houses on them. He expanded the city limits and, in the 1730s, replaced the Great Elector’s old fortifications with a new wall built around the expanded city. This was not a fortification but a customs barrier to regulate commerce and prevent soldiers from deserting. (For all the differences, in both these purposes we can see a resemblance to Ulbricht’s later wall.) Among the wall’s eighteen gates, the most prominent lay at the southern and western edges of the expanded Friedrichstadt, where large plazas were laid out inside the gates: a circular plaza inside the southern Halle Gate, an octagon at the Potsdam Gate, and a square at the western terminus of Unter den Linden. Friedrich Wilhelm envisioned all three spaces as military parade grounds. The last of these gates concludes our look at the eighteenthcentury city. It marks the outer end of the grand axis of Unter den Linden, scene of royal processions, military parades, and elegant promenades throughout the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. Though it is not the original Brandenburg all that remains of the eighteenth-century wall, apart from a fragment excavated in Stresemannstrasse. The original baroque gate that separated Unter den Linden from the Tiergarten was replaced at the order of King Friedrich Wilhelm II, Frederick the Great’s successor. The commission given to the architect Carl Gotthard Langhans ushered in a new era in Berlin architecture. To the end of his long life (in 1786), Frederick the Great had insisted on building in ornate rococo forms that had long since fallen from favor in Europe’s more fashionable capitals. Langhans’s Brandenburg Gate, completed in 1791, brought the more severe lines of neoclassicism to Berlin. Langhans’s simple design, modeled on the Propylaea of Athens, comprises a double row of Doric columns that frame five openings. The gate’s other famous feature is the copper quadriga that was mounted atop it in 1793. This work of the young sculptor Johann Gottfried Schadow portrays a goddess riding in a chariot drawn by four horses galloping into the city. The Brandenburg Gate, with its quadriga, has long been Berlin’s most famous symbol, rivaled only by the more ephemeral Wall. Its image has adorned commemorative coins, playing cards, historicist and expressionist paintings, posters for all kinds of events, and East and West Berlin postcards and tourist brochures. It may be an admirable work of architecture and sculpture, but that does not explain its symbolic resonance. Nor does its intended function. Unlike many nineteenth-century structures, it was not erected as a national monument. Its size and form made it much more than a utilitarian structure, but it was nevertheless a functional gate in the city wall, flanked by guardhouses. History has made the Brandenburg Gate a German monument. At first its official name was the “Gate of Peace”; it was not, after all, a Roman triumphal arch. But its identity changed in 1806, when Napoleon defeated Prussia and triumphantly entered its capital through the western gate. He showed his admiration for the quadriga by ordering that it be taken down and shipped to Paris to join his other confiscated art treasures. The emperor thus became known locally as the “horse thief of Berlin”, and the denuded gate became the symbol of Prussian and German resistance. In 1813 Schadow himself proposed to fill the quadriga’s place atop the gate with an enormous cast of the Iron Cross, the new military medal designed by Schinkel at the behest of King Friedrich Wilhelm III. Upon Napoleon’s defeat in 1814, however, a triumphant procession returned the quadriga to Berlin, the neighboring square was renamed Paris Square (Pariser Platz), and the “Gate of Peace” became a “Gate of Victory”. Schinkel designed new insignia for the goddess’s staff: a Prussian eagle and, within a wreath, the Iron Cross. Thereafter, the gate became ever more firmly established as a symbol of Prussia and its capital. It became the traditional backdrop for military parades (following Napoleon’s example) and for the ceremonial reception of state guests. When the entire customs wall was tom down in the 1860s, the Brandenburg Gate remained; from then on, it was strictly a monument. After Germany was unified under Prussian leadership in 1871, the victorious troops returning from France were welcomed at the Brandenburg Gate. The Prussian monument had become firmly established as a German national symbol, the site of many more ceremonies before soldiers marched through it on their way back to France in 1914. The Nazis, too, embraced the old symbol of victory. The night Hitler was appointed chancellor, January 30, 1933, thousands of torch-bearing Nazi brownshirts marched through the gate. When the bombers came, the Nazis generally did a better job of evacuating art treasures than saving people. But they apparently did not dare risk morale by removing the goddess and her horses. Instead, in 1942 they had plaster casts made of the quadriga. By 1945, when Soviet soldiers planted their red flag atop the gate, it was badly damaged and only fragments of the quadriga remained. The East German leaders who inherited these ruins decided to keep the gate and adopt it as their own. The shattered quadriga’s fate was less certain. Artists and politicians entertained several proposals for a suitable new sculpture: a group of workers, children dancing around a globe, a mother with child, Picasso’s dove of peace. A Western newspaper, hearing of the last proposal in 1949, declared that if the dove of peace were to nest placidly at the entrance to the Communist world, the West would be obliged to raise a banner in front of the gate with the words Dante had affixed to the gates of Hell in his lnferno: “Abandon all hope, ye who enter here.” {N23} Eventually, however, the East decided to restore the quadriga instead. Unfortunately, the gate stood in the Soviet sector, the plaster casts were in the West, and during the 1950s the two regimes were busy denouncing each other as criminals and usurpers. After the failed uprising against the East German government on June 17, 1953, the West renamed the street that continued Unter den Linden west of the gate “the Street of 17 June.“ But the two Berlins had only one Brandenburg Gate, and it provided a rare opportunity for cooperation. West Berlin agreed to recreate the statues while the East restored the gate. This joint venture did not, of course, proceed without incident. In 1958 the reconstructed quadriga was brought to the sectoral boundary, a few steps from the gate, and simply left there for the East Germans to claim. Before putting it up, the Easterners sawed the Prussian eagle off the top of the goddess’s staff and the Iron Cross out of the wreath. For the Western public, this was vandalism and deceit, but it should not really have been a surprise. In 1957 West Germany had legalized the display of the Iron Cross, which the GDR had banned as a militarist symbol. In 1958 the Eastern press was filled with editorials and letters demanding the removal of these “fascist“ ornaments. The Brandenburg Gate was once again to be a gate of peace, declared the East Berlin government. {N24} With the goddess’s staff crowned only by a wreath, the quadriga and gate would remain from 1958 until 1990; only their surroundings would change utterly. At first the gate still filtered traffic passing across the sector line between the Tiergarten and the shattered ruins along Unter den Linden. As the two halves of the city grew apart, the gate acquired a rich new symbolic resonance, captured, for example, in scenes of the 1961 American comedy film &lt;i&gt;One, Two, Three&lt;/i&gt;, directed by Billy Wilder (whose ties to Berlin went back to the 1920s) and starring James Cagney as a representative of the Coca-Cola Company caught between the intrigues of Communists and ex-Nazis. But the film was a commercial flop: by the time it was completed, the Wall had made crossing the Brandenburg Gate anything but a laughing matter. Because the western edge of the Mitte district coincided with the location of Friedrich Wilhelm I’s wall, the sectoral boundary followed the same course after 1945, and after 1961, so did a long stretch of the new wall. The Brandenburg Gate was thus once again part of a wall. Here was a historical continuity that no one wanted to acknowledge. This time it was not a gate; the crossing points lay elsewhere. Erich Honecker, the Politbüro member in charge of national security and hence the man directing construction of the Wall, apparently pressed for the gate’s closure because he thought any activity around it would attract Western media attention, demonstrations, and provocations.{N25} He was probably right, but he may also have been swayed by his own regime’s frequent evocation of the Napoleon-like specter of West German troops marching triumphantly through the Brandenburg Gate on their way to destroy peace and socialism. Both the gate and the quadriga had been designed to face into the City—that is, to the east. That is not what a visitor would expect, but the gate’s intended audience was local residents, not outsiders. The folk memory of Berlin seems to offer evidence of confusion on this point. Visitors are often told that the quadriga Originally faced the other direction and was turned around at some point—something that never happened. This is an old legend: an 1860 guidebook asserts that the goddess had faced away from town before Napoleon, but had been reerected looking inward in 1814.{N26} Late-twentieth-century versions of the legend tend to be vaguer about the date of the reversal; Ulbricht as well as Napoleon comes under suspicion as a possible culprit. In its uncertain stance toward inside and outside, residents and visitors, the Brandenburg Gate resembled nothing so much as its newer neighbor, the Berlin Wall. With the Wall’s presence, the poignancy of the gate as symbol became stronger than ever. On its Eastern side, Pariser Platz starkly illustrated the desolation brought by the Wall. Once among Berlin’s most elegant squares, a place of palaces, the French and U.S. embassies, the Academy of Arts, and the city’s premier hotel, the Adlon, it was now bare except for the gate and the Wall. Tourists were restricted to its far end, but distinguished guests and officially invited delegations were brought to the gate and asked to admire the work of the border guards. From the Western side, the gate was now entirely inaccessible, and could only be seen from a dead-end street in the middle of the Tiergarten. Nevertheless, tourist buses regularly came by, and state visitors were brought there too. In 1963, when John F. Kennedy came to see it, he found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/25699972@N08/4255970301/&quot;&gt;the East had hung red banners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; {&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;i.e. five perpendicular flags, four of them were red (symbolizing the four-power-status of Berlin), the fifth in the main-gateway was black | red | golden signed with the GDR-coat of arms.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;klp&amp;nbsp;} &lt;i&gt;between the columns that blocked any view beyond the gate—interpreted as a Cold War gesture with more figurative meaning than the East had intended. In 1987, the gate served as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/usnationalarchives/4092170995/&quot;&gt;backdrop for Ronald Reagan’s speech&lt;/a&gt;, with bulletproof glass erected behind the rostrum. (Bill Clinton, in 1994, was the first U.S. President privileged to speak on Pariser Platz, under the heads of the quadriga’s horses instead of their posteriors.) Both East and West Berliners claimed the gate as the symbol of their city and of their version of German unity. But it may have been the foreign media from the West that made the gate the preeminent symbol of the less telegenic Berlin Wall. During the days after November 9, 1989, the TV networks made the &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.de/books?id=tzL37_S_nWcC&amp;amp;pg=PA80&amp;amp;lpg=PA80&amp;amp;dq=restored+quadriga&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=A9q3-t6hGV&amp;amp;sig=xiTNZRQYELp2zlA55o-YEibrEhs&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ei=PoFxSseVJoucnQOT44SDDA&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=book_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Brandenburg Gate the backdrop for their cameras&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fortunate coincidence that the semicircular barrier blocking the gate was the only section of the Wall wide and flat enough to stand (and dance) on. Since the Brandenburg Gate was not a functioning gate, however, the hordes of East Germans actually passed through the Wall elsewhere for several weeks. Finally, on December 22 , 1989. West German chancellor Helmut Kohl led a phalanx of politicians in a ceremony reopening the Brandenburg Gate. Evidence later surfaced that Kohl had in fact pressured the East Germans to delay the opening for five weeks so that he could be present. A few days later. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/authenticfoto/3524016951/&quot;&gt;New Year’s revelers climbed up to the newly accessihle quadriga&lt;/a&gt; and left it seriously damaged. Soon afterward, while the gate was being restored, the quadriga. too, was taken down for a careful restoration. Thereupon controversy erupted anew. The summer of 1991 saw a reprise of the 1958 debate about the quadriga, this time without the Cold War to define positions. A young Christian Democratic member of the Bundestag, Friedbert Pflüger, called for the Iron Cross and Prussian eagle to be left off the restored quaclriga. (They had been preserved since 1958 in an East Berlin museum; the reunification of the quadriga coincided with that of Germany.) His campaign found supponers across the political spectrum, only some of whom could be dismissed as leftists antipathetic to any sign of German national pride. The Berlin press anti public was nonetheless hard on Pflüger. He argued that symbols of Prussian patriotism had no place in the new Germany; but others suspected that his real motive was bitterness over the decision to move the governmcnt from Bonn. He was, more pointedly, accused of wanting to falsify history “à la Ulbricht”. Little attention was paid to his claim that he wanted to restore the original “Gate of Peace” and the original quadriga as it had existed up to 1806. It was easy for Pflüger’s supporters to conclude that Berlin was rejecting historical authenticity in favor of patriotic nostalgia. In fact, no one was proposing the return of the goddess’s original staff, gone since 1814, when Schinkel had not merely added the Iron Cross and Prussian eagle but had redesigned the entire staff. The quadriga Napoleon took, for example, had a Roman eagle where the Prussian one later perched. And that had actually been the goddess’s &lt;i&gt;third&lt;/i&gt; staff: Schadow’s first two designs had proved so unpopular that he was obligated to replace each of them within months. In other words, the debate in 1991 was between restoring the 1814 quadriga and the 1958 version. Since the latter’s repudiation of Prussian militarism had been the work of Ulbricht’s regime, it found few defenders. Amid good words for Prussian symbols—the Iron Cross, it was pointed out, came out of the wars of liberation against Napoleon, not World War I or II—Berlin’s leaders ceremonially rededicated the restored quadriga, with the staff of 1814-1945 as well as an artificial patina, on August 6, 1991, the two hundredth anniversary of the gate. The gate itself could thus claim its traditional place as the symbol of Berlin as well as its newer status as the preeminent symbol of unity. Yet it stood in the middle of the city’s main east-west thoroughfare; the symbol of unity physically separated the two Berlins. The relationship between the gate and the all-important circulation of traffic sparked another debate. The attachment many Germans have to their cars has always stopped short of the American practice of tearing down cities to make way for cars, but the passion of Gennan car lovers seems to arouse in Green-thinking Germans the same kind of suspicion that passionate patriotism does. Happily the question of driving through the Brandenburg Gate did not create clear battle lines. Some car haters wanted to reserve the gate for pedestrians and bicyclists, but others thought that the gate could serve to limit and slow auto traffic. Car lovers’ favourited solutions were a tunnel under the gate or a scheme to circumvent it. The latter, in fact, had first proposed at the tum of the century, and Nazi planners as well had sought to remove the buildings on each side of the gate to make way for traffic. In the 1990s, those buildings were long gone, but plans to direct traffic away from the gate were nevertheless opposed by some who thought it should serve as a gate, a symbol or German unity, not a traffic island, and by others who wanted to rebuild Pariser Platz as the enclosed space it once had been. An initial compromise permitted only buses and taxis through the gate, and they were restricted to the wider central passage, once reserved for the emperor’s carriage. When the monarchy ended in 1918, that central passage was not the only place that lost its identity. For all the turbulence of Berlin’s history under the Hohenzollerns, they arguably presided over a degree of stability that has not been approached in the rest of the twentieth century. Many Berliners are understandably reluctant to frame their identity in terms of the troubled eras that followed: the weak Weimar Republic, the Third Reich, and the divided city. Hence the wish to reach back to the relatively placid era of monarchs. How can that nostalgia possibly be satisfied? Since hardly anyone actually wants a king, it is difficult to know just what to salvage from the royal past. The much-restored but never removed Brandenburg Gate, with its twice-removed and thrice-reconstructed quadriga, is as authentic a symbol as Berlin can offer. Other buildings, visible or remembered, embody too rich a variety of meanings to permit any consensus about the legacy of old Berlin, or about how to restore it.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;NOTES&lt;/b&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;{N23. Michael S. Cullen and Uwe Kieling, &lt;i&gt;Das Brandenburger Tor: Geschichte eines deutschen Symbols&lt;/i&gt; (Berlin: Argon, 1990), 108. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;{N24. Jürgen Reiche, “Symbolgehalt und Bedeutungswandel eines politischen Monuments,” in &lt;i&gt;Das Brandenburger Tor: Eine Monographie&lt;/i&gt;, ed. Willmuth Arenhovel and Rolf Bothe (Berlin: Arenhövel, 1991), 304. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;{N25. Peter Möbius and Helmut Trotnow, “Das Mauer-Komplott”, &lt;i&gt;Die Zeit&lt;/i&gt; (overseas ed.), Aug. 16, 1991. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;{N26. Friedrich Morin, &lt;i&gt;Berlin und Potsdam im Jahre 1860&lt;/i&gt; (reprint, Braunschweig: Archiv-Verlag, 1980), 16. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;{N27. &lt;i&gt;Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung&lt;/i&gt;, April 18, 1991. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;{N28. Ulrike Krenzlin, “Eisemes Kreuz und Preussen-Adler: Ja oder Nein?” in &lt;i&gt;Hauptstadt Berlin-wohin mit der Mitte?&lt;/i&gt; ed. Helmut Engel and Wolfgang Ribbe (Berlin: Akademie, 1993), 104-7. &lt;b&gt;SOURCE: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.history.ucsb.edu/faculty/marcuse/classes/133c/133cproj/06proj/LaddGhostsSMalcolm063.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Ghosts of Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Ghosts-Berlin-Confronting-History-Landscape/product-reviews/0226467627/ref=dp_top_cm_cr_acr_txt?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;showViewpoints=1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Confronting German History in the Urban Landscape&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mitworld.mit.edu/video/85&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Brian Ladd&lt;/a&gt;. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1997, pp70-81, UCSB: HT169.G32B4127 1997}" id="2938685282" latitude="52.516265" license="4" longitude="13.377757" nbComments="8" rank="21" tags="brandenburggate quadriga thewall ironcross triumphalarch thoroughfare gateway sculpture buildup monument corona banner standard wreath trophy verdigris prussianeagle friedrichwilhelm brandenburgertor gloomy eiserneskreuz restauration berlin urbanlandscape venue archway geotagged geo:lat=52516265 geo:lon=13377757 geo:dir=276 wahrzeichen landmark" title="restored quadriga atop Brandenburg Gate ►pale-verdigris gateway build-up (“horses'-herma”) in gloomy night◄" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3061/2938685282_2ec0da1c1a_b.jpg" username="quapan" views="32212" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-18 00:39:05" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pavlovsk_Palace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pavlovsk_Palace&lt;/a&gt; Pavlovsk Palace is an 18th-century Russian Imperial residence built by Paul I of Russia in Pavlovsk, near Saint Petersburg. After his death, it became the home of his widow, Maria Feodorovna. The palace and the large English garden surrounding it are now a Russian state museum and public park. Creation In 1777 The Empress Catherine II of Russia gave a parcel of a thousand hectares of forest along the winding Slavyanka River, four kilometers from her residence at Tsarskoye Selo, to her son and heir Paul I and his wife Maria Feodorovna, to celebrate the birth of their first son, the future Alexander I of Russia. At the time the land was given to Paul and Maria Feodorovna, there were two rustic log lodges in the called 'Krik' and 'Krak.' Paul and his wife spent the summers of 1777 to 1780 in Krik, while their new homes and the garden were being built.[1] They began by building two wooden buildings, one kilometer apart. Paul's house, a two-story house in the Dutch style, with small gardens, was called &amp;quot;Marienthal&amp;quot;, or the &amp;quot;Valley of Maria.&amp;quot; Maria's house was a small wooden house with a cupola, flower beds, named &amp;quot;Paullust&amp;quot;, or &amp;quot;Paul's Joy.&amp;quot; Paul and Maria Feodorovna began to create picturesque &amp;quot;ruins&amp;quot;, a Chinese kiosk, Chinese bridges and classical temples in the English landscape garden style which had spread rapidly across Europe in the second half of the 18th century.[2] In 1780, Catherine the Great loaned her official architect, the Scotsman Charles Cameron, to design a palace on a hillside overlooking the Slavyanka River, near the site of Marienthal. Cameron had studied under English architect Isaac Ware, who was close to the architect of Chiswick House, the villa of Lord Burlington one of the earliest and finest Palladian houses in England. Through this connection Cameron became familiar with the original plans of Palladio, which were in the personal collection of Lord Burlington. This style was the major influence on Cameron when he designed Pavlovsk.[3] Cameron began his project not with the palace itself but with two classical pavilions. The first was the Temple of Friendship, a circular Dorian temple with sixteen columns supporting a low dome, containing a statute of Catherine the Great. It was placed at a bend of the Slavyanka River, below the future palace, and was surrounded by silver poplars and transplanted Siberian pines. The second was the Apollo Colonnade, a double row of columns with an entablature, forming a setting for a reproduction of a reproduction of the Belvedere Apollo. It was placed at the entrance of the park, and it was made of porous limestone with a coarse finish the surfaces to suggest that they had been aged by centuries of weather. At the same time the Slavyanka River was dammed, to create a lake which would mirror the facade of the palace above.[4] Maria Feodorovna also insisted in having several rustic structures which recalled the palace where she grew up at Étupes, forty miles from Basel, in what was then the Duchy of Württemberg and today is in Alsace. Cameron constructed a small Swiss chalet with a library; a dairy of rough stones with a thatched roof, where milk products were kept and prepared, and an aviary in the form of a small classical temple with metal netting between the Dorian columns, which was filled with nightingale, goldfinch, starling and quail. For the palace itself, Cameron conceived a country house which seems to have been based on a design of Palladio shown in a woodcut in his book Quattro libri dell'architectura, for the Villa Tressino at Meledo in Italy. This same drawing was later used by Thomas Jefferson in his design for the University of Virginia. The palace he designed had a cube-shaped central block three stories high with a low dome supported by sixty-four columns. On either side of the building were two single story colonnades of curved open winged galleries connected to service buildings one and a half stories high. Each facade of the palace was decorated with molded friezes and reliefs.[5] In September 1781, as construction of the Pavlovsk Palace began, Paul and Maria set off on a journey to Austria, Italy, France and Germany. They traveled under the incognito of &amp;quot;The Count and Countess of the North&amp;quot;. During their travels they saw the palaces and French gardens of Versailles and Chantilly, which strongly influenced the future appearance of Pavlovsk Park. King Louis XVI presented them with four Gobelins tapestries, Marie Antoinette presented Maria Feodorovna with a sixty-piece toilet set of Sèvres porcelain, and they ordered more sets of porcelain and purchased statues, busts, paintings, furniture and paintings, all for Pavlovsk. While they traveled, they kept in contact almost daily with Kuchelbecker, the supervisor of construction at Pavlovsk, sending back and forth drawings, plans and notes on the smallest details.[6] Paul and Maria Feodorovna returned in November 1782, and they continued to fill Pavlovsk with art objects. A shipment of antique marbles, statues, busts, urns, and pottery discovered and purchased at Pompei, arrived in 1783. Sixteen sets of furniture, over two hundred pieces, were ordered from Paris between 1783 and 1785 for the State Rooms. In 1784, twelve Hubert Robert landscapes were commissioned for Pavlovsk. The couple purchased ninety-six clocks from Europe. The Imperial Glass factory, made special chandeliers for each room. In the midst of the construction, and tensions grew between her and Cameron; Cameron was used to the unlimited budget for materials given him by Catherine the Great, while Catherine gave very little money to Paul; and Cameron was annoyed by the furniture, tapestries and fireplaces brought back from Europe by Maria Feodorovna without consulting him. Maria Feodorovna in turn was annoyed by the bright polychrome decoration and Pompeian arabesques used by Cameron, and wanted more delicate colors, and Paul did not like anything that resembled the style of his mother's house, the Catherine Palace at Tsarskoye Selo. The tensions led to a parting in 1786. Cameron left to build a new palace for Catherine in the Crimea. He had finished entry vestibule and the five rooms of the private apartments. The work of decorating the interior was taken over by an Italian architect, Vincenzio Brenna, from Florence, who had come to Russia in 1783. Brenna designed interiors which reflected Paul's taste for Roman classicism. He created the white and gold Halls of War and Peace, on either side of the Greek Hall by Cameron, which had a colonnade of green false marble columns, resembling a Greek temple. He made the Italian hall into a replica of a Roman temple, and he built the State Bedroom for Maria Feodorovna as an imitation of the state bedroom of the King of France, with a huge gilded bed, and cream silk wallpaper painted in tempura with colorful flowers, fruit, musical instruments and gardening tools.[6] Catherine the Great died in 1796, and Paul became Emperor. He decided to enlarge Pavlovsk into a palace suitable for a royal residence, adding two new wings on either side of the main building, and a church attached to the south wing. Between 1797 and 1799, he lavished money and the finest materials on Brenna's interiors. The reign of Emperor Paul did not last long. He alienated the nobles, and became increasingly fearful of conspiracies. His fears were justified; the Emperor Paul was murdered by members of his court in 1801, and his son Alexander became Emperor. Pavlovsk Palace became the residence of the Empress Maria Feodorovna (1759–1828), the mother of both Emperor Alexander I of Russia and Emperor Nicholas I of Russia. She turned the house into a memorial to her murdered husband, filled with his furniture and portraits, and made the house a showcase for finest 18th century French furnishings, paintings, sculpture and porcelain. Another disaster struck Pavlovsk in 1803; a fire caused by a defective chimney destroyed a major part of the interior of the palace, including all the decor of the State Apartments and living rooms. Most of the furniture was saved, along with some door panels, fireplaces and mirrors, but most of the Palace had to be rebuilt. Maria Feodorovna brought Cameron and Brenna's young assistant, the Italian architect Carlo Rossi, to help restore the Palace. She also employed a Russian architect, Andrei Voronykhin, who had been born a serf, and was trained in decoration and design, who rose to become the architect of Kazan Cathedral in St. Petersburg. Voronykhin was named chief architect of Pavlovsk by Maria Feodorovna. He brought back the architect Quarenghi, who had redecorated five rooms on the main floor, to recreate his work. He remade some of the rooms, such as the Tapestry Room and the State Bedroom, exactly as they had been, but for other rooms he added decoration inspired by Roman models discovered at Pompeii and Herculaneum; Roman-style lamps, furniture, Roman couches, and chairs copied after those of Roman senators. Following the French taste of the time for Egyptian art, he added black Egyptian statues in the entry vestibule of the Palace, He also redesigned the Greek and Italian halls, replacing the molding on the walls with false marble, and he added a Russian touch; fireplaces faced with Russian lapis-lazuli and jasper, which had originally been in the Mikhailovsky Palace that Paul had built in St. Petersburg. Voronykhin also made plans for a semi-circular library in one of the wings, which was later built by Carlo Rossi, and he redesigned the private apartments of Maria Feodorovna on the ground floor, which included a library, boudoir and bedroom. He installed French doors and large windows in the apartment, so the flower garden outside seemed to be part of the interior.[7] In 1805 Voronykhin built the Centaur bridge in the park, and the Visconti bridge, which crossed the Slavyanka at a point it was filled with water lilies. His last construction in the park was the Rose Pavilion, built in 1811, a simple structure surrounded entirely by rosebushes. The Rose Pavilion was the site of a grand fete on July 12, 1814, celebrating the return of Alexander I to St. Petersburg after the defeat of Napoleon. For the occasion the architect Pietro de Gottardo Gonzaga built a ballroom the size of the Rose Pavilion itself in just seventeen days, and surrounded it with huge canvases of Russian villagers celebrating the victory. The ball inside the pavilion opened with a Polonaise led by Alexander and his mother, and ended with a huge display of fireworks. In her later years Maria Feodorovna had a literary salon at Pavlovsk, which was frequented by the poet Vasily Zhukovsky, the fable writer Ivan Krylov, and the historian Nikolai Karamzin. The last great St. Petersburg architect to work at Pavlovsk was Carlo Rossi, who in 1824 designed the library, which contained more than twenty thousand books as well as collections of rare coins and butterflies. He also designed the Corner Salon, where Maria Feodorovna received guests such as the first American Ambassador to Russia, John Quincy Adams, and the Lavender Room, whose walls were made of lilac-colored false marble, matching the lilac flowers outside the windows. These rooms were furnished with furniture made of native Russian woods, including Karelian birch, poplar and walnut.[8] Maria Feodorovna died on October 24, 1828, fourteen days after her sixty-seventh birthday. She left the house to her younger son, Michael, and specified that none of the furniture should be taken away. After Michael's death, it went to the second son of Nicholas I, Constantine Nikolayevich. It then passed to his widow and then their eldest son, Constantine Constantinovich. Her descendants respected the will, and turned the house into a family museum, just as it was when she died. After the Russian Revolution At the time of the Russian Revolution in 1917, the eldest son of Constantine Constantinovich, Prince Jean, along with his wife Helen, the daughter of the King of Serbia, and the sister of Constantine, Queen Olga of Greece, were living in one of the wings of Pavlovsk. As the political situation deteriorated, they left, and the house was left to the care of Alexander Polovotsoff, director of the Art Institute and the Museum of Applied Arts in St. Petersburg, When Lenin and the Bolsheviks seized power in November 1917, Polovtsoff went to the Winter Palace, found Anatoly Lunacharsky, the Commissar of Enlightenment of the new government, and demanded that Pavlovsk be saved as a museum. Lunacharsky agreed and named him Commissar Curator of Pavlovsk. He returned to the Palace and found that a group of revolutionary sailors had searched the Palace for weapons and taken a few sabers, but otherwise everything was in its place. He hired former soldiers to guard the house, put all the furniture into the main building, made an inventory of all the treasures in the Palace, and successfully resisted demands from various revolutionary committees for dishes, chairs, tables, and all the books from the library. He was able to persuade Lunacharsky himself to come to Pavlovsk, After Lunacharsky's visit, Pavlovsk was officially confiscated, but turned into a museum, open to the public two or three days a week. Having succeeded in saving the Palace, Polovtsoff took family and belongings and slipped across the border to Finland and moved to Paris. World War II The German attack on the Soviet Union in June 1941 and the swiftness of the German advance took the Soviet government by surprise. The morning after the attack, the curators of Pavlovsk, under the direction of museum curator Anatoliy Kuchumov, began to pack as many of art objects as possible, starting with the Sèvres porcelain toilet set given by Louis XVI to Maria Feodorovna and Paul in 1780. Ninety-six hours after the announcement of the beginning of the war, the first thirty-four crates were being carried from the palace by horse-drawn cart. Boards were put over the windows, and sand on the floor of the Palace. The thirty curators often worked by candlelight, and by July there were air raids. The paintings, chandeliers, crystal, porcelain, rare furniture, and works of ivory and amber were packed and sent first. They worked with great care – each piece of furniture had to be carefully dismantled, porcelain vases had to be separated from the bases, and delicate clocks had to have their casing and mechanisms separated and packed separately, with diagrams on how to put them back together. One piece of each set of furniture was saved, and the others left behind. The Roman and Greek antiquities were too heavy and delicate to move, so they were taken to the basements, placed as close together as possible, and then hidden by a brick wall. By the third week of August thirteen thousand objects, plus all the documentation, had been packed and sent away. Some crates were sent to Gorky, others to Sarapul, and the last group, on August 20, 1941, went to Leningrad, where the crates were stored in the basement of St. Isaac's Cathedral. The last shipment included the chandelier from the Italian Hall and the jasper vases from the Greek Hall. On August 30, the last rail link from Leningrad to Moscow was cut, and the city was under blockade. By August 28 the Germans were fifty kilometers from Pavlovsk. A Soviet division headquarters was located in one wing of the palace, As the Germans came closer, the park and Palace came under bombardment. The museum staff began to bury the statues which were too heavy to evacuate. They calculated that the Germans would not dig deeper than one meter eighty centimeters, so they buried all the statues as deep as three meters. The statues of the Three Graces were buried three meters beneath the private garden of Maria Feodorovna. Their calculations were correct; the statues were still there after the war. On September 16, the last soldiers left, and the Germans occupied Pavlovsk Palace, which was still occupied by a group of elderly women guardians. The Germans occupied Pavlovsk palace for two and a half years. Officers were quartered in the salons on the first floor, and the ballroom was made into a garage for cars and motorcycles. Barracks were located in the north wing and a hospital in the south wing. German soldiers, Dutch soldiers and Spanish soldiers in special units of the German army occupied the buildings in the Park. The sculpture and furniture that remained in the house and all the books of the Rossi Library were taken to Germany. The statue of Emperor Paul in the courtyard was used as a telephone pole. Fortunately the Germans did not discover the antiquities hidden behind the brick wall in the basement. Pavlovsk was liberated on January 24, 1944. When the Soviet troops arrived, the Palace had already been burning for three days. The main building of the Palace was a hollow shell, without a roof or floors. The north wall had fallen. Most of the parquet floors of the palace had been used as firewood; a few pieces were found in unburned portions of the palace near the stoves. Of the over one hundred thousand trees that had been in the park before the War, seventy thousand had been cut down or destroyed by the shelling. All the decorative bridges in the park had been blown up. Eight hundred bunkers had been dug in the park. The Rose Pavilion was gone; the Germans had used the materials to construct a fortified dugout. Restoration On February 18, 1944, a meeting was held at the House of Architects in Leningrad to discuss the fate of the ruined Palaces. The academician and architect Aleksei Shchusev, who had designed the Lenin Mausoleum, called for the immediate reconstruction of the Palaces. &amp;quot;If we do not do this&amp;quot;, he said, &amp;quot;we who know and remember these palaces in all their glory as they were, then the next generation will never be able to reconstruct them.&amp;quot; [11] Even before the war had ended, the Soviet government decided to restore Pavlovsk and the other ruined palaces around Leningrad. First the mines had to be cleared from the ruins and palace and the park. Then the remaining walls were supported with scaffolding, and casts were made of the remaining molding. Fragments of plaster molding were collected, sorting, and casts made. The color of paint still on the remaining walls was carefully noted for later copying. Photographs and early plans of the palace were brought together to help with the restoration. As soon as the war ended, a search began for treasures stolen from the Palace. Curators collected pieces of furniture, fabric, the legs of tables and pieces of doors and gilded cornices from the German fortifications around the Palace. In the buildings which had been German headquarters, they found chairs, marble statues and rolled-up paintings from the Palace. They found other furniture and objects as far away as Riga, Tallinn, and in Konigsberg, in Germany. Some precious objects from Pavlovsk left Russia even before the war. Four Gobelins tapestries from Pavlovsk were sold by the Soviet Government to J. Paul Getty, and are now on display in the Getty Museum in Malibu, California.[12] The restorers used only the original variants of the architectural decoration; those created by Cameron, Brenna, Voronykhin, and Rossi. The only changes permitted were to use modern materials. Columns made of wood were replaced by poured concrete or bricks, and the ceilings of the Italian and Greek Halls were made of steel and concrete so they would be fireproof. A special school, the Mukhina Leningrad Higher Artistic Industry School, was created in Leningrad to teach the arts of restoring architectural details, furniture, and art objects. This school produced a corps of restoration experts who worked on all the palaces around Leningrad. The work was meticulous and difficult, and proceeded very slowly. In 1950, after six years of planting new trees, parts of the Park opened to the public. In 1955, the restoration of the facade of the Palace was completed, and restoration of the interiors began. Fortunately for the restorers, the original plans by Cameron, Brenna, Voronykhin and Rossi still existed. Also, fragments of the original interior molding, cornices, friezes and the frames for the carvings, bas-reliefs, medallions and paintings still remained, and could be copied. In addition, there were twenty-five hundred photographic negatives taken in the early century by Benois, and another eleven thousand photographs taken just before the war.[12] The chief of the restoration, Feodor Oleinik, was insistent that all the restoration be faithful to the original work: &amp;quot;Pay attention and do not use later details&amp;quot;, he demanded. &amp;quot;Only the original variant, only that done by Cameron, Brenna, Vornykhin, or Rossi.&amp;quot; Old techniques of artisans of the 18th century, such as painting false marble and gilding furniture, had to be relearned and applied. A silk workshop was opened in Moscow to recreate the original woven fabrics for wall coverings and upholstery, copying the texture, color and thread counts of the originals. In forty rooms of the Palace, painted decoration on the walls and ceilings had to be precisely recreated in the original colors and designs. A Master painter and six helpers recreated the original trompe l'oeil ceilings and wall paintings.[13] Once the interior walls and decoration had been exactly recreated, the next step was the furnishings. The twelve thousand pieces of furniture and art objects removed from their original places, from paintings and tapestries to water pitchers and glasses, had to be put back where they belonged. Furniture, doors, and parquet floors of many different colors of wood which had been burned or stolen were remade exactly like the originals. The crystal chandeliers of the 18th century were exactly copied. In 1957, thirteen years after the Palace had been burned, the first seven rooms were opened to the public. In 1958, four more rooms were opened, and eleven more in 1960. The Egyptian Vestibule was finished in 1963, and the Italian Room opened in 1965. Eleven more rooms were ready by 1967. By 1977, on the 200th anniversary of the beginning of the Palace, fifty rooms were finished, and the Palace looked again as it had in the time of Maria Feodorovna." id="7389026438" latitude="59.686157" license="1" longitude="30.451955" nbComments="29" rank="22" tags="pavlovsk palace павловский дворец nx10" title="Pavlovsk Palace. Павловский Дворец." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7222/7389026438_8655e57bea_b.jpg" username="Peer.Gynt" views="487" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-04 13:21:01" description="In Loving / Memory of / John Henry Iles OBE / Master of the Worshipful / Company of Musicians 1932-1933 / Who devoted his Life to the / advancement of Brass Bands / Died 29th May 1951 aged 79 years ... &lt;b&gt;Biography&lt;/b&gt;: &amp;quot;(John) Henry Iles (1871-1951), brass-band promoter and entertainment entrepreneur, was born at 8 Clarence Road, Bristol, on 17 September 1871, the son of John Thomas Iles and his wife, Mary Ann Butler. After leaving Ashville College, Harrogate, he entered his father's timber business. At the same time he built on his strong interest in music to develop a business career of his own. A keen church organist, choirmaster, and singer, he began by buying the journal Organist and Choirmaster before turning his interest to the brass-band movement. He appears first to have encountered brass bands when attending a contest while on a business trip to Belle Vue, Manchester, in 1898. Almost immediately after this he purchased the band music publishing house, Richard Smith &amp;amp; Co., turning its journal, the &lt;i&gt;British Bandsman&lt;/i&gt; (founded 1887), into the movement's only weekly paper in March 1902. With its combination of regional news and gossip, technical hints, and extensive advertising columns, it rapidly became the most important element of the band press. &amp;quot;In January 1900 Iles, a highly effective publicist for the band movement, persuaded Sir Arthur Sullivan to conduct massed bands in a rendition of the composer's setting of Kipling's 'The Absent-Minded Beggar' during a concert at the Royal Albert Hall in London in aid of South African War charities. Building on the enthusiasm that this engendered and using Sullivan's influence as a director of the Crystal Palace, he established the &lt;b&gt;National Brass Band Championship&lt;/b&gt;, which was held at the palace from 1900 until it was destroyed by fire in 1936. Until the early twentieth century, brass-band contest music typically comprised operatic selections and Iles was instrumental in the decision to encourage composers to produce complete pieces specifically designed for the brass band's distinctive configuration. In 1913 'Labour and Love', an unsolicited work by the light orchestral and theatre music composer, Percy Fletcher, was selected as the championship test piece with this consideration in mind. &lt;b&gt;Gustav Holst&lt;/b&gt; (1928), &lt;b&gt;Sir Edward Elgar&lt;/b&gt; (1930), &lt;b&gt;John Ireland&lt;/b&gt; (1932), and &lt;b&gt;Arthur Bliss&lt;/b&gt; (1936) were among the many composers commissioned to produce test pieces in the next decades: Iles was especially proud of his achievement in securing a work from Elgar. The best of these pieces did much to increase the level of technical ability within bands. &amp;quot;These commissions, the positive publicity that Iles consistently brought to a movement prone to suffer from an inferiority complex, and, not least, his personal popularity, made 'John Henry' an immensely respected figure within the band movement. On his death, a number of obituaries termed him 'our chief' and many commentators clearly saw him essentially as a philanthropist and not a businessman. At a memorial service, the composer Eric Ball claimed that for Iles, the band movement was 'a crusade, an ideal; material gain from it did not worry him'. Certainly, by the inter-war period, Iles seemed to see his band work as more hobby and social obligation than money-making venture, but this had not been the case at the outset, when philanthropy and profit fused in fruitful combination. &amp;quot;Iles's band work also led him indirectly into the business ventures which were to be the eventual basis of the considerable wealth which he enjoyed at one stage. In 1906, he managed a 'world tour' undertaken by the Besses o' th' Barn Band, during which he was much inspired by the amusement parks of North America. He returned with the British rights to the switchback ride and with plans for the 'scenic railway', a feature which he soon introduced at Blackpool and the White City in London. Eventually Iles was to enjoy major interests in amusement parks in Barcelona, Berlin, Brussels, Cairo, Copenhagen, Paris, and Pittsburgh. In terms of the English outdoor entertainment industry, he was most closely associated with &lt;b&gt;Margate&lt;/b&gt;, where he developed the &lt;b&gt;Dreamland Amusement Park&lt;/b&gt; and the Cliftonville Lido on a seafront site purchased in 1919. He also had interests in greyhound racing, introducing the sport into Kent in the late 1920s, at which time he also became a director of Belle Vue, Manchester. Unsuccessful investment in the British film industry in the later 1930s effectively destroyed Iles's business empire, a loss of some £250,000 resulting in his bankruptcy in July 1938. He resigned from all his directorships, though he maintained control of the brass-band National Championship until 1945, when he finally relinquished it to the &lt;i&gt;Daily Herald&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;quot;Iles served as master of the &lt;b&gt;Worshipful Company of Musicians&lt;/b&gt; in 1933. He was appointed &lt;b&gt;OBE&lt;/b&gt; for his services to the band movement in 1944 and was also made an officer of the &lt;b&gt;Académie Française&lt;/b&gt;. A keen sportsman, he was an occasional member of the Gloucestershire county cricket side in 1890-91 (he was proud once to have bowled W. G. Grace in a net practice), enjoyed a lifelong enthusiasm for golf, and wrote a cyclist's guide to Bristol and its environs in 1898. In 1893 Iles married Eleanor Marion (b. 1869/70), daughter of Frederick Bird, a merchant of Midsomer Norton; they had a daughter and three sons, the eldest of whom, H. F. B. Eric Iles, took over a number of his father's directorships after 1938. The family made their home at Birchington in Kent from the 1920s, Iles serving as a Margate JP from 1935 to 1938. &amp;quot;Iles died at his home, 'Aurora', Cliff Road, Birchington, on 29 May 1951 and was buried in Birchington on 7 June. He was survived by his wife. A well-attended memorial service, held at St Sepulchre's, Holborn, saw a number of leading figures in the band world pay verbal and musical tributes to a man whose respect for bandsmen's skills and commitment led him, directly and indirectly, into fertile business operations and the band movement into a level of public exposure beyond anything it had previously received.&amp;quot; Source: Dave Russell (&lt;i&gt;Oxford Dictionary of National Biography&lt;/i&gt;)" id="384529067" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="23" tags="johnhenryiles memorial inscription text parishchurchofallsaints birchington graffiti worshipfulcompanyofmusicians brassband obe lichen dreamlandmargate chrisbeckett" title="John Henry Iles OBE, memorial inscription, Parish Church of All Saints, Birchington" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/123/384529067_766cf6b61e_b.jpg" username="chrisjohnbeckett" views="1146" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-08-28 15:59:56" description="(Graphic courtesy Huffington Post) Originally published in the Huffington Post With Megan Fromm COLLEGE PARK, Md. - Many of the world's major news outlets covered the 2012 London Olympics, one of the most visually engaging events of the year, in surprising -- and surprisingly lackluster -- ways. A new study of 20 major media outlets used the image-curating website Pinterest to help measure the photographic coverage of four days of the Olympics -- days at the height of the swimming, gymnastics, cycling, diving, basketball, judo, weightlifting and equestrian events. Researchers at the Salzburg Academy on Media &amp;amp; Global Change in partnership with the International Center for Media &amp;amp; the Public Agenda at the University of Maryland evaluated the visual content of each of the sites' London 2012 pages to see which news outlets used photos well -- compelling images, published large enough to see without clicking on them -- and what sports, athletes and moments each outlet chose to highlight. Researchers found particularly striking that women athletes were pictured in 43 percent of the images pinned to Pinterest -- yet another signal of the gains made by women in these Games which were the first in history in which all the participating countries included a woman athlete. In a similar study four years ago of the Beijing Olympics conducted by the Salzburg Academy, women athletes only appeared in 36 percent of the photos. This year's London 2012 study did find marked differences among the global media in their reporting on women athletes, however. Some outlets devoted significantly more coverage to one gender -- The New York Times showed three times as many images of women as men during the period studied, for example, while The Times of South Africa showed images of men four times as often as those of women. The greatest surprise of the study? Only about a third of the news outlets prioritized pictures over text, despite the fact that all but one of the global outlets hosted dedicated web pages to cover London 2012. Researchers were stunned to see how few photos appeared above the scroll on many websites. The best websites included roughly a half a dozen thrill-of-victory or agony-of-defeat photos and posted them in a clear hierarchy of importance, as signaled by size and placement (as did the Daily Mail, Yahoo! and the Sydney Morning Herald). The best websites? * BBC (UK) * Daily Mail (UK) * Yahoo! (USA) * The New York Times (USA) * Sydney Morning Herald (Australia) * Al Jazeera (Qatar) * The Times (South Africa) The most disappointing sites? * The Telegraph (UK) * NBC (USA) * ESPN (USA) * People's Daily (China) * The Hindu (India) * El Pais (Spain) The surprisingly weak sites? * The Guardian * CNN Unexpectedly, those sites with the strongest visual coverage (five or more medium to large photos above the scroll) often did not include critical content above the scroll: links to breaking news across sports and a live medal count. The site that came closest to a useful balance of visual and story content was the BBC. The BBC did a good job posting photos, averaging five photos at a time above the scroll, and its page format included a center column giving viewers quick navigation to different sports -- although its update on the medal race was elsewhere. By contrast, researchers gave The Guardian poor marks for only featuring three photos on average at a time, although it did get the highest marks for including above-the-scroll links to a full range of sports as well as a live medal count. Researchers also rated CNN as ho-hum -- researchers appreciated that its lead photo and three smaller images emphasized the human element of the Games, but the layout included very limited content. The least visually engaging and user-friendly sites ran only a couple of photos (such as The Telegraph, People's Daily, and The Standard) or featured a very dominant video or slide show with a sprinkling or row of thumbnail or quite small photos. These latter sites often ran photos that were greyed-out until clicked on or until the Flash gallery cycled through (such as NBC, ESPN, The Hindu and Televisa Deportes). Such websites frustrated researchers by making them scroll down, click-through or patiently wait to see multiple medium-sized photos pass by in a Flash gallery. Visitors must have the time or inclination to sit through a video or automated slide show -- and many don't. Other sites, such as Paris Match which had no dedicated Olympics page, and the Süddeutsche Zeitung, which posted ads and Twitter feeds as prominently as articles with photos, seemed less than committed to covering the Games well. A last takeaway? Every outlet, from the UK to China, South Africa to Mexico, Australia to France, featured the athletes from their own countries, even athletes competing in &amp;quot;minor&amp;quot; sports. In fact, almost two-thirds of all images published were of athletes from the home country of the news outlet. When U.S. gymnast Gabby Douglas leaped and tumbled her way to individual gold, for example, hundreds of photographers clicked away to capture her performance. But judging by the online content of this study's news outlets, viewers wouldn't necessarily have seen those pictures unless they surfed to a U.S.-based site. Make your own assessment of which outlets you think covered the Olympics the best. View the Pinterest boards here. And check out the sites directly to revisit the photographic coverage. 1. Al Jazeera (Qatar) 2. BBC News (UK) 3. Clarin (Argentina) 4. CNN/Sports Illustrated (USA) 5. Daily Mail (UK) 6. El Pais (Spain) 7. ESPN (USA) 8. Guardian (UK) 9. NBC Olympics (USA) 10. Paris Match (France) 11. People's Daily (China) 12. Süddeutsche Zeitung (Germany) 13. Sydney Morning Herald (Australia) 14. Televisa Deportes (Mexico) 15. The Hindu (India) 16. The New York Times (USA) 17. The Standard (Kenya) 18. The Telegraph (UK) 19. The Times (South Africa) 20. Yahoo! (USA) --- A Note on Methodology: The Olympix study used the image-curating site Pinterest to investigate the photographic coverage of the 2012 Olympic Games in London. The study, conducted live during the Olympics by faculty and students attending the Salzburg Academy on Media &amp;amp; Global Change in Salzburg, Austria, looked at the coverage of the first four days of the games, from July 30 to August 2. In 2008, the Salzburg Academy conducted an evaluation of the Beijing Olympics, which can be seen here. Global faculty, from the regions and countries considered, selected the news outlets: they selected each news outlet for its general popularity and its attention to sports. Researchers then used Pinterest and screengrabs of the home pages to capture images from those 20 news outlets in 13 countries and evaluate them using a codebook hosted on SurveyMonkey. (Note that in order to code rapidly changing sites, researchers grabbed screenshots of the London 2012 dedicated pages as well as the photos that appeared on those pages. As a result, the Pinterest &amp;quot;pins&amp;quot; do not link back to the originating visuals and also include some evaluative comments of the coders.) The roughly 75 coders came from five continents and 12 countries and they all were native speakers of the news outlets they coded. Screen grabs were evaluated for the web content that appeared under the website's banner title, but before a visitor to the site would have to scroll down. (Note that some of the screen grabs posted to Pinterest include information lower down; that content was not coded.) Video embeds that appeared as photos until clicked were treated as still photos, and special slideshows (often in Flash) were considered as one image unless the show advanced through the images automatically. Sites were checked once daily, so the total number of evaluated photos does not account for websites refreshing their images throughout the days of breaking events. In most cases, however, the sites simply replaced photos, rather than updated the format of their pages. Therefore the number of photos on each London 2012 webpage remained relatively constant. Megan Fromm, PhD, directed the Olympix study, in consultation with professors Susan Moeller, Paul Mihailidis and Jad Melki. The International Center for Media &amp;amp; the Public Agenda (ICMPA), partnered in the study, conducted at the 6th annual Salzburg Academy on Media &amp;amp; Global Change hosted by the Salzburg Global Seminar. Susan Moeller is the director of ICMPA and a co-founder of the Salzburg Academy, now going into its 7th year. For more information contact: Professor Susan D. Moeller smoeller@umd.edu Philip Merrill College of Journalism University of Maryland, College Park, MD 20742-7111 phone: 301 405 2419" id="7882510404" latitude="51.50632" license="2" longitude="-0.12714" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="londonolympics olympics photos pinterest photocovergeoftheolympics sports swimming gymnastics cycling diving basketball judo weightlifting equestrianevents salzburgacademyonmediaglobalchange internationalcenterformediathepublicagenda womenathletes athletes" title="New University of Maryland Study Shows Global News Sites Poorly Covered the Olympics in Photos" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8308/7882510404_71640137a6_b.jpg" username="University of Maryland Press Releases" views="52" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-16 17:56:20" description="&lt;strong&gt;The National Monument&lt;/strong&gt; - Washington DC Photos The Washington &lt;strong&gt;Monument&lt;/strong&gt; is an obelisk near the west end of the National Mall in Washington, D.C., built to commemorate the first U.S. president, General George Washington. &lt;strong&gt;The National Monument&lt;/strong&gt;, made of marble, granite, and bluestone gneiss, is both the world's tallest stone structure and the world's tallest obelisk, standing 555 feet 5⅛ inches (169.294 m). There are taller monumental columns, but they are neither all stone nor true obelisks. It is also the tallest structure in Washington D.C.. It was designed by Robert Mills, an architect of the 1840s. The actual construction of the monument began in 1848 but was not completed until 1884, almost 30 years after the architect's death. This hiatus in construction happened because of co-option by the Know Nothing party, a lack of funds, and the intervention of the American Civil War. A difference in shading of the marble, visible approximately 150 feet (46 m or 27%) up, shows where construction was halted for a number of years. The cornerstone was laid on July 4, 1848; the capstone was set on December 6, 1884, and the completed monument was dedicated on February 21, 1885. It officially opened October 9, 1888. Upon completion, it became the world's tallest structure, a title previously held by the Cologne Cathedral. The monument held this designation until 1889, when the Eiffel Tower was completed in Paris, France. The monument stands due east of the Reflecting Pool and the Lincoln Memorial. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nps.gov/wamo/index.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.nps.gov/wamo/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; More Photos At: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glynlowe.com/national_monument/e56b3e1#h56b3e1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.glynlowe.com/national_monument&lt;/a&gt;" id="7400585446" latitude="38.889387" license="4" longitude="-77.037988" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="dc general george lincoln mall memorial monument national photos pool reflecting stock us washington buy digital digitaldownload download first foto photo president sale stockphoto stockphotos" title="The National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5455/7400585446_fd8b679b8f_b.jpg" username="Glyn Lowe Photoworks" views="808" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-06 11:38:46" description="A bright blue sky to compliment the July Column." id="2298388543" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="paris france europe vacation julycolumn placedelabastille" title="Top of July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3197/2298388543_3c9a61318b_b.jpg" username="midnightglory" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-23 11:31:41" description="Column in the center of the Place de la Bastille in Paris, France. Commemorates the 1830 Trois Glorieuses, the &amp;quot;three glorious&amp;quot; days." id="8218687134" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="2012 france paris september vacation julycolumn placedelabastille monument memorial gold revolutionof1830" title="July column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8068/8218687134_feb35ce6a7_b.jpg" username="John Kroll" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-06 11:41:30" description="Look at it from a different angle and it's just another cloudy day in Paris." id="2299186244" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="paris france europe vacation julycolumn placedelabastille" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3185/2299186244_f39d5ac092_b.jpg" username="midnightglory" views="23" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-30 21:14:31" description="" id="3596476566" latitude="48.853392" license="1" longitude="2.369098" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="france upcoming:event=1307144 paris nightshoot night bastille placedelabastille monument julycolumn frenchrevolution architecture 28mm" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2479/3596476566_e8bb2ff205_b.jpg" username="garrettc" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-01 18:01:51" description="" id="6027104516" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="1445mm bastille france gf1 julycolumn lumix panasonic paris" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6146/6027104516_5e09d6839e_b.jpg" username="skibler" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-01 10:37:23" description="" id="6915085852" latitude="48.853722" license="3" longitude="2.369282" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="paris placedelabastille julycolumn" title="July column, place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7241/6915085852_ca3d738eed_b.jpg" username="Eerko" views="89" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-14 02:49:22" description="" id="5776304221" latitude="48.856809" license="6" longitude="2.343006" nbComments="1" rank="32" tags="0097 france french street scene historical sightseeing blue sky column bastille square travel colonnedejuillet 法国 巴黎 街拍 nikon d90 18200vr bronze clouds view" title="July Column, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5147/5776304221_2ba439e867_b.jpg" username="faungg" views="96" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-23 13:44:13" description="" id="2654144053" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="paris bastille julycolumn placedelabastille landmarks france" title="July Column in the Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3181/2654144053_3286ef2e33_b.jpg" username="Following the Equator" views="56" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 04:16:58" description="La Colonne de Juillet (The July Column), a monument to the Revolution of 1830 in the center of Place de la Bastille, was inaugurated in 1840. The 147-meter tall column rests on a white marble base ornamented with brass bas-reliefs and is engraved in gold with the names of Parisians who died during the Revolution--many of whom are interred beneath. Over the Corinthian capital is a 5-meter wide gallery, surmounted by a gilt globe and the colossal gold figure, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1440357104&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;le Génie de la Liberté&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (The Spirit of Freedom), which appeared on the old French ten-franc coins. straddling the 4th, 11th and 12th arrondissements, Place de la Bastille rests on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1439496567&quot;&gt;ground that was once occupied by the Bastille&lt;/a&gt;, an early fortification built during the Hundred Years War under Charles V that later served as a political prison and ultimately the scene for the defining event of the French Revolution--the storming of the Bastille on July 14, 1789. By 1790, the area was turned into a square commemorating liberty and a construction of a column was planned. Although an initial stone was laid, construction never progressed and was replaced by a fountain in 1793. In 1808, Napoléon planned a 24-meter high elephant-shaped monument to be cast form the bronze of cannons taken from the Spanish, of which only a full scale plaster model was ever completed. In 1833, Louis-Philippe decided to build a column as originally planned." id="1440356780" latitude="48.853166" license="3" longitude="2.368959" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="france europe colonnedejuillet sculpture geniusofliberty legéniedelaliberté legeniedelaliberte bastille julycolumn paris" title="Paris - The Marais: Place de Bastille - Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1031/1440356780_05f48a379d_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="874" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-09 04:18:36" description="La Colonne de Juillet (The July Column), a monument to the Revolution of 1830 in the center of Place de la Bastille, was inaugurated in 1840. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1440356780&quot;&gt;147-meter tall column&lt;/a&gt; rests on a white marble base ornamented with brass bas-reliefs and is engraved in gold with the names of Parisians who died during the Revolution--many of whom are interred beneath. Over the Corinthian capital is a 5-meter wide gallery, surmounted by a gilt globe and the colossal gold figure, &lt;i&gt;le Génie de la Liberté&lt;/i&gt;(The Spirit of Freedom), which appeared on the old French ten-franc coins. straddling the 4th, 11th and 12th arrondissements, Place de la Bastille rests on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/1439496567&quot;&gt;ground that was once occupied by the Bastille&lt;/a&gt;, an early fortification built during the Hundred Years War under Charles V that later served as a political prison and ultimately the scene for the defining event of the French Revolution--the storming of the Bastille on July 14, 1789. By 1790, the area was turned into a square commemorating liberty and a construction of a column was planned. Although an initial stone was laid, construction never progressed and was replaced by a fountain in 1793. In 1808, Napoléon planned a 24-meter high elephant-shaped monument to be cast form the bronze of cannons taken from the Spanish, of which only a full scale plaster model was ever completed. In 1833, Louis-Philippe decided to build a column as originally planned." id="1440357104" latitude="48.853166" license="3" longitude="2.368959" nbComments="1" rank="35" tags="france europe marais placedebastille colonnedejuillet sculpture geniusofliberty géniedelaliberté geniedelaliberte bastille julycolumn paris" title="Paris - The Marais: Place de Bastille - Colonne de Juillet - Le Génie de la Liberté" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1127/1440357104_43c19e0b2c_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1244" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-05 19:31:27" description="Standing in the center of Place de la Bastille, close to where we stayed." id="2298384639" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="paris france europe vacation julycolumn placedelabastille" title="July Column at night" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3145/2298384639_014584534b_b.jpg" username="midnightglory" views="34" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-06 11:38:35" description="" id="2298387263" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="paris france europe vacation julycolumn placedelabastille" title="July Column by day" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3194/2298387263_b98c968ee5_b.jpg" username="midnightglory" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-16 20:58:57" description="Featured here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://library.stmarys-ca.edu/subjects/history/europe/restoration/index.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;European History - Enlightenment and restoration &lt;/a&gt;" id="2706353948" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="julycolumn placedelabastille bastille europe france frenchrevolution holiday paris people silhouette tourist" title="July Column at Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3146/2706353948_4fab0f9a04_b.jpg" username="ZeHawk" views="92" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-04-10 03:48:06" description="" id="5854308505" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="bastille camera julycolumn litter orangepeel orangepeels paris parismarathon tvcrane" title="July Column surrounded by thousands of orange peels from marathon runners" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3119/5854308505_99ca4ddf65_b.jpg" username="waitscm" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-22 10:13:39" description="Thanks croche for pointing out that the name of this statue is July Column." id="4844667558" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="40" tags="paris france statue" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4129/4844667558_b438c8988a_b.jpg" username="Arjan Eising" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-21 13:12:52" description="Place de la Bastille &amp;amp; Colonne de Juillet (July Column) A square in Paris, where the Bastille prison stood until the 'Storming of the Bastille' and its subsequent physical destruction between 14 July 1789 and 14 July 1790 during the French Revolution; no vestige of it remains. The square straddles 3 arrondissements of Paris, namely the 4th, 11th and 12th. The square and its surrounding areas are normally called simply Bastille. The July Column (Colonne de Juillet) which commemorates the events of the July Revolution (1830) stands at the center of the square. -http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Bastille Paris Day 2 August 21, 2009" id="3996831533" latitude="48.853589" license="2" longitude="2.368763" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="photo paris placedelabastille colonnedejuillet julycolumn monument bastille" title="DSC02596" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2445/3996831533_878902ecb7_b.jpg" username="BethanyWeeks" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-21 18:45:00" description="'Génie de la Liberté' atop the July Column, Place de la Bastille, Paris, France (2010/193)" id="4921369668" latitude="48.854162" license="3" longitude="2.36912" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="monument julycolumn colonnedejuillet géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom placedelabastille dumont mercury" title="Place de la Bastille, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4093/4921369668_c4289236b1_b.jpg" username="GothPhil" views="121" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 12:24:29" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8208613768" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8198/8208613768_5e03f0f42a_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 12:22:18" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8208613054" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8477/8208613054_495165affc_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="0" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 12:24:18" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8207522459" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8487/8207522459_c868262f70_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="0" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 11:20:36" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8208609344" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="46" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8067/8208609344_297b64744d_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 12:24:24" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8207522657" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8477/8207522657_50edabbf60_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 12:22:10" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8208612818" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8477/8208612818_8536983741_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 12:22:26" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8207522287" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8065/8207522287_649f079395_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-01 16:39:38" description="The July column at the centre of the &lt;i&gt;Place de la Bastille&lt;/i&gt; celebrates the 3 glorious days of the July uprising in 1830 - just 40 years after the revolution it succeeded in getting rid of Charles X. Read all about it &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/July_Revolution&quot;&gt; here &lt;/a&gt;. Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Genie_de_la_bastille2.jpg&quot;&gt;zoom&lt;/a&gt; on that stunning gold statue, the &lt;i&gt;Génie de la Liberté&lt;/i&gt; - seen against the autumn colours in the parc by the &lt;i&gt;Bassin de l'Arsenal&lt;/i&gt;" id="297525030" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="10" rank="50" tags="julycolumn autumn bastille paris france" title="Colonne de juillet au mois de novembre" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/105/297525030_e13d1430a7_b.jpg" username="Max xx" views="285" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 12:18:55" description="The July Column. This column is found in the Place de la Bastille. Although, in 1792, a commemorative column had been planned to mark the fall of the Bastille, the finances of the First Empire were never able to fund it. It took a further 40 years before a column was erected, this time to mark the Revolution of 1830, or the July Revolution, (when the Bourbon King Charles X, was overthrown and replaced with his cousin Louis-Philippe, Duke of Orléans) and the 615 victims who died. The first stone was laid 1831, the column was completed 1840. The architect was Jean-Antoine Alavoine (1778-1834), following a commision from Louis-Philippe I (1773-1850). On top of the column is a gilded statue, Génie de la Liberté (&amp;quot;Spirit of Freedom&amp;quot;) by Auguste Dumont (1801-84)." id="8208612470" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="200912 paris colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille fallofthebastille revolutionof1830 julyrevolution jeanantoinealavoine louisphilippei gildedstatue géniedelaliberté spiritoffreedom augustedumont bourbonking charles xlouisphilippeduke orléans" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8488/8208612470_fddb306680_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-31 17:27:19" description="To the left is the opera bastille, which apparently is called the hippopotamus by locals." id="1809734179" latitude="48.853195" license="1" longitude="2.369184" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="autumn paris sunset bastille julycolumn opera" title="july monument, bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2141/1809734179_1aea7fcec9_b.jpg" username="jerseysam" views="50" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-09 11:53:57" description="This stands in the center of Place de la Bastille as a monument to the Revolution of 1830. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/July_Column&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/July_Column&lt;/a&gt;" id="3750805331" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="paris france marais placedelabastille julycolumn" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2540/3750805331_77ce4024ff_b.jpg" username="HeyRocker" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-10 13:17:47" description="La colonne de Juillet. July Column. La Columna de Julio." id="3989993471" latitude="48.852898" license="1" longitude="2.369624" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="paris parís francia france bastille bastilla colonne column columna july juillet julio" title="Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2619/3989993471_c320b8eb59_b.jpg" username="SamwiseGamgee69" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-10 11:02:15" description="La colonne de Juillet. July Column. La Columna de Julio." id="3989987433" latitude="48.852898" license="1" longitude="2.369624" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="paris parís francia france bastille bastilla colonne column columna july juillet julio" title="Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2520/3989987433_ea00b82060_b.jpg" username="SamwiseGamgee69" views="56" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-16 00:00:13" description="" id="5986760429" latitude="48.85847" license="4" longitude="2.294499" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="france seminarineurope baldwinwallace bw paris july column seminar europe sie baldwinwallacecollege bwc baldwinwallaceuniversity bwu baldwin wallace university" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6026/5986760429_fe82d86d91_b.jpg" username="Erik Daniel Drost" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-16 00:00:14" description="" id="5987319622" latitude="48.85847" license="4" longitude="2.294499" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="france july column seminarineurope baldwinwallace bw paris seminar europe sie baldwinwallacecollege bwc baldwinwallaceuniversity bwu baldwin wallace university" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6150/5987319622_aac25a9a5f_b.jpg" username="Erik Daniel Drost" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-08 03:39:18" description="We got a Velib' pass, and rode our bikes around until we found something interesting, like this column." id="6624118501" latitude="48.8527" license="5" longitude="2.369484" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="julycolumn paris france" title="IMG_2300" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7031/6624118501_1035985fd6_b.jpg" username="jpkotta" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-10-02 17:10:50" description="This monument stands in the center of the Place de la Bastille, which is the former site of the infamous Bastille prison." id="3068059288" latitude="48.853223" license="6" longitude="2.369098" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="paris france europe" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3011/3068059288_00bbb2ef34_b.jpg" username="rowens27" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-03 06:11:40" description="" id="8072823020" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="paris canon7d andydreads andypersing" title="July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8178/8072823020_9b3ded6156_b.jpg" username="Andydreads" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-27 23:11:27" description="July 2009" id="3888749148" latitude="48.853124" license="1" longitude="2.369163" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="france paris bastille placedelabastille colonnedejuillet julycolumn" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3514/3888749148_c3ea4bb7fa_b.jpg" username="Alex Cameron" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-26 21:32:43" description="" id="5114423898" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="paris bastille" title="July Column - Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1194/5114423898_bd28bdce13_b.jpg" username="Dave Pinter" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-27 23:15:20" description="July 2009" id="3888749566" latitude="48.853124" license="1" longitude="2.369163" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="france paris bastille placedelabastille colonnedejuillet julycolumn utilitypole" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2606/3888749566_f1d6527a73_b.jpg" username="Alex Cameron" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-07-12 13:37:45" description="" id="2667628087" latitude="48.853336" license="4" longitude="2.368927" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="paris summer2008" title="July Column, Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3097/2667628087_2a6ea0a2e6_b.jpg" username="Brett Hammond" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-06 11:04:39" description="Place de la Bastille, Paris" id="6167574397" latitude="48.852997" license="3" longitude="2.368927" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="placedelabastille gray cloudy gold paris france julycolumn" title="Storming of the Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6151/6167574397_4507370a56_b.jpg" username="N1D0" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-06 17:58:58" description="La colonne de Juillet. July Column. La Columna de Julio." id="3906985830" latitude="48.853512" license="1" longitude="2.369667" nbComments="5" rank="66" tags="paris parís francia france bastille colonne juillet july column columna julio bastilla" title="Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3478/3906985830_15699c9ac7_b.jpg" username="SamwiseGamgee69" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-06 18:01:08" description="La colonne de Juillet. July Column. La Columna de Julio." id="3906212953" latitude="48.853682" license="1" longitude="2.368894" nbComments="2" rank="67" tags="paris parís francia france bastille colonne juillet july column columna julio bastilla" title="Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3449/3906212953_4dbe63eedb_b.jpg" username="SamwiseGamgee69" views="89" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-11-17 09:57:28" description="Place de la Bastille Paris, France Wednesday, November 17, 2004" id="1834780689" latitude="48.852993" license="5" longitude="2.369779" nbComments="2" rank="68" tags="colonnedejuillet julycolumn revolutionof1830 column géniedelaliberté thespiritoffreedom paris france cars night monument" title="Colonne de Juillet (July Column)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2369/1834780689_4308568084_b.jpg" username="bredgur" views="131" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-10-26 14:50:30" description="In the Place Bastille in Paris, this statue stands at the top of a column commemorating the citizens of France who took up arms to finally rid themselves of a hereditary monarchy. Despite accepting its reinstatement a few years before, the king was creating unjust, self-serving laws without accountability and the citizens mounted &amp;quot;Occupy Paris&amp;quot; to end the problem. Hundreds died in the defence of liberty and the defeat of the unaccountable. Which is why I find it deeply ironic to find surveillance cameras on the column." id="6285860990" latitude="48.853103" license="1" longitude="2.368762" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="raw paris france bastille statue july column monument surveillance camera" title="Liberty and Vigilance" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6043/6285860990_20e5fda705_b.jpg" username="webmink" views="194" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-15 11:03:39" description="" id="2127888888" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="70" tags="etg cambridge theatre europeantheatregroup tour paris bastille julycolumn colonnedejuillet" title="July Column and Lights" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2290/2127888888_2398085776_b.jpg" username="NickStenning" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-26 21:33:52" description="" id="5114428830" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="71" tags="paris bastille" title="Buildings Adjacent to the July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4130/5114428830_f5ec1c8c33_b.jpg" username="Dave Pinter" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-01 00:00:00" description="" id="5114347034" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="72" tags="paris bastille" title="Buildings Adjacent to the July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1103/5114347034_0291e69b5c_b.jpg" username="Dave Pinter" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-01 00:00:00" description="" id="5114359216" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="73" tags="paris bastille" title="Buildings Adjacent to the July Column" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1128/5114359216_5eaa4ccc6a_b.jpg" username="Dave Pinter" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-03-22 11:28:48" description="" id="2363380231" latitude="48.853293" license="1" longitude="2.368905" nbComments="0" rank="74" tags="place de la bastille paris july column france" title="Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3140/2363380231_8140f72263_b.jpg" username="Jonathan Ziapour" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-11-21 09:50:52" description="" id="8271856516" latitude="48.852785" license="2" longitude="2.368808" nbComments="0" rank="75" tags="france paris eurotrip placedelabastille place bastille july column julycolumn gold statue bronze" title="Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8077/8271856516_352d53214e_b.jpg" username="Scott SM" views="18" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-09-12 14:09:04" description="" id="395818010" latitude="48.85246" license="2" longitude="2.369645" nbComments="0" rank="76" tags="colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille bastille dusk paris france theparadigmshifter" title="colonne de juillet at dusk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/138/395818010_d2dabe1ddc_b.jpg" username="theparadigmshifter" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-17 16:05:42" description="lots and lots of people" id="6273229679" latitude="48.853067" license="1" longitude="2.369098" nbComments="0" rank="77" tags="europe france paris technoparade colonnedejuillet julycolumn placedelabastille" title="Techno parade" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6050/6273229679_edeaa698ae_b.jpg" username="1yen" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-17 16:04:40" description="Techno parade" id="6273749786" latitude="48.853138" license="1" longitude="2.368969" nbComments="0" rank="78" tags="europe france paris technoparade placedelabastille colonnedejuillet julycolumn" title="Party on the Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6042/6273749786_d28f0691f9_b.jpg" username="1yen" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-10-21 12:40:29" description="The one and only July Column in the Place de la Bastille. According to Wikipedia: &lt;i&gt; The July Column (French: Colonne de Juillet) is a monument to the Revolution of 1830. It stands in the center of the Place de la Bastille, in Paris, to commemorate the Trois Glorieuses, the &amp;quot;three glorious&amp;quot; days in July 1830 that saw the fall of Charles X of France and the commencement of the &amp;quot;July Monarchy&amp;quot; of Louis-Philippe.&lt;/i&gt;" id="5127163520" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="79" tags="paris bastille colonne juillet" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4025/5127163520_9112cd301b_b.jpg" username="livatlantis" views="48" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-04 15:39:00" description="colonne de juillet - july column in the place de la bastille, which stands in the 4th, 11th, and 12th arrondissements." id="389165158" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="80" tags="paris" title="france 027" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/128/389165158_16a1647c7b_b.jpg" username="wickey29" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-06-27 15:56:05" description="July Column in Place de la Batille" id="5243104875" latitude="48.853082" license="1" longitude="2.369227" nbComments="0" rank="81" tags="paris parigi france francia place bastille piazza bastiglia revolution rivoluzione" title="Vive la Révolution!" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5161/5243104875_4601c97903_b.jpg" username="Carlo Rainone" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-01-23 13:54:26" description="Dark, menacing clouds surround the &lt;i&gt;Génie de la Liberté&lt;/i&gt; on top of Paris' July Column (&lt;i&gt;Colonne de Juillet&lt;/i&gt;) at Bastille. You can read more about the history of this famous Parisian landmark on &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/July_Column&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;." id="3631847965" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="82" tags="bastille clouds colonnedejuillet flickr paris storm brefoto" title="Dark skies..." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2462/3631847965_b464d3953e_b.jpg" username="Breff" views="68" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-03 10:43:36" description="Column in Place Vendôme was erected by Napoleon to commemorate the battle of Austerlitz. Paris, France. Photographed on 3 July 2010." id="4862382330" latitude="48.8675" license="1" longitude="2.3294" nbComments="0" rank="83" tags="column napoleon battleofausterlitz placevendôme paris france geocode:accuracy=200meters geocode:method=googleearth geo:country=france" title="Place Vendôme, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4119/4862382330_323f715257_b.jpg" username="Arthur Chapman" views="66" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-23 16:40:22" description="In June 16, 1792, it was decided the area occupied by the Bastille should be turned into a square celebrating liberty, and that a column would be erected there. The first stone was laid by Palloy, however construction did not commence. A fountain was built in 1793. In 1808, as part of several urban improvement projects for Paris, Napoléon planned to have a monument in the shape of an elephant built here. It was designed to be 24 m (78 ft) in height, and to be cast from the bronze of cannons taken from the spanish. Access to the top was to be achieved by a stairway set in one of the legs. However, only a full scale plaster model was built. Victor Hugo immortalized the monument in the novel Les Misérables where it is used as a shelter by Gavroche. The monument was demolished in 1846. In 1833, Louis-Philippe decided to build the July Column as originally planned in 1792. It was inaugurated in 1840" id="265260596" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="84" tags="karmor paris france mercy" title="Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/119/265260596_a6595a6f29_b.jpg" username="Karmor" views="39" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-05-15 11:48:02" description="rue St-Antoine with the July Column of the Bastille in the distance" id="4657530664" latitude="48.848337" license="2" longitude="2.347126" nbComments="0" rank="85" tags="paris france" title="DSCN1792" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4024/4657530664_10950596c8_b.jpg" username="TomFlemming" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-05 15:03:42" description="Or July Column in English. Place de la Bastille" id="2818053411" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="86" tags="paris placedelabastille colonnedejuillet france" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3227/2818053411_a3b6278f44_b.jpg" username="enric archivell" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-11 14:54:09" description="The “Spirit of Freedom” July Column. Le “Génie de la Liberté”, Colonne de Juillet, Place de la Bastille – Paris" id="4424536831" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="87" tags="paris 500d canon génie bastille or blue bleue" title="Génie de la liberté" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4032/4424536831_d54c1d6429_b.jpg" username="r.Lou²" views="69" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-07-12 21:40:17" description="The Colonne de Juillet is located in the middle of the square and is surrounded by a rather busy roundabout. The column dates back to July 28, 1840, and was build in order of King Louis-Philippe (1773 – 1850) who wanted a monument to commemorate both the French revolution of 1789 (also known as the storming of the Bastille) and the &amp;quot;three glorious days&amp;quot; of the July revolt in 1830. The column is located roughly where the medieval Porte Sainte-Antoine once stood." id="898595213" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="88" tags="france paris july2007 statue bastille juillet frs monument" title="Paris_Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1071/898595213_39aac3f2ce_b.jpg" username="ktylerconk" views="204" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-18 15:30:06" description="" id="3805047314" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="89" tags="paris france lesinvalides invalides column columns" title="Les Invalides,  Paris, July 18, 2009" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3519/3805047314_9a9f205d2a_b.jpg" username="Mark Iverson" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-09-30 07:52:39" description="" id="279979942" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="90" tags="paris france placedelabastille julyrevolution memorial column" title="Memorial of the 1830 July Revolution, Place de la Bastille, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/120/279979942_06a7d93556_b.jpg" username="graham chandler" views="48" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-04-24 11:20:43" description="The Place de la Bastille is a square in Paris, where the Bastille prison stood until the 'Storming of the Bastille' and its subsequent physical destruction between 14 July 1789 and 14 July 1790 during the French Revolution; no vestige of it remains. The square straddles 3 arrondissements of Paris, namely the 4th, 11th and 12th. The square and its surrounding areas are normally called simply Bastille. The July Column (Colonne de Juillet) which commemorates the events of the July Revolution (1830) stands at the center of the square. Source: Wikipedia." id="5710805374" latitude="48.853207" license="3" longitude="2.369055" nbComments="0" rank="91" tags="4eme 11eme 12eme 75004 75011 75012 arrondissement place de la bastille french revolution colonne juillet" title="Colonne de Juillet, Place de la Bastille - Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2672/5710805374_b117d23772_b.jpg" username="Juan_Carlos_Cruz" views="188" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-07-04 20:23:05" description="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Bastille&quot;&gt;Place de la Bastille&lt;/a&gt; is the location of the old &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bastille&quot;&gt;Bastille&lt;/a&gt; fortress that was captured on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bastille_Day&quot;&gt;14th of July&lt;/a&gt; 1789, marking the beginning of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_Revolution&quot;&gt;French Revolution&lt;/a&gt;. The fortress was subsequently destroyed, and part of the materials where used to build the Pont de la Concorde.  The column seen in the picture is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/July_Column&quot;&gt;Colonne de Juillet&lt;/a&gt;, a memorial to the parisian that died in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revolution_of_1830&quot;&gt;July Revolution&lt;/a&gt; of 1830 against &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_X_of_France&quot;&gt;Charles X&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, another revolution." id="215603420" latitude="48.853223" license="1" longitude="2.368884" nbComments="5" rank="92" tags="voyage travel trip france paris statue statues sculpture colonne column bastille placedelabastille colonnedejuillet jourdelabastille bastilleday" title="Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/89/215603420_91818335ac_b.jpg" username="Djof" views="1253" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-02-01 00:12:47" description="Opéra Bastille from 1989, the column commemorating the July Revolution in 1830 and another &amp;quot;Colonne Morris&amp;quot;." id="111450177" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="93" tags="night paris bastille colonnemorris monument architecture france" title="Place de la Bastille" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/38/111450177_06cbcde6b7_b.jpg" username="cicilief" views="69" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-25 15:40:12" description="This statue is in the Place de la Bastille, where the Bastille prison stood. The column, though, is to commemorate the July Revolution." id="622698028" latitude="48.860762" license="3" longitude="2.337684" nbComments="0" rank="94" tags="colonnedejuillet paris" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1189/622698028_a30ffc4102_b.jpg" username="tmivy" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-09 10:56:18" description="" id="876854225" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="95" tags="paris france bastille column julycolumn colonnedejuillet" title="IMG_6528" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1410/876854225_175986279c_b.jpg" username="kenner116" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-23 20:22:32" description="In 1806 Napoleon made his decision to erect a memorial, a Temple de la Gloire de la Grande Armée (&amp;quot;Temple to the Glory of the Great Army&amp;quot;); following an elaborate competition with numerous entries and a jury that decided on a design by Beaumont, the Emperor trumped all, instead commissioning Pierre-Alexandre Barthélémy Vignon (1763-1828) to build his design on an antique temple (Compare the Maison Carrée, Nîmes, illustration left.) The then-existing foundations were razed, preserving the standing columns, and work begun anew. With completion of the Arc de Triomphe in 1808, the original commemorative role for the temple was blunted. After the fall of Napoleon, with the Catholic reaction during the Restoration, King Louis XVIII determined that the structure would be used as a church, dedicated to Mary Magdalene. Vignon died in 1828 before completing the project and was replaced by Jacques-Marie Huvé. A new competition was set up in 1828-29, to determine the design for sculptures for the pediment, a Last Judgment, in which Mary Magdalene knelt to intercede for the Damned; the winner was Charles Lemaire. The July Monarchy rededicated the monument of repentance for Revolution as a monument of national reconciliation, and the nave was vaulted in 1831. In 1837 it was briefly suggested that the building might best be utilized as a train station, but the building was finally consecrated as a church in 1842. From the english wikipedia &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%c3%89glise_de_la_Madeleine#History&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;." id="3750591966" latitude="48.87065" license="5" longitude="2.324938" nbComments="0" rank="96" tags="madeleine paris france παρίσι γαλλία μαγδαληνή" title="Église de la Madeleine" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2660/3750591966_34bee8a40e_b.jpg" username="Giorgos Michalogiorgakis" views="331" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-26 21:21:10" description="The July column is a column erected on the Place de la Bastille in Paris. &amp;quot;To the glory of French citizens who armed themselves and fought for civil liberties in the memorable days of 27, 28, 29 July 1830.&amp;quot; The shaft of the column has the names of victims of the revolutionary days of 1830 and the top is decorated with a gilt bronze sculpture ofAuguste Dumont : the Genius of Liberty." id="4831857552" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="97" tags="placedelabastille" title="Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4092/4831857552_574064ab56_b.jpg" username="tarabrown" views="23" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-12 18:37:08" description="The July column in the Place de la Bastille The Place de la Bastille is a square in Paris, where the Bastille prison stood until the 'Storming of the Bastille' and its subsequent physical destruction between 14 July 1789 and 14 July 1790 during the French Revolution; no vestige of it remains. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Bastille&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Bastille&lt;/a&gt;" id="8058477282" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="98" tags="" title="DSC_0015" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8042/8058477282_49c7f19ea9_b.jpg" username="aaalcant" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:15:59" description="The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8208667710" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="99" tags="200912 paris luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="Detail of the Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8068/8208667710_9ac61fd89f_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:15:00" description="The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8207576423" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="100" tags="200912 paris luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8210/8207576423_995811cba5_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:14:34" description="The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8208667190" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="101" tags="200912 paris luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="Detail of the Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8345/8208667190_cfbce4a567_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:15:54" description="The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8207576553" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="102" tags="200912 paris luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8058/8207576553_64a1eda35e_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:14:23" description="The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8208666946" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="103" tags="200912 paris luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8205/8208666946_57b5f1ccb7_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:10:55" description="Obelisk of Luxor and the Eiffel Tower. The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8207575383" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="104" tags="200912 paris eiffeltower luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="Obelisk and Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8338/8207575383_baf5fcea04_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:08:00" description="The Obelisk of Luxor and the Eiffel Tower, almost dwarfed by a lamp post. The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8207574597" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="105" tags="200912 paris eiffeltower luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="All Three in Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8200/8207574597_c3b706e22c_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-20 22:08:06" description="The Obelisk of Luxor and the Eiffel Tower, almost dwarfed by a lamp post. The Luxor Obelisk is one of a pair that once stood by the entrance to Luxor Temple; it was gifted to France by the Ottoman Viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, in 1829. The Obelisk arrived in France in 1833, and was erected in the Place de la Concorde in 1836, on the instructions of on the instructions of Louis Philippe I (1773-1850), it was placed where the guillotine had been there. The obelisk is a red granite column, 23m tall (75 ft), and weighs over 250 tonnes. Place de la Concorde was designed in 1755 by Ange-Jacques Gabriel as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées and the Tuileries Gardens. The Place was originally called Place Louis XV, but renamed Place de la Révolution during the French Revolution, with a guillotine erected here (where the Luxor Obelisk now is). The name changed once again to Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795-99), renamed to Place Louis XV under the Bourbon restoration, and then to Place Louis XVI in 1826. Following the July Revolution of 1830, there was another renaming, bringing it back to Place de la Concorde." id="8208665582" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="106" tags="200912 paris eiffeltower luxorobelisk luxortemple ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali placedelaconcorde louisphilippei angejacquesgabriel placelouisxv placedelarévolution placelouisxvi julyrevolution champsélysées" title="All Three in Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8484/8208665582_bce8e843ed_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-16 11:27:25" description="Place de la Bastille" id="3858028753" latitude="48.85318" license="3" longitude="2.369066" nbComments="1" rank="107" tags="paris frança francia france europe europa viatge travel viaje carrer calle street rue place plaça plaza square bastilla bastille columna column colonne juillet julio july" title="La Colonne de Juillet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2641/3858028753_18b737c832_b.jpg" username="Baptiste Pons" views="129" />
</photos>
