<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Little Ben London">

<photo  date_taken="2010-06-26 21:16:24" description="Little Ben. É sério, é esse o nome do relógio, mesmo! &lt;i&gt;Little Ben is a cast iron miniature clock tower, situated at the intersection of Vauxhall Bridge Road and Victoria Street, in Westminster, central London, close to the approach to Victoria station. In design it mimics the famous clock tower known as Big Ben at the Palace of Westminster, found at the other end of Victoria Street. Little Ben was manufactured, according to Pevsner, by Gillett &amp;amp; Johnston of Croydon, and was erected in 1892; removed from the site in 1964, and restored and re-erected in 1981 by Westminster City Council with sponsorship from Elf Aquitaine Ltd &amp;quot;offered as a gesture of Franco-British friendship&amp;quot;. There is a rhyming couplet Apology for Summer Time signed J.W.R. affixed to the body of the clock: My hands you may retard or may advance my heart beats true for England as for France. &lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;" id="5052286810" latitude="51.496455" license="3" longitude="-0.142631" nbComments="1" rank="1" tags="londres london england inglaterra summer verão 2010 rua street little ben relógio clock" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4107/5052286810_c244d84b3a_b.jpg" username="Marcio Cabral de Moura" views="126" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-11 07:54:30" description="Little Ben is a cast iron miniature clock tower, situated at the intersection of Vauxhall Bridge Road and Victoria Street, near the approach to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/299046703/&quot;&gt;Victoria station&lt;/a&gt;. In design it mimics the clock tower commonly known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/299908721/&quot;&gt;Big Ben&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/299909312/&quot;&gt;Palace of Westminster&lt;/a&gt;. Little Ben was manufacturedby Gillett &amp;amp; Johnston of Croydon, and was erected in 1892; removed from the site in 1964, and restored and re-erected in 1981 by Westminster City Council with sponsorship from Elf Aquitaine Ltd &amp;quot;offered as a gesture of Franco-British friendship&amp;quot;. Little Ben is set one hour in advance of Greenwich Mean Time throughout the year. During the summer this coincides with British Summer Time, while in the winter this is the same as Central European Time. Although this means that the clock displays the local time for only half the year, it does demonstrate a preference for neither Britain nor Europe. This sentiment is captured in the rhyming couplet Apology for Summer Time signed J.W.R. affixed to the body of the clock: &lt;i&gt;My hands you may retard or may advance my heart beats true for England as for France&lt;/i&gt;" id="299044324" latitude="51.496434" license="3" longitude="-0.142709" nbComments="2" rank="2" tags="uk unitedkingdom britain greatbritain pimlico westminster littleben clock clocktower miniature victoria londonist london england europe 1155" title="UK - London - Pimlico: Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/101/299044324_2dcb1e3392_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1775" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-07 14:04:19" description="Little Ben was built by Gillett &amp;amp; Johnston of Croydon and erected in 1892; removed from the site in 1964, and restored and re-erected in 1981 by Westminster City Council with sponsorship from Elf Aquitaine Ltd &amp;quot;offered as a gesture of Franco-British friendship (from Wikipedia) &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&lt;/a&gt;" id="759931128" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="3" tags="littleben victoria pub clock westminster tourdefrance london weathervane 1892 1405" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1219/759931128_d9a45047f4_b.jpg" username="sarflondondunc" views="300" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-06 08:10:50" description="The is a mini-version of Big Ben clock tower, found near Victoria station, I don't think anyone knows what is it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&lt;/a&gt;" id="735596824" latitude="51.496474" license="1" longitude="-0.142757" nbComments="0" rank="4" tags="london britain england uk unitedkingdom greatbritain britishisles 2007 d50 nikon nikdond50 city capital travel littleben victoria" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1057/735596824_047728517b_b.jpg" username="Kol Tregaskes" views="165" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-26 12:12:58" description="Gps : N51 29.776 W0 08.580 Ok, I geotagged this by hand. You can now see this on the map Decimal Degrees (WGS84) LatitudeLongitude 51.496267-0.143 Degrees, Minutes &amp;amp; Seconds LatitudeLongitude N51 29 46W0 08 34 GPS LatitudeLongitude N 51 29.776W 0 08.580 UTM XY 30N6983105708885" id="279768711" latitude="51.496267" license="4" longitude="-0.143" nbComments="1" rank="5" tags="little ben london clock spy cammera geotagged geo:lat=51496267 geo:lon=0143" title="Little Ben - geotag test" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/95/279768711_d3602ad226_b.jpg" username="xJason.Rogersx" views="154" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-11 15:47:02" description="" id="3730492305" latitude="51.496483" license="2" longitude="-0.142687" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="cityofwestminster victoria london england uk unitedkingdom littleben" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3488/3730492305_cc2b4d24fb_b.jpg" username="-AX-" views="23" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-05 14:30:57" description="" id="3718014885" latitude="51.496308" license="2" longitude="-0.142789" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="cityofwestminster victoria london england uk unitedkingdom littleben" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2581/3718014885_6c52074ecc_b.jpg" username="-AX-" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-26 12:12:58" description="" id="279768712" latitude="51.496267" license="4" longitude="-0.143" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="little ben london clock spy cammera" title="P1010004" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/97/279768712_7b8af57076_b.jpg" username="xJason.Rogersx" views="46" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-30 16:54:03" description="" id="2836034903" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="9" tags="london stmartinsinthefields tower spire bluesky clock bigben ststephenstower inflatable bouncy" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3064/2836034903_7c41eb11e9_b.jpg" username="internets_dairy" views="18" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-06-13 19:01:59" description="" id="5829675399" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="8" rank="10" tags="london tourist parliamentsquare alexljacksontourismassignment" title="Big Ben, Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5150/5829675399_2d63d9422b_b.jpg" username="alexljackson" views="56" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-18 16:57:03" description="Last weekend I was doing another cross-town walk and I was thrilled to see another one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://einesigns.co.uk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ben Eine's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/search/?ss=2&amp;amp;w=50847591@N00&amp;amp;q=eine&amp;amp;m=text&quot;&gt;huge lettering&lt;/a&gt; murals going up on Valencia and 19th. I walked past the sellers of bits and bobs and up to the small crew that were rapidly finishing off the mural. At the top of a ladder was Ben Eine himself. &amp;quot;I take it that this is a new Eine mural?&amp;quot;, I ventured. &amp;quot;Yes it is.&amp;quot;, replied the noodly man at the top of the ladder, deftly filling in lines with his spray can. &amp;quot;So I'd also take it that you are Mr. Eine?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You are indeed correct, sir!&amp;quot;, replied Ben in a cheeky cockney accent. &amp;quot;Sweet. Mind if I follow you around for a bit and take some snaps?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Go ahead!&amp;quot;, Ben said as he climbed down from the ladder to work lower down. &amp;quot;Do you prefer if I don't take a picture of your face? I'm cool with that if that's what you'd like.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Nah, I'm past all that shit.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;So what brings you back to SF?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Fuckin' Olympics. I can't paint in London because they want to keep things neat and tidy until the games.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Wow yeah... fair enough, I guess?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I'm kidding. Sort of.&amp;quot; He laughs. &amp;quot;I love it here, I love coming to SF to paint.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Cool! And how do you sort out where you are going to put up the next mural? Do you get invited sort of thing?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;A lot of the time we'll go around and find walls, and work with the building owners to work something out.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;...and how do you decide what lettering you are going to put up?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Yeah sometimes we'll work with the owners to decide on the words, and sometimes they'll just let us put up whatever we fuckin' like. Its great.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Cool. Well, thanks - looking forward to seeing more of your work around SF!&amp;quot;" id="6165542291" latitude="37.76032" license="2" longitude="-122.421662" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="sf sanfrancisco california 2011 streetart mural word words lettering eine beneine einesign einesigns sfist itsalittlescary sunglasses muralist spraycan letter portrait art artist themission missiondistrict mission valenciastreet valencia valenciaand19th bhautikjoshi art:category=mural art:title=unknown art:artist=beneine art:description=none art:citycommission=no art:neighborhood=mission" title="Ben Eine and his new mural on Valencia" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6169/6165542291_20383969ca_b.jpg" username="bhautik joshi" views="513" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-16 21:54:26" description="Seeing as this was on the path of the little wander that I took, I couldn't resist taking it." id="363395005" latitude="51.501877" license="1" longitude="-0.120077" nbComments="0" rank="12" tags="westminster parliament bigbenlondon favcol fuji thames" title="Sterotypical tourist photo" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/130/363395005_44bd7d8dd7_b.jpg" username="swishphotos" views="46" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-03-25 06:45:06" description="Enlarge the photo to &amp;quot;All Sizes&amp;quot; for a more detailed view." id="122317586" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="13" tags="london aerialview" title="London England Aerial View 2" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/43/122317586_93dda2a6c6_b.jpg" username="Bobcatnorth" views="1434" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-16 11:29:14" description="" id="3794899663" latitude="51.500875" license="5" longitude="-0.126063" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="uk london england travel tourism july2009 709 eeyore eeyoresgloomyadventures travelingtoys littlefriendsaroundtheworld bigben westminsterpalace westminster whitehall traveling tour touris holiday britan british english unitedkingdom angleterre summer 2009 july united kingdom britian gloomy adventure donkey blue toy britain londres inghilterra anglaterra англия inglaterra lloegr" title="Eeyore visits Big Ben, Whitehall, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2611/3794899663_d941312b6f_b.jpg" username="nikoretro" views="77" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-15 18:46:30" description="The &amp;quot;Programme&amp;quot; for Steve Prefontaine's first race in London, a 5000 &amp;quot;Metres&amp;quot; race in which he came in 4th, White City Stadium, London, August 13, 1969. Pre's event is the page to the right, Frank Shorter and Kenny Moore ran the 10,000m on the page to the left--Kenny came in 2nd and Frank 4th. Marty Liquori was slated to enter the 1500m, but he was a no-show. The venerable White City Stadium served as the venue for the 1908 London Olympic Games. In 1931, a 440yd running track was installed for the Amateur Athletic Association Championships, held there from 1932 to 1970. The stadium was torn down for new development in 1985 after serving various uses, including greyhound racing, rugby and soccer league play, a motor speedway, the 1934 British Empire Games, and a match of the 1966 World Cup. This was the fourth international meet in Pre's first international tour the summer after he graduated from Marshfield High School. Because he was not yet enrolled in the University of Oregon, he ran this meet with the AAU's US Team as being from Coos Bay, Oregon, his home town. This was the first of Pre's three meets in London--the other two were at the Coca-Cola Meet on September 15, 1972, six days after he placed fourth in the 5000m of the Munich Olympics; and the Coca-Cola Meet on September 13, 1974, which was the only race he never completed, due to injury. This London meet was a two-day track and field meet, with the 5000m as the 9th event of the second day. The 5000m event page above from the program displays a photo of Washington State University Runner Gerry Lindgren, the featured US runner for this event--Pre was still little known outside Oregon, and especially not known in Europe. To see a brief clip of Pre in this race, go to the link below and go fullscreen with the video--Pre's race shows up about 44 seconds into the clip, first showing the two Brits, followed by Gerry Lindgren, then Pre. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.britishpathe.com/record.php?id=46140&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.britishpathe.com/record.php?id=46140&lt;/a&gt; Pre had graduated from high school in the spring of 1969 and qualified for the AAU's US Team by placing fourth in the AAU Championship 3-mile event on June 29th in Miami, Florida—the only high school runner in the race. He was picked up from the AAU Team alternates list and ran the 5000 meter events in Los Angeles (5th//US-USSR-Commonwealth meet), Stuttgart (3rd//US-Europe meet), Augsburg (2nd//US-W. Germany meet), and London (4th//US-Great Britain meet). His London race was his last before enrolling in the University of Oregon in the fall. While Pre had a spectacular high school racing history, he was not yet a headliner in the international or collegiate running community. The big news for the London 5000m race was the slated competition between US runners Gerry Lindgren, formerly of Washington State University, Tracy Smith, formerly of Oregon State University, and the British runners Ian Stewart and Dick Taylor. Pre had been slated for the US Team 3000m event but was added to the 5000m race instead when Tracy Smith decided not to enter (see Smith's name crossed out above and Pre listed as a &amp;quot;reserve&amp;quot; runner). Dick Taylor went on to win the race, setting the fastest time of the year in the 5000m in 13:29.0 and a new British record: Finishing times--there were only four runners competing: 1. Dick Taylor (Britain) 13:29.0 2. Ian Stewart (Britain) 13:36.4 3. Gerry Lindgren (So. Lake Tahoe) 14:16.8 4. Pre (Coos Bay, OR) 14:38.4 Oregon athletes gained points with Neal Steinhauser winning the shot put in 64-3, and Kenny Moore placing second with 29:08.8 in the 10,000m behind the UK's Ron Hill and his 29:03.8. Frank Shorter placed 4th in the same event in 29:16.4. US athletes also won other events: the women's 100 meters by Iris Davis of Nashville, the Women's 400 meters by Kathy Hammond of Sacramento, the men's 200 meters by Ben Vaughn of Atlanta, the discus throw by Tim Volmer of Oregon State, and the high jump by Otis Burrell of Los Angeles. The US men won the meet 131-90, the women's title went to Britain 67-66. Pre wore an AAU team singlet--Pre's combat against AAU treatment of athletes was to be a signature part of his running career in the future. This European tour would be his baptism. Most members of the US track team returned to the US carrying a letter of protest to President Nixon after a European tour full of dissension and some disappointment. The trouble blew up in Germany where the athletes complained of poor accommodations. When the US athletes arrived in London they formed a committee which drew up the letter to Nixon, listing what they considered are essential changes which should be made in AAU policy. At one stage the athletes threatened to pull out of the London meet. They cabled a copy of the letter to the White House. The info above was derived from the August 13 &amp;amp; 14, 1969 issues of the Eugene Register-Guard." id="6047202175" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="pre steve prefontaine aau coosbay or oregon london uk britain international meet whitecity stadium 5000m 5000 m meter event race 4th fourth aug august 13 1969 european tour gerrylindgren dicktaylor ianstewart tracysmith protest letter whitehouse president nixon amateurathleticunion program programme metre thehappyrower happy rower" title="The &quot;Programme&quot; for Steve Prefontaine's first race in London, during his first international track meet tour,  a 5000 &quot;Metres&quot; race in which he came in 4th, White City Stadium, London, August 13, 1969" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6198/6047202175_6c40ce2059_b.jpg" username="The Happy Rower" views="950" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-02-24 15:19:54" description="Alright, I know it is the Westminster Palace Clock Tower. And a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-15243118&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;lean&lt;/a&gt; of 0.26 degrees officially. Seemed a little more than that to me on the day we went past..." id="6235924390" latitude="51.500716" license="6" longitude="-0.12391" nbComments="4" rank="16" tags="bigben westminsterpalaceclocktower leaning fisheye 8mm bustour london" title="Big Ben is leaning" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6111/6235924390_cbbb78372e_b.jpg" username="Rum Bucolic Ape" views="160" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-31 11:59:53" description="in his &amp;quot;couples for christ&amp;quot; shirt." id="237182093" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="honeymoon london joe thames bigben" title="parliament, ben, joe" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/96/237182093_f6a3b3c1c7_b.jpg" username="cuttlefish" views="58" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-07-14 15:47:32" description="I was surprised when walking around London to see this sticker on a bus stop. This is in Westmister near to Big Ben. Should have shot this from a little angle to make it more interesting. 20080714-london_0251" id="2678035641" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="london westminster impeachment georgewbush" title="Bush impeachment sticker on London bus stop" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3057/2678035641_299dd04f94_b.jpg" username="ryantxr" views="176" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-11-26 12:51:03" description="Big Ben and a little tweeder" id="6410533367" latitude="51.500461" license="2" longitude="-0.126857" nbComments="2" rank="19" tags="bicycles cycling events fashion grouprides london rugbytweedrunlondon2011 tweedride vintage wool londonist bigben bespokebicycle" title="RL Rugby London Tweed Run" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7011/6410533367_41f24da8bb_b.jpg" username="M.J.S." views="288" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-14 11:44:37" description="England swings like a pendulum do Bobbies on bicycles, two by two Westminster Abbey, &lt;b&gt;the tower of Big Ben&lt;/b&gt; The rosy red cheeks of the little children. (England Swings - Roger Miller) If you don't know the song , look it up on youtube! ;-) &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/flickr/onblack.php?id=1750312372&amp;amp;size=large&quot;&gt;View On Black&lt;/a&gt; Look at my stream in black on the really cool site &lt;a target=&quot;NEW&quot; href=&quot;http://www.darckr.com/username?username=neilalderney123&quot;&gt; DARCKR &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://loc.alize.us/#/flickr:1750312372&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="1750312372" latitude="51.500869" license="2" longitude="-0.124551" nbComments="7" rank="20" tags="london england bigben geo:lat=51500869 geo:lon=0124551 geotagged diamondclassphotographer" title="Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2028/1750312372_362c2e9acb_b.jpg" username="neilalderney123" views="1627" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-10 13:46:16" description="Halfway through the PhotoWalk in London, we stopped here at Big Ben to get a shot. It’s a little tough for me sometimes to do this while on a PhotoWalk because I can’t fully focus on the photography. I have to talk, explain, converse, answer questions, and the like. Don’t get me wrong… I love all that stuff. But I do find it hard to fully focus on the photography side of the evening! from the blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stuckincustoms.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.stuckincustoms.com&lt;/a&gt;" id="5677835994" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="59" rank="21" tags="england london stuckincustoms treyratcliff uk stuck customs stuckincustomscom travel blog travelblog photography photoblog photographyblog hdr high dynamic range imaging digital processing software tutorial hdrtutorial trey ratcliff world europe unitedkingdom greatbritain great britain island continental empire capital metropolitan city urban westminster palace bigben clock bell tower clocktower belltower chiming neogothic architecture icon history historic dusk speed traffic streaks blur cars green light sundown street september 2010 nikond3x" title="Big Ben at Dusk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5229/5677835994_7dce67423d_b.jpg" username="Stuck in Customs" views="4920" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-12-08 23:12:28" description="" id="8255277667" latitude="34.80598" license="4" longitude="-92.291228" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="instagramapp square squareformat iphoneography uploaded:by=instagram xproii foursquare:venue=4cd5971caeb1224b047023ff lucero ice diner starltediner littlerock arkansas" title="Ice. I now see what Ben Nichols was ranting about in London." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8224/8255277667_f9031db7b4_b.jpg" username="matt-lucht" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-16 13:01:13" description="NIGHTINGALES Born out of Birmingham's original punk group The Prefects, the Nightingales have stubbornly ploughed their own furrow in the field of alternative rock n roll for three decades. Described in John Robb's definitive post punk biography 'Death To Trad Rock' as &amp;quot;the misfits' misfits&amp;quot;, the band has constantly garnered praise and respect from other artists and received endless glowing press reports, particularly for their live shows. Led by singer/lyricist Robert Lloyd ('The most underestimated songwriter of his generation' according to Ben Thompson in the Independent) the latest incarnation of the Nightingales - the best batch - yet release their new album &amp;quot;No Love Lost&amp;quot; on Cooking Vinyl in April 2012. To coincide with the album's release the Nightingales will be touring the UK and mainland Europe. The UK shows follow their May 2011 tour which culminated in a headline performance at the Southbank Centre in London as part of Stewart Lee's Austerity Binge and the Festival Of Britain, which Mojo magazine called &amp;quot;Astonishing&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Gig of the year&amp;quot;. Birmingham's original punk group The Prefects had been part of The Clash's 'White Riot Tour', recorded a couple of Peel sessions, released a 45 on Rough Trade and, years after splitting up, had a retrospective CD released by NY label Acute Records to all round glowing reviews - from Rolling Stone to webzines. The Nightingales was formed by former members of The Prefects following that band's demise in 1979. With an ever fluctuating line up, based around lyricist/singer Robert Lloyd, the Nightingales enjoyed cult status in the early '80's as darlings of the credible music scene and were championed by John Peel, who said of them - &amp;quot;Their performances will serve to confirm their excellence when we are far enough distanced from the 1980's to look at the period rationally and other, infinitely better known, bands stand revealed as charlatans&amp;quot;. The group recorded a bunch of critically acclaimed singles (Almost always 'Single Of The Week' in the music press) and three albums, plus many radio sessions for their great supporter Peel - more than any other band bar The Fall. They also regularly toured the UK and Northern Europe, as headliners and supporting acts as diverse as Bo Diddley and Nico. In the late Eighties the Nightingales stopped working but, following the occasional gig between times, they re-grouped in 2004, with Lloyd being joined by original Prefects guitarist Alan Apperley. After fucking about with various wastrels, precious sorts and mercenaries the group arrived at it's current line up, which features Lloyd, Apperley, Andreas Schmid (Faust Studio engineer) on bass, ex Violet Violet drummer Fliss Kitson and guitarist Matt Wood. Since restarting the group have been more productive than ever - releasing five 7&amp;quot; vinyl singles and three studio albums (Plus two live 'bootleg' albums), touring England, mainland Europe and USA numerous times, recording many radio sessions along the way. They have been invited to play various festivals in Europe and the States, including Glastonbury and SXSW. Their &amp;quot;Let's Think About Living&amp;quot; 45 was 'Single Of The Week' on BBC 6 Music and they have continued to receive regular rave reviews for their records and live shows. In 2008 the band recorded &amp;quot;Insult to Injury&amp;quot; produced by Hans Joachim Irmler of krautrock legends Faust which was released in 2009 on Irmler's Klangbad label and &amp;quot;The Lost Plot&amp;quot;, an Irmler produced 10&amp;quot; EP was released to coincide with the band's Euro tours in 2011. &amp;quot;No Love Lost&amp;quot; the new Nightingales album - their finest yet and first for Cooking Vinyl - was also recorded at Faust Studio in Germany but this time self produced and will be released in April 2012. The group will be touring the UK in May, followed by dates in Europe, a bunch of festivalsduring the Summer and another U.S tour later in the year. In addition to the group's own activity there is a Nightingales 'tribute' album planned featuring 'Gales covers by punk and post punk legends (Raincoats, Mekons, Subway Sect, others), young contemporary bands (Art Brut, Lovely Eggs, others), stand up comedians (Stewart Lee, Phill Jupitus) and academic/author Greil Marcus. from Southbank web site: Birmingham's indomitable punk survivors fuse Beefheart licks and pulverising rhythms with a strangely sensitive cynicism, and arrive at Southbank Centre in advance of imminent National Treasure status. 'One day their excellence will be confirmed, as other, infinitely better known, bands stand revealed as charlatans.' (John Peel on The Nightingales) small selection of recent press: Nothing could have prepared for the astonishing revelation of Robert Lloyd's Nightingales... The cumulative effect is one of euphoric delight, of old knowledge in the hands of new disciples. &amp;quot;Dig the depth of the furrow of mirth that I can plough,&amp;quot; sings Lloyd on The Overreactor. Tonight The Nightingales hit an epic new low. Catch them when they're at it again - MOJO, UK The Nightingales have always been simply a great rock 'n' roll band and 32 years on they're right at the top of their game - THE STOOL PIGEON, UK The Nightingales - they're back and they're marvellous - MARC RILEY/BBC 6 MUSIC, UK Nightingales are unreal. The level of playing and songwriting after their post-punk hiatus is unparalled by any of their generational comeback cohorts - TERRE T/WFMU, USA With The Fall getting Lifetime Achievement awards and Gang Of Four canonised it is long past time the wayward genius of Robert Lloyd and his cohorts was recognised - RECORD COLLECTOR, UK Rock &amp;amp; Roll at its best - SUDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG, GERMANY Consistently excellent, the Nightingales are back, as ferociously sardonic as ever. Nice to see them still mad, still funny, still wrecking the furniture after all these years. - DUSTED, USA Shows just how poor these skinny jeaned little shits currently doing the rounds really are. - TASTY, UK The Nightingales in Southend on Friday jetted in to my top ten gigs of all time - PHILL JUPITUS/BBC 6 MUSIC, UK Forget all these NME Band of the Week types, who make out they don't care, they won't compromise, etc, whilst wearing the same indie uniform and churning out the same tired old riffs. They don't need your attention. The Nightingales do. Because rock 'n' roll rarely gets as uncompromising as this - PLASTELIN, SERBIA The Nightingales revisited their past and offered up the future. Still stunningly relevant - LONDON EVENING STANDARD, UK The Nightingales subjugate a rapt and breathless audience with a performance of sinewy magnificence - DAILY TELEGRAPH, UK Tuesday night at the Cake Shop in NYC. One of the best shows I've seen in years. Jangly, angsty, angular, punk, post-punk, just rock and roll, whatever, they destroyed - DAN SELZER/ILXOR, USA The Nightingales have been responsible for some of the most genuinely innovative minority music of the past three decades. - THE QUIETUS, UK They sound wired, edgy, boozy and as dangerous as ever, like a new band full of that energy that comes with those first moves and not a band who’ve been doing this since the start of punk. Robert Lloyd really shouldn’t be this good after all these years, should he? - THE ORGAN, UK Boozy and deranged, Insult to Injury is how the new Franz record ought to sound - VICE, UK This is a living, breathing beast of an album - ARTROCKER MAGAZINE, UK This is their fiercest, most lacerating album yet, better by a good margin than the mid-1980s Pigs on Purpose...and that was excellent - BLURT, USA Their freshest and most subtly intoxicating work to date - OBSERVER MUSIC MONTHLY, UK The new album from the 'Gales is their finest for 27 years. Start here and work backwards - SUNDAY TIMES, UK Unlovable as ever. The Nightingales remain hard work for precious little gain - MOJO, UK &amp;quot;The new album by Nightingales is brilliant. One of the fiercest and most exhilarating rock records I've heard in ages.&amp;quot; Andrew Male, MOJO Nightingales 'No Love Lost' cd/dd - Cooking Vinyl - Released April 30th 2012 - Press Report March 30th 2012 Radio Marc Riley played 'Dishwater Kid' on Wednesday 28th March BBC6Music - Marc Riley played 'The Burster' on Thursday 22nd March BBC 6Music - Marc Riley played 'Best of British Luck' on 8th,13th and 19th March Resonance FM - (London) Artrocker Radio - played 'Ace of Hearts' on 19th March &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenightingales.org.uk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.thenightingales.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myspace.com/nightingalesmusic&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.myspace.com/nightingalesmusic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Nightingales/8860762012&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/pages/The-Nightingales/8860762012&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/_Nightingales&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;twitter.com/_Nightingales&lt;/a&gt;" id="7043285301" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="nolovelost albumcover artwork may stewartlee wolverhampton shrewsbury thevaults brighton greendoorstore nightingales robertlloyd alanapperley theprefects punk rock birmingham midlands gigs tourdates shows live london nambucca southampton talkingheads sladerooms yorkfibbers manchester nightandday glasgow nicensleazy stockton arc bristol thunderbolt tedchippington comedy comedian funny joke" title="Nightingales - No Love Lost (album cover)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7076/7043285301_6fa0ab72dd_b.jpg" username="Iron Man Records" views="386" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-10-24 14:17:04" description="MAY Fri 25 - Stewart Lee gig in wolves Tue 29 - SHREWSBURY, The Vaults Wed 30 - BRIGHTON, Green Door Store JUNE Fri 1 - LONDON, Nambucca Sat 2 - SOUTHAMPTON, Talking Heads Sun 3 - WOLVERHAMPTON, Slade Rooms Mon 4 - YORK, Fibbers Tue 5 - MANCHESTER, Night &amp;amp; Day Wed 6 - GLASGOW, Nice N Sleazy Thu 7 - STOCKTON, ARC Fri 8 - tbc Sat 9 - BRISTOL, Thunderbolt Sun 10 - tbc NIGHTINGALES Born out of Birmingham's original punk group The Prefects, the Nightingales have stubbornly ploughed their own furrow in the field of alternative rock n roll for three decades. Described in John Robb's definitive post punk biography 'Death To Trad Rock' as &amp;quot;the misfits' misfits&amp;quot;, the band has constantly garnered praise and respect from other artists and received endless glowing press reports, particularly for their live shows. Led by singer/lyricist Robert Lloyd ('The most underestimated songwriter of his generation' according to Ben Thompson in the Independent) the latest incarnation of the Nightingales - the best batch - yet release their new album &amp;quot;No Love Lost&amp;quot; on Cooking Vinyl in April 2012. To coincide with the album's release the Nightingales will be touring the UK and mainland Europe. The UK shows follow their May 2011 tour which culminated in a headline performance at the Southbank Centre in London as part of Stewart Lee's Austerity Binge and the Festival Of Britain, which Mojo magazine called &amp;quot;Astonishing&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Gig of the year&amp;quot;. Birmingham's original punk group The Prefects had been part of The Clash's 'White Riot Tour', recorded a couple of Peel sessions, released a 45 on Rough Trade and, years after splitting up, had a retrospective CD released by NY label Acute Records to all round glowing reviews - from Rolling Stone to webzines. The Nightingales was formed by former members of The Prefects following that band's demise in 1979. With an ever fluctuating line up, based around lyricist/singer Robert Lloyd, the Nightingales enjoyed cult status in the early '80's as darlings of the credible music scene and were championed by John Peel, who said of them - &amp;quot;Their performances will serve to confirm their excellence when we are far enough distanced from the 1980's to look at the period rationally and other, infinitely better known, bands stand revealed as charlatans&amp;quot;. The group recorded a bunch of critically acclaimed singles (Almost always 'Single Of The Week' in the music press) and three albums, plus many radio sessions for their great supporter Peel - more than any other band bar The Fall. They also regularly toured the UK and Northern Europe, as headliners and supporting acts as diverse as Bo Diddley and Nico. In the late Eighties the Nightingales stopped working but, following the occasional gig between times, they re-grouped in 2004, with Lloyd being joined by original Prefects guitarist Alan Apperley. After fucking about with various wastrels, precious sorts and mercenaries the group arrived at it's current line up, which features Lloyd, Apperley, Andreas Schmid (Faust Studio engineer) on bass, ex Violet Violet drummer Fliss Kitson and guitarist Matt Wood. Since restarting the group have been more productive than ever - releasing five 7&amp;quot; vinyl singles and three studio albums (Plus two live 'bootleg' albums), touring England, mainland Europe and USA numerous times, recording many radio sessions along the way. They have been invited to play various festivals in Europe and the States, including Glastonbury and SXSW. Their &amp;quot;Let's Think About Living&amp;quot; 45 was 'Single Of The Week' on BBC 6 Music and they have continued to receive regular rave reviews for their records and live shows. In 2008 the band recorded &amp;quot;Insult to Injury&amp;quot; produced by Hans Joachim Irmler of krautrock legends Faust which was released in 2009 on Irmler's Klangbad label and &amp;quot;The Lost Plot&amp;quot;, an Irmler produced 10&amp;quot; EP was released to coincide with the band's Euro tours in 2011. &amp;quot;No Love Lost&amp;quot; the new Nightingales album - their finest yet and first for Cooking Vinyl - was also recorded at Faust Studio in Germany but this time self produced and will be released in April 2012. The group will be touring the UK in May, followed by dates in Europe, a bunch of festivalsduring the Summer and another U.S tour later in the year. In addition to the group's own activity there is a Nightingales 'tribute' album planned featuring 'Gales covers by punk and post punk legends (Raincoats, Mekons, Subway Sect, others), young contemporary bands (Art Brut, Lovely Eggs, others), stand up comedians (Stewart Lee, Phill Jupitus) and academic/author Greil Marcus. from Southbank web site: Birmingham's indomitable punk survivors fuse Beefheart licks and pulverising rhythms with a strangely sensitive cynicism, and arrive at Southbank Centre in advance of imminent National Treasure status. 'One day their excellence will be confirmed, as other, infinitely better known, bands stand revealed as charlatans.' (John Peel on The Nightingales) small selection of recent press: Nothing could have prepared for the astonishing revelation of Robert Lloyd's Nightingales... The cumulative effect is one of euphoric delight, of old knowledge in the hands of new disciples. &amp;quot;Dig the depth of the furrow of mirth that I can plough,&amp;quot; sings Lloyd on The Overreactor. Tonight The Nightingales hit an epic new low. Catch them when they're at it again - MOJO, UK The Nightingales have always been simply a great rock 'n' roll band and 32 years on they're right at the top of their game - THE STOOL PIGEON, UK The Nightingales - they're back and they're marvellous - MARC RILEY/BBC 6 MUSIC, UK Nightingales are unreal. The level of playing and songwriting after their post-punk hiatus is unparalled by any of their generational comeback cohorts - TERRE T/WFMU, USA With The Fall getting Lifetime Achievement awards and Gang Of Four canonised it is long past time the wayward genius of Robert Lloyd and his cohorts was recognised - RECORD COLLECTOR, UK Rock &amp;amp; Roll at its best - SUDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG, GERMANY Consistently excellent, the Nightingales are back, as ferociously sardonic as ever. Nice to see them still mad, still funny, still wrecking the furniture after all these years. - DUSTED, USA Shows just how poor these skinny jeaned little shits currently doing the rounds really are. - TASTY, UK The Nightingales in Southend on Friday jetted in to my top ten gigs of all time - PHILL JUPITUS/BBC 6 MUSIC, UK Forget all these NME Band of the Week types, who make out they don't care, they won't compromise, etc, whilst wearing the same indie uniform and churning out the same tired old riffs. They don't need your attention. The Nightingales do. Because rock 'n' roll rarely gets as uncompromising as this - PLASTELIN, SERBIA The Nightingales revisited their past and offered up the future. Still stunningly relevant - LONDON EVENING STANDARD, UK The Nightingales subjugate a rapt and breathless audience with a performance of sinewy magnificence - DAILY TELEGRAPH, UK Tuesday night at the Cake Shop in NYC. One of the best shows I've seen in years. Jangly, angsty, angular, punk, post-punk, just rock and roll, whatever, they destroyed - DAN SELZER/ILXOR, USA The Nightingales have been responsible for some of the most genuinely innovative minority music of the past three decades. - THE QUIETUS, UK They sound wired, edgy, boozy and as dangerous as ever, like a new band full of that energy that comes with those first moves and not a band who’ve been doing this since the start of punk. Robert Lloyd really shouldn’t be this good after all these years, should he? - THE ORGAN, UK Boozy and deranged, Insult to Injury is how the new Franz record ought to sound - VICE, UK This is a living, breathing beast of an album - ARTROCKER MAGAZINE, UK This is their fiercest, most lacerating album yet, better by a good margin than the mid-1980s Pigs on Purpose...and that was excellent - BLURT, USA Their freshest and most subtly intoxicating work to date - OBSERVER MUSIC MONTHLY, UK The new album from the 'Gales is their finest for 27 years. Start here and work backwards - SUNDAY TIMES, UK Unlovable as ever. The Nightingales remain hard work for precious little gain - MOJO, UK &amp;quot;The new album by Nightingales is brilliant. One of the fiercest and most exhilarating rock records I've heard in ages.&amp;quot; Andrew Male, MOJO Nightingales 'No Love Lost' cd/dd - Cooking Vinyl - Released April 30th 2012 - Press Report March 30th 2012 Radio Marc Riley played 'Dishwater Kid' on Wednesday 28th March BBC6Music - Marc Riley played 'The Burster' on Thursday 22nd March BBC 6Music - Marc Riley played 'Best of British Luck' on 8th,13th and 19th March Resonance FM - (London) Artrocker Radio - played 'Ace of Hearts' on 19th March &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenightingales.org.uk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.thenightingales.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myspace.com/nightingalesmusic&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.myspace.com/nightingalesmusic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Nightingales/8860762012&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/pages/The-Nightingales/8860762012&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/_Nightingales&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;twitter.com/_Nightingales&lt;/a&gt;" id="7043286469" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="80s andisapey andreasschmid apperley band drummer fauststudio flisskitson flisskitsonmattwood indie lloyd music norfolk norwich promo thenightingales uk violetviolet guitaristchristineedwards studio may stewartlee wolverhampton shrewsbury thevaults brighton greendoorstore nightingales robertlloyd alanapperley theprefects punk rock birmingham midlands gigs tourdates shows live london nambucca southampton talkingheads sladerooms yorkfibbers manchester nightandday glasgow nicensleazy stockton arc bristol thunderbolt tedchippington comedy comedian funny joke 80sandisapeyandreasschmidapperleybanddrummerfauststudioflisskitsonflisskitsonmattwoodindielloydmusicnorfolknorwichpromothenightingalesukvioletvioletguitaristchristineedwardsstudio" title="Nightingales PROMO Photo FEB 2012" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5315/7043286469_e739ce43ff_b.jpg" username="Iron Man Records" views="343" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-28 14:09:36" description="In the pedestrian subway under Park Lane in Mayfair. At the time of building, a condition of the development was that access should be maintained to all the little bits of park that had ben cut off by the development of the large new Park Lane dual carriageway. This was abandoned soo after and many of the access routs (and some complete subways) have been closed off. No-one really wants you to go to the central island now..." id="2453605559" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="central island only sign lonely london marblearch pedestrian subway tunnel underpass underground walkway" title="Central island only" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2178/2453605559_7f80f5b380_b.jpg" username="Swissdave" views="147" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-23 13:48:00" description="Went for a very long walk from Ben's house up to Wimbledon Common, around the Common, and back down. 6 or 7 miles total? Was nice to &amp;quot;get out of the city&amp;quot; for a little bit. Wimbledon Common is where these little dudes live: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wombles.easyweb-solutions.co.uk/&quot;&gt;www.wombles.easyweb-solutions.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt; ." id="251227996" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="common wimbledoncommon wombles london wimbledon" title="Wimbledon Common" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/104/251227996_e15d247a41_b.jpg" username="Alex Mahan" views="142" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-18 16:55:54" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.littlekingdom.co.uk/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Little Kingdom&lt;/a&gt; series 1 and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peppapig.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Peppa Pig&lt;/a&gt; series 3 crew. 16 animators, 2 directors, 1 producer, 1 animation director, 3 designers, 2 layout artists, 1 stills artist, 1 colourist, 2 editors, 2 production staff. Not pictured are storyboard artists, writers, sound recordists, sound mixers, software support, all the vocal talent, licensing and distribution, accountant, in-house masseur, and many more. The BAFTA being held in the front row is one of two that were won in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bafta.org/awards/childrens/awards-2009,879,BA.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;2009 British Academy Children's Awards&lt;/a&gt; (Best Pre-School Animation series for Ben and Holly's Little Kingdom and Independent Production Company). [photo by Nev]" id="4203576959" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="27" tags="bafta studio peppapig animationstudio benandhollyslittlekingdom littlekingdom crownhouse theelffactory peppapigcrew littlekingdomcrew studiothe london" title="The Elf Factory" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4041/4203576959_a486666683_b.jpg" username="slimmer_jimmer" views="787" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-02 23:45:31" description="Not meant to be viewed large... &lt;a href=&quot;http://loc.alize.us/#/flickr:4009076828&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="4009076828" latitude="28.42018" license="3" longitude="-81.582112" nbComments="30" rank="28" tags="geo:lat=2842018 geo:lon=81582112 geotagged peterpansflight fantasyland darkride london youcanfly river bigben londonbridge citylights difficult motion moving dark blacklight classicfantasylanddarkride eticketattraction expressmonorail joepenniston disneyphotography disneyphotos disneypics disneypictures disneyimages disney walt waltdisney walter elias fun vacation travel nikon d300 dream magic magical imagine wonder wish fantasy imagineering orangecounty disneyparks theme themepark paintshopprophotox2 psp usa america mickey mickeymouse wdi wed availablelight waltdisneyworldresort waltdisneyworld disneyworld wdw kissimmee orlando lakebuenavista baylake florida" title="Any Merry Little Thought..." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3640/4009076828_37c0cbcaa9_b.jpg" username="Express Monorail" views="2293" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-16 11:29:56" description="" id="3794900025" latitude="51.500875" license="5" longitude="-0.126063" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="uk london england travel tourism july2009 709 eeyore eeyoresgloomyadventures travelingtoys littlefriendsaroundtheworld bigben westminsterpalace westminster whitehall parliament traveling tour touris holiday britan british english unitedkingdom angleterre summer 2009 july united kingdom britian gloomy adventure donkey blue toy britain londres inghilterra anglaterra англия inglaterra lloegr" title="Kube, Eeyore &amp; I visit Big Ben, Parlaiment" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2449/3794900025_05bcab7669_b.jpg" username="nikoretro" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-02-16 13:26:57" description="Henry Howard, 1st Earl of Northampton (1540-June 15, 1614) was a significant English aristocrat and courtier. Northampton was suspect as a crypto-Catholic throughout his life, and went through periods of royal disfavour, in which his reputation suffered greatly. He was distinguished for learning, artistic culture and his public charities. He built Northumberland House in London and superintended the construction of the fine house of Audley End. He founded and planned several hospitals. Francis Bacon included three of his sayings in his Apophthegms, and chose him as &amp;quot;the learnedest councillor in the kingdom to present to the king his Advancement of Learning.&amp;quot; He was born at Shottesham, Norfolk, on 25 February 1540, the second son of Henry Howard, Earl of Surrey, the poet, and of his wife, the former Lady Frances de Vere, daughter of the 15th Earl of Oxford. He was the younger brother of the 4th Duke of Norfolk, and uncle of Thomas Howard, Earl of Arundel. On the death of his father in 1547 he and his brother and sisters were entrusted to the care of his aunt, Mary FitzRoy, Duchess of Richmond and Somerset, who employed John Foxe as their tutor. With Foxe Howard remained at Reigate, a manor belonging to the Duke of Norfolk, throughout Edward VI's reign. On Mary's accession, the children's grandfather, the Duke of Norfolk, was released from prison, and he dismissed Foxe.[1] Afterwards Henry Howard studied with John White, Bishop of Lincoln; when White was translated to Winchester in 1556, Henry went with him. While with White, Howard read largely in philosophy, civil law, divinity, and history, and seems to have acquired a strong sympathy with Roman Catholicism. On Mary's death and Queen Elizabeth's accession, White was deprived of his bishopric, and Elizabeth undertook the charge of Howard's education. He was restored in blood 8 May 1559. At the queen's expense he proceeded to King's College, Cambridge, where he graduated M. A. in 1564. He afterwards joined Trinity Hall, read Latin lectures on rhetoric and civil law in public, and applied to a friend in London for a master to teach him the lute.[1] Subsequently in 1568 he was incorporated M.A., at Oxford. He protested in 1568 to Lord Burghley that his religious views were needlessly suspected, and wrote a treatise on natural and moral philosophy for his youngest sister, Catharine, wife of Henry Berkeley, 7th Baron Berkeley,[3] dated from Trinity Hall 6 August 1569; she supported him in some hard times.[4] It was rumoured that he contemplated taking holy orders in the vague hope of succeeding Thomas Young as Archbishop of York. He came to court about 1570 at a low ebb, but the intrigues of which his brother the Duke of Norfolk was suspected at the time further depressed his prospects. When in 1572 Norfolk was charged with conspiring to marry Mary, Queen of Scots, Banister, Norfolk's confidential agent, declared in his confession that Henry Howard was himself first proposed as husband. He was arrested, but, after repeated examinations, established his innocence to Elizabeth's satisfaction, was readmitted to court, and was granted a yearly pension. It was generally reported, however, that he had by bad advice brought about his brother's ruin.[1] After the Duke his brother's execution Howard retired to Audley End, and directed the education of his brother's children. He tried by frequent letters to Burghley and to Christopher Hatton to keep himself in favour with the queen's ministers, and managed to offer satisfactory explanations when it was reported in 1574 that he was exchanging tokens with Mary, Queen of Scots. He supplied her for many years with political information, but, according to his own account, gave her prudent advice. Howard sought to regain Elizabeth's favour by grossly flattering her in long petitions. About 1580 he circulated a manuscript tract in support of the scheme for the marriage of Elizabeth with François, Duke of Anjou, in answer to John Stubbe's Discoverie of a Gaping Gulf (1579), and at Burghley's request began a reply to a pamphlet denouncing female government, which he completed in 1589. In 1582 his cousin Edward de Vere, 17th Earl of Oxford, quarrelled with him, and revived the charges of heresy and of treasonable correspondence with Mary. He was again arrested, and defended himself at length in a letter to Elizabeth, in which he admitted that he had taken part in Roman Catholic worship owing to conscientious difficulties on the sacramentary, but denied that he could win Mary Stuart's favour. He was soon set free, and, retiring to St. Albans, spent a year (1582-3) in writing his Preservative against the Poison of supposed Prophecies, a learned attack on judicial astrology, dedicated to Francis Walsingham, and said to have been suggested by the astrological exploits of Richard Harvey. The book was suspected of apparent heresies and concealed treason, and in 1583 Howard was sent to the Fleet Prison. He complained to Hatton of harsh treatment. Mary, it was now asserted, had sent him a ring with a message. Burghley declined to intervene in his behalf, but by the favour of Burghley's son Robert Cecil he was sent on parole to the house of Sir Nicholas Bacon at Redgrave, Suffolk. On 19 July 1585 he wrote from there to Burghley, begging permission to visit the wells at Warwick for the benefit of his health.[1] He was set at liberty, and is said to have travelled in Italy, visiting Florence and Rome. In 1587 his repeated requests to take an active part in resisting the threatened Spanish attack were refused. He was at the time without any means of livelihood, except his irregularly-paid pension. He attached himself both to Lord Essex and to Robert Cecil, and through the influence of the latter was in 1600 again received by Elizabeth. At the close of the Queen's reign he joined with Cecil in courting James, the heir to the English throne who was reigning in Scotland (in fact James suggested Howard as a trusted intermediary with Cecil).[5] He sent long letters of advice, which James termed &amp;quot;Asiatic and endless volumes&amp;quot;. He had success in intriguing against Sir Walter Raleigh and other rivals.[6] On the 1603 accession of James as James I of England, Howard received a multitude of favours.[1]In 1603 he was made a Privy Counsellor, on 1 January 1604 Lord Warden of the Cinque Ports, and on 13 March Earl of Northampton and Baron Marnhull, of Marnhull in the County of Dorset; on 24 February 1605 he was given the Garter and on 29 April was appointed Lord Privy Seal. In 1609 he was elected High Steward of the University of Oxford, and in 1612 Chancellor of the University of Cambridge. The same year he was appointed one of the Commissioners of the Treasury. He was one of the judges at the trials of Walter Raleigh and Lord Cobham in 1603, of Guy Fawkes in 1605, and of Henry Garnet in 1606, in each case pressing for a conviction. In 1604 he was one of the commissioners who composed the treaty of peace with Spain, and from that date he received from the Spanish Court a pension of £1000. In 1604, Howard called playwright Ben Jonson before the Privy Council, accusing him of popery and treason in Sejanus.[8] In 1610 he received a royal grant of territory in Newfoundland, and the London and Bristol Company (Newfoundland Company) was set up around him for its commercial exploitation. He assisted his great-niece, Lady Essex, in obtaining her divorce from her husband (son of the 2nd Earl of Essex whom Northampton had followed in the 1590s) in order to marry the favourite Somerset, whose mistress she already was. While Northampton may have treated this as routine intrigue, the outcome was a major murder scandal. Northampton and her father Thomas Howard, 1st Earl of Suffolk represented her in an interview with Essex held at Whitehall in May 1613, in the hope of obtaining his assent to a divorce. Essex proved uncompliant, and Northampton contrived that the case should be brought before a special commission. When, however, the divorce was obtained, Somerset's intimate acquaintance, Sir Thomas Overbury, dissuaded him from pursuing the project of marriage with Lady Frances. Northampton recommended, on slender grounds, Overbury's imprisonment in the Tower of London, and contrived that a friend of the Howard family, Sir Gervase Helwys, should be appointed Lord Lieutenant of the Tower. Helwys frequently wrote to Northampton about Overbury's conduct and health. In his extant letters to Helwys Northampton writes with contempt of Overbury and expresses a desire that his own name should not be mentioned in connection with his imprisonment, but he introduced to Helwys John Craig, one of the royal physicians, to report on the prisoner's health. When, in 1615, after Northampton's death, the matter was judicially investigated, and his political enemies credited him with a direct hand in the murder. Overbury died from the effects of poison administered by the direction of Lady Essex; the discovery of the crime was not made till some little time after Overbury had succumbed, and meanwhile Northampton's own death had occurred. He advised against the summoning of Parliament in 1614,[10] and then fomented disputes to compel James to dissolve it. He died unmarried on 15 June 1614, when his title became extinct, and was buried in the chapel of Dover Castle, the monument erected above his grave being subsequently removed to the chapel at Trinity Hospital, Greenwich. His will, in phrasing that has been considered equivocal, can be reasonably interpreted to say that he died a Roman Catholic. by; after R. Clamp; Harding,print,published 1796" id="3828448432" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="30" tags="londonstmartinsplacewc20he unitedkingdom" title="Henry Howard, 1st Earl of Northampton, son of Henry Howard, Earl of Surrey, cousin of Queen Kathryn Howard and Elizabeth I" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2531/3828448432_2b14e6dc32_b.jpg" username="lisby1" views="956" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-05-03 09:44:17" description="&lt;b&gt;Youth Culture - Mods - Late 1950s to Mid 1960s&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Mod &lt;/b&gt;(from modernist) is a subculture that originated in London, England in the late 1950s and peaked in the early-to-mid 1960s. Significant elements of the mod subculture include: fashion (often tailor-made suits); pop music, including African American soul, Jamaican ska, and British beat music and R&amp;amp;B; and Italian motor scooters. The original mod scene was also associated with amphetamine-fuelled all-night dancing at clubs. From the mid-to-late 1960s onwards, the mass media often used the term mod in a wider sense to describe anything that was believed to be popular, fashionable or modern. There was a mod revival in the United Kingdom in the late 1970s, which was followed by a mod revival in North America in the early 1980s, particularly in Southern California. Coffee bars were attractive to youths, because in contrast to typical British pubs, which closed at about 11 pm, they were open until the early hours of the morning. Coffee bars had jukeboxes, which in some cases reserved some of the space in the machines for the students' own records. In the late 1950s, coffee bars were associated with jazz and blues, but in the early 1960s, they began playing more R&amp;amp;B music. By the summer of 1966, the mod scene was in sharp decline. Dick Hebdige argues that the mod subculture lost its vitality when it became commercialised, artificial and stylised to the point that new mod clothing styles were being created &amp;quot;from above&amp;quot; by clothing companies and by TV shows like Ready Steady Go!, rather than being developed by young people customising their clothes and mixing different fashions together. As psychedelic rock and the hippie subculture grew more popular in the United Kingdom, many people drifted away from the mod scene. Bands such as The Who and Small Faces had changed their musical styles and no longer considered themselves mods. Another factor was that the original mods of the early 1960s were getting into the age of marriage and child-rearing, which meant that they no longer had the time or money for their youthful pastimes of club-going, record-shopping and scooter rallies. The peacock or fashion wing of mod culture evolved into the swinging London scene and the hippie style, which favored the gentle, marijuana-infused contemplation of esoteric ideas and aesthetics, which contrasted sharply with the frenetic energy of the mod ethos. The hard mods of the mid-to-late 1960s eventually transformed into the skinheads. Many of the hard mods lived in the same economically depressed areas of South London as West Indian immigrants, and those mods emulated the rude boy look of pork pie hats and too-short Levis jeans. These &amp;quot;aspiring 'white negros'&amp;quot; listened to Jamaican ska and mingled with black rude boys at West Indian nightclubs like Ram Jam, A-Train and Sloopy's. Dick Hebdige claims that the hard mods were drawn to black culture and ska music in part because the educated, middle-class hippie movement's drug-oriented and intellectual music did not have any relevance for them. He argues that the hard mods were also attracted to ska because it was a secret, underground, non-commercialised music that was disseminated through informal channels such as house parties and clubs. The early skinheads also liked soul, rocksteady and early reggae. The early skinheads retained basic elements of mod fashion — such as Fred Perry and Ben Sherman shirts, Sta-Prest trousers and Levi's jeans — but mixed them with working class-oriented accessories such as braces and Dr. Martens work boots. Hebdige claims that as early as the Margate and Brighton brawls between mods and rockers, some mods were seen wearing boots and braces and sporting close cropped haircuts, which &amp;quot;artificially reproduces the texture and appearance of the short negro hair styles&amp;quot; (though this was as much for practical reasons, as long hair was a liability in industrial jobs and streetfights). It was also a reaction to middle class hippie aesthetics. Mods and ex-mods were also part of the early northern soul scene, a subculture based on obscure 1960s and 1970s American soul records. Some mods evolved into, or merged with, subcultures such as individualists, stylists, and scooterboys, creating a mixture of &amp;quot;taste and testosterone&amp;quot; that was both self-confident and streetwise. A mod revival started in the late 1970s in the United Kingdom, with thousands of mods attending scooter rallies in places like Scarborough and the Isle of Wight. This revival was partly inspired by the 1979 film Quadrophenia and by mod-influenced bands such as The Jam, Secret Affair, Purple Hearts and The Chords. Many of the mod revival bands were influenced by the energy of British punk rock and New Wave music. The British revival was followed by a mod revival in North America in the early 1980s, particularly in Southern California, led by bands such as The Untouchables. The mod scene in Los Angeles and Orange County was partly influenced by the 2 Tone ska revival in England, and was unique in its racial diversity, with black, white, Hispanic and Asian participants. The 1990s Britpop scene featured noticeable mod influences on bands such as Oasis, Blur, Ocean Colour Scene and The Verve. &lt;b&gt;Fashion&lt;/b&gt; Jobling and Crowley called the mod subculture a &amp;quot;fashion-obsessed and hedonistic cult of the hyper-cool&amp;quot; young adults who lived in metropolitan London or the new towns of the south. Due to the increasing affluence of post-war Britain, the youths of the early 1960s were one of the first generations that did not have to contribute their money from after-school jobs to the family finances. As mod teens and young adults began using their disposable income to buy stylish clothes, the first youth-targeted boutique clothing stores opened in London in the Carnaby Street and Kings Road districts. Maverick fashion designers emerged, such as Mary Quant, who was known for her increasingly short miniskirt designs, and John Stephen, who sold a line named &amp;quot;His Clothes&amp;quot;, and whose clients included bands such as The Small Faces. Two youth subcultures helped pave the way for mod fashion by breaking new ground; the beatniks, with their bohemian image of berets and black turtlenecks, and the Teddy Boys, from which mod fashion inherited its &amp;quot;narcissitic and fastidious fashion tendencies&amp;quot; and the immaculate dandy look. The Teddy Boys paved the way for making male interest in fashion socially acceptable, because prior to the Teddy Boys, male interest in fashion in Britain was mostly associated with the underground homosexual subculture's flamboyant dressing style. The Royal Air Force roundel, was a mod symbol. Newspaper accounts from the mid-1960s focused on the mod obsession with clothes, often detailing the prices of the expensive suits worn by young mods, and seeking out extreme cases such as a young mod who claimed that he would &amp;quot;go without food to buy clothes&amp;quot;. Jobling and Crowley argue that for working class mods, the subculture's focus on fashion and music was a release from the &amp;quot;humdrum of daily existence&amp;quot; at their jobs. Jobling and Crowley note that while the subculture had strong elements of consumerism and shopping, mods were not passive consumers; instead they were very self-conscious and critical, customising &amp;quot;existing styles, symbols and artefacts&amp;quot; such as the Union flag and the Royal Air Force roundel symbol, and putting them on their jackets in a pop art-style, and putting their personal signatures on their style. The song &amp;quot;Dedicated Follower of Fashion&amp;quot; by The Kinks from 1966 jokes about the fashion obsession of the mod community. Mod fashion adopted new Italian and French styles in part as a reaction to the rural and small-town rockers, who were seen as trapped in the 1950s, with their leather motorcycle clothes and American greaser look. Male mods adopted a smooth, sophisticated look that emphasised tailor-made Italian suits (sometimes white) with narrow lapels, mohair clothes, thin ties, button-down collar shirts, wool or cashmere jumpers (crewneck or V-neck), pointed-toe leather shoes that were nicknamed winklepickers, as well as Chelsea or &amp;quot;Beatle&amp;quot; boots, Tassel Loafers,Clarks' Desert Boots even Bowling shoes, and hairstyles that imitated the look of the French Nouvelle Vague cinema actors of the era, such as Jean-Paul Belmondo. A few male mods went against gender norms of the era by enhancing their appearance with eye shadow, eyepencil or even lipstick. Female mods dressed androgynously, with short haircuts, men's trousers or shirts (sometimes their boyfriend's), flat shoes, and little makeup — often just pale foundation, brown eye shadow, white or pale lipstick and false eyelashes. Female mods pushed the boundaries of parental tolerance with their miniskirts, which got progressively shorter between the early and mid-1960s. As female mod fashion went from an underground style to a more commercialised fashion, slender models like Jean Shrimpton and Twiggy began to exemplify the high-fashion mod look. The television programme Ready Steady Go!, presented by Cathy McGowan, helped to spread awareness of mod fashions and music to a larger audience. &lt;b&gt;Fishtail Parka&lt;/b&gt; The Fishtail Parka was first used by the United States Army in 1951 to help protect soldiers from the elements in the Korean War. There are two main styles of fishtail parkas; the M-51 fishtail parka; and the M-65. The M stands for military, and the number is the year it was standardized. The name fishtail comes from the fact that the coat is longer at the back than it is at the front. This was so the coat could be tied around the upper legs, much like a Knochensack for added wind proofing as they are not, as some think, waterproof. The hood of the M-51 Fishtail Parka is integral to the jacket and folds down inside the jacket collar when not in use. The M-65 Fishtail parka has a detachable hood. Both types feature a removable liner. Designed primarily for combat arms forces such as infantry, they are to be worn over other layers of clothing; alone, the fishtail parka is insufficient to protect against &amp;quot;dry cold&amp;quot; (as used in the US military; see FM 31-70, Cold Weather Field Manual) conditions (i.e., below 14 deg. F.). On the other hand, the N-3B parka has more integral insulation and can be worn alone in colder temperatures than the fishtail parka. Because it has less insulation but is designed to fit loosely, it allows infantry more latitude to add or subtract layers underneath to adapt to changing weather or situational conditions than that allowed by the N-3B parka, which was designed for aircrews who typically worked under more static weather and geographic conditions. With proper additional insulating garments in the US military inventory, one can remain warm with the fishtail parka in -60 deg. F. temperatures. The fishtail parka has been replaced in the US military by the Extended Cold Weather Clothing System (ECWCS). In the 1960s UK, the fishtail parka became a symbol of the mod subculture. Due to their practicality, cheapness and availability from army surplus shops, the parka was seen as the ideal garment for fending off the elements when on the mod's vehicle of choice, the scooter. Its place in popular culture was assured by newspaper pictures of parka-clad mods during the Bank Holiday riots of the 1960s. &lt;b&gt;Brutus&lt;/b&gt; Brutus Jeans is a British clothing company founded in 1966 by brothers Keith and Alan Freedman, who were 18 and 17 years old at the time, respectively. The company started with one style of sweater and kept adding to the range, which eventually included shirts and jeans (for both men and women). The brand was very popular in the 1960's and 1970s with skinheads, Mod's and the football crowds. They won awards for their TV advertising, and had a hit record with one of the jingles called &amp;quot;Jeans On&amp;quot; (performed by David Dundas). &lt;b&gt;Ben Sherman&lt;/b&gt; Ben Sherman is a British based clothing company, designing shirts, suits, shoes, accessories and other items that are, in common with many British brands, now made overseas, largely in the Far East. Their designs sometimes feature the Royal Air Force roundel which is often called the mod target. Some of the recent Ben Sherman shirts have unusual and complex designs, and have a Carnaby-style fit. The company makes clothing predominantly for men. &lt;b&gt;Crombie&lt;/b&gt; A Crombie coat is a three-quarter length, usually wool, overcoat. It is named after the company Crombie (also known as J&amp;amp;J Crombie), although not all coats known as Crombies are made by that company. Starting in the late 1960s or early 1970s, Crombie-style coats were popular within the skinhead and suedehead subcultures, although very few skinheads would have been able to afford a new Crombie brand coat. Crombies were also fashionable among some mods, who saw them as a stylish item of clothing that enhanced their clean-cut image. It was an alternative to the popular fishtail parka or trenchcoat. The Crombie company, which produces high-end wool and tweed clothing, was founded in Aberdeen, Scotland in 1805. The Grandholm Woollen Mill in Aberdeen was the A-listed factory building where Crombie's clothing was originally made, although production at that site ceased in 1990. In 2005 it was converted into a residential project by the Cala Group. The Crombie Woollen Mill is now an Indian Restaurant called The Spice Mill. They specialise in Indian fusion cuisine and have maintained the original elements of the factory. &lt;b&gt;Scooters&lt;/b&gt; Scooters were chosen over motorbikes because scooters' use of bodypanelling and concealed moving parts made them cleaner and less likely to stain an expensive suit with grease. Scootering led to the wearing of military parkas to protect costly suits and trousers from mud and rain. Many mods used motorscooters for transportation, usually Vespas or Lambrettas. Scooters had provided inexpensive transportation for decades before the development of the mod subculture, but the mods stood out in the way that they treated the vehicle as a fashion accessory. Italian scooters were preferred due to their cleanlined, curving shapes and gleaming chrome. For young mods, Italian scooters were the &amp;quot;embodiment of continental style and a way to escape the working-class row houses of their upbringing&amp;quot;. They customised their scooters by painting them in &amp;quot;two-tone and candyflake and over accessorized them with luggage racks, crash bars, and scores of mirrors and fog lights&amp;quot;, and they often put their names on the small windscreen. Engine side panels and front bumpers were taken to local electroplating workshops and recovered in highly reflective chrome. Scooters were also a practical and accessible form of transportation for 1960s teens. In the early 1960s, public transport stopped relatively early in the night, and so having scooters allowed mods to stay out all night at dance clubs. To keep their expensive suits clean and keep warm while riding, mods often wore long army parkas. For teens with low-end jobs, scooters were cheaper than cars, and they could be bought on a payment plan through newly-available Hire purchase plans. After a law was passed requiring at least one mirror be attached to every motorcycle, mods were known to add four, ten, or as many as 30 mirrors to their scooters. The cover of The Who's album Quadrophenia, (which includes themes related to mods and rockers), depicts a young man on a Vespa GS with four mirrors attached. After the seaside resort brawls, the media began to associate Italian scooters with the image of violent mods. When groups of mods rode their scooters together, the media began to view it as a &amp;quot;menacing symbol of group solidarity&amp;quot; that was &amp;quot;converted into a weapon&amp;quot;. With events like the November 6, 1966, &amp;quot;scooter charge&amp;quot; on Buckingham Palace, the scooter, along with the mods' short hair and suits, began to be seen as a symbol of subversion. After the 1964 beach riots, hard mods (who later evolved into the skinheads) began riding scooters more for practical reasons. Their scooters were either unmodified or cut down, which was nicknamed a &amp;quot;skelly&amp;quot;. Lambrettas were cutdown to the bare frame, and the unibody (monocoque)-design Vespas had their body panels slimmed down or reshaped. &lt;b&gt;Mods &amp;amp; Rockers&lt;/b&gt; The Mods and Rockers were two conflicting British youth subcultures of the early-mid 1960s. Gangs of mods and rockers fighting in 1964 sparked a moral panic about British youths, and the two groups were seen as folk devils. The rockers adopted a macho biker gang image, wearing clothes such as black leather jackets. The mods adopted a pose of scooter-driving sophistication, wearing suits and other cleancut outfits. By late 1966, the two subcultures had faded from public view and media attention turned to two new emerging youth subcultures — the hippies and the skinheads. Rockers, who wore leather jackets and rode heavy motorcycles, poured scorn on the mods, who often wore suits and rode scooters. The rockers considered mods to be weedy, effeminate snobs, and mods saw rockers as out of touch, oafish and grubby. Mod or Rocker - 'You had to be one or the other ' The Mods had designer suits, Italian scooters and The Who. Rockers had leathers, motorbikes and Elvis. For a few years in the early 1960s, the two groups represented a sharp division in British youth culture. Their rivalry often spilled over into violence, and the 1964 holiday weekend clashes in resort towns on the south coast terrorised local residents and outraged much of the nation. But soon after the seaside riots of 1964, this volatile split in British teen life faded away. Musically, there was not much common ground. Rockers listened to 1950s rock and roll, mostly by white American artists such as Elvis Presley, Gene Vincent and Eddie Cochran. Elvis, The King of Rock &amp;amp; Roll Beatles Stones The Jimi Hendrix Experience Janis Joplin The Doors Blind Faith Credence Clearwater Revival Jethro Tull Pink Floyd Moody Blues Deep Purple Jefferson Airplane Cream Steppenwolf Procol Harem The Byrds Frank Zappa and the Mothers of Invention Mods generally favoured 1960s rhythm and blues, soul and ska by black American and Jamaican musicians, as well as British R&amp;amp;B/beat groups such as The Who, The Small Faces and The Yardbirds. In the United Kingdom, rockers were often engaged in brawls with mods. BBC News stories from May 1964 stated that mods and rockers were jailed after riots in seaside resort towns on the south coast of England, such as Margate, Brighton, Bournemouth and Clacton. &lt;b&gt;Were you a Mod or a Rocker? Do you have any stories from that era?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;See Mod Links Below&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/3353594076/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/3353594076/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5004064473/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5004064473/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/3658869353/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/3658869353/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/4316146588/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/4316146588/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;See My Other Youth Culture Links Below&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/4082458089/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/4082458089/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130733677/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130733677/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130851019/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5130851019/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/6802418072/in/photostream&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/6802418072/in/ph...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5131064113/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5131064113/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Mods &amp;amp; Rockers on Video&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zn5vYOwCTak&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=zn5vYOwCTak&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lEW56xumtq4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=lEW56xumtq4&lt;/a&gt;" id="5130733677" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="5" rank="31" tags="youthculture britishyouth mods mod 1960s subculture modfashion africanamericansoul jamaicanska britishbeatmusic rb scooters motorscooters modscene amphetamines coffeebars readysteadygo thewho smallfaces porkpiehats modsrockers modrevivalbands carnabystreet kingsroad maryquant royalairforceroundel unionflag dedicatedfolloweroffashion winklepickers chelseaboots beatleboots tasselloafers clarksdesertboots jeanpaulbelmondo miniskirts jeanshrimpton twiggy cathymcgowan fishtailparka brutusshirts bensherman crombiecoat vespas lambrettas seasidebrawls rockers leatherjackets theyardbirds margate brighton bournemouth clacton teenagers youthcult greasers gangs bristol uk 19612007" title="Youth Culture - Mods &amp; Rockers 1960s - 1970s" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4125/5130733677_086ebba86a_b.jpg" username="brizzle born and bred" views="55645" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-24 04:50:29" description="John Fletcher (1579 – 1625) was a Jacobean playwright. Following William Shakespeare as house playwright for the King's Men, he was among the most prolific and influential dramatists of his day; both during his lifetime and in the early Restoration, his fame rivaled Shakespeare's. Though his reputation has been eclipsed since, Fletcher remains an important transitional figure between the Elizabethan popular tradition and the popular drama of the Restoration. Fletcher was born in December 1579 (baptised December 20) in Rye, Sussex, and died of the plague in August 1625 (buried August 29 in St. Saviour's, Southwark). His father Richard Fletcher was an ambitious and successful cleric who was in turn Dean of Peterborough, Bishop of Bristol, Bishop of Worcester, and Bishop of London (shortly before his death) as well as chaplain to Queen Elizabeth. As dean of Peterborough, Richard Fletcher, at the execution of Mary, Queen of Scots at Fotheringay &amp;quot;knelt down on the scaffold steps and started to pray out loud and at length, in a prolonged and rhetorical style as though determined to force his way into the pages of history&amp;quot; and who cried out at her death, &amp;quot;So perish all the Queen's enemies!&amp;quot; Richard Fletcher died shortly after falling out of favor with the queen, over a marriage the queen had advised against. He appears to have been partly rehabilitated before his death in 1596; however, Fletcher died substantially in debt. The upbringing of John Fletcher and his seven siblings was entrusted to his paternal uncle Giles Fletcher, a poet and minor official. His uncle's connections ceased to be a benefit, and may even have become a liability, after the rebellion of the Earl of Essex, who had patronized him. Fletcher appears to have entered Corpus Christi College, Cambridge University in 1591, at the age of eleven.[1] It is not certain that he took a degree, but evidence suggests that he was preparing for a career in the church. Little is known about his time at college, but he evidently followed the same path previously trod by the University wits before him, from Cambridge to the burgeoning commercial theater of London. In 1606, he began to appear as an author for the Children of the Queen's Revels, then performing at the Blackfriars Theatre. Commendatory verses by Richard Brome in the Beaumont and Fletcher 1647 folio place Fletcher in the company of Ben Jonson; a comment of Jonson's to Drummond corroborates this claim, although it is not known when this friendship began. At the beginning of his career, his most important association was with Francis Beaumont. The two wrote together for close to a decade, first for the children and then for the King's Men. According to a legend transmitted or invented by John Aubrey, they also lived together (in Bankside), sharing clothes and having &amp;quot;one wench in the house between them.&amp;quot; This domestic arrangement, if it existed, was ended by Beaumont's marriage in 1613, and their dramatic partnership ended after Beaumont fell ill, probably of a stroke, the same year. By this time, Fletcher had moved into a closer association with the King's Men. He is commonly assumed to have collaborated with Shakespeare on Henry VIII, The Two Noble Kinsmen, and the lost Cardenio; a play he wrote singly around this time. The Woman's Prize or the Tamer Tamed, is a sequel to The Taming of the Shrew. After Shakespeare's death, Fletcher appears to have entered into an exclusive arrangement with the King's Men similar to that with which Shakespeare had worked; Fletcher wrote only for that company between the death of Shakespeare and his own death nine years later. He never lost his habit of collaboration, working with Nathan Field and later with Philip Massinger, who succeeded him as house playwright for the King's Men. His popularity continued unabated throughout his life; during the winter of 1621, three of his plays were performed at court. He died in 1625, apparently of the plague. He seems to have been buried in what is now Southwark Cathedral, although the precise location is not known; there is a reference by Aston Cockayne to a single grave for Fletcher and Massinger (also buried in Southwark). His mastery is most notable in two dramatic types, tragicomedy and comedy of manners, both of which exerted a pervasive influence on dramatists in the reign of Charles I and during the Restoration. by Unknown artist,painting,circa 1620" id="3858396247" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="londonstmartinsplacewc20he unitedkingdom" title="John Fletcher, dramatist" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2643/3858396247_6ec46c63b0_b.jpg" username="lisby1" views="494" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-24 05:00:44" description="Michael Drayton (1563 – December 23, 1631) was an English poet who came to prominence in the Elizabethan era. He was born at Hartshill, near Nuneaton, Warwickshire, England. Almost nothing is known about his early life, beyond the fact that in 1580 he was in the service of Thomas Goodere of Collingham, Nottinghamshire. Nineteenth- and twentieth-century scholars, on the basis of scattered allusions in his poems and dedications, suggested that Drayton might have studied at the University of Oxford, and been intimate with the Polesworth branch of the Goodere family. More recent work has cast doubt on those speculations. In 1591 he produced his first book, The Harmony of the Church, a volume of spiritual poems, dedicated to Lady Devereux. It is notable for a version of the Song of Solomon, executed with considerable richness of expression. However, with the exception of forty copies, seized by the Archbishop of Canterbury, the whole edition was destroyed by public order. Nevertheless, Drayton published a vast amount within the next few years. In 1593 appeared Idea: The Shepherd's Garland, a collection of nine pastorals, in which he celebrated his own love-sorrows under the poetic name of Rowland. The basic idea was expanded in a cycle of sixty-four sonnets, published in 1594, under the title of Idea's Mirror, by which we learn that the lady lived by the river Ankor in Warwickshire. It appears that he failed to win his &amp;quot;Idea,&amp;quot; and lived and died a bachelor. In 1593 appeared the first of Drayton's historical poems, The Legend of Piers Gaveston, and the next year saw the publication of Matilda, an epic poem in rhyme royal. It was about this time, too, that he brought out Endimion and Phoebe, a volume which he never republished, but which contains some interesting autobiographical matter, and acknowledgments of literary help from Thomas Lodge, if not from Edmund Spenser and Samuel Daniel also. In his Fig for Momus, Lodge reciprocated these friendly courtesies. In 1596 Drayton published his long and important poem Mortimeriados, which deals with the Wars of the Roses and is a very serious production in ottava rima. He later enlarged and modified this poem, and republished it in 1603 under the title of The Barons' Wars. In 1596 also appeared another historical poem, The Legend of Robert, Duke of Normandy, with which Piers Gaveston was reprinted. In 1597 appeared England's Heroical Epistles, a series of historical studies, in imitation of those of Ovid. These last poems, written in the heroic couplet, contain some of the finest passages in Drayton's writings. By 1597, the poet was resting on his laurels. It seems that he was much favoured at the court of Elizabeth, and he hoped that it would be the same with her successor. But when, in 1603, he addressed a poem of compliment to James I, on his accession, it was ridiculed, and his services rudely rejected. His bitterness found expression in a satire, The Owl (1604), but he had no talent in this kind of composition. Not much more entertaining was his scriptural narrative of Moses in a Map of his Miracles, a sort of epic in heroics printed the same year. In 1605 Drayton reprinted his most important works, his historical poems and the Idea, in a single volume which ran through eight editions during his lifetime. He also collected his smaller pieces, hitherto unedited, in a volume undated, but probably published in 1605, under the title of Poems Lyric and Pastoral; these consisted of odes, eclogues, and a fantastic satire called The Man in the Moon. Some of the odes are extremely spirited. In this volume he printed for the first time the famous Ballad of Agincourt. He had adopted as early as 1598 the extraordinary resolution of celebrating all the points of topographical or antiquarian interest in the island of Great Britain, and on this laborious work he was engaged for many years. At last, in 1613, the first part of this vast work was published under the title of Poly-Olbion, eighteen books being produced, to which the learned Selden supplied notes. The success of this great work, which has since become so famous, was very small at first, and not until 1622 did Drayton succeed in finding a publisher willing to undertake the risk of bringing out twelve more books in a second part. This completed the survey of England, and the poet, who had hoped &amp;quot;to crown Scotland with flowers,&amp;quot; and arrive at last at the Orcades, never crossed the Tweed. In 1627 he published another of his miscellaneous volumes, and this contains some of his most characteristic and exquisite writing. It consists of the following pieces: The Battle of Agincourt, an historical poem in ottava rima (not to be confused with his ballad on the same subject), and The Miseries of Queen Margaret, written in the same verse and manner; Nimphidia, the Court of Faery, a most joyous and graceful little epic of fairyland; The Quest of Cinthia and The Shepherd's Sirena, two lyrical pastorals; and finally The Moon Calf, a sort of satire. Of these Nimphidia is perhaps the best thing Drayton ever wrote, except his famous ballad on the battle of Agincourt; it is quite unique of its kind and full of rare fantastic fancy. The last of Drayton's voluminous publications was The Muses' Elizium in 1630. He died in London, was buried in Westminster Abbey, and had a monument placed over him by the Countess of Dorset, with memorial lines attributed to Ben Jonson. Like other poets of his era, Drayton was active in writing for the theater; but unlike Shakespeare, Ben Jonson, or Samuel Daniel, he invested little of his art in the genre. For a period of only five years, from 1597 to 1602, Drayton was a member of the stable of playwrights who supplied material for the theatrical syndicate of Philip Henslowe. Henslowe's Diary links Drayton's name with 23 plays from that period, and shows that Drayton almost always worked in collaboration with other Henslowe regulars, like Thomas Dekker, Anthony Munday, and Henry Chettle, among others.[2] Of these 23 plays, only one has survived, that being Part 1 of Sir John Oldcastle, which Drayton composed in collaboration with Munday, Robert Wilson, and Richard Hathwaye. The text of Oldcastle shows no clear signs of Drayton's hand; traits of style consistent through the entire corpus of his poetry (the rich vocabulary of plant names, star names, and other unusual words; the frequent use of original contractional forms, sometimes with double apostrophes, like &amp;quot;th'adult'rers&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;pois'ned'st&amp;quot;) are wholly absent from the text, suggesting that his contribution to the collaborative effort was not substantial. William Longsword, the one play that Henslowe's Diary suggests was a solo Drayton effort, was never completed. (Drayton may have preferred the role of impressario to that of playwright; he was one of the lessees of the Whitefriars Theatre when it was started in 1608. Around 1606, Drayton was also part of a syndicate that chartered a company of child actors, The Children of the King's Revels. These may or may not have been the Children of Paul's under a new name, since the latter group appears to have gone out of existence at about this time. The venture was not a success, dissolving in litigation in 1609.) Drayton was a friend of some of the most famous men of the age. He corresponded familiarly with Drummond; Ben Jonson, William Browne, George Wither and others were among his friends. There is a tradition that he was a friend of Shakespeare, supported by a statement of John Ward, once vicar of Stratford-on-Avon, that &amp;quot;Shakespear, Drayton and Ben Jonson had a merry meeting, and it seems, drank too hard, for Shakespear died of a feavour there contracted.&amp;quot; In one of his poems, an elegy or epistle to Mr Henry Reynolds, he has left some valuable criticisms on poets whom he had known. That he was a restless and discontented, as well as a worthy, man may be gathered from his own admissions. Drayton was also a contemporary of John Donne, though it is not known if Drayton and Donne ever knew each other. by Unknown artist,painting,1599" id="3862551506" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="crownsandtiaras londonstmartinsplacewc20he unitedkingdom" title="Michael Drayton, poet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2548/3862551506_664e09ce90_b.jpg" username="lisby1" views="959" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-28 13:39:41" description="First of all thanks to Liam for being my beautiful model on the millenium bridge. This camera was given to me as a gift by Aaron &amp;amp; Ruth for my birthday - little did they know that I wanted one of these camera types for my collection. Thank you also to leanne &amp;amp; Ben for buying me a camera for christmas (coming soon) Dated 1960's - 70's I can't really use the camera as it takes 126 film which is a roll film with a paper backing (like 120 medium format) but the size of a 35mm film. I believe I can still get 126 but it is expensive for what I would get from an exposed film (not very high quaility) so it wouldnt be worth it. Some cameras in my collection are just for the collection Latest blog post &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philhearingphotography.com/2012/04/ben-ellie/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt; Ben &amp;amp; Ellie &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philhearingphotography.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/pages/Phil-Hearing-Photography/161236573912745&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/photking&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;" id="7125994639" latitude="51.509497" license="4" longitude="-0.098508" nbComments="7" rank="34" tags="instamatic104 instamatic kodak 126film london milleniumbridge uk england oldcamera cameraporn porn old camera 16mm 1635 stpauls thames" title="+ I collect old cameras + Kodak Instamatic 104 {a}" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7135/7125994639_e970b78051_b.jpg" username="PhotKing ♛" views="676" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-06 08:09:36" description="The is a mini-version of Big Ben clock tower, found near Victoria station, I don't think anyone knows what is it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&lt;/a&gt;" id="735587018" latitude="51.496474" license="1" longitude="-0.142757" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="london britain england uk unitedkingdom greatbritain britishisles 2007 d50 nikon nikdond50 city capital travel littleben victoria bestof best squashyfrog squashyfrogphotography koltregaskes koltregaskescom squasyfrogcom koltregaskesdeviantartcom blogsquashyfrogcom kolin tregaskes" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1277/735587018_132eaa58bf_b.jpg" username="Kol Tregaskes" views="270" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-18 16:51:32" description="" id="264376534" latitude="51.496434" license="4" longitude="-0.14272" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="london littleben" title="Little Ben's plaque" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/110/264376534_caba8dc1e5_b.jpg" username="brianteutsch" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-18 16:51:17" description="" id="264375883" latitude="51.496434" license="4" longitude="-0.14272" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="london littleben clock" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/94/264375883_349535e38f_b.jpg" username="brianteutsch" views="49" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-15 11:34:41" description="Victoria" id="6152511871" latitude="51.495572" license="3" longitude="-0.141534" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="london littleben" title="Clock Tower Housing &quot;Little Ben&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6073/6152511871_2164a0641f_b.jpg" username="Mabacam" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-04-07 13:37:41" description="Little Ben." id="2454266688" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="london england uk april 2008 westminster clock bus tower ben little" title="London_0335" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2346/2454266688_bfb659c8d0_b.jpg" username="Dain Sandoval" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-24 14:17:02" description="" id="3425990159" latitude="51.496372" license="2" longitude="-0.142567" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="cityofwestminster littleben victoria london england uk unitedkingdom" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3364/3425990159_8fe535ac33_b.jpg" username="-AX-" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-28 19:42:09" description="Little Ben" id="8119763326" latitude="51.495258" license="4" longitude="-0.1466" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="littleben london" title="110528_0473" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8333/8119763326_89c4288338_b.jpg" username="Poul-Werner" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-06-05 03:52:43" description="This is little ben, but I don't hink he can ring any bells" id="18851885" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="london london2005" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/15/18851885_ff376db791_b.jpg" username="mollyeh11" views="162" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-10-20 11:34:12" description="Tietoa englanniksi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Ben&quot;&gt;Information in English about Little_Ben&lt;/a&gt;" id="55654595" latitude="51.514297" license="3" longitude="-0.082054" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="london lontoo littleben" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/33/55654595_98e0a2c9ed_b.jpg" username="TimoOK" views="160" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-28 19:39:05" description="Little Ben" id="8119749753" latitude="51.495258" license="4" longitude="-0.1466" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="littleben london victoriastreet england unitedkingdom" title="110528_0470" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8191/8119749753_111e476ea1_b.jpg" username="Poul-Werner" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-07-31 10:16:27" description="" id="203096516" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="london ben" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/61/203096516_fb68056f52_b.jpg" username="GuruAnt" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-28 09:35:41" description="Back in October, few days before leaving, some friends of mine in London gave me this as goodbye present. Now I have a little London in my house, great memory." id="4223099505" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="9" rank="46" tags="little london city muji bigben bttower royalalberthall gherkin londoneye" title="Little London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4043/4223099505_fc61719fcb_b.jpg" username="dirac3000" views="94" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-19 12:27:57" description="One Day in London. All of these pictures were taken on my first trip from Uxbridge into the center of London, taken 19/9/06." id="248170305" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="london eye england ferris wheel" title="London's Eye, and A little Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/83/248170305_f7d7f6a64e_b.jpg" username="Benjamin Pender" views="69" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-23 10:33:22" description="" id="636546759" latitude="51.49652" license="4" longitude="-0.1428" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="london" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1110/636546759_4ba7cfc134_b.jpg" username="Marcin Chady" views="23" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-28 08:10:25" description="The square near Victoria station" id="235364374" latitude="51.500902" license="4" longitude="-0.143079" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="london" title="Little Ben?" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/89/235364374_f51a73ed48_b.jpg" username="tobiashm" views="90" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-22 13:15:51" description="London" id="6748181135" latitude="51.508502" license="1" longitude="-0.128059" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="london england uk trafalgarsquare nelsons column sky clouds bw bigben" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7026/6748181135_33c5811802_b.jpg" username="Bjørn Giesenbauer" views="70" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-02 12:19:55" description="" id="771917748" latitude="51.49656" license="1" longitude="-0.143004" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="london blighty" title="Little Ben?" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1020/771917748_fac5fb093d_b.jpg" username="moacirpdsp" views="21" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-04-29 11:38:43" description="More Big Ben models than anyone could reasonably need. Someone presumably buys them, but I'm not sure who." id="3637734061" latitude="51.510278" license="1" longitude="-0.134711" nbComments="2" rank="52" tags="london gift tat souvenir big ben clock parliament tower england uk westminster" title="Little Bens" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3617/3637734061_d4d99157cd_b.jpg" username="Nick Treby" views="100" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-24 13:07:45" description="" id="1387290226" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="londra agosto london" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1051/1387290226_49ed423f87_b.jpg" username="PB-rock" views="18" />
<photo  date_taken="2002-07-30 23:19:19" description="" id="1252584074" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="london" title="Little Ben and Victoria Station" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1030/1252584074_be939598c9_b.jpg" username="anthonyjhicks" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-09 11:45:50" description="" id="539676817" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="london clock victoria littleben" title="Little Ben?" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1315/539676817_05dfb84839_b.jpg" username="simplebitsdan" views="290" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-04-15 17:47:08" description="Took this picture in the shop... the lowest form of stealing." id="129509080" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="4" rank="56" tags="london gherkin 30stmaryaxe londoneye bigben england" title="Little London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/43/129509080_dd051a45fe_b.jpg" username="Olly Farrell" views="157" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-06-26 18:52:08" description="" id="6257178830" latitude="51.448818" license="3" longitude="-0.107202" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="london southlondon brockwellpark lambeth flickr" title="&quot;Little Ben&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6041/6257178830_d8505c1873_b.jpg" username="Pgd" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-11-13 13:25:31" description="Walking Big Ben, seen the Lord Mayor's Show in London." id="5196315690" latitude="51.516067" license="4" longitude="-0.10151" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="unitedkingdom england london lordmayorsshow2010 bigben walk" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4129/5196315690_bbbccb7841_b.jpg" username="Ariaski" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 16:33:26" description="" id="283799305" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="59" tags="london" title="Big Ben, Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/117/283799305_266dcab21f_b.jpg" username="Benjamin Pender" views="30" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-01-01 00:57:40" description="Little Ben (seriously)." id="29395587" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="london europetrip old" title="london" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/22/29395587_29a9d3d36a_b.jpg" username="dfyoung" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-14 13:31:54" description="" id="248449980" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="london bigben street" title="little ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/88/248449980_276554225c_b.jpg" username="dog on wheels" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-12 05:32:12" description="" id="2724883825" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="london england europe" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3115/2724883825_9c8b23aba9_b.jpg" username="jasonippolito" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-12 05:31:58" description="" id="2725702878" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="london england europe" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3102/2725702878_aed69abf0c_b.jpg" username="jasonippolito" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-31 14:56:41" description="Awww" id="242392956" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="2006londonholiday londonbustour" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/88/242392956_c6c192ea5e_b.jpg" username="EmerandSam" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-26 20:50:21" description="" id="3972060885" latitude="51.496681" license="1" longitude="-0.142028" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="london uk unitedkingdom 2009 travel" title="Little Ben‎" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3513/3972060885_fae5196c5a_b.jpg" username="czechian" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-11 12:31:00" description="" id="145273197" latitude="51.500955" license="3" longitude="-0.124347" nbComments="0" rank="66" tags="35mm londoneye london bigben ds:camera=eos30" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/47/145273197_1c85e2bb5f_b.jpg" username="Dave Smith" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-10-03 10:18:18" description="" id="6266109341" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="67" tags="uk ireland globus republicofireland london england" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6153/6266109341_cf5fb0d87b_b.jpg" username="bcostin" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-12-19 18:08:15" description="" id="418566812" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="68" tags="vacation london england britain uk" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/174/418566812_679fa5e354_b.jpg" username="alkasesser" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-04 00:00:00" description="&lt;i&gt;My hands you may retard or may advance my heart beats true for England as for France.&lt;/i&gt;" id="1441516818" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="clock weathervane london england britain unitedkingdom europe" title="Little Ben (p9040913)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1007/1441516818_1ccfad319c_b.jpg" username="uzvards" views="32" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-04 10:23:04" description="" id="4519412018" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="70" tags="040410 london westminster easter" title="04042010 - 010 Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2584/4519412018_f8f9f6670b_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="0" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-04 10:23:18" description="" id="4518777005" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="71" tags="040410 london westminster easter" title="04042010 - 011 Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2730/4518777005_e9c0c3d9e2_b.jpg" username="failing_angel" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-04 16:45:30" description="A little monkey Ben and I saw at London Zoo when we took a trip. &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/spots/23672&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;gowalla.com/spots/23672&lt;/a&gt; There are more photos from this one, coming in the new year." id="4218872138" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="72" tags="2009yip 3652 project3661 monkey londonzoo gowalla zoo london gowalla:spot=23672" title="2009YIP/247 London Zoo" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2694/4218872138_8a1db899cc_b.jpg" username="angelsk" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-25 11:30:27" description="" id="2863903018" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="73" tags="london benhawksworth stephenhawksworth bigben saintsephenstower" title="Big Ben, Little Ben, Saint Stephen, Stephen" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3185/2863903018_41c67ce34e_b.jpg" username="Phil Hawksworth" views="46" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-25 15:51:41" description="" id="2188502468" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="74" tags="londres inglaterra london uk" title="O Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2414/2188502468_c22d6408e7_b.jpg" username="Capitu" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-04 16:43:37" description="Taken on the Thames beach" id="2093860966" latitude="51.503934" license="1" longitude="-0.119819" nbComments="2" rank="75" tags="thames beach bed river london south bank night urban available light tungsten 20mm low tide dark evening big ben parliament bridge jubilee hungerford" title="Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2116/2093860966_dae8dfeb3d_b.jpg" username="Rooney." views="147" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-02-16 04:22:12" description="Escapada flash a Londres" id="3215748575" latitude="51.508012" license="3" longitude="-0.125055" nbComments="0" rank="76" tags="londres london viaje escapada" title="Con el Little Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3441/3215748575_b9e161f11a_b.jpg" username="Engel Serón" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-12 11:50:55" description="" id="6985533271" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="77" tags="ben bus public transport london girl friend sleeping little fists staring pram orange prams bentot" title="." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7188/6985533271_26381929c9_b.jpg" username="Martino's doodles" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-24 07:52:41" description="" id="4854499362" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="78" tags="london uk bigben" title="Little Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4082/4854499362_df0d318d42_b.jpg" username="awsandlight" views="27" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-07 11:47:09" description="" id="322249148" latitude="51.503667" license="3" longitude="-0.120077" nbComments="0" rank="79" tags="london trip 2006 december" title="little big ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/126/322249148_d2952a0748_b.jpg" username="simontingle74" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-16 10:53:18" description="three little men working on it" id="1309420009" latitude="51.507032" license="1" longitude="-0.182647" nbComments="0" rank="80" tags="london bigben" title="ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1418/1309420009_6f489cdc06_b.jpg" username="pacamanca" views="34" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-29 20:34:48" description="And I also saw some more things on the Southbank" id="2632486848" latitude="51.506151" license="2" longitude="-0.114669" nbComments="0" rank="81" tags="southbank andisaw southbankandisaw ispy hideandseek bigben hideandseekfest2008 londoneye bigwheel andialsosaw" title="Little Big Ben and the London Eye" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3024/2632486848_bc9a1d1263_b.jpg" username="angelsk" views="21" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-25 01:40:34" description="" id="4988663347" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="82" tags="julian toddler london bigben" title="Little Julian, Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4087/4988663347_936c243f1b_b.jpg" username="GrahamKing" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-14 12:16:29" description="" id="4014305072" latitude="51.500461" license="3" longitude="-0.124368" nbComments="0" rank="83" tags="london" title="Little K at Big Ben!" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3481/4014305072_ed3245366e_b.jpg" username="caldjr" views="0" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-18 14:15:25" description="Little Ben." id="2874156450" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="84" tags="mondayne london" title="P1000288.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3072/2874156450_a9ac5a961f_b.jpg" username="Mondayne" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-06-29 05:47:48" description="Little Ben- given by French merchants (if I rem. correctly) as a gift for Charles &amp;amp; Diana's wedding." id="180689752" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="85" tags="london" title="IMG_7555" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/57/180689752_e576d229e8_b.jpg" username="lizdance14" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-29 20:31:52" description="I took this at mid-day at Southbank near the London Eye (I stopped down a little.) Big Ben is on the right, and Parliament is the attached building to the left. Westminster Bridge is visible to the far left." id="3152069268" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="86" tags="london parliament unitedkingdom england bigben cityscapes skyline" title="London has great light" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3231/3152069268_b2f8acf6d1_b.jpg" username="Jen Bowman" views="45" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-04-09 12:25:24" description="By Bryony Knox" id="8875313" latitude="51.521708" license="4" longitude="-0.07214" nbComments="0" rank="87" tags="redbull artofcan exhibition oldtrumanbrewery bricklane london can art artwork bigben" title="Little Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8/8875313_c6ec79d38e_b.jpg" username="coda" views="3312" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-25 16:43:16" description="Little Brooker" id="4046208502" latitude="51.510746" license="5" longitude="-0.098362" nbComments="0" rank="88" tags="bigben brookmorgan london street" title="Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2633/4046208502_77ece50dfb_b.jpg" username="San Sharma" views="45" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-08 15:09:02" description="I don't normally post personal pix much but I had such fun shooting my friends and their little ones I had to post. Great soft winter light - amazing colours. I'm loving what I'm getting from the vintage Angenieux cinema lens. Also, finally confirmed what I've suspected long time - flickr's resize is rubbish. Uploading a pre-sized pix is much better! I just never bothered to get it sorted. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighugelabs.com/flickr/onblack.php?id=4094291245&amp;amp;size=large&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View On Black&lt;/a&gt;" id="4094291245" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="7" rank="89" tags="people portraits leica m8 angenieux 50mmf18types2 cinemalens london uk england" title="Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2669/4094291245_cd5a127473_b.jpg" username="Glass&amp;Tubes" views="317" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-18 08:55:48" description="Little Ben" id="148931563" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="90" tags="london england" title="dscf5492" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/46/148931563_0838fb38a3_b.jpg" username="Mr. Pi" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-29 23:10:45" description="" id="1298541142" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="91" tags="lexianddavesweddingengland london" title="uncle ben plays with desirée" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1419/1298541142_fa1916e957_b.jpg" username="bess grant" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-23 22:19:24" description="Needed a bit more distance or little less focal length than my Sigma 18-50mm to get the whole thing in. Oh well. Terrible weather didn't help the cause, either." id="3131706955" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="92" tags="london travel" title="Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3289/3131706955_3bc91eff75_b.jpg" username="Dr. RawheaD" views="86" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-16 11:45:32" description="" id="3794908039" latitude="51.500882" license="5" longitude="-0.124711" nbComments="0" rank="93" tags="uk london england travel tourism july2009 709 traveling tour touris holiday britan british english unitedkingdom angleterre parliament bigben houseofcommons westminsterpalace whitehall houseofcommonslibrary houseoflords eeyore eeyoresgloomyadventures travelingtoys littlefriendsaroundtheworld summer 2009 july united kingdom britian gloomy adventure donkey blue toy britain londres inghilterra anglaterra англия inglaterra lloegr" title="Eeyore says hello from Big Ben, Whitehall, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3450/3794908039_68e2d318a9_b.jpg" username="nikoretro" views="52" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-12-28 16:30:40" description="In fabulous surroundings at the Caledonian Hotel in Edinburgh, Ben and Caroline were just married a short time ago. All went pretty smoothly, that is apart from Ben getting a little tongue tied during the vows! The ceremony was finished off by all the women watching blowing bubbles instead of confetti. All in all wonderfull. Where's that glass of Champagne I had five minutes ago..." id="78521316" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="94" tags="dcinput moblog nottinghill carnival london hrefhttptechnoraticomtagmoblogmoblog abrbrfrom mobile" title="Ben and Caroline tie the knott" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/42/78521316_db9510d9c4_b.jpg" username="dcinput" views="304" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-11-19 16:55:05" description="Sunset over the London Skyline. On the far left is the London Eye and a little to the right of it the Palace of Westminster with the Big Ben." id="6364716979" latitude="51.508341" license="3" longitude="-0.116772" nbComments="0" rank="95" tags="london skyline sunset silhouette eye thames westminster big ben" title="London Skyline Silhouette" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6105/6364716979_84668eeee3_b.jpg" username="npmeijer" views="364" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-18 19:47:08" description="Smiling a little too ;)" id="2952386705" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="96" tags="me brettcook bigben london" title="Me by Big Ben Looking Drunk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3059/2952386705_e1ac5b48f3_b.jpg" username="BuhSnarf" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-06-17 01:47:27" description="I really should learn to hold the camera straight. For some reason my pictures always lean a little to the right. Unlike my politics. Ba dum bump!" id="170630712" latitude="51.500441" license="4" longitude="-0.123864" nbComments="0" rank="97" tags="bigben london england uk" title="Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/48/170630712_a44321d39f_b.jpg" username="Dano" views="96" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-02-27 04:22:47" description="U might the see the street lights are still on. quite dark. I took it with a little high exposure and slow speed so that i can catch the movement of the spray from the fountain." id="4398994582" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="98" tags="london bigben thames stthomashospital" title="Morning at London!! Black and white" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4023/4398994582_933d0b9ce4_b.jpg" username="Pavel ahmed" views="149" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-06-02 03:03:54" description="A little better view as we walked down the street." id="23059388" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="99" tags="london england uk honeymoon bigben" title="Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/18/23059388_d1035036c5_b.jpg" username="Christine ™" views="190" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-11-07 12:45:27" description="Found a great little free browser app that makes fake Tilt-Shift pics. Try it at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiltshiftmaker.com&quot;&gt;tiltshiftmaker.com&lt;/a&gt;" id="3495174060" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="100" tags="london bigben housesofpaliament tiltshift rumpleproofskin aerial westminster abbey thames" title="Aerial London Tilt Shifted" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3570/3495174060_695dddc9ab_b.jpg" username="Del Adams" views="364" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-17 03:41:15" description="Big Ben is the nickname of the great bell of the clock at the north end of the Palace of Westminster. It's a little over 150 years old." id="5982595013" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="101" tags="london england 2011 bigben" title="Top of Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6029/5982595013_f85fe95707_b.jpg" username="Sam Fam" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-23 18:03:27" description="Sneaky peek at little Ben :)" id="401313757" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="102" tags="bigben londoneye london" title="scan0114" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/181/401313757_8474ffd24d_b.jpg" username="Yuen-Hui" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-03-15 19:57:43" description="Arriving from the London City Airport after a little bit more than a 1 hour flight from Zuerich. The next level. A one hour London taxi cab drive trough the busy commuter traffic... perfect timing within the twilight (night and day). Enjoy :-) - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickriver.com/photos/yjv/popular-interesting/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Flickr Interesting&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yago1.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.yago1.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/yago1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/yago1photography&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;" id="5550361920" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="103" tags="bigben london taxi cab yago1 canon eos5d uk england twilight 2011" title="London Taxi cab #30 big ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5294/5550361920_879c8c4e9c_b.jpg" username="yago1.com" views="164" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-05 13:23:33" description="" id="1466011202" latitude="51.499469" license="1" longitude="-0.12757" nbComments="1" rank="104" tags="littlecloister cloister bigben westminsterabbey londonenglanduk londonengland london westminster cathedralofstphilipchoirtour panasonic lumix dmcfz50 fz50" title="Little Cloister and Big Ben/St. Stephen's Tower/Clock Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1254/1466011202_00403c71ef_b.jpg" username="MaestroBen" views="53" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-03-15 19:57:47" description="EOS 5D Mark II | 1/25 | f/4.0 | 24 mm | ISO 800 - Arriving from the London City Airport after a little bit more than a 1 hour flight from Zuerich. The next level. A one hour London taxi cab drive trough the busy commuter traffic... perfect timing within the twilight (night and day). Enjoy :-) - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickriver.com/photos/yjv/popular-interesting/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Flickr Interesting&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yago1.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.yago1.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/yago1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/yago1photography&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;" id="5549853731" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="105" tags="bigben england london taxi cab yago1 canon eos5d uk twilight 2011" title="London Taxi cab #31 big ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5012/5549853731_5a993d8b29_b.jpg" username="yago1.com" views="136" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-19 20:16:44" description="I got this set of mini London landmarks made of wood from my cousin, Rachel, when I went to stay with her in December as a little present so that I could have my own London when I am away from London. It's on my bedside table (sadly, not set up in the actual 'locations' of where they should be because they kept getting knocked about) with some other London paraphernalia! I'm feeling relatively relaxed for tomorrow, may I continue to feel this relaxed about exams in the future! &lt;i&gt;Jessica Keating © All rights reserved. It is illegal to use this image without my written permission. If you would like to use it then message or email me to agree terms.&lt;/i&gt;" id="6727251549" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="106" tags="minilondon sepia macro londoneye bigben miniature models" title="Day 166 - Mini London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7003/6727251549_433b4697ce_b.jpg" username="Jessica Keating Photography" views="53" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-06-29 12:57:33" description="A little shadowy. Could use some adjustment but I'm not the one to do it." id="5931369851" latitude="51.500514" license="2" longitude="-0.126557" nbComments="0" rank="107" tags="bigben london england greatbritain scenic uk unitedkingdom southbank westminsterabbey housesofparliament" title="Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6127/5931369851_72df56681c_b.jpg" username="firepile" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-03-23 17:37:15" description="A lot of history and charm to this old 50s coffeehouse along Old Brompton Road. Besides these old pots and pans hanging from the ceiling and on their walls, they have a lot of other antiques on display as well. And of course, the breakfast was excellent! A little more about this coffeehouse (taken from the Troubadour website): The Troubadour is a proper café. The last 50s coffee house in Earls Court with a proud history as a low temperature centre of courtesy, peace and artistic energy. One review called the Troubadour &amp;quot;the best eatery West of Big Ben&amp;quot;. Downstairs is the Club where Jimi Hendrix, Joni Mitchell, Bob Dylan and Paul Simon all played in the '60s." id="2357631520" latitude="51.489767" license="3" longitude="-0.189042" nbComments="1" rank="108" tags="fuji f30 troubadour london old brompton coffeehouse 1950s antiques" title="Pots and Pans and Other Old Stuff @ Troubadour, London." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3165/2357631520_e979b2fcf1_b.jpg" username="Yiping Lim" views="791" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-11-04 21:21:12" description="Spent several hours at the BFI library for my dissertation, took my camera along to get some shots, sadly I was too tired to get anything decent, the colour version of this shot is horrific. This isn't much better to be honest. Disappointing, but I shouldn't have been so optimistic I could've got amazing shots on such little sleep after a long day." id="5146839489" latitude="51.505951" license="3" longitude="-0.120077" nbComments="15" rank="109" tags="greater central bridge london eye river thames big ben houses parliament adams black white bw schtumple canon eos 550d kiss x4 long exposure night" title="London Eye, Thames &amp; Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4066/5146839489_1b6357a608_b.jpg" username="Ben K Adams" views="384" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-04-26 13:14:17" description="" id="2486315620" latitude="51.500581" license="1" longitude="-0.120077" nbComments="0" rank="110" tags="luc parliament amis architecture building friends people vrienden london england unitedkingdom" title="Big Ben and Little Luc" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3053/2486315620_f6fec2017f_b.jpg" username="plαdys" views="21" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-21 18:32:00" description="very little editing (cropping)" id="2965577868" latitude="51.500868" license="2" longitude="-0.126235" nbComments="2" rank="111" tags="europe greatbritain londres london parliament thames bigben thethames londoneye nightlight" title="dusk on Big Ben" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3289/2965577868_260ea1bb31_b.jpg" username="Pierre Metivier" views="91" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-01 16:35:18" description="Tourisme à Londres" id="3340684933" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="112" tags="london londres voyage city ville town england" title="Big Ben and Little Marie-Odile" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3378/3340684933_c75e836d06_b.jpg" username="luc legay" views="59" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-04-26 12:54:26" description="135mm lens" id="135519410" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="113" tags="zenit westminster park london fountain bigben clock" title="Little Sanctuary" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/51/135519410_d0e8373b2b_b.jpg" username="sarboo" views="112" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-17 21:36:47" description="ZoneTag: &lt;a href=&quot;http://zonetag.research.yahoo.com/photos/index.php?flickrname=Flickmor&quot;&gt;Photosphere&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;http://zonetag.research.yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Owner only&lt;/i&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://zonetag.research.yahoo.com/setLocation.php?flickrid=561709590&quot;&gt;Fix Location&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a target=&quot;popup&quot; href=&quot;http://zonetag.research.yahoo.com/suggestedtags.php?flickrid=561709590&quot;&gt;Add Tags&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;http://zonetag.research.yahoo.com/myzonetag.php&quot;&gt;Settings&lt;/a&gt; A little fuzzy, but it is a cameraphone..." id="561709590" latitude="51.500983" license="2" longitude="-0.125216" nbComments="0" rank="114" tags="zonetag cameraphone london unitedkingdom geotagged geo:lat=515009833333 geo:long=0125216666667 celltagged cell:cgi=234201079134274634 bigben underground tube tower westminster night sign" title="Is this a classic London shot or what?" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1226/561709590_a552bd7e7d_b.jpg" username="Flickmor" views="126" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-17 09:51:13" description="" id="330940525" latitude="51.524124" license="3" longitude="-0.109863" nbComments="1" rank="115" tags="geotagged gnome gnomad ninpi mrninpi" title="Big with Little Gnomad" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/154/330940525_1875155e61_b.jpg" username="SageE." views="75" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-19 19:33:14" description="a little surprising as it was so hot in the day !" id="3368236205" latitude="51.525386" license="3" longitude="-0.056508" nbComments="0" rank="116" tags="bazaart london graffiti stencil kguy benslow blam" title="it was a bit nippy at bazzart" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3432/3368236205_f594a4e1ec_b.jpg" username="Leeks" views="54" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-07-23 21:10:39" description="With a little drama and colour in sky. Canon 5d 24-70 @ 27mm Lee GND 0.9 + 0.75 soft grads Slik Sprint Pro 2 tripod" id="5976378132" latitude="51.49974" license="4" longitude="-0.123982" nbComments="2" rank="117" tags="westminster housesofparliament bigben london uk lambeth waterloo thames england gnd leefilters slik canon 5d" title="Houses of Parliament at dusk, London, UK" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6135/5976378132_d92dd448e3_b.jpg" username="hozinja" views="2917" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-11 23:06:02" description="Will and Trev Olympus Pen EE3 + Fuji Provia 100F + xpro" id="3522910133" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="118" tags="xpro animationstudio animators peppapigstudio olympuspenee3 london peppapiganimators crossprocessed stjamesssquare littlekingdom olympuspen halfframecamera halfframe benandhollyslittlekingdom fujiprovia100f peppapig lunchinstjamessquare picnic willandtrev" title="picnic lunch" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3550/3522910133_c7bdd06615_b.jpg" username="slimmer_jimmer" views="158" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-04-16 19:14:47" description="" id="165169796" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="119" tags="uk london bigben ststephenstower housesofparliament damien" title="Big Ben, Little Damien" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/45/165169796_28ba8ec744_b.jpg" username="metamoof" views="80" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-11-12 12:09:18" description="Impressive the old archtecture and even the little older Big Ben in the background, rising high above the typical London chimneys. (Taken with: Canon EOS 40D - 1/125 s, f/6.4, 92 mm, ISO 250) More about me: &lt;a href=&quot;\&quot; target=&quot;\&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Photo-Stream&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;\&quot; target=&quot;\&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Web-Site&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;\&quot; target=&quot;\&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;" id="5231285365" latitude="51.502091" license="3" longitude="-0.12645" nbComments="0" rank="120" tags="city kurzurlaub london metropole stadt urlaub vacation england greatbritain public rating4 meironke canoneos40d cityofwestminster grosbritannien gbr stjamessward" title="Old meets older" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5081/5231285365_bb860debe7_b.jpg" username="meironke" views="21" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-17 18:58:33" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chadstoneshopping.com.au/event.aspx?id=19024&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Runway Show - Chadstone: The Fashion Capital&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Fashion Capital will be showcasing all the must have Autumn/Winter 2010 trends from your favorite designers and labels at the VIP Shopping &amp;amp; Fashion Party, Wednesday March 17th. Runway Show A 6:30pm Wednesday March 17 Discover key Autumn/Winter 2010 directions from international and Australian designers including ck Calvin Klein, Coach, Fleur Wood, Gorman, Hugo Boss, Jimmy Choo, Lisa Ho, Little Joe, and more. Runway Show B 8:30pm Wednesday March 17 Featuring the finest winter weekend collections from Ben Sherman, Calibre, FAT, G-Star, White Suede and other renowned local designers. Both shows will be held on the lower level in Chadstone's new mall.&lt;/i&gt;" id="4445481904" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="121" tags="tedbakelondon tedbaker chadstoneshoppingcentre chadstonethefashioncapital chadstonevic chadstone vic fashionshow runwayshow lmff2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival2010 melbournefashionfestival2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival melbournefashionfestival autumnwinter2010 fashion model catwalk runway" title="Sign - Ted Baker, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2782/4445481904_a78d0e0ff6_b.jpg" username="avlxyz" views="185" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-05-11 23:05:57" description="Will, Boris and Boris. Olympus Pen EE3 + Fuji Provia 100F + xpro" id="3522909945" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="122" tags="xpro animationstudio animators peppapigstudio olympuspenee3 london peppapiganimators crossprocessed regentsstreet littlekingdom olympuspen halfframecamera halfframe benandhollyslittlekingdom fujiprovia100f peppapig hackett firealarm willandboris" title="fire alarm" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3622/3522909945_93b2c78ffa_b.jpg" username="slimmer_jimmer" views="216" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-03-25 16:51:37" description="I like the way the London Eye looms over this shot of the South Bank. I had to place around in Lightbox to make the sky a little less washed out grey and that provided a nice contrasting background to the wheel." id="434330415" latitude="51.504919" license="3" longitude="-0.118789" nbComments="0" rank="123" tags="south bank crowd london eye house parliament big ben riverside thames" title="The South Bank and London Eye" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/184/434330415_ebb336d43d_b.jpg" username="neilsphotoalbum" views="65" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-11-10 14:56:41" description="It's a little bit blurry... but Big Ben sucks anyway." id="64005038" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="124" tags="london bigben underground touristy" title="WARNING: Stock Tourist Photo" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/34/64005038_eff9ade05e_b.jpg" username="Travis Nicholson!" views="101" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-17 18:59:20" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chadstoneshopping.com.au/event.aspx?id=19024&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Runway Show - Chadstone: The Fashion Capital&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Fashion Capital will be showcasing all the must have Autumn/Winter 2010 trends from your favorite designers and labels at the VIP Shopping &amp;amp; Fashion Party, Wednesday March 17th. Runway Show A 6:30pm Wednesday March 17 Discover key Autumn/Winter 2010 directions from international and Australian designers including ck Calvin Klein, Coach, Fleur Wood, Gorman, Hugo Boss, Jimmy Choo, Lisa Ho, Little Joe, and more. Runway Show B 8:30pm Wednesday March 17 Featuring the finest winter weekend collections from Ben Sherman, Calibre, FAT, G-Star, White Suede and other renowned local designers. Both shows will be held on the lower level in Chadstone's new mall.&lt;/i&gt;" id="4444711801" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="125" tags="tedbakelondon tedbaker chadstoneshoppingcentre chadstonethefashioncapital chadstonevic chadstone vic fashionshow runwayshow lmff2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival2010 melbournefashionfestival2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival melbournefashionfestival autumnwinter2010 fashion model catwalk runway" title="Grey trenchcoat - Ted Baker, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4019/4444711801_870979e9b3_b.jpg" username="avlxyz" views="381" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-31 13:55:07" description="" id="1342711005" latitude="51.500989" license="1" longitude="-0.123617" nbComments="0" rank="126" tags="londoneyebigbenparliamentlondonenglandlondon unitedkingdomlondonenglandunitedkingdomcathedralofstphilipchoirtourpanasoniclumixdmcfz50fz50 londoneye bigben parliament londonengland london england londonenglanduk panasonic lumix dmcfz50 fz50 cathedralofstphilipchoirtour" title="Little help" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1282/1342711005_10c88f6225_b.jpg" username="MaestroBen" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-17 18:59:23" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chadstoneshopping.com.au/event.aspx?id=19024&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Runway Show - Chadstone: The Fashion Capital&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Fashion Capital will be showcasing all the must have Autumn/Winter 2010 trends from your favorite designers and labels at the VIP Shopping &amp;amp; Fashion Party, Wednesday March 17th. Runway Show A 6:30pm Wednesday March 17 Discover key Autumn/Winter 2010 directions from international and Australian designers including ck Calvin Klein, Coach, Fleur Wood, Gorman, Hugo Boss, Jimmy Choo, Lisa Ho, Little Joe, and more. Runway Show B 8:30pm Wednesday March 17 Featuring the finest winter weekend collections from Ben Sherman, Calibre, FAT, G-Star, White Suede and other renowned local designers. Both shows will be held on the lower level in Chadstone's new mall.&lt;/i&gt;" id="4445482738" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="127" tags="tedbakelondon tedbaker chadstoneshoppingcentre chadstonethefashioncapital chadstonevic chadstone vic fashionshow runwayshow lmff2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival2010 melbournefashionfestival2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival melbournefashionfestival autumnwinter2010 fashion model catwalk runway" title="Grey suit - Ted Baker, London - blurred" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4020/4445482738_3e9c119757_b.jpg" username="avlxyz" views="226" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-09 11:12:13" description="" id="2100620594" latitude="51.513969" license="3" longitude="-0.128384" nbComments="6" rank="128" tags="benward monkey ape rar headphones yahoo yahooeurope yahoolondon gizusanana" title="Going a Little Ape" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2228/2100620594_5b2306e9ae_b.jpg" username="Ben Ward" views="82" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-16 11:45:26" description="" id="3795729358" latitude="51.500882" license="5" longitude="-0.124711" nbComments="0" rank="129" tags="uk london england travel tourism july2009 709 traveling tour touris holiday britan british english unitedkingdom angleterre parliament bigben houseofcommons westminsterpalace whitehall houseofcommonslibrary houseoflords eeyore eeyoresgloomyadventures travelingtoys littlefriendsaroundtheworld summer 2009 july united kingdom britian donkey blue toy adventure gloomy britain londres plush soft inghilterra anglaterra англия inglaterra lloegr" title="Compared to Eeyore Big Ben is VERY BIG! Whitehall, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2440/3795729358_9c5b498d47_b.jpg" username="nikoretro" views="46" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-31 17:19:37" description="The only thing to possibly improve upon this would be ERII poking her head out from behind the roundel wearing a policeman's helmet and waving a little English flag. (HDR exposure technique)" id="4524370200" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="130" tags="london england underground towerofwestminster parliament bigbenisonlytheclock tube erii unionjack bobbie helmet stereotypes howmanysymbolscanyoushoveinoneimagewithoutusingphotoshop" title="No Icon Left Behind; Westminster, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4030/4524370200_587cb28fa9_b.jpg" username="I am I.A.M." views="74" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-07-23 21:02:21" description="This was taken on our first full day in London. When you are up that high overlooking the city (and The City, is it were), you really get a feel for how so many people can live in such a small area, especially since hardly none of the buildings in this shot are over six stories high. Look at how close the roads are to the buildings and look at how little space there is between buildings. It really put things in perspective when you think about how wide Whitemud Drive is, for example. Notes in photo." id="196774859" latitude="51.51391" license="1" longitude="-0.098286" nbComments="0" rank="131" tags="vacation uk london" title="Panorama from St Paul's" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/67/196774859_44057ee13c_b.jpg" username="robertwmartin" views="68" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-26 01:34:54" description="" id="8045498575" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="132" tags="london uk greatbritain england streetsign westminster britain cityofwestminster bigben antjenuk sign canonef50mmf14usm" title="Little Sanctuary" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8310/8045498575_7d02981ac7_b.jpg" username="NotoriousJEN" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-17 18:58:49" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chadstoneshopping.com.au/event.aspx?id=19024&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Runway Show - Chadstone: The Fashion Capital&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Fashion Capital will be showcasing all the must have Autumn/Winter 2010 trends from your favorite designers and labels at the VIP Shopping &amp;amp; Fashion Party, Wednesday March 17th. Runway Show A 6:30pm Wednesday March 17 Discover key Autumn/Winter 2010 directions from international and Australian designers including ck Calvin Klein, Coach, Fleur Wood, Gorman, Hugo Boss, Jimmy Choo, Lisa Ho, Little Joe, and more. Runway Show B 8:30pm Wednesday March 17 Featuring the finest winter weekend collections from Ben Sherman, Calibre, FAT, G-Star, White Suede and other renowned local designers. Both shows will be held on the lower level in Chadstone's new mall.&lt;/i&gt;" id="4445482116" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="133" tags="tedbakelondon tedbaker chadstoneshoppingcentre chadstonethefashioncapital chadstonevic chadstone vic fashionshow runwayshow lmff2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival2010 melbournefashionfestival2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival melbournefashionfestival autumnwinter2010 fashion model catwalk runway" title="Black leather jacket, red blouse - Ted Baker, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2515/4445482116_7c15f2c9a5_b.jpg" username="avlxyz" views="429" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-17 18:59:03" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chadstoneshopping.com.au/event.aspx?id=19024&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Runway Show - Chadstone: The Fashion Capital&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Fashion Capital will be showcasing all the must have Autumn/Winter 2010 trends from your favorite designers and labels at the VIP Shopping &amp;amp; Fashion Party, Wednesday March 17th. Runway Show A 6:30pm Wednesday March 17 Discover key Autumn/Winter 2010 directions from international and Australian designers including ck Calvin Klein, Coach, Fleur Wood, Gorman, Hugo Boss, Jimmy Choo, Lisa Ho, Little Joe, and more. Runway Show B 8:30pm Wednesday March 17 Featuring the finest winter weekend collections from Ben Sherman, Calibre, FAT, G-Star, White Suede and other renowned local designers. Both shows will be held on the lower level in Chadstone's new mall.&lt;/i&gt;" id="4444711601" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="134" tags="tedbakelondon tedbaker chadstoneshoppingcentre chadstonethefashioncapital chadstonevic chadstone vic fashionshow runwayshow lmff2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival2010 melbournefashionfestival2010 lorealmelbournefashionfestival melbournefashionfestival autumnwinter2010 fashion model catwalk runway" title="Black leather jacket, red blouse - close-up - Ted Baker, London" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4063/4444711601_b8ee45f598_b.jpg" username="avlxyz" views="334" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-07-08 16:42:14" description="this was a yummmy friendly little place not far from bens" id="185405025" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="135" tags="london cute yummy" title="dinner" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/73/185405025_82af96180a_b.jpg" username="icyFrance" views="33" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-04-26 14:27:06" description="" id="2450267260" latitude="51.504161" license="1" longitude="-0.119218" nbComments="0" rank="136" tags="mylittlepony mlp london peachy" title="Peachy by the Millennium Wheel" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2419/2450267260_e0b01cda17_b.jpg" username="linniekin" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-07 17:43:29" description="Vivitar Ultra Wide and Slim + Lomo LCA (shot upside down) + Kodak Elitechrome 100 + xpro From the press / preview days at Peppa Pig World, at Paultons Park near Southampton. The park opened to the public on Saturday 9th April 2011. I am a Layout Artist on Peppa Pig (I also work on Ben and Holly's Little Kingdom)" id="5696709168" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="137" tags="double xpro kodakelitechrome100 vivitarultrawideandslim toycamera lomolca crossprocessed crossprocessing paultonspark doubleexposure london sign office" title="Peppa Doubles #1 - prototypes" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3257/5696709168_b9ef37dcf8_b.jpg" username="slimmer_jimmer" views="260" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-05 12:08:24" description="Best viewed in Original size for detail (if a little hazy). Seen in: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/exploringphotographybeginners_amateurs/pool&quot;&gt;Exploring Photography : Beginners and Amateurs&lt;/a&gt; This is a truly amazing image (which my photo hardly does justice to). It stretches from the East of London (Canary Wharf) right across to the West (Big Ben) - both of which landmarks can be seen. In between look out for St. Pancras Station, The 'Gherkin' Tower, The NatWest Tower, the dome of St. Paul's Cathedral, Guys Hospital, Bankside Power Station, The Royal Courts of Justice, Euston Centre, Centre Point, The BT Tower, The London Eye, All Saints Church and St. Stevens Tower ('Big Ben'). The green area in the foreground is Primrose Hill, and the structure in the right middle foreground is part of London Zoo. It was worth the climb!!" id="3792872839" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="5" rank="138" tags="london londoneye stpaulscathedral canarywharf bigben centrepoint exploringphotographybeginnersandamateurs londonzoo primrosehill" title="Panorama" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2491/3792872839_5edd687f73_b.jpg" username="canonsnapper" views="105" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-28 19:57:31" description="This was shot in the early evening sun down on the Embankment in London. I dialled in +1 stop on the exposure compensation to brighten it up and to keep the details from the shadows. The shot was taken as wide as my kit lens will go at f/11 to retain detail throughout the shot. I used a circular polariser to keep some richness in the sky. I've tried to use the foreground lampost and tree to frame Big Ben and the Houses of Parliament and to fill the foreground with people walking along the path to help place the user int he photo making them feel like they're there. The only post-processing was a little highlight recovery, a slight crop, and slight white balance adjustment. Focal Length: 43mm (18-55mm kit lens) F'stop: f/11 Shutter Speed: 1/90 sec. ISO: 100 This is one of my candidate photos for the Exposure module of Practical Photography's Digital SLR Skills course (see Set and Collection descriptions). I'd be greatful for your feedback, comments, and reccomendations for submission (the deadline is July 9th)." id="2628144934" latitude="51.504926" license="3" longitude="-0.118789" nbComments="0" rank="139" tags="london embankment thames river bigben parliament exposure" title="Embankment 01" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3006/2628144934_3f928902fb_b.jpg" username="Derek Lakin" views="137" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-04-08 19:58:03" description="I feel I might've gone little overboard playing with RAW" id="3424452539" latitude="51.500888" license="1" longitude="-0.120913" nbComments="2" rank="140" tags="london westminster big ben sunset" title="Westminster at Sunset" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3612/3424452539_acf2f4da09_b.jpg" username="Tommi Komulainen" views="77" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-05-17 18:06:02" description="There's a little peace village been put up in Parliament Square recently. They're pretty inviting people and there's a fair amount to see and read about if you get the chance to head on over." id="4621911521" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="141" tags="london londonist parliamentsquare peace village troops bigben" title="Democracy Village In Parliament Square - 106/365" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4067/4621911521_122407b7e7_b.jpg" username="Simon Wicks" views="118" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-04-10 13:53:39" description="" id="6558797285" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="142" tags="london holiday love british tube gap bigben bricklane portobellord" title="You're a silly little boy!!!!!! i know where are you!" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7024/6558797285_16dfdaa8cb_b.jpg" username="-BerrY-" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-08 06:42:46" description="" id="337028541" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="143" tags="" title="London, England - Big Ben, Big Ben and Little Steph" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/161/337028541_bf136303fb_b.jpg" username="plusgood" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-01 17:31:19" description="Viewed from Little Dorrit Park, off Borough High Street. Originally posted to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/guesswherelondon/&quot;&gt;Guess Where London&lt;/a&gt; group. &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com?q=51.50207107177321,-0.09431451559066772(Disney Place SE1)&amp;amp;t=h&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="212490985" latitude="51.502071" license="1" longitude="-0.094315" nbComments="19" rank="144" tags="yersinia london se1 southwark southlondon disneyplace littledorritpark geo:lat=51502071 geo:lon=0094315 geotagged guessedbybenpatio nst postedbyyersinia zone1 southoftheriver gwl2006 guesswherelondon postcoded se travelcard uk unitedkingdom britain greatbritain europe londonpool inygm england gb eu yuck public safe photographical ccnc londonset se1set southlondonset guessed londonguessed gwlg demolishthis southwarkpool casioexz110 londonboroughcollection" title="Disney Place SE1" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/67/212490985_58a2d44116_b.jpg" username="Yersinia" views="380" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-21 12:04:23" description="TRIP TO LONDON: Up in the London Eye looking at Big Ben" id="3789931608" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="145" tags="gallery sockbunny bunny sock widget rabbit widgetsockbunny" title="Little Spotty Sockbunny's Adventures" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2454/3789931608_56451e7f52_b.jpg" username="The Bunny Maker" views="31" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-04-25 10:12:34" description="It had been 36 hours without sleep, and I was beginning to regret my decision to get tea rather than coffee. Eser Cafe is a greasy little jewel of a cafe in Market Row, Brixton. Back when it was Ergens I used to get breakfast in here most days before jumping on the tube up to college. Photo'd by Ben on the morning of the 25th April 2007, using my cameraphone." id="503785862" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="146" tags="k800i cameraphone esercafe marketrow brixton sw9 tea lambeth londonboroughoflambeth london me insomnia" title="Not-Ergens-Cafe anymore, Brixton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/230/503785862_3c4e4978e2_b.jpg" username="Nicobobinus" views="299" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-24 02:05:33" description="this is a little festive test-batch. (i thought it high time i got a decent printer/scanner/all-in-one affair, especially as at least 3 Christmas presents i'm giving this year depend on me printing digital pics. ok, so maybe it's a little Christmas present to myself, too... this is one of my favourite black &amp;amp; white shots. taken by my old friend Zoe.... we were both developing our passion for photography when we met back in around '99. this must have been taken December '99, I think. We shared so many new discoveries, passions &amp;amp; ideas. You know how sometimes someone sails into your life out of nowhere (and sometimes out again just as fast), you share a short time together - whether mad, intense, easy, as friends, lovers, etc - and it's not until your paths have grown apart again, that you realise what it was all about, why you were meant to cross paths, learn/share/help eachother in whatever way you do... just because.... sorry, philosophising out loud again.... anyway...she was v cool. now living deliriously happily with a lovely chap &amp;amp; gorgeous little baby in Brighton, i'm very glad to say. ben patio &amp;amp; rb - i'm expecting one of you to tag it &amp;quot;guesswhere&amp;quot;! just realised it's the anniversary of this photograph today... how strange." id="331386161" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="5" rank="147" tags="bobcat bobcatrock scanthepast bw blackandwhite thepastissobeautifulthefuturelikeacaptivesnow london christmas old history" title="zoe church (front).jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/155/331386161_68cda5fe25_b.jpg" username="bobcat rock" views="101" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-12 11:43:17" description="" id="4179489124" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="148" tags="chrismas 2009 germanmarket bratwurst police candid telephonebooth phonebox bigben ben big zombie unicycle train bauble horseguards buckinghampalace buckinghamlondon12129 jagerbomb" title="Jagerbomb!... 11am a little too early" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2788/4179489124_9b0d0f12bf_b.jpg" username="Matt Chantry" views="40" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-11-20 21:11:26" description="Our favortite photos from our travels. Center is an elephant from Tanzania shot handheld with the Sigma 55-200 zoom at 200mm (effective focal length: 400mm). Took a little massaging to look good at 20x30, but it worked out." id="2050938825" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="149" tags="interior decoration" title="travel wall" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2323/2050938825_685f0bb6b7_b.jpg" username="jeremiahblatz" views="50" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-28 19:58:32" description="This was shot in the early evening sun down on the Embankment in London. I dialled in +1 stop on the exposure compensation to brighten it up and to keep the details from the shadows. The shot was taken as wide as my kit lens will go at f/11 to retain detail throughout the shot. I used a circular polariser to keep some richness in the sky. I've tried to use the two lamposts to frame Big Ben and the Houses of Parliament as well as using the tree and foreground lampost to frame the picture as a whole. The only post-processing was a little highlight recovery, a slight crop, and slight white balance adjustment. Focal Length: 18mm (18-55mm kit lens) F'stop: f/11 Shutter Speed: 1/60 sec. ISO: 100 This is one of my candidate photos for the Exposure module of Practical Photography's Digital SLR Skills course (see Set and Collection descriptions). I'd be greatful for your feedback, comments, and reccomendations for submission (the deadline is July 9th)." id="2628148902" latitude="51.504926" license="3" longitude="-0.118789" nbComments="0" rank="150" tags="london exposure sunset thames river bigben parliament" title="Embankment" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3116/2628148902_ae8a32a8a3_b.jpg" username="Derek Lakin" views="101" />
</photos>
