<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Rainbow Bridge Utah">

<photo  date_taken="1998-04-05 00:00:09" description="" id="6422209269" latitude="37.079826" license="4" longitude="-110.970271" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="rainbowbridge lakepowell utah" title="19980405 11 Rainbow Bridge National Monument, Utah" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7172/6422209269_b789bd8368_b.jpg" username="davidwilson1949" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-06-12 21:02:45" description="" id="5081221487" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="2" tags="utah lakepowell rainbowbridge travel beautiful scenery lake water rocks" title="Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4007/5081221487_2fa4e806fe_b.jpg" username="premieroctobre" views="72" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-02 14:00:44" description="Photo was developed by myself processed from RAW, small vignetting was added for just a touch of dramatics. Let me know what you think! I have just started processing from RAW and any insight is welcome." id="3796552421" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="6" rank="3" tags="lakepowell rainbowbridge powell rockformation rainbow naturalbridge nature geology utah" title="Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3548/3796552421_d15df8111e_b.jpg" username="Jeff Hill Photo" views="77" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-27 09:21:25" description="We stopped here on our way from photographing sunrise at Inspiration point - heading towards Rainbow Point. We were originally going to head straight to the highest point in Bryce Canyon which is Rainbow point and stop by all the other places on our way back.. but we thought the light was just right for this one. Plus, it was something finally different at Bryce! &lt;i&gt;The best way to view my stream&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fluidr.com/photos/bala_&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;FLUIDR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;!" id="4165961782" latitude="37.605902" license="4" longitude="-112.205085" nbComments="7" rank="4" tags="nikon d700 sigma50mmf14exdghsm brycecanyonnationalpark utah naturalbridge hoodos bridge sandstone" title="Natural Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2796/4165961782_bd03d96c09_b.jpg" username=".Bala" views="1706" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 14:44:37" description="Sipapu Bridge is a natural bridge or arch located in the Natural Bridges National Monument in the U.S. state of Utah. The bridge spans White Canyon. .... The Natural Arch and Bridge Society has published a revised span of 225 feet, demoting the arch to a seventh place ranking. .... Sipapu is still ranked as the second longest natural bridge after the more famous Rainbow Bridge National Monument, also in Utah. Source &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&lt;/a&gt; accessed 13 Feb 2011 gc533" id="5421722707" latitude="37.613712" license="5" longitude="-110.009729" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="gc utah hiking bdgroup naturalbridges" title="Sipapu Bridge - Natural Bridges National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5054/5421722707_6194d3341d_b.jpg" username="brewbooks" views="48" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 14:44:52" description="Sipapu Bridge is a natural bridge or arch located in the Natural Bridges National Monument in the U.S. state of Utah. The bridge spans White Canyon. .... The Natural Arch and Bridge Society has published a revised span of 225 feet, demoting the arch to a seventh place ranking. .... Sipapu is still ranked as the second longest natural bridge after the more famous Rainbow Bridge National Monument, also in Utah. Source &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&lt;/a&gt; accessed 13 Feb 2011 gc534" id="5421723385" latitude="37.613683" license="5" longitude="-110.009697" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="gc utah hiking bdgroup naturalbridges" title="Sipapu Bridge - Natural Bridges National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5180/5421723385_74dca45bc6_b.jpg" username="brewbooks" views="62" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 14:46:17" description="Sipapu Bridge is a natural bridge or arch located in the Natural Bridges National Monument in the U.S. state of Utah. The bridge spans White Canyon. .... The Natural Arch and Bridge Society has published a revised span of 225 feet, demoting the arch to a seventh place ranking. .... Sipapu is still ranked as the second longest natural bridge after the more famous Rainbow Bridge National Monument, also in Utah. Source &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&lt;/a&gt; accessed 13 Feb 2011 gc536" id="5422331008" latitude="37.613729" license="5" longitude="-110.009697" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="gc utah hiking bdgroup naturalbridges" title="Sipapu Bridge - Natural Bridges National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5053/5422331008_f657ab229b_b.jpg" username="brewbooks" views="52" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 14:46:37" description="Sipapu Bridge is a natural bridge or arch located in the Natural Bridges National Monument in the U.S. state of Utah. The bridge spans White Canyon. .... The Natural Arch and Bridge Society has published a revised span of 225 feet, demoting the arch to a seventh place ranking. .... Sipapu is still ranked as the second longest natural bridge after the more famous Rainbow Bridge National Monument, also in Utah. Source &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&lt;/a&gt; accessed 13 Feb 2011 gc537" id="5422331874" latitude="37.613734" license="5" longitude="-110.009697" nbComments="2" rank="8" tags="gc utah hiking bdgroup naturalbridges" title="Sipapu Bridge - Natural Bridges National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5131/5422331874_7b89bf2afe_b.jpg" username="brewbooks" views="57" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 14:46:02" description="Bruce is describing some of the area geology Sipapu Bridge is a natural bridge or arch located in the Natural Bridges National Monument in the U.S. state of Utah. The bridge spans White Canyon. .... The Natural Arch and Bridge Society has published a revised span of 225 feet, demoting the arch to a seventh place ranking. .... Sipapu is still ranked as the second longest natural bridge after the more famous Rainbow Bridge National Monument, also in Utah. Source &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sipapu_Bridge&lt;/a&gt; accessed 13 Feb 2011 gc535" id="5422330226" latitude="37.613717" license="5" longitude="-110.009708" nbComments="0" rank="9" tags="gc utah hiking bdgroup naturalbridges bruced marye brendar jerryb" title="Sipapu Bridge - Natural Bridges National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5292/5422330226_04470bee43_b.jpg" username="brewbooks" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-24 08:36:30" description="Navajo Mountain is a peak in San Juan County, Utah, with its southern flank extending into Coconino County, Arizona. It holds an important place in the traditions of three local Native American tribes. Navajo Mountain is a prominent free-standing laccolith, a dome-shaped body of igneous rock that intruded into sedimentary layers and lifted up the overlying layer. The igneous rock at the core of the mountain is wrapped in sedimentary layers. Such igneous intrusions have been exposed by erosion and well studied in similar mountain ranges on the Colorado Plateau, such as the Henry Mountains, the Abajo Mountains, and the La Sal Range. The Navajo Mountain region has special cultural significance to the Navajo people, who know it as Naatsis’áán. Together with Rainbow Bridge to the northwest, Navajo Mountain figures prominently as the first settlement area in western Navajo origin stories. Following the military defeat of the Diné (Navajo) by United States forces in 1863, the political landscape was changed by new boundaries and major physical alterations. The establishment of Rainbow Bridge National Monument (1910), and the filling of Glen Canyon by Lake Powell in 1963, has facilitated tourism of this previously remote region. Access to Navajo Mountain is still regulated by the sovereign Navajo Nation, and a permit is required to hike in the region. Climbing the mountain itself is forbidden. Before becoming part of the Navajo Nation, the area was inhabited by the Anasazi, or Ancestral Pueblans. Their descendants, the Hopi call Navajo Mountain Tokonave, or &amp;quot;Heart of the Earth&amp;quot;. Ruins in the area of Navajo Mountain are still strongly associated with certain Hopi clans, with priests still making pilgrimages to shrines in the area. Before 1933, when the area between the Colorado and San Juan Rivers and the Arizona border was added to the Navajo reservation, the area was known as the Paiute Strip, and the mountain itself was known as Paiute Mountain, due to the population of San Juan Paiutes living between the mountain and Monument Valley. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navajo_Mountain&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navajo_Mountain&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="6780639629" latitude="37.03441" license="5" longitude="-110.869817" nbComments="0" rank="10" tags="" title="Lake Powell and Navajo Mountain, Utah" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7171/6780639629_0a01e3b9bb_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-03 10:22:03" description="Lake Powell is a reservoir on the Colorado River, straddling the border between Utah and Arizona (most of it, along with Rainbow Bridge, is in Utah). It is the second largest man-made reservoir in maximum water capacity in the United States behind Lake Mead, storing 24,322,000 acre feet (3.0001×1010 m3) of water when full. Current water levels, however, put Lake Powell ahead of Lake Mead in water volume and surface area. Lake Powell was created by the flooding of Glen Canyon by the controversial Glen Canyon Dam, which also led to the creation of Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, a popular summer destination. The reservoir is named for explorer John Wesley Powell, a one-armed American Civil War veteran who explored the river via three wooden boats in 1869. In 1972, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area was established. It is public land managed by the National Park Service, and available to the public for recreational purposes. It lies in parts of Garfield, Kane, and San Juan counties in southern Utah, and Coconino County in northern Arizona. The northern limits of the lake extend at least as far as the Hite Crossing Bridge. A map centered at the confluence of the Escalante River 37°17′22″N 110°52′20″W with the Colorado River gives a good view of the extent of the lake. Lake Powell is a storage facility for the Upper Basin states of the Colorado River Compact (Colorado, Utah, Wyoming, and New Mexico). The Compact specifies that the Upper Basin states are to provide a minimum annual flow of 7,500,000 acre feet (9.3 km3) to the Lower Basin states (Arizona, Nevada, and California). More Photos At: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glynlowe.com/lake_powell_antelope_point/e1e394807#h1e394807&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.glynlowe.com/lake_powell_antelope_point&lt;/a&gt;" id="7370304356" latitude="36.96684" license="4" longitude="-111.436729" nbComments="27" rank="11" tags="lake powell desert reflection utah arizona" title="Lake Powell - Desert Reflection" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8018/7370304356_0cf20852b5_b.jpg" username="Glyn Lowe Photoworks" views="818" />
<photo  date_taken="2001-06-06 15:10:00" description="Thor's Hammer, a geological feature in Bryce Canyon National Park, which is located in southern Utah about 50 miles (80 km) northeast of—and 1,000 feet (300 m) higher than—Zion National Park. The weather in Bryce Canyon is therefore cooler, and the park receives more precipitation: a total of 15 to 18 inches (38 to 46 cm) per year. Yearly temperatures vary from an average minimum of 9 °F (−13 °C) in January to an average maximum of 83 °F (28 °C) in July, but extreme temperatures can range from −30 °F to 97 °F (−34 °C to 36 °C). The national park lies within the Colorado Plateau geographic province of North America and straddles the southeastern edge of the Paunsagunt Plateau west of the Paunsagunt Fault (Paunsagunt is Paiute for &amp;quot;home of the beaver&amp;quot;). Park visitors arrive from the plateau part of the park and look over the plateau's edge toward a valley containing the fault and the Paria River just beyond it (Paria is Paiute for &amp;quot;muddy or elk water&amp;quot;). The edge of the Kaiparowits Plateau bounds the opposite side of the valley. Bryce Canyon was not formed from erosion initiated from a central stream, meaning it technically is not a canyon. Instead headward erosion has excavated large amphitheater-shaped features in the Cenozoic-aged rocks of the Paunsagunt Plateau. This erosion exposed delicate and colorful pinnacles called hoodoos that are up to 200 feet (61 m) high. A series of amphitheaters extends more than 20 miles (32 km) north-to-south within the park. The largest is Bryce Amphitheater, which is 12 miles (19 km) long, 3 miles (4.8 km) wide and 800 feet (240 m) deep. A nearby example of amphitheaters with hoodoos in the same formation but at a higher elevation, is in Cedar Breaks National Monument, which is 25 miles (40 km) to the west on the Markagunt Plateau. Rainbow Point, the highest part of the park at 9,105 feet (2,775 m), is at the end of the 18-mile (29 km) scenic drive. From there, Aquarius Plateau, Bryce Amphitheater, the Henry Mountains, the Vermilion Cliffs and the White Cliffs can be seen. Yellow Creek, where it exits the park in the north-east section, is the lowest part of the park at 6,620 feet (2,020 m). Most park visitors sightsee using the scenic drive, which provides access to 13 viewpoints over the amphitheaters. Bryce Canyon has eight marked and maintained hiking trails that can be hiked in less than a day (round trip time, trailhead): Mossy Cave (one hour, State Route 12 northwest of Tropic), Rim Trail (5–6 hours, anywhere on rim), Bristlecone Loop (one hour, Rainbow Point), and Queens Garden (1–2 hours, Sunrise Point) are easy to moderate hikes. Navajo Loop (1–2 hours, Sunset Point) and Tower Bridge (2–3 hours, north of Sunrise Point) are moderate hikes. Fairyland Loop (4–5 hours, Fairyland Point) and Peekaboo Loop (3–4 hours, Bryce Point) are strenuous hikes. Several of these trails intersect, allowing hikers to combine routes for more challenging hikes. The park also has two trails designated for overnight hiking: the 9-mile (14 km) Riggs Loop Trail and the 23-mile (37 km) Under the Rim Trail. Both require a backcountry camping permit. In total there are 50 miles (80 km) of trails in the park. More than 10 miles (16 km) of marked but ungroomed skiing trails are available off of Fairyland, Paria, and Rim trails in the park. Twenty miles (32 km) of connecting groomed ski trails are in nearby Dixie National Forest and Ruby's Inn. The air in the area is so clear that on most days from Yovimpa and Rainbow points, Navajo Mountain and the Kaibab Plateau can be seen 90 miles (140 km) away in Arizona. On extremely clear days, the Black Mesas of eastern Arizona and western New Mexico can be seen some 160 miles (260 km) away. The park also has a 7.4 magnitude night sky, making it the one of the darkest in North America. Stargazers can therefore see 7,500 stars with the naked eye, while in most places fewer than 2,000 can be seen due to light pollution (in many large cities only a few dozen can be seen). Park rangers host public stargazing events and evening programs on astronomy, nocturnal animals, and night sky protection. The Bryce Canyon Astronomy Festival, typically held in June, attracts thousands of visitors. In honor of this astronomy festival, Asteroid 49272 was named after the national park. There are two campgrounds in the park, North Campground and Sunset Campground. Loop A in North Campground is open year-round. Additional loops and Sunset Campground are open from late spring to early autumn. The 114-room Bryce Canyon Lodge is another way to overnight in the park. A favorite activity of most visitors is landscape photography. With Bryce Canyon's high altitude and clean air, the sunrise and sunset photographs can be spectacular. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&lt;/a&gt;" id="2485746786" latitude="37.516414" license="5" longitude="-112.264695" nbComments="0" rank="12" tags="brycecanyonnationalpark brycecanyon kane utah" title="Thor's Hammer, Bryce Canyon National Park, Utah" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3094/2485746786_59a40f4857_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="172" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-24 08:33:21" description="Lake Powell is a reservoir on the Colorado River, straddling the border between Utah and Arizona (most of it, along with Rainbow Bridge, is in Utah). It is a major vacation spot that around 2 million people visit every year. It is the second largest man-made reservoir in maximum water capacity in the United States behind Lake Mead, storing 24,322,000 acre feet (3.0001×1010 m3) of water when full. Current water levels, however, put Lake Powell ahead of Lake Mead in water volume and surface area. Lake Powell was created by the flooding of Glen Canyon by the controversial Glen Canyon Dam, which also led to the creation of Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, a popular summer destination. The reservoir is named for explorer John Wesley Powell, a one-armed American Civil War veteran who explored the river via three wooden boats in 1869. In 1972, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area was established. It is public land managed by the National Park Service, and available to the public for recreational purposes. It lies in parts of Garfield, Kane, and San Juan counties in southern Utah, and Coconino County in northern Arizona. The northern limits of the lake extend at least as far as the Hite Crossing Bridge. A map centered at the confluence of the Escalante River Lake Powell is a storage facility for the Upper Basin states of the Colorado River Compact (Colorado, Utah, Wyoming, and New Mexico). The Compact specifies that the Upper Basin states are to provide a minimum annual flow of 7,500,000 acre feet (9.3 km3) to the Lower Basin states (Arizona, Nevada, and California). &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_powell&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_powell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="6780636205" latitude="37.022016" license="5" longitude="-111.400852" nbComments="0" rank="13" tags="" title="Labyrinth Bay, Lake Powell, Utah" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7148/6780636205_b8f4c2a4ab_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-24 08:33:53" description="Lake Powell is a reservoir on the Colorado River, straddling the border between Utah and Arizona (most of it, along with Rainbow Bridge, is in Utah). It is a major vacation spot that around 2 million people visit every year. It is the second largest man-made reservoir in maximum water capacity in the United States behind Lake Mead, storing 24,322,000 acre feet (3.0001×1010 m3) of water when full. Current water levels, however, put Lake Powell ahead of Lake Mead in water volume and surface area. Lake Powell was created by the flooding of Glen Canyon by the controversial Glen Canyon Dam, which also led to the creation of Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, a popular summer destination. The reservoir is named for explorer John Wesley Powell, a one-armed American Civil War veteran who explored the river via three wooden boats in 1869. In 1972, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area was established. It is public land managed by the National Park Service, and available to the public for recreational purposes. It lies in parts of Garfield, Kane, and San Juan counties in southern Utah, and Coconino County in northern Arizona. The northern limits of the lake extend at least as far as the Hite Crossing Bridge. A map centered at the confluence of the Escalante River Lake Powell is a storage facility for the Upper Basin states of the Colorado River Compact (Colorado, Utah, Wyoming, and New Mexico). The Compact specifies that the Upper Basin states are to provide a minimum annual flow of 7,500,000 acre feet (9.3 km3) to the Lower Basin states (Arizona, Nevada, and California). &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_powell&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_powell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="6780636665" latitude="37.022016" license="5" longitude="-111.400852" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="" title="Padre Bay, Lake Powell, Utah" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7163/6780636665_31c6d005e9_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-15 21:41:50" description="Lake Powell is a reservoir on the Colorado River, straddling the border between Utah and Arizona (most of it, along with Rainbow Bridge, is in Utah). It is the second largest man-made reservoir in maximum water capacity in the United States behind Lake Mead, storing 24,322,000 acre feet of water when full. Current water levels, however, put Lake Powell ahead of Lake Mead in water volume and surface area. Lake Powell was created by the flooding of Glen Canyon by the controversial Glen Canyon Dam, which also led to the creation of Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, a popular summer destination. The reservoir is named for explorer John Wesley Powell, a one-armed American Civil War veteran who explored the river via three wooden boats in 1869. In 1972, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area was established. It is public land managed by the National Park Service, and available to the public for recreational purposes. It lies in parts of Garfield, Kane, and San Juan counties in southern Utah, and Coconino County in northern Arizona. The northern limits of the lake extend at least as far as the Hite Crossing Bridge. A map centered at the confluence of the Escalante River with the Colorado River gives a good view of the extent of the lake. Lake Powell is a storage facility for the Upper Basin states of the Colorado River Compact (Colorado, Utah, Wyoming, and New Mexico). The Compact specifies that the Upper Basin states are to provide a minimum annual flow of 7,500,000 acre feet to the Lower Basin states (Arizona, Nevada, and California). &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Powell&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Powell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7235107772" latitude="37.180022" license="5" longitude="-110.897551" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="newjerseyday1" title="Confluence of the San Juan and Colorado Rivers, Lake Powell and the Kaiparowits Plateau, Utah" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5198/7235107772_4327d70c27_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-24 08:36:41" description="Lake Powell is a reservoir on the Colorado River, straddling the border between Utah and Arizona (most of it, along with Rainbow Bridge, is in Utah). It is a major vacation spot that around 2 million people visit every year. It is the second largest man-made reservoir in maximum water capacity in the United States behind Lake Mead, storing 24,322,000 acre feet (3.0001×1010 m3) of water when full. Current water levels, however, put Lake Powell ahead of Lake Mead in water volume and surface area. Lake Powell was created by the flooding of Glen Canyon by the controversial Glen Canyon Dam, which also led to the creation of Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, a popular summer destination. The reservoir is named for explorer John Wesley Powell, a one-armed American Civil War veteran who explored the river via three wooden boats in 1869. In 1972, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area was established. It is public land managed by the National Park Service, and available to the public for recreational purposes. It lies in parts of Garfield, Kane, and San Juan counties in southern Utah, and Coconino County in northern Arizona. The northern limits of the lake extend at least as far as the Hite Crossing Bridge. A map centered at the confluence of the Escalante River Lake Powell is a storage facility for the Upper Basin states of the Colorado River Compact (Colorado, Utah, Wyoming, and New Mexico). The Compact specifies that the Upper Basin states are to provide a minimum annual flow of 7,500,000 acre feet (9.3 km3) to the Lower Basin states (Arizona, Nevada, and California). &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_powell&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_powell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="6780640103" latitude="37.03441" license="5" longitude="-110.869817" nbComments="0" rank="16" tags="" title="Confluence of San Juan River and Colorado River, Lake Powell, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, Utah" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7173/6780640103_72b6a0afd6_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-07-21 17:03:27" description="Klick &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photo_zoom.gne?id=2217173388&amp;amp;size=l&quot;&gt; here &lt;/a&gt; for a large view! Der &lt;b&gt;Lake Powell&lt;/b&gt; ist ein Stausee in den Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika und liegt rund 350 km nordöstlich von Las Vegas im Grenzgebiet von Utah und Arizona. Er entstand Mitte der 1960er Jahre durch Aufstauung des Colorado an der Ostseite des Grand Canyon und entwickelte sich auf Grund vielfältiger Freizeitangebote um den See und zahlreicher Sehenswürdigkeiten im Umland zu einem beliebten Urlaubsziel. Niederschlagsarme Jahre und eine verstärkte Wasserentnahme lassen den Wasserpegel des Sees seit Jahren stetig sinken. &lt;b&gt;Geschichte&lt;/b&gt; Mit der Fertigstellung des Glen-Canyon-Staudamms wurde der Glen Canyon ab dem 13. März 1963 vom Colorado überflutet und bis zum 22. Juni 1966 zum Lake Powell aufgestaut. Benannt wurde er nach dem Bürgerkriegsveteranen Major John Wesley Powell, der im August 1879 mit acht weiteren Männern den Glen Canyon erforschte. Heute ist der See nach dem Lake Mead (Nevada/Arizona) der zweitgrößte Stausee der Vereinigten Staaten. Bei maximaler Stauhöhe hat er eine Länge von rund 300 km, ist am Damm 171 m tief und bedeckt eine Fläche von 645 km². Mit rund 33,3 Milliarden m³ (= 33,3 km³) Wasser überflutet der Lake Powell dann 96 Canyons und erstreckt sich weit in die Mündungen des von Nordwesten her kommenden Escalante River sowie des von Osten her kommenden San Juan River. Die Küstenlinie des Sees ist mit 3.150 km länger als die gesamte Westküste der USA. Im Jahre 1972 beschloss der amerikanische Kongress die Einrichtung der Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, die ca 5.000 km² umfasst und von denen der Stausee selbst nur 13% einnimmt. Das Nationalerholungsgebiet gehört zum National Park System und grenzt im Nordosten an den Canyonlands- sowie im Süden an den Grand-Canyon-Nationalpark. Nach sechs niederschlagsarmen Jahren und intensiver Wasserentnahme (u.a. aus Las Vegas) ist der Pegel bis zum Sommer 2005 um etwa 45 m gesunken, was rund zwei Drittel des ursprünglichen Wasservolumens entspricht. Durch den Rückgang sind breite Strände entstanden, die Enden der äußeren Canyons sind trocken gefallen, die Rainbow Bridge ist vom Ufer her nur über einen längeren Fußweg zu erreichen und es sind Felsformationen aus dem Wasser aufgetaucht, die seit 30 Jahren nicht mehr zu sehen waren. From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia" id="2217173388" latitude="37.545261" license="4" longitude="-110.377349" nbComments="325" rank="17" tags="lakepowell page arizona usa amerika navajo navajoindianreservation glencanyon glencanyondam coloradoplateau coloradoriver water lake sky clouds desert wüste nordamerika southwest reservoir glencanyonnationalrecreationarea johnwesleypowell nikon wolfgangstaudt 66111 utah sigma nikond70 summer 2006 sandstone kayentasandstone blue red boats marina blueribbonwinner reflexions thebestofmimamorsgroups" title="Lake Powell" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2026/2217173388_1d7af32c4b_b.jpg" username="Wolfgang Staudt" views="14249" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-24 08:36:55" description="Navajo Mountain is a peak in San Juan County, Utah, with its southern flank extending into Coconino County, Arizona. It holds an important place in the traditions of three local Native American tribes. Navajo Mountain is a prominent free-standing laccolith, a dome-shaped body of igneous rock that intruded into sedimentary layers and lifted up the overlying layer. The igneous rock at the core of the mountain is wrapped in sedimentary layers. Such igneous intrusions have been exposed by erosion and well studied in similar mountain ranges on the Colorado Plateau, such as the Henry Mountains, the Abajo Mountains, and the La Sal Range. The Navajo Mountain region has special cultural significance to the Navajo people, who know it as Naatsis’áán. Together with Rainbow Bridge to the northwest, Navajo Mountain figures prominently as the first settlement area in western Navajo origin stories. Following the military defeat of the Diné (Navajo) by United States forces in 1863, the political landscape was changed by new boundaries and major physical alterations. The establishment of Rainbow Bridge National Monument (1910), and the filling of Glen Canyon by Lake Powell in 1963, has facilitated tourism of this previously remote region. Access to Navajo Mountain is still regulated by the sovereign Navajo Nation, and a permit is required to hike in the region. Climbing the mountain itself is forbidden. Before becoming part of the Navajo Nation, the area was inhabited by the Anasazi, or Ancestral Pueblans. Their descendants, the Hopi call Navajo Mountain Tokonave, or &amp;quot;Heart of the Earth&amp;quot;. Ruins in the area of Navajo Mountain are still strongly associated with certain Hopi clans, with priests still making pilgrimages to shrines in the area. Before 1933, when the area between the Colorado and San Juan Rivers and the Arizona border was added to the Navajo reservation, the area was known as the Paiute Strip, and the mountain itself was known as Paiute Mountain, due to the population of San Juan Paiutes living between the mountain and Monument Valley. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navajo_Mountain&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navajo_Mountain&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="6780640507" latitude="37.03441" license="5" longitude="-110.869817" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="" title="Navajo Mountain and Lake Powell, Utah in Flight from Las Vegas, Nevada to Denver, Colorado" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7004/6780640507_5dc96137e8_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2001-06-06 14:00:00" description="Bryce Point is arguably the most spectacular (and most visited) viewpoint in Bryce Canyon National Park. Bryce Canyon National Park is a national park located in southwestern Utah in the United States. The major feature of the park is Bryce Canyon which, despite its name, is not actually a canyon but a giant natural amphitheater created by erosion along the eastern side of the Paunsaugunt Plateau. Bryce is distinctive due to geological structures called hoodoos, formed by wind, water and ice erosion of the river and lake bed sedimentary rocks. The red, orange and white colors of the rocks provide spectacular views for park visitors. Bryce is at a much higher elevation than nearby Zion National Park. The rim at Bryce varies from 8,000 to 9,000 feet (2,400 to 2,700 m). Bryce Canyon National Park is located in southern Utah about 50 miles (80 km) northeast of—and 1,000 feet (300 m) higher than—Zion National Park. The weather in Bryce Canyon is therefore cooler, and the park receives more precipitation: a total of 15 to 18 inches (38 to 46 cm) per year. Yearly temperatures vary from an average minimum of 9 °F (−13 °C) in January to an average maximum of 83 °F (28 °C) in July, but extreme temperatures can range from −30 °F to 97 °F (−34 °C to 36 °C). Bryce Canyon was not formed from erosion initiated from a central stream, meaning it technically is not a canyon. Instead headward erosion has excavated large amphitheater-shaped features in the Cenozoic-aged rocks of the Paunsagunt Plateau. This erosion exposed delicate and colorful pinnacles called hoodoos that are up to 200 feet (61 m) high. A series of amphitheaters extends more than 20 miles (32 km) north-to-south within the park. The largest is Bryce Amphitheater, which is 12 miles (19 km) long, 3 miles (4.8 km) wide and 800 feet (240 m) deep. A nearby example of amphitheaters with hoodoos in the same formation but at a higher elevation, is in Cedar Breaks National Monument, which is 25 miles (40 km) to the west on the Markagunt Plateau. Responding to increased visitation and traffic congestion, the National Park Service implemented a voluntary, summer-only, in-park shuttle system in June 2000. In 2004, reconstruction began on the aging and inadequate road system in the park. Most park visitors sightsee using the scenic drive, which provides access to 13 viewpoints over the amphitheaters. Bryce Canyon has eight marked and maintained hiking trails that can be hiked in less than a day (round trip time, trailhead): Mossy Cave (one hour, State Route 12 northwest of Tropic), Rim Trail (5–6 hours, anywhere on rim), Bristlecone Loop (one hour, Rainbow Point), and Queens Garden (1–2 hours, Sunrise Point) are easy to moderate hikes. Navajo Loop (1–2 hours, Sunset Point) and Tower Bridge (2–3 hours, north of Sunrise Point) are moderate hikes. Fairyland Loop (4–5 hours, Fairyland Point) and Peekaboo Loop (3–4 hours, Bryce Point) are strenuous hikes. Several of these trails intersect, allowing hikers to combine routes for more challenging hikes. The park also has two trails designated for overnight hiking: the 9-mile (14 km) Riggs Loop Trail and the 23-mile (37 km) Under the Rim Trail. Both require a backcountry camping permit. In total there are 50 miles (80 km) of trails in the park. More than 10 miles (16 km) of marked but ungroomed skiing trails are available off of Fairyland, Paria, and Rim trails in the park. Twenty miles (32 km) of connecting groomed ski trails are in nearby Dixie National Forest and Ruby's Inn. The air in the area is so clear that on most days from Yovimpa and Rainbow points, Navajo Mountain and the Kaibab Plateau can be seen 90 miles (140 km) away in Arizona. On extremely clear days, the Black Mesas of eastern Arizona and western New Mexico can be seen some 160 miles (260 km) away. The park also has a 7.4 magnitude night sky, making it the one of the darkest in North America. Stargazers can therefore see 7,500 stars with the naked eye, while in most places fewer than 2,000 can be seen due to light pollution (in many large cities only a few dozen can be seen). Park rangers host public stargazing events and evening programs on astronomy, nocturnal animals, and night sky protection. The Bryce Canyon Astronomy Festival, typically held in June, attracts thousands of visitors. There are two campgrounds in the park, North Campground and Sunset Campground. Loop A in North Campground is open year-round. Additional loops and Sunset Campground are open from late spring to early autumn. The 114-room Bryce Canyon Lodge is another way to overnight in the park. A favorite activity of most visitors is landscape photography. With Bryce Canyon's high altitude and clean air, the sunrise and sunset photographs can be spectacular. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&lt;/a&gt;" id="2519290513" latitude="37.606152" license="5" longitude="-112.157503" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="garfield utah" title="Bryce Point, Bryce Canyon National Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3127/2519290513_a32f85078f_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="96" />
<photo  date_taken="2001-06-06 14:00:03" description="Bryce Point is arguably the most spectacular (and most visited) viewpoint in Bryce Canyon National Park. I was surprised to learn that Bryce is very high in elevation and is quite green. Bryce Canyon National Park is a national park located in southwestern Utah in the United States. The major feature of the park is Bryce Canyon which, despite its name, is not actually a canyon but a giant natural amphitheater created by erosion along the eastern side of the Paunsaugunt Plateau. Bryce is distinctive due to geological structures called hoodoos, formed by wind, water and ice erosion of the river and lake bed sedimentary rocks. The red, orange and white colors of the rocks provide spectacular views for park visitors. Bryce is at a much higher elevation than nearby Zion National Park. The rim at Bryce varies from 8,000 to 9,000 feet (2,400 to 2,700 m). Bryce Canyon National Park is located in southern Utah about 50 miles (80 km) northeast of—and 1,000 feet (300 m) higher than—Zion National Park. The weather in Bryce Canyon is therefore cooler, and the park receives more precipitation: a total of 15 to 18 inches (38 to 46 cm) per year. Yearly temperatures vary from an average minimum of 9 °F (−13 °C) in January to an average maximum of 83 °F (28 °C) in July, but extreme temperatures can range from −30 °F to 97 °F (−34 °C to 36 °C). Bryce Canyon was not formed from erosion initiated from a central stream, meaning it technically is not a canyon. Instead headward erosion has excavated large amphitheater-shaped features in the Cenozoic-aged rocks of the Paunsagunt Plateau. This erosion exposed delicate and colorful pinnacles called hoodoos that are up to 200 feet (61 m) high. A series of amphitheaters extends more than 20 miles (32 km) north-to-south within the park. The largest is Bryce Amphitheater, which is 12 miles (19 km) long, 3 miles (4.8 km) wide and 800 feet (240 m) deep. A nearby example of amphitheaters with hoodoos in the same formation but at a higher elevation, is in Cedar Breaks National Monument, which is 25 miles (40 km) to the west on the Markagunt Plateau. Responding to increased visitation and traffic congestion, the National Park Service implemented a voluntary, summer-only, in-park shuttle system in June 2000. In 2004, reconstruction began on the aging and inadequate road system in the park. Most park visitors sightsee using the scenic drive, which provides access to 13 viewpoints over the amphitheaters. Bryce Canyon has eight marked and maintained hiking trails that can be hiked in less than a day (round trip time, trailhead): Mossy Cave (one hour, State Route 12 northwest of Tropic), Rim Trail (5–6 hours, anywhere on rim), Bristlecone Loop (one hour, Rainbow Point), and Queens Garden (1–2 hours, Sunrise Point) are easy to moderate hikes. Navajo Loop (1–2 hours, Sunset Point) and Tower Bridge (2–3 hours, north of Sunrise Point) are moderate hikes. Fairyland Loop (4–5 hours, Fairyland Point) and Peekaboo Loop (3–4 hours, Bryce Point) are strenuous hikes. Several of these trails intersect, allowing hikers to combine routes for more challenging hikes. The park also has two trails designated for overnight hiking: the 9-mile (14 km) Riggs Loop Trail and the 23-mile (37 km) Under the Rim Trail. Both require a backcountry camping permit. In total there are 50 miles (80 km) of trails in the park. More than 10 miles (16 km) of marked but ungroomed skiing trails are available off of Fairyland, Paria, and Rim trails in the park. Twenty miles (32 km) of connecting groomed ski trails are in nearby Dixie National Forest and Ruby's Inn. The air in the area is so clear that on most days from Yovimpa and Rainbow points, Navajo Mountain and the Kaibab Plateau can be seen 90 miles (140 km) away in Arizona. On extremely clear days, the Black Mesas of eastern Arizona and western New Mexico can be seen some 160 miles (260 km) away. The park also has a 7.4 magnitude night sky, making it the one of the darkest in North America. Stargazers can therefore see 7,500 stars with the naked eye, while in most places fewer than 2,000 can be seen due to light pollution (in many large cities only a few dozen can be seen). Park rangers host public stargazing events and evening programs on astronomy, nocturnal animals, and night sky protection. The Bryce Canyon Astronomy Festival, typically held in June, attracts thousands of visitors. There are two campgrounds in the park, North Campground and Sunset Campground. Loop A in North Campground is open year-round. Additional loops and Sunset Campground are open from late spring to early autumn. The 114-room Bryce Canyon Lodge is another way to overnight in the park. A favorite activity of most visitors is landscape photography. With Bryce Canyon's high altitude and clean air, the sunrise and sunset photographs can be spectacular. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&lt;/a&gt;" id="2519289063" latitude="37.606152" license="5" longitude="-112.157503" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="garfield utah" title="Bryce Point, Bryce Canyon National Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3107/2519289063_9c1aa7b53a_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="107" />
<photo  date_taken="2001-06-06 15:00:01" description="I was much skinnier in 2001. This was taken during my first trip to Bryce Canyon, which was quite a revelation about the spectacular scenery of southern Utah. Bryce Canyon National Park is located in southern Utah about 50 miles (80 km) northeast of—and 1,000 feet (300 m) higher than—Zion National Park. The weather in Bryce Canyon is therefore cooler, and the park receives more precipitation: a total of 15 to 18 inches (38 to 46 cm) per year. Yearly temperatures vary from an average minimum of 9 °F (−13 °C) in January to an average maximum of 83 °F (28 °C) in July, but extreme temperatures can range from −30 °F to 97 °F (−34 °C to 36 °C). The national park lies within the Colorado Plateau geographic province of North America and straddles the southeastern edge of the Paunsagunt Plateau west of the Paunsagunt Fault (Paunsagunt is Paiute for &amp;quot;home of the beaver&amp;quot;). Park visitors arrive from the plateau part of the park and look over the plateau's edge toward a valley containing the fault and the Paria River just beyond it (Paria is Paiute for &amp;quot;muddy or elk water&amp;quot;). The edge of the Kaiparowits Plateau bounds the opposite side of the valley. Bryce Canyon was not formed from erosion initiated from a central stream, meaning it technically is not a canyon. Instead headward erosion has excavated large amphitheater-shaped features in the Cenozoic-aged rocks of the Paunsagunt Plateau. This erosion exposed delicate and colorful pinnacles called hoodoos that are up to 200 feet (61 m) high. A series of amphitheaters extends more than 20 miles (32 km) north-to-south within the park. The largest is Bryce Amphitheater, which is 12 miles (19 km) long, 3 miles (4.8 km) wide and 800 feet (240 m) deep. A nearby example of amphitheaters with hoodoos in the same formation but at a higher elevation, is in Cedar Breaks National Monument, which is 25 miles (40 km) to the west on the Markagunt Plateau. Rainbow Point, the highest part of the park at 9,105 feet (2,775 m), is at the end of the 18-mile (29 km) scenic drive. From there, Aquarius Plateau, Bryce Amphitheater, the Henry Mountains, the Vermilion Cliffs and the White Cliffs can be seen. Yellow Creek, where it exits the park in the north-east section, is the lowest part of the park at 6,620 feet (2,020 m). Most park visitors sightsee using the scenic drive, which provides access to 13 viewpoints over the amphitheaters. Bryce Canyon has eight marked and maintained hiking trails that can be hiked in less than a day (round trip time, trailhead): Mossy Cave (one hour, State Route 12 northwest of Tropic), Rim Trail (5–6 hours, anywhere on rim), Bristlecone Loop (one hour, Rainbow Point), and Queens Garden (1–2 hours, Sunrise Point) are easy to moderate hikes. Navajo Loop (1–2 hours, Sunset Point) and Tower Bridge (2–3 hours, north of Sunrise Point) are moderate hikes. Fairyland Loop (4–5 hours, Fairyland Point) and Peekaboo Loop (3–4 hours, Bryce Point) are strenuous hikes. Several of these trails intersect, allowing hikers to combine routes for more challenging hikes. The park also has two trails designated for overnight hiking: the 9-mile (14 km) Riggs Loop Trail and the 23-mile (37 km) Under the Rim Trail. Both require a backcountry camping permit. In total there are 50 miles (80 km) of trails in the park. More than 10 miles (16 km) of marked but ungroomed skiing trails are available off of Fairyland, Paria, and Rim trails in the park. Twenty miles (32 km) of connecting groomed ski trails are in nearby Dixie National Forest and Ruby's Inn. The air in the area is so clear that on most days from Yovimpa and Rainbow points, Navajo Mountain and the Kaibab Plateau can be seen 90 miles (140 km) away in Arizona. On extremely clear days, the Black Mesas of eastern Arizona and western New Mexico can be seen some 160 miles (260 km) away. The park also has a 7.4 magnitude night sky, making it the one of the darkest in North America. Stargazers can therefore see 7,500 stars with the naked eye, while in most places fewer than 2,000 can be seen due to light pollution (in many large cities only a few dozen can be seen). Park rangers host public stargazing events and evening programs on astronomy, nocturnal animals, and night sky protection. The Bryce Canyon Astronomy Festival, typically held in June, attracts thousands of visitors. In honor of this astronomy festival, Asteroid 49272 was named after the national park. There are two campgrounds in the park, North Campground and Sunset Campground. Loop A in North Campground is open year-round. Additional loops and Sunset Campground are open from late spring to early autumn. The 114-room Bryce Canyon Lodge is another way to overnight in the park. A favorite activity of most visitors is landscape photography. With Bryce Canyon's high altitude and clean air, the sunrise and sunset photographs can be spectacular. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&lt;/a&gt;" id="2484927925" latitude="37.472439" license="5" longitude="-112.240383" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="brycecanyonnationalpark brycecanyon kane utah" title="Ken, First Bryce Canyon Trip 2001" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2152/2484927925_52506bb7ca_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="83" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-15 21:44:05" description="Lake Powell is a reservoir on the Colorado River, straddling the border between Utah and Arizona (most of it, along with Rainbow Bridge, is in Utah). It is the second largest man-made reservoir in maximum water capacity in the United States behind Lake Mead, storing 24,322,000 acre feet of water when full. Current water levels, however, put Lake Powell ahead of Lake Mead in water volume and surface area. Lake Powell was created by the flooding of Glen Canyon by the controversial Glen Canyon Dam, which also led to the creation of Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, a popular summer destination. The reservoir is named for explorer John Wesley Powell, a one-armed American Civil War veteran who explored the river via three wooden boats in 1869. In 1972, Glen Canyon National Recreation Area was established. It is public land managed by the National Park Service, and available to the public for recreational purposes. It lies in parts of Garfield, Kane, and San Juan counties in southern Utah, and Coconino County in northern Arizona. The northern limits of the lake extend at least as far as the Hite Crossing Bridge. A map centered at the confluence of the Escalante River with the Colorado River gives a good view of the extent of the lake. Lake Powell is a storage facility for the Upper Basin states of the Colorado River Compact (Colorado, Utah, Wyoming, and New Mexico). The Compact specifies that the Upper Basin states are to provide a minimum annual flow of 7,500,000 acre feet to the Lower Basin states (Arizona, Nevada, and California). &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Powell&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Powell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7235110294" latitude="37.270415" license="5" longitude="-110.5803" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="newjerseyday1" title="Nokai Dome and Castle Creek Canyon, Near Lake Powell" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7220/7235110294_8dbaef2895_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2001-06-06 16:00:00" description="Yovimba Point is the southern terminus of the scenic drive through Bryce Canyon NP. It also affords the highest and best views looking south. Bryce Canyon National Park is located in southern Utah about 50 miles (80 km) northeast of—and 1,000 feet (300 m) higher than—Zion National Park. The weather in Bryce Canyon is therefore cooler, and the park receives more precipitation: a total of 15 to 18 inches (38 to 46 cm) per year. Yearly temperatures vary from an average minimum of 9 °F (−13 °C) in January to an average maximum of 83 °F (28 °C) in July, but extreme temperatures can range from −30 °F to 97 °F (−34 °C to 36 °C). The national park lies within the Colorado Plateau geographic province of North America and straddles the southeastern edge of the Paunsagunt Plateau west of the Paunsagunt Fault (Paunsagunt is Paiute for &amp;quot;home of the beaver&amp;quot;). Park visitors arrive from the plateau part of the park and look over the plateau's edge toward a valley containing the fault and the Paria River just beyond it (Paria is Paiute for &amp;quot;muddy or elk water&amp;quot;). The edge of the Kaiparowits Plateau bounds the opposite side of the valley. Bryce Canyon was not formed from erosion initiated from a central stream, meaning it technically is not a canyon. Instead headward erosion has excavated large amphitheater-shaped features in the Cenozoic-aged rocks of the Paunsagunt Plateau. This erosion exposed delicate and colorful pinnacles called hoodoos that are up to 200 feet (61 m) high. A series of amphitheaters extends more than 20 miles (32 km) north-to-south within the park. The largest is Bryce Amphitheater, which is 12 miles (19 km) long, 3 miles (4.8 km) wide and 800 feet (240 m) deep. A nearby example of amphitheaters with hoodoos in the same formation but at a higher elevation, is in Cedar Breaks National Monument, which is 25 miles (40 km) to the west on the Markagunt Plateau. Rainbow Point, the highest part of the park at 9,105 feet (2,775 m), is at the end of the 18-mile (29 km) scenic drive. From there, Aquarius Plateau, Bryce Amphitheater, the Henry Mountains, the Vermilion Cliffs and the White Cliffs can be seen. Yellow Creek, where it exits the park in the north-east section, is the lowest part of the park at 6,620 feet (2,020 m). Most park visitors sightsee using the scenic drive, which provides access to 13 viewpoints over the amphitheaters. Bryce Canyon has eight marked and maintained hiking trails that can be hiked in less than a day (round trip time, trailhead): Mossy Cave (one hour, State Route 12 northwest of Tropic), Rim Trail (5–6 hours, anywhere on rim), Bristlecone Loop (one hour, Rainbow Point), and Queens Garden (1–2 hours, Sunrise Point) are easy to moderate hikes. Navajo Loop (1–2 hours, Sunset Point) and Tower Bridge (2–3 hours, north of Sunrise Point) are moderate hikes. Fairyland Loop (4–5 hours, Fairyland Point) and Peekaboo Loop (3–4 hours, Bryce Point) are strenuous hikes. Several of these trails intersect, allowing hikers to combine routes for more challenging hikes. The park also has two trails designated for overnight hiking: the 9-mile (14 km) Riggs Loop Trail and the 23-mile (37 km) Under the Rim Trail. Both require a backcountry camping permit. In total there are 50 miles (80 km) of trails in the park. More than 10 miles (16 km) of marked but ungroomed skiing trails are available off of Fairyland, Paria, and Rim trails in the park. Twenty miles (32 km) of connecting groomed ski trails are in nearby Dixie National Forest and Ruby's Inn. The air in the area is so clear that on most days from Yovimpa and Rainbow points, Navajo Mountain and the Kaibab Plateau can be seen 90 miles (140 km) away in Arizona. On extremely clear days, the Black Mesas of eastern Arizona and western New Mexico can be seen some 160 miles (260 km) away. The park also has a 7.4 magnitude night sky, making it the one of the darkest in North America. Stargazers can therefore see 7,500 stars with the naked eye, while in most places fewer than 2,000 can be seen due to light pollution (in many large cities only a few dozen can be seen). Park rangers host public stargazing events and evening programs on astronomy, nocturnal animals, and night sky protection. The Bryce Canyon Astronomy Festival, typically held in June, attracts thousands of visitors. In honor of this astronomy festival, Asteroid 49272 was named after the national park. There are two campgrounds in the park, North Campground and Sunset Campground. Loop A in North Campground is open year-round. Additional loops and Sunset Campground are open from late spring to early autumn. The 114-room Bryce Canyon Lodge is another way to overnight in the park. A favorite activity of most visitors is landscape photography. With Bryce Canyon's high altitude and clean air, the sunrise and sunset photographs can be spectacular. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryce_Canyon_National_Park&lt;/a&gt;" id="2520096826" latitude="37.472439" license="5" longitude="-112.240383" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="kane utah brycecanyon brycecanyonnationalpark brycecanyonnp southwest america us west" title="Yovimpa Point, Bryce Canyon National Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2238/2520096826_1036c18797_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="97" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-01-09 05:14:16" description="Canyon de Chelly, entirely within Navajo Nation. The Navajo Nation (Diné in Navajo language) is a Native American homeland covering about 26,000 square miles (67,339 square kilometres, 17 million acres), occupying all of northeastern Arizona, the southeast portion of Utah, and northwestern New Mexico. It is the largest land area assigned primarily to a Native American jurisdiction within the United States. The Nation encompasses all things important to the Navajo people: the land, kinship, language, religion and the right to govern themselves. Members of the Nation are often known as Navajo (or Navaho) but traditionally call themselves Diné (sometimes spelled in English as Dineh) which means Navajo people. The Nation's boundaries are the Ute Mountain Ute Indian Reservation at the Four Corners Monument and stretch across the Colorado Plateau into Arizona, Utah, and New Mexico. Located within the Navajo Nation are Canyon de Chelly National Monument, Monument Valley, Rainbow Bridge National Monument, the Hopi Indian Reservation, and the Shiprock landmark. The seat of government is located at the census-designated city of Window Rock in Apache County, Arizona. There are several adjacent &amp;quot;Navajo Indian Reservations&amp;quot; (such as Alamocita) in this area, but generally function as sub-units of the &amp;quot;Big Rez&amp;quot; with considerable local autonomy). The Diné's traditional boundaries are the four sacred mountains, which actually include an area much larger than the present-day reservation. The Navajo Nation was a very complex one. The eastern portion of the reservation, located in New Mexico is popularly called the &amp;quot;Checkerboard&amp;quot; because Navajo lands are mingled with fee lands (owned by both Navajo and non-Navajo people) and federal and state lands under various jurisdictions. Large non-contiguous sections of the Navajo Nation in New Mexico are: Ramah Navajo Indian Reservation in western Cibola County and southern McKinley County; Alamo Bend Navajo Indian Reservation in northwestern Socorro County; and Canoncito Indian Reservation in western Bernalillo County and eastern Cibola County. The total land area of the reservation is 62,362.062 km² (24,078.127 sq mi), making it by far the largest Indian reservation in the United States. It is almost exactly the same size as the state of West Virginia; it is slightly larger in land area, but slightly smaller if water area is included. Its resident population was 180,462 as of the 2000 census. The Navajo Nation is recognized as the largest federally tribe in the United States. Other Amerind tribes are located in this area, including several Pueblo nations: Congress established a Hopi (Navajo, Oozéí, or Ayahkinii &amp;quot;underground-house-people&amp;quot;) reservation within the Navajo Nation's reservation at an historic homeland where Hopi history predates that of Diné in the area. Adjacent or nearly adjacent to the Navajo Reservation are the Southern Ute of Colorado, the Ute Mountain Ute Tribe of Colorado, Utah, and New Mexico, both to the north; the Jicarilla Apache to the east, and other tribes to the west and south. A conflict over shared lands emerged in the 1980s, when the Department of the Interior attempted to relocate Diné living in the Navajo/Hopi Joint Use Area. The conflict was resolved, or at least forestalled, by the award of a seventy-five-year lease to Diné who refused to leave the former shared lands. From Wikipedia: &amp;quot;Navajo Nation&amp;quot;" id="92895837" latitude="36.138767" license="5" longitude="-109.512126" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="canyondechellynationalmonument canyondechelly canyon navajo dine arizona chinle southwest west" title="Dusk, Canyon de Chelly" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/15/92895837_e91794df40_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="553" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-04 09:47:00" description="She's a cute little thing. At first glance, you would assume she is a highly adoptable, lovely little house kitty. But as you get to know her, you learn about her medical problems. Cats without tails are often called Manx cats. Manx are a specific breed, that not only has no tail, but has a depression where the tail should be. The last vertebrae is missing. Your spinal cord runs through your vertebrae, and connects to nerves all over your body. When nerves are damaged, or nonexistent, you lose sensation and or the use of parts of the body. Because of this abnormal body structure, Manx cats, are very prone to nerve problems near the end of the spine. Without grossing you out with too much medical detail, this is the area that controls one's bowels and one's bladder. Deformities in this area leads to issues such as incontinence, inability to go potty by oneself, and constant leakage. Gilda &amp;amp; Steve were caring for Nicole at their home in Pennsylvania. They foster and do adoptions through Stray Cat Blues, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.petfinder.com/shelters/straycatblues.html&quot;&gt;www.petfinder.com/shelters/straycatblues.html&lt;/a&gt;. I met Gilda &amp;amp; Steve at Best Friends Animal Sanctuary in Utah in 1998, after acquiring the land for Rikki's Refuge, while I was still in the &amp;quot;oh my gosh, what have I gotten myself into !!!&amp;quot; mode. I spent two weeks out there studying, and begging all of their directors for every last little bit of helpful information that could give me. Gilda &amp;amp; Steve were there visiting and volunteering, and we hit it off. They were so excited to hear at Rikki's Refuge would soon become a home for un-adoptable animals. A few months later they picked up a precious little girl off the streets who was a Manx. She was named Kelly, and her medical problems were far more severe than Nicole's. Kelly was animal number 12 at Rikki's Refuge. She came to join us on December 1, 1998, long before we have built anything. Her condition required constant medical attention. She crossed the Rainbow Bridge on July 25, 2001 from medical complications. She had been the Spokes Cat of Cat House Number One, adorable and charming, and never complaining about all the medical treatment she needed - including daily baths." id="2113442785" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="nokill sanctuary refuge “rikki’s refuge” rescue saved love peace beautiful animal shelter volunteer pets give donate charity “save animals“ “help critters” “love your life” an animal” catfood dogfood cat dog" title="Nicole, Animal Number 3,000 Arrives at Rikki's Refuge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2382/2113442785_b5427a3b22_b.jpg" username="rikkis_refuge" views="674" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-20 00:02:19" description="The William B. Douglas party, including Navaho and Paiute Indians, celebrate their discovery of Rainbow Bridge, Utah, as they eat watermelon in Paiute Canyon, 1909." id="2594791808" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="williambdouglas navaho paiute indians rainbowbridge utah paiutecanyon 1909 history us america" title="Discovery of Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3026/2594791808_378a12ffda_b.jpg" username="Marion Doss" views="330" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-12-27 15:24:40" description="''''''''''''" id="2549160869" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="usnationalparks usnationalmonuments utah rainbowbridge nationalmonument file:name=20031225imga0157jpg file:digest=aef2f29e507f62d70647ad6bfa47b1fb" title="Rainbow bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3158/2549160869_8a9a8ec0ea_b.jpg" username="exquisitur" views="435" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-08 02:42:05" description="OK so for all you seasoned veteran houseboat runners, we thought this was too far to go from Bullfrog over 5 days. Did it on a half tank of gas. Surprised us, but we were frugal with the generator, etc." id="5001374250" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="lakepowell rainbowbridge utah water canyon southwest reflections" title="Rainbow Bridge Peek" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4113/5001374250_f78339f0cf_b.jpg" username="jah~" views="45" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-07 15:17:31" description="" id="4238701731" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="az americanwest arizona rainbowbridge utah bluesky redrock" title="Sun behind Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4038/4238701731_22465d9c5a_b.jpg" username="AlanH2O" views="68" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-12-03 10:49:49" description="An aerial view of Rainbow Bridge on Lake Powell, Utah." id="8242220980" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="rainbowbridge utah lakepowell" title="RainbowBridge2" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8340/8242220980_79afbe1d4b_b.jpg" username="Melissa Bowersock" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-12 20:42:41" description="Rainbow Bridge, Lake Powell, Arizona" id="2931669622" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="lake powell arizona utah usa america amerique etatsunis unitedstates west ouest" title="Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3233/2931669622_1db9a2e86f_b.jpg" username="La_Caille" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-12 20:56:56" description="Rainbow Bridge, Lake Powell, Arizona" id="2930835567" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="lake powell arizona utah usa america amerique etatsunis unitedstates west ouest" title="Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3249/2930835567_aa1c812da1_b.jpg" username="La_Caille" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-12 20:37:42" description="Rainbow Bridge, Lake Powell, Arizona" id="2931666658" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="lake powell arizona utah usa america amerique etatsunis unitedstates west ouest" title="Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3160/2931666658_6712f53deb_b.jpg" username="La_Caille" views="42" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-07-09 07:58:50" description="" id="24686394" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="rainbow bridge lake powell utah" title="Rainbow Bridge7" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/22/24686394_be74e0edf3_b.jpg" username="Knight of Roses" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2000-06-27 07:08:17" description="Rainbow Bridge" id="226793891" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="utah lakepowell glencanyon nationalrecreationarea desert geology canyon rainbowbridge nationalmonument trail" title="DSCN0077_b106_s8" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/57/226793891_fd512b527a_b.jpg" username="12fh" views="227" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-12-27 14:29:45" description="Near rainbow bridge." id="2549208201" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="utah rainbowbridge nationalmonument file:name=20031225imga0133jpg file:digest=15c4e7438fb3a12def35fdbf15723c97" title="Lake" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3190/2549208201_dc91f26b3b_b.jpg" username="exquisitur" views="31" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-08 19:55:21" description="Lake Powell, Utah" id="3704769716" latitude="37.065451" license="3" longitude="-111.107139" nbComments="4" rank="37" tags="rainbowbridge naturalbridge nature rock sly bridge red blue hdr 3exp tonemapped travel holidays utah lakepowell nikond70 vin60 postcard" title="Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2651/3704769716_04d78a6b5a_b.jpg" username="Vin60" views="207" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-08 03:22:12" description="Going after that old time look. From the south, opposite site entrance." id="5000800221" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="lakepowell rainbowbridge utah water canyon southwest" title="Rainbow in sepia" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4153/5000800221_e972433bea_b.jpg" username="jah~" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-08 02:53:56" description="HDR isn't what I normally do, but this was probably a good candidate." id="5001464540" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="6" rank="39" tags="lakepowell rainbowbridge utah water canyon southwest" title="Rainbow in high-def" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4084/5001464540_fbf213071a_b.jpg" username="jah~" views="49" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-12 20:55:21" description="Around Rainbow Bridge, Lake Powell, Arizona" id="2930825691" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="lake powell arizona utah usa america amerique etatsunis unitedstates west ouest" title="Tiny tribute to the indians who discovered the Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3062/2930825691_71c5681730_b.jpg" username="La_Caille" views="51" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-08 20:02:49" description="HDR 3exp +/-2 blended with a yellow-filtered B&amp;amp;W layer in hard lihgt" id="3704777562" latitude="37.065451" license="3" longitude="-111.107139" nbComments="3" rank="41" tags="rainbowbridge naturalbridge nature rock sly bridge red blue hdr 3exp tonemapped travel holidays utah lakepowell nikond70 vin60 yellowfilter" title="Rainbow Bridge (alt. take)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2567/3704777562_8d4e113caf_b.jpg" username="Vin60" views="62" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-04-30 03:31:02" description="back to the most known &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/vin60/3694230351&quot;&gt;North face&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;" id="3694251967" latitude="37.065451" license="3" longitude="-111.107139" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="rainbowbridge naturalbridge utah lakepowell rock red sky blue hdr 3exp tonemapped postcard travel holidays nikond70 vin60 5photosaday" title="Rainbow Bridge, South" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2464/3694251967_5ccb151b98_b.jpg" username="Vin60" views="48" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-04-29 20:33:31" description="" id="3703974291" latitude="37.065451" license="3" longitude="-111.107139" nbComments="6" rank="43" tags="rainbowbridge naturalbridge bridge nature rock sky sun blue red arch utah lakepowell travl holidays nikond70 vin60" title="Below Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3510/3703974291_ee3c5836a1_b.jpg" username="Vin60" views="45" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-08 02:58:18" description="Probably the spot where most pictures of this monster are taken. The scale really cant be conveyed in a photo. This this hunk of rock is enormous. Take a wide angle if you go." id="5000816553" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="44" tags="lakepowell rainbowbridge utah canyon southwest" title="Cliché View" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4144/5000816553_b31b8d0fa0_b.jpg" username="jah~" views="50" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-05-02 17:19:26" description="A rainbow bridges between two monuments in the area of Mexican Mountain in the San Rafael Swell in east-central Utah." id="482376565" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="45" tags="rainbow sanrafaelswell sanrafael sunset sky clouds sun sanrafaelreef sanrafaeldesert desertredrockutahtkellyphototkelly phototom kellytomusautgreen river" title="Rainbow Over San Rafael Swell" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/211/482376565_7bc76f345e_b.jpg" username="tomkellyphoto" views="248" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-24 20:19:31" description="聽說Utah的拱門國家公園也很多這樣的景色" id="2280534111" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="46" tags="2000usa" title="Lake Powell - Rainbow Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2055/2280534111_3375e97731_b.jpg" username="synnwang" views="54" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-26 01:09:11" description="Angles rest is a special area of BFAS where those who cross the rainbow bridge find their final resting place. The gate was designed by Cyrus Mejia who was one of the original founders of Best Friends. Inside the gate hundreds of memorials and markers for beloved animals and the sound of wind chimes create a touching atmosphere." id="3975559707" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="47" tags="photo bestfriendstrip bestfriendsanimalsanctuary puck90 kanab utah angelsrest petcemetery anglecanyon bfas" title="Angles Rest" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3487/3975559707_0ec9953fd8_b.jpg" username="puck90" views="256" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-12 20:43:05" description="Around Rainbow Bridge, Lake Powell, Arizona" id="2931674702" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="lake powell arizona utah usa america amerique etatsunis unitedstates west ouest" title="Lake Powell" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3159/2931674702_9d9a3529e1_b.jpg" username="La_Caille" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-12 20:56:41" description="Around Rainbow Bridge, Lake Powell, Arizona" id="2931689724" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="lake powell arizona utah usa america amerique etatsunis unitedstates west ouest" title="Lake Powell" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3232/2931689724_2bfc7fb001_b.jpg" username="La_Caille" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-12 20:44:19" description="Around Rainbow Bridge, Lake Powell, Arizona" id="2930820587" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="lake powell arizona utah usa america amerique etatsunis unitedstates west ouest" title="Lake Powell" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3220/2930820587_64a81aefb7_b.jpg" username="La_Caille" views="32" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-10-05 16:29:19" description="" id="5088156991" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="naturalbridge utahautumnroadtrip brycecanyonnationalpark brycecanyoncity utahhighway12 rainbowpointdrivehighway63 fallcolors utah usa" title="Natural Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4151/5088156991_49be563384_b.jpg" username="TTVo" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-10-05 16:35:00" description="" id="5088754856" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="naturalbridge utahautumnroadtrip brycecanyonnationalpark brycecanyoncity utahhighway12 rainbowpointdrivehighway63 fallcolors utah usa" title="Natural Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4129/5088754856_0810280e64_b.jpg" username="TTVo" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-21 09:44:57" description="" id="4079217764" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="utah canyon wildlife adventure camping roadtrip antelope island bison sunset rainbow parks longexposure sky night stars timelapse" title="nada bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2778/4079217764_3a0bc1dd50_b.jpg" username="craigregular" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-28 18:19:19" description="From my good friend Linda: Last Monday evening Gypsy crossed the Rainbow Bridge. Mother had Gypsy for about 10 years. Her beloved Tui had gone to her reward and Mother was with me at the vets so we took a peak at the ones there. Gypsy was already grown and we received different stories regarding her background. But, bottom line was that she had been there for a year waiting for a home. We believe that she had been being chased by dogs and had been trapped and turned over to the vet in the hopes of finding a good home. She was absolutely terrified. Mother kept saying that her eyes haunted her so we ended back at the vets and took her home. Thus began a long period of time before she would trust anyone. At first we put her in a third room that Mother used for her office. Mother didn't see her but knew she was eating. Then one day she pushed open the louvered doors and didn't know where she was. After a long search, I got down under Mother's desk and pulled aside some magazine holders next to the file cabinet. There she was with a look of terror on her face. (Whoever says that animals don't have expressions needs to take another look.) Mother decided to spend time each day reading to her. So, every day she would go into the room and rock and read. We thought Gypsy needed to hear the sound of her voice. After a while we gradually moved the litter box toward the bathroom and into the tub. Gypsy cooperated with that relocation as well as the relocation of her food and water. Gradually she began to trust Mother and me. The first time I went to put her in the carrier I didn't know what she would do. She hid inside the litter box. I picked her up and she just froze. When we evacuated for Katrina I had to board her for a month. After Mother was settled by my sister Leslie Kay in Utah, Joe and I picked her up from the vet's and flew her out of New Orleans. Gypsy was with Mother until she moved back from Utah in July of 06. Through the years Gypsy gradually became a little more confident with strangers. When Mother had to leave for her first surgery in mid June, it took several weeks of lying on the floor beside the bed for me to coax her out. Gradually she got to the point where she would come out shortly after I arrived and let me comb and pet her. I was over there with her last Sunday and she came out several times, purring and nudging to be combed and scratched Phyllis has started to go over and spend the night several times a week to keep her company. When she went over Monday night Gypsy appeared to have peacefully gone. I went to Mother's, met Phyllis and together we took her to the Emergency Pet Clinic where they respectfully took her remains. The young man was very nice and commented that she was obviously a well taken care of cat. Mother is having a tough time dealing with this loss and it has dampened the excitement of being discharged on Monday. I will give further details on that following this email. I just felt that Gypsy deserved her own. Please note her beautiful nails. We had soft claws (or is it paws, I never can remember) put on every 6-8 weeks. Linda" id="4142604096" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="4" rank="54" tags="safoocat gypsy laura linda cat rainbowbridge" title="Gypsy Linda's mother's cat" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2746/4142604096_399fe350dc_b.jpg" username="safoocat" views="173" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-20 09:54:42" description="Monument Valley, Arizona; part of the Navajo Nation. -- NOT FOR COMMERCIAL USE -- Creative Commons - Attribution - Non commercial - No Derivative Works 3.0 United States License. creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/us/ === Ya' At' Eeh - Navajo Greeting The Navajo Nation stretches from the Four Corners Monument landmark across the Colorado Plateau into Arizona, Utah, and New Mexico. Located within the Navajo Nation are Canyon de Chelly National Monument, Monument Valley, Rainbow Bridge National Monument, the Hopi Indian Reservation, and the Shiprock landmark. The seat of government is located at the town of Window Rock, Arizona. ~~~ For more info see my blog :: &lt;a href=&quot;http://wp.me/pBIIx-63&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wp.me/pBIIx-63&lt;/a&gt; ~~~ Four Cardinal Light Phenomena: Time and space are defined by the four cardinal light phenomena: Dawn (white, east); Midday (blue, south); Evening Twilight (yellow, west) and Night (black, north). ~~~ Elements Used in this Production: Photography: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motionblurstudios.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.motionblurstudios.com&lt;/a&gt; - Chris Luckhardt; Leo Bar; Wikimedia Art &amp;amp; Paintings: R Yellowhair Research: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Navajo.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.Navajo.org&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.NavajoNationParks.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.NavajoNationParks.org&lt;/a&gt; Watch this &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/10302274&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; on Vimeo. Video created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/leobar&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Leo Bar PIX IN MOTION&lt;/a&gt;." id="4447950644" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="55" tags="leobar pixinmotion navajo nativeamerican monumentvalley photography animation timelapse hdr hd nature photostory aerial vimeo vimeo:id=10302274" title="Video - Navajo Lights on Vimeo by Leo Bar PIX IN MOTION" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2723/4447950644_a0e0c88c52_b.jpg" username="Leo Bar PIX IN MOTION" views="123" />
</photos>
