<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Reliance Building Chicago">

<photo  date_taken="2006-05-26 12:53:29" description="Reliance Building (Burnham and Root, 1890)" id="3268853708" latitude="41.883" license="1" longitude="-87.628167" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="chicago illinois loop reliancebuilding burnhamroot 1890 nrhp 70000237" title="Reliance" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3432/3268853708_95813bbaf6_b.jpg" username="reallyboring" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-10 17:17:41" description="I'm staying here for the weekend. This is the Reliance Building on the corner of State and Washington. It used to be one of my favorite places back when I was young. The building was a total derelict, I dreamed of having an office here, with yellow walls and linoleum floors." id="1078625010" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="7" rank="2" tags="chicago hotelburnham burnhamandroot reliancebuilding" title="Hotel Burnham, Chicago" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1262/1078625010_6e28f662cb_b.jpg" username="yuzu" views="275" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-13 18:14:36" description="Reliance Building  Chicago, IL" id="145862245" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="3" tags="chicago architecture classwithblairkamin" title="reliance" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/47/145862245_62c5f9585c_b.jpg" username="suttonhoo" views="90" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-03-26 12:00:23" description="&amp;quot;Chicago Windows&amp;quot; with terra cotta ornamentation in the historic Reliance Building (now the Burnham Hotel) on State Street in Chicago, Illinois." id="126766597" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="4" rank="4" tags="portal window chicago illinois ornamentalart atelierteee terencefaircloth" title="Reliance Building Windows" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/55/126766597_fb5068dbdd_b.jpg" username="Atelier Teee" views="1076" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-02-25 22:32:16" description="View Large on Black at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewindypixel.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.thewindypixel.com!&lt;/a&gt; The Reliance building at 20 N. State Street is one of the earliest “skyscrapers”; being a construction whose weight is supported primarily by an internal steel frame. The very famous Burnham firm was responsible for its design and construction. The building is all glass and terra cotta tiles on the outside and is the current home, appropriately, to the Burnham Hotel. Ironically, however, the ground floor is home to the Atwood Cafe despite the fact that the ground floor and basement were designed by Burnham’s previous partner, John Root. Never eaten here, but I’d love to stay in the hotel sometime – it’s got a great location and looks like it would have wonderful rooms and views. By the way - was out Baltimore way at my brother in law's wedding - back now, exhausted, with full memory cards in tow. I'll catch up with you later as well as post tWp and Garrett's Table stuff here on flickr ASAP!" id="3716488901" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="32" rank="5" tags="kernjustin nikon d700 wwwthewindypixelcom the atwood cafe reliance building chicago chicagoist hdr night" title="The Atwood Cafe and The Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3421/3716488901_584e17740f_b.jpg" username="kern.justin" views="816" />
<photo  date_taken="1989-09-07 16:35:50" description="Vivian, South Dakota, looking southwest, September 1989. The depot was built in 1906, the same year Vivian came into existence. That is the year that the Chicago, Milwaukee &amp;amp; St. Paul Railway extended its line as far as Vivian. Reliance, Presho and Kennebec had come into existence in 1905, when the railroad had reached those points. The last C. M. &amp;amp; St. P. train came through Vivian sometime in the late 1970s or early 1980s (the railroad crossing sign is visible at the far left). I wasn't living there at the time, so I can only guess. The line was refurbished (sort of) in the late 1980s, and the Dakota Central Railroad would send an occasional train crawling at a snail's pace past Vivian about once a week or once a month, or so it seemed to me. They crawled because the tracks were in such bad shape, even after the &amp;quot;refurbishing,&amp;quot; that things &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/welfl/529224160/&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt; happened occasionally. I was in the depot many times in 1983, 1984 and again from 1989 to 1993, as it was used as a storage building by my employers, Midwest Custom Pools and Kevin Patrick Construction. The historian in me continually pestered my friend Kevin Patrick to refurbish the depot before it was too late. He always refused. Then in 2006 he told me he wished he had refurbished the depot while there was still a chance. The historian in me shouted something like this at him, &amp;quot;Aaaacccchhhhh!&amp;quot; Here is what the same scene looks like today: &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?hl=en&amp;amp;source=embed&amp;amp;q=Vivian,+SD&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Vivian,+Lyman,+South+Dakota&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;ei=Ca8lS_-IJ5TYNemh9OMJ&amp;amp;ved=0CAoQ8gEwAA&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbll=43.925985,-100.291956&amp;amp;panoid=hknsITKtUTM0H3jO77bKrw&amp;amp;cbp=13,223.75,,0,-2.37&amp;amp;ll=43.935978,-100.287838&amp;amp;spn=0.002596,0.004672&amp;amp;z=14&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View Google Image&lt;/a&gt;. The yellow truck is parked where the depot stood. Sad." id="4184093894" latitude="43.926057" license="3" longitude="-100.291968" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="vivian lymancounty southdakota kevinpatrick chicagomilwaukeestpaulrailroad depot 1989 viviansouthdakota searsks500" title="Vivian, SD, Railroad Depot, Sept. 1989 (20 Years Ago)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2689/4184093894_0500935c3d_b.jpg" username="WELFL" views="340" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-02-06 21:46:28" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; View of the State Street Mall from Madison Street to Washington Street &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; Holabird &amp;amp; Roche (Chicago, Ill.); Ahlschlager, Walter W.; D.H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co.; Rapp and Rapp &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of State Street showing the Woolworth building and the Reliance Building (now the Hotel Burnham). The Chicago Theater can be seen on the right. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William, 1987 &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1905; 1928 (Woolworth); 1895; 1921(Chicago Theater) &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru005_05_cF For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5430028986" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="highrisebuildings highrises hotels commercialbuildings streetscapes pedestrianmall pedestrians theaters architecture" title="View of the State Street Mall from Madison Street to Washington Street" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5100/5430028986_0e029a6600_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="995" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-21 13:47:02" description="Army Photography Contest - 2007 - FMWRC - Arts and Crafts - Chicago in December Photo By: 2LT Matthew Fitzgibbon To learn more about the annual U.S. Army Photography Competition, visit us online at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.armymwr.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.armymwr.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;U.S. Army Arts and Crafts History&lt;/strong&gt; After World War I the reductions to the Army left the United States with a small force. The War Department faced monumental challenges in preparing for World War II. One of those challenges was soldier morale. Recreational activities for off duty time would be important. The arts and crafts program informally evolved to augment the needs of the War Department. On January 9, 1941, the Secretary of War, Henry L. Stimson, appointed Frederick H. Osborn, a prominent U.S. businessman and philanthropist, Chairman of the War Department Committee on Education, Recreation and Community Service. In 1940 and 1941, the United States involvement in World War II was more of sympathy and anticipation than of action. However, many different types of institutions were looking for ways to help the war effort. The Museum of Modern Art in New York was one of these institutions. In April, 1941, the Museum announced a poster competition, “Posters for National Defense.” The directors stated “The Museum feels that in a time of national emergency the artists of a country are as important an asset as men skilled in other fields, and that the nation’s first-rate talent should be utilized by the government for its official design work... Discussions have been held with officials of the Army and the Treasury who have expressed remarkable enthusiasm...” In May 1941, the Museum exhibited “Britain at War”, a show selected by Sir Kenneth Clark, director of the National Gallery in London. The “Prize-Winning Defense Posters” were exhibited in July through September concurrently with “Britain at War.” The enormous overnight growth of the military force meant mobilization type construction at every camp. Construction was fast; facilities were not fancy; rather drab and depressing. In 1941, the Fort Custer Army Illustrators, while on strenuous war games maneuvers in Tennessee, documented the exercise The Bulletin of the Museum of Modern Art, Vol. 9, No. 3 (Feb. 1942), described their work. “Results were astonishingly good; they showed serious devotion ...to the purpose of depicting the Army scene with unvarnished realism and a remarkable ability to capture this scene from the soldier’s viewpoint. Civilian amateur and professional artists had been transformed into soldier-artists. Reality and straightforward documentation had supplanted (replaced) the old romantic glorification and false dramatization of war and the slick suavity (charm) of commercial drawing.” “In August of last year, Fort Custer Army Illustrators held an exhibition, the first of its kind in the new Army, at the Camp Service Club. Soldiers who saw the exhibition, many of whom had never been inside an art gallery, enjoyed it thoroughly. Civilian visitors, too, came and admired. The work of the group showed them a new aspect of the Army; there were many phases of Army life they had never seen or heard of before. Newspapers made much of it and, most important, the Army approved. Army officials saw that it was not only authentic material, but that here was a source of enlivenment (vitalization) to the Army and a vivid medium for conveying the Army’s purposes and processes to civilians and soldiers.” Brigadier General Frederick H. Osborn and War Department leaders were concerned because few soldiers were using the off duty recreation areas that were available. Army commanders recognized that efficiency is directly correlated with morale, and that morale is largely determined from the manner in which an individual spends his own free time. Army morale enhancement through positive off duty recreation programs is critical in combat staging areas. To encourage soldier use of programs, the facilities drab and uninviting environment had to be improved. A program utilizing talented artists and craftsmen to decorate day rooms, mess halls, recreation halls and other places of general assembly was established by the Facilities Section of Special Services. The purpose was to provide an environment that would reflect the military tradition, accomplishments and the high standard of army life. The fact that this work was to be done by the men themselves had the added benefit of contributing to the esprit de corps (teamwork, or group spirit) of the unit. The plan was first tested in October of 1941, at Camp Davis, North Carolina. A studio workshop was set up and a group of soldier artists were placed on special duty to design and decorate the facilities. Additionally, evening recreation art classes were scheduled three times a week. A second test was established at Fort Belvoir, Virginia a month later. The success of these programs lead to more installations requesting the program. After Pearl Harbor was bombed, the Museum of Modern Art appointed Mr. James Soby, to the position of Director of the Armed Service Program on January 15, 1942. The subsequent program became a combination of occupational therapy, exhibitions and morale-sustaining activities. Through the efforts of Mr. Soby, the museum program included; a display of Fort Custer Army Illustrators work from February through April 5, 1942. The museum also included the work of soldier-photographers in this exhibit. On May 6, 1942, Mr. Soby opened an art sale of works donated by museum members. The sale was to raise funds for the Soldier Art Program of Special Services Division. The bulk of these proceeds were to be used to provide facilities and materials for soldier artists in Army camps throughout the country. Members of the Museum had responded with paintings, sculptures, watercolors, gouaches, drawings, etchings and lithographs. Hundreds of works were received, including oils by Winslow Homer, Orozco, John Kane, Speicher, Eilshemius, de Chirico; watercolors by Burchfield and Dufy; drawings by Augustus John, Forain and Berman, and prints by Cezanne, Lautrec, Matisse and Bellows. The War Department plan using soldier-artists to decorate and improve buildings and grounds worked. Many artists who had been drafted into the Army volunteered to paint murals in waiting rooms and clubs, to decorate dayrooms, and to landscape grounds. For each artist at work there were a thousand troops who watched. These bystanders clamored to participate, and classes in drawing, painting, sculpture and photography were offered. Larger working space and more instructors were required to meet the growing demand. Civilian art instructors and local communities helped to meet this cultural need, by providing volunteer instruction and facilities. Some proceeds from the Modern Museum of Art sale were used to print 25,000 booklets called “Interior Design and Soldier Art.” The booklet showed examples of soldier-artist murals that decorated places of general assembly. It was a guide to organizing, planning and executing the soldier-artist program. The balance of the art sale proceeds were used to purchase the initial arts and crafts furnishings for 350 Army installations in the USA. In November, 1942, General Somervell directed that a group of artists be selected and dispatched to active theaters to paint war scenes with the stipulation that soldier artists would not paint in lieu of military duties. Aileen Osborn Webb, sister of Brigadier General Frederick H. Osborn, launched the American Crafts Council in 1943. She was an early champion of the Army program. While soldiers were participating in fixed facilities in the USA, many troops were being shipped overseas to Europe and the Pacific (1942-1945). They had long periods of idleness and waiting in staging areas. At that time the wounded were lying in hospitals, both on land and in ships at sea. The War Department and Red Cross responded by purchasing kits of arts and crafts tools and supplies to distribute to “these restless personnel.” A variety of small “Handicraft Kits” were distributed free of charge. Leathercraft, celluloid etching, knotting and braiding, metal tooling, drawing and clay modeling are examples of the types of kits sent. In January, 1944, the Interior Design Soldier Artist program was more appropriately named the “Arts and Crafts Section” of Special Services. The mission was “to fulfill the natural human desire to create, provide opportunities for self-expression, serve old skills and develop new ones, and assist the entire recreation program through construction work, publicity, and decoration.” The National Army Art Contest was planned for the late fall of 1944. In June of 1945, the National Gallery of Art in Washington D.C., for the first time in its history opened its facilities for the exhibition of the soldier art and photography submitted to this contest. The “Infantry Journal, Inc.” printed a small paperback booklet containing 215 photographs of pictures exhibited in the National Gallery of Art. In August of 1944, the Museum of Modern Art, Armed Forces Program, organized an art center for veterans. Abby Rockefeller, in particular, had a strong interest in this project. Soldiers were invited to sketch, paint, or model under the guidance of skilled artists and craftsmen. Victor d’Amico, who was in charge of the Museum’s Education Department, was quoted in Russell Lynes book, Good Old Modern: An Intimate Portrait of the Museum of Modern Art. “I asked one fellow why he had taken up art and he said, Well, I just came back from destroying everything. I made up my mind that if I ever got out of the Army and out of the war I was never going to destroy another thing in my life, and I decided that art was the thing that I would do.” Another man said to d’Amico, “Art is like a good night’s sleep. You come away refreshed and at peace.” In late October, 1944, an Arts and Crafts Branch of Special Services Division, Headquarters, European Theater of Operations was established. A versatile program of handcrafts flourished among the Army occupation troops. The increased interest in crafts, rather than fine arts, at this time lead to a new name for the program: The “Handicrafts Branch.” In 1945, the War Department published a new manual, “Soldier Handicrafts”, to help implement this new emphasis. The manual contained instructions for setting up crafts facilities, selecting as well as improvising tools and equipment, and basic information on a variety of arts and crafts. As the Army moved from a combat to a peacetime role, the majority of crafts shops in the United States were equipped with woodworking power machinery for construction of furnishings and objects for personal living. Based on this new trend, in 1946 the program was again renamed, this time as “Manual Arts.” At the same time, overseas programs were now employing local artists and craftsmen to operate the crafts facilities and instruct in a variety of arts and crafts. These highly skilled, indigenous instructors helped to stimulate the soldiers’ interest in the respective native cultures and artifacts. Thousands of troops overseas were encouraged to record their experiences on film. These photographs provided an invaluable means of communication between troops and their families back home. When the war ended, the Navy had a firm of architects and draftsmen on contract to design ships. Since there was no longer a need for more ships, they were given a new assignment: To develop a series of instructional guides for arts and crafts. These were called “Hobby Manuals.” The Army was impressed with the quality of the Navy manuals and had them reprinted and adopted for use by Army troops. By 1948, the arts and crafts practiced throughout the Army were so varied and diverse that the program was renamed “Hobby Shops.” The first “Interservice Photography Contest” was held in 1948. Each service is eligible to send two years of their winning entries forward for the bi-annual interservice contest. In 1949, the first All Army Crafts Contest was also held. Once again, it was clear that the program title, “Hobby Shops” was misleading and overlapped into other forms of recreation. In January, 1951, the program was designated as “The Army Crafts Program.” The program was recognized as an essential Army recreation activity along with sports, libraries, service clubs, soldier shows and soldier music. In the official statement of mission, professional leadership was emphasized to insure a balanced, progressive schedule of arts and crafts would be conducted in well-equipped, attractive facilities on all Army installations. The program was now defined in terms of a “Basic Seven Program” which included: drawing and painting; ceramics and sculpture; metal work; leathercrafts; model building; photography and woodworking. These programs were to be conducted regularly in facilities known as the “multiple-type crafts shop.” For functional reasons, these facilities were divided into three separate technical areas for woodworking, photography and the arts and crafts. During the Korean Conflict, the Army Crafts program utilized the personnel and shops in Japan to train soldiers to instruct crafts in Korea. The mid-1950s saw more soldiers with cars and the need to repair their vehicles was recognized at Fort Carson, Colorado, by the craft director. Soldiers familiar with crafts shops knew that they had tools and so automotive crafts were established. By 1958, the Engineers published an Official Design Guide on Crafts Shops and Auto Crafts Shops. In 1959, the first All Army Art Contest was held. Once more, the Army Crafts Program responded to the needs of soldiers. In the 1960’s, the war in Vietnam was a new challenge for the Army Crafts Program. The program had three levels of support; fixed facilities, mobile trailers designed as portable photo labs, and once again a “Kit Program.” The kit program originated at Headquarters, Department of Army, and it proved to be very popular with soldiers. Tom Turner, today a well-known studio potter, was a soldier at Ft. Jackson, South Carolina in the 1960s. In the December 1990 / January 1991 “American Crafts” magazine, Turner, who had been a graduate student in art school when he was drafted, said the program was “a godsend.” The Army Artist Program was re-initiated in cooperation with the Office of Military History to document the war in Vietnam. Soldier-artists were identified and teams were formed to draw and paint the events of this combat. Exhibitions of these soldier-artist works were produced and toured throughout the USA. In 1970, the original name of the program, “Arts and Crafts”, was restored. In 1971, the “Arts and Crafts/Skills Development Program” was established for budget presentations and construction projects. After the Vietnam demobilization, a new emphasis was placed on service to families and children of soldiers. To meet this new challenge in an environment of funding constraints the arts and crafts program began charging fees for classes. More part-time personnel were used to teach formal classes. Additionally, a need for more technical-vocational skills training for military personnel was met by close coordination with Army Education Programs. Army arts and crafts directors worked with soldiers during “Project Transition” to develop soldier skills for new careers in the public sector. The main challenge in the 1980s and 90s was, and is, to become “self-sustaining.” Directors have been forced to find more ways to generate increased revenue to help defray the loss of appropriated funds and to cover the non-appropriated funds expenses of the program. Programs have added and increased emphasis on services such as, picture framing, gallery sales, engraving and trophy sales, etc... New programs such as multi-media computer graphics appeal to customers of the 1990’s. The Gulf War presented the Army with some familiar challenges such as personnel off duty time in staging areas. Department of Army volunteer civilian recreation specialists were sent to Saudi Arabia in January, 1991, to organize recreation programs. Arts and crafts supplies were sent to the theater. An Army Humor Cartoon Contest was conducted for the soldiers in the Gulf, and arts and crafts programs were set up to meet soldier interests. The increased operations tempo of the ‘90’s Army has once again placed emphasis on meeting the “recreation needs of deployed soldiers.” Arts and crafts activities and a variety of programs are assets commanders must have to meet the deployment challenges of these very different scenarios. The Army arts and crafts program, no matter what it has been titled, has made some unique contributions for the military and our society in general. Army arts and crafts does not fit the narrow definition of drawing and painting or making ceramics, but the much larger sense of arts and crafts. It is painting and drawing. It also encompasses: * all forms of design. (fabric, clothes, household appliances, dishes, vases, houses, automobiles, landscapes, computers, copy machines, desks, industrial machines, weapon systems, air crafts, roads, etc...) * applied technology (photography, graphics, woodworking, sculpture, metal smithing, weaving and textiles, sewing, advertising, enameling, stained glass, pottery, charts, graphs, visual aides and even formats for correspondence...) * a way of making learning fun, practical and meaningful (through the process of designing and making an object the creator must decide which materials and techniques to use, thereby engaging in creative problem solving and discovery) skills taught have military applications. * a way to acquire quality items and save money by doing-it-yourself (making furniture, gifts, repairing things ...). * a way to pursue college credit, through on post classes. * a universal and non-verbal language (a picture is worth a thousand words). * food for the human psyche, an element of morale that allows for individual expression (freedom). * the celebration of human spirit and excellence (our highest form of public recognition is through a dedicated monument). * physical and mental therapy (motor skill development, stress reduction, etc...). * an activity that promotes self-reliance and self-esteem. * the record of mankind, and in this case, of the Army. What would the world be like today if this generally unknown program had not existed? To quantitatively state the overall impact of this program on the world is impossible. Millions of soldier citizens have been directly and indirectly exposed to arts and crafts because this program existed. One activity, photography can provide a clue to its impact. Soldiers encouraged to take pictures, beginning with WW II, have shared those images with family and friends. Classes in “How to Use a Camera” to “How to Develop Film and Print Pictures” were instrumental in soldiers seeing the results of using quality equipment. A good camera and lens could make a big difference in the quality of the print. They bought the top of the line equipment. When they were discharged from the Army or home on leave this new equipment was showed to the family and friends. Without this encouragement and exposure to photography many would not have recorded their personal experiences or known the difference quality equipment could make. Families and friends would not have had the opportunity to “see” the environment their soldier was living in without these photos. Germany, Italy, Korea, Japan, Panama, etc... were far away places that most had not visited. As the twenty first century approaches, the predictions for an arts renaissance by Megatrends 2000 seem realistic based on the Army Arts and Crafts Program practical experience. In the April ‘95 issue of “American Demographics” magazine, an article titled “Generation X” fully supports that this is indeed the case today. Television and computers have greatly contributed to “Generation X” being more interested in the visual arts and crafts. Connect with us: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Facebook.com/FamilyMWR&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.Facebook.com/FamilyMWR&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Twitter.com/FamilyMWR&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.Twitter.com/FamilyMWR&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.YouTube.com/FamilyMWR&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.YouTube.com/FamilyMWR&lt;/a&gt;" id="4930277480" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="matthewfitzgibbon black white photo contest army fmwrc mwr digital photography crafts arts crafting home winner best images 35mm nikon canon camera soldier warrior military photoshop landscape experimental catagory family morale welfare recreation united states first place second" title="Army Photography Contest - 2007 - FMWRC - Arts and Crafts - Chicago in December" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4134/4930277480_a5358de688_b.jpg" username="familymwr" views="1895" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-11-05 09:18:10" description="President-Elect Barack Obama’s Victory Speech at Grant Park, Chicago November 4, 2008 If there is anyone out there who still doubts that America is a place where all things are possible; who still wonders if the dream of our founders is alive in our time; who still questions the power of our democracy, tonight is your answer. It’s the answer told by lines that stretched around schools and churches in numbers this nation has never seen; by people who waited three hours and four hours, many for the very first time in their lives, because they believed that this time must be different; that their voice could be that difference. It’s the answer spoken by young and old, rich and poor, Democrat and Republican, black, white, Latino, Asian, Native American, gay, straight, disabled and not disabled - Americans who sent a message to the world that we have never been a collection of Red States and Blue States: we are, and always will be, the United States of America. It’s the answer that led those who have been told for so long by so many to be cynical, and fearful, and doubtful of what we can achieve to put their hands on the arc of history and bend it once more toward the hope of a better day. It’s been a long time coming, but tonight, because of what we did on this day, in this election, at this defining moment, change has come to America. I just received a very gracious call from Senator McCain. He fought long and hard in this campaign, and hes fought even longer and harder for the country he loves. He has endured sacrifices for America that most of us cannot begin to imagine, and we are better off for the service rendered by this brave and selfless leader. I congratulate him and Governor Palin for all they have achieved, and I look forward to working with them to renew this nations promise in the months ahead. I want to thank my partner in this journey, a man who campaigned from his heart and spoke for the men and women he grew up with on the streets of Scranton and rode with on that train home to Delaware, the Vice President-elect of the United States, Joe Biden. I would not be standing here tonight without the unyielding support of my best friend for the last sixteen years, the rock of our family and the love of my life, our nations next First Lady, Michelle Obama. Sasha and Malia, I love you both so much, and you have earned the new puppy that’s coming with us to the White House. And while she’s no longer with us, I know my grandmother is watching, along with the family that made me who I am. I miss them tonight, and know that my debt to them is beyond measure. To my campaign manager David Plouffe, my chief strategist David Axelrod, and the best campaign team ever assembled in the history of politics - you made this happen, and I am forever grateful for what you’ve sacrificed to get it done. But above all, I will never forget who this victory truly belongs to - it belongs to you. I was never the likeliest candidate for this office. We didnt start with much money or many endorsements. Our campaign was not hatched in the halls of Washington - it began in the backyards of Des Moines and the living rooms of Concord and the front porches of Charleston. It was built by working men and women who dug into what little savings they had to give five dollars and ten dollars and twenty dollars to this cause. It grew strength from the young people who rejected the myth of their generations apathy; who left their homes and their families for jobs that offered little pay and less sleep; from the not-so-young people who braved the bitter cold and scorching heat to knock on the doors of perfect strangers; from the millions of Americans who volunteered, and organized, and proved that more than two centuries later, a government of the people, by the people and for the people has not perished from this Earth. This is your victory. I know you didn’t do this just to win an election and I know you didn’t do it for me. You did it because you understand the enormity of the task that lies ahead. For even as we celebrate tonight, we know the challenges that tomorrow will bring are the greatest of our lifetime - two wars, a planet in peril, the worst financial crisis in a century. Even as we stand here tonight, we know there are brave Americans waking up in the deserts of Iraq and the mountains of Afghanistan to risk their lives for us. There are mothers and fathers who will lie awake after their children fall asleep and wonder how they’ll make the mortgage, or pay their doctors bills, or save enough for college. There is new energy to harness and new jobs to be created; new schools to build and threats to meet and alliances to repair. The road ahead will be long. Our climb will be steep. We may not get there in one year or even one term, but America - I have never been more hopeful than I am tonight that we will get there. I promise you - we as a people will get there. There will be setbacks and false starts. There are many who wont agree with every decision or policy I make as President, and we know that government cant solve every problem. But I will always be honest with you about the challenges we face. I will listen to you, especially when we disagree. And above all, I will ask you join in the work of remaking this nation the only way its been done in America for two-hundred and twenty-one years - block by block, brick by brick, calloused hand by calloused hand. What began twenty-one months ago in the depths of winter must not end on this autumn night. This victory alone is not the change we seek - it is only the chance for us to make that change. And that cannot happen if we go back to the way things were. It cannot happen without you. So let us summon a new spirit of patriotism; of service and responsibility where each of us resolves to pitch in and work harder and look after not only ourselves, but each other. Let us remember that if this financial crisis taught us anything, its that we cannot have a thriving Wall Street while Main Street suffers - in this country, we rise or fall as one nation; as one people. Let us resist the temptation to fall back on the same partisanship and pettiness and immaturity that has poisoned our politics for so long. Let us remember that it was a man from this state who first carried the banner of the Republican Party to the White House - a party founded on the values of self-reliance, individual liberty, and national unity. Those are values we all share, and while the Democratic Party has won a great victory tonight, we do so with a measure of humility and determination to heal the divides that have held back our progress. As Lincoln said to a nation far more divided than ours, We are not enemies, but friends, though passion may have strained it must not break our bonds of affection. And to those Americans whose support I have yet to earn - I may not have won your vote, but I hear your voices, I need your help, and I will be your President too. And to all those watching tonight from beyond our shores, from parliaments and palaces to those who are huddled around radios in the forgotten corners of our world - our stories are singular, but our destiny is shared, and a new dawn of American leadership is at hand. To those who would tear this world down - we will defeat you. To those who seek peace and security - we support you. And to all those who have wondered if Americas beacon still burns as bright - tonight we proved once more that the true strength of our nation comes not from our the might of our arms or the scale of our wealth, but from the enduring power of our ideals: democracy, liberty, opportunity, and unyielding hope. For that is the true genius of America - that America can change. Our union can be perfected. And what we have already achieved gives us hope for what we can and must achieve tomorrow. This election had many firsts and many stories that will be told for generations. But one that’s on my mind tonight is about a woman who cast her ballot in Atlanta. Shes a lot like the millions of others who stood in line to make their voice heard in this election except for one thing - Ann Nixon Cooper is 106 years old. She was born just a generation past slavery; a time when there were no cars on the road or planes in the sky; when someone like her couldn’t vote for two reasons - because she was a woman and because of the color of her skin. And tonight, I think about all that shes seen throughout her century in America - the heartache and the hope; the struggle and the progress; the times we were told that we cant, and the people who pressed on with that American creed: Yes we can. At a time when women’s voices were silenced and their hopes dismissed, she lived to see them stand up and speak out and reach for the ballot. Yes we can. When there was despair in the dust bowl and depression across the land, she saw a nation conquer fear itself with a New Deal, new jobs and a new sense of common purpose. Yes we can. When the bombs fell on our harbor and tyranny threatened the world, she was there to witness a generation rise to greatness and a democracy was saved. Yes we can. She was there for the buses in Montgomery, the hoses in Birmingham, a bridge in Selma, and a preacher from Atlanta who told a people that We Shall Overcome. Yes we can. A man touched down on the moon, a wall came down in Berlin, a world was connected by our own science and imagination. And this year, in this election, she touched her finger to a screen, and cast her vote, because after 106 years in America, through the best of times and the darkest of hours, she knows how America can change. Yes we can. America, we have come so far. We have seen so much. But there is so much more to do. So tonight, let us ask ourselves - if our children should live to see the next century; if my daughters should be so lucky to live as long as Ann Nixon Cooper, what change will they see? What progress will we have made? This is our chance to answer that call. This is our moment. This is our time - to put our people back to work and open doors of opportunity for our kids; to restore prosperity and promote the cause of peace; to reclaim the American Dream and reaffirm that fundamental truth - that out of many, we are one; that while we breathe, we hope, and where we are met with cynicism, and doubt, and those who tell us that we cant, we will respond with that timeless creed that sums up the spirit of a people: Yes We Can. Thank you, God bless you, and may God Bless the United States of America." id="3004843529" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="6" rank="9" tags="obama barackobama victory hopechangepeace newpresident" title="Hope defeats Fear" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3012/3004843529_fc12dc6c0c_b.jpg" username="Todd Barnard" views="2357" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-11-05 00:54:45" description="Remarks of President-Elect Barack Obama-as prepared for delivery Election Night Tuesday, November 4th, 2008 Chicago, Illinois If there is anyone out there who still doubts that America is a place where all things are possible; who still wonders if the dream of our founders is alive in our time; who still questions the power of our democracy, tonight is your answer. It's the answer told by lines that stretched around schools and churches in numbers this nation has never seen; by people who waited three hours and four hours, many for the very first time in their lives, because they believed that this time must be different; that their voice could be that difference. It's the answer spoken by young and old, rich and poor, Democrat and Republican, black, white, Latino, Asian, Native American, gay, straight, disabled and not disabled - Americans who sent a message to the world that we have never been a collection of Red States and Blue States: we are, and always will be, the United States of America. It's the answer that led those who have been told for so long by so many to be cynical, and fearful, and doubtful of what we can achieve to put their hands on the arc of history and bend it once more toward the hope of a better day. It's been a long time coming, but tonight, because of what we did on this day, in this election, at this defining moment, change has come to America. I just received a very gracious call from Senator McCain. He fought long and hard in this campaign, and he's fought even longer and harder for the country he loves. He has endured sacrifices for America that most of us cannot begin to imagine, and we are better off for the service rendered by this brave and selfless leader. I congratulate him and Governor Palin for all they have achieved, and I look forward to working with them to renew this nation's promise in the months ahead. I want to thank my partner in this journey, a man who campaigned from his heart and spoke for the men and women he grew up with on the streets of Scranton and rode with on that train home to Delaware, the Vice President-elect of the United States, Joe Biden. I would not be standing here tonight without the unyielding support of my best friend for the last sixteen years, the rock of our family and the love of my life, our nation's next First Lady, Michelle Obama. Sasha and Malia, I love you both so much, and you have earned the new puppy that's coming with us to the White House. And while she's no longer with us, I know my grandmother is watching, along with the family that made me who I am. I miss them tonight, and know that my debt to them is beyond measure. To my campaign manager David Plouffe, my chief strategist David Axelrod, and the best campaign team ever assembled in the history of politics - you made this happen, and I am forever grateful for what you've sacrificed to get it done. But above all, I will never forget who this victory truly belongs to - it belongs to you. I was never the likeliest candidate for this office. We didn't start with much money or many endorsements. Our campaign was not hatched in the halls of Washington - it began in the backyards of Des Moines and the living rooms of Concord and the front porches of Charleston. It was built by working men and women who dug into what little savings they had to give five dollars and ten dollars and twenty dollars to this cause. It grew strength from the young people who rejected the myth of their generation's apathy; who left their homes and their families for jobs that offered little pay and less sleep; from the not-so-young people who braved the bitter cold and scorching heat to knock on the doors of perfect strangers; from the millions of Americans who volunteered, and organized, and proved that more than two centuries later, a government of the people, by the people and for the people has not perished from this Earth. This is your victory. I know you didn't do this just to win an election and I know you didn't do it for me. You did it because you understand the enormity of the task that lies ahead. For even as we celebrate tonight, we know the challenges that tomorrow will bring are the greatest of our lifetime - two wars, a planet in peril, the worst financial crisis in a century. Even as we stand here tonight, we know there are brave Americans waking up in the deserts of Iraq and the mountains of Afghanistan to risk their lives for us. There are mothers and fathers who will lie awake after their children fall asleep and wonder how they'll make the mortgage, or pay their doctor's bills, or save enough for college. There is new energy to harness and new jobs to be created; new schools to build and threats to meet and alliances to repair. The road ahead will be long. Our climb will be steep. We may not get there in one year or even one term, but America - I have never been more hopeful than I am tonight that we will get there. I promise you - we as a people will get there. There will be setbacks and false starts. There are many who won't agree with every decision or policy I make as President, and we know that government can't solve every problem. But I will always be honest with you about the challenges we face. I will listen to you, especially when we disagree. And above all, I will ask you join in the work of remaking this nation the only way it's been done in America for two-hundred and twenty-one years - block by block, brick by brick, calloused hand by calloused hand. What began twenty-one months ago in the depths of winter must not end on this autumn night. This victory alone is not the change we seek - it is only the chance for us to make that change. And that cannot happen if we go back to the way things were. It cannot happen without you. So let us summon a new spirit of patriotism; of service and responsibility where each of us resolves to pitch in and work harder and look after not only ourselves, but each other. Let us remember that if this financial crisis taught us anything, it's that we cannot have a thriving Wall Street while Main Street suffers - in this country, we rise or fall as one nation; as one people. Let us resist the temptation to fall back on the same partisanship and pettiness and immaturity that has poisoned our politics for so long. Let us remember that it was a man from this state who first carried the banner of the Republican Party to the White House - a party founded on the values of self-reliance, individual liberty, and national unity. Those are values we all share, and while the Democratic Party has won a great victory tonight, we do so with a measure of humility and determination to heal the divides that have held back our progress. As Lincoln said to a nation far more divided than ours, &amp;quot;We are not enemies, but friends...though passion may have strained it must not break our bonds of affection.&amp;quot; And to those Americans whose support I have yet to earn - I may not have won your vote, but I hear your voices, I need your help, and I will be your President too. And to all those watching tonight from beyond our shores, from parliaments and palaces to those who are huddled around radios in the forgotten corners of our world - our stories are singular, but our destiny is shared, and a new dawn of American leadership is at hand. To those who would tear this world down - we will defeat you. To those who seek peace and security - we support you. And to all those who have wondered if America's beacon still burns as bright - tonight we proved once more that the true strength of our nation comes not from our the might of our arms or the scale of our wealth, but from the enduring power of our ideals: democracy, liberty, opportunity, and unyielding hope. For that is the true genius of America - that America can change. Our union can be perfected. And what we have already achieved gives us hope for what we can and must achieve tomorrow. This election had many firsts and many stories that will be told for generations. But one that's on my mind tonight is about a woman who cast her ballot in Atlanta. She's a lot like the millions of others who stood in line to make their voice heard in this election except for one thing - Ann Nixon Cooper is 106 years old. She was born just a generation past slavery; a time when there were no cars on the road or planes in the sky; when someone like her couldn't vote for two reasons - because she was a woman and because of the color of her skin. And tonight, I think about all that she's seen throughout her century in America - the heartache and the hope; the struggle and the progress; the times we were told that we can't, and the people who pressed on with that American creed: Yes we can. At a time when women's voices were silenced and their hopes dismissed, she lived to see them stand up and speak out and reach for the ballot. Yes we can. When there was despair in the dust bowl and depression across the land, she saw a nation conquer fear itself with a New Deal, new jobs and a new sense of common purpose. Yes we can. When the bombs fell on our harbor and tyranny threatened the world, she was there to witness a generation rise to greatness and a democracy was saved. Yes we can. She was there for the buses in Montgomery, the hoses in Birmingham, a bridge in Selma, and a preacher from Atlanta who told a people that &amp;quot;We Shall Overcome.&amp;quot; Yes we can. A man touched down on the moon, a wall came down in Berlin, a world was connected by our own science and imagination. And this year, in this election, she touched her finger to a screen, and cast her vote, because after 106 years in America, through the best of times and the darkest of hours, she knows how America can change. Yes we can. America, we have come so far. We have seen so much. But there is so much more to do. So tonight, let us ask ourselves - if our children should live to see the next century; if my daughters should be so lucky to live as long as Ann Nixon Cooper, what change will they see? What progress will we have made? This is our chance to answer that call. This is our moment. This is our time - to put our people back to work and open doors of opportunity for our kids; to restore prosperity and promote the cause of peace; to reclaim the American Dream and reaffirm that fundamental truth - that out of many, we are one; that while we breathe, we hope, and where we are met with cynicism, and doubt, and those who tell us that we can't, we will respond with that timeless creed that sums up the spirit of a people: Yes We Can. Thank you, God bless you, and may God Bless the United States of America." id="3004982970" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="7" rank="10" tags="barackobama president election 2008 democrats hope acceptancespeech obama voting speech obamabiden change" title="We Finally Got It Right!  Congratulations President-Elect Barack Obama" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3159/3004982970_420b8137d2_b.jpg" username="DustyAllDayLong" views="1188" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-11-04 09:12:47" description="In 18 years of voting at this polling place, nevr took longer than 5 minutes...today it took 1 hr and 5 minutes! &lt;b&gt;Explore Nov 4, 2008 #289&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Remarks of President-Elect Barack Obama&lt;/b&gt; Election Night Tuesday, November 4th, 2008 Chicago, Illinois If there is anyone out there who still doubts that America is a place where all things are possible; who still wonders if the dream of our founders is alive in our time; who still questions the power of our democracy, tonight is your answer. It’s the answer told by lines that stretched around schools and churches in numbers this nation has never seen; by people who waited three hours and four hours, many for the very first time in their lives, because they believed that this time must be different; that their voice could be that difference. It’s the answer spoken by young and old, rich and poor, Democrat and Republican, black, white, Latino, Asian, Native American, gay, straight, disabled and not disabled – Americans who sent a message to the world that we have never been a collection of Red States and Blue States: we are, and always will be, the United States of America. It’s the answer that led those who have been told for so long by so many to be cynical, and fearful, and doubtful of what we can achieve to put their hands on the arc of history and bend it once more toward the hope of a better day. It’s been a long time coming, but tonight, because of what we did on this day, in this election, at this defining moment, change has come to America. I just received a very gracious call from Senator McCain. He fought long and hard in this campaign, and he’s fought even longer and harder for the country he loves. He has endured sacrifices for America that most of us cannot begin to imagine, and we are better off for the service rendered by this brave and selfless leader. I congratulate him and Governor Palin for all they have achieved, and I look forward to working with them to renew this nation’s promise in the months ahead. I want to thank my partner in this journey, a man who campaigned from his heart and spoke for the men and women he grew up with on the streets of Scranton and rode with on that train home to Delaware, the Vice President-elect of the United States, Joe Biden. I would not be standing here tonight without the unyielding support of my best friend for the last sixteen years, the rock of our family and the love of my life, our nation’s next First Lady, Michelle Obama. Sasha and Malia, I love you both so much, and you have earned the new puppy that’s coming with us to the White House. And while she’s no longer with us, I know my grandmother is watching, along with the family that made me who I am. I miss them tonight, and know that my debt to them is beyond measure. To my campaign manager David Plouffe, my chief strategist David Axelrod, and the best campaign team ever assembled in the history of politics – you made this happen, and I am forever grateful for what you’ve sacrificed to get it done. But above all, I will never forget who this victory truly belongs to – it belongs to you. I was never the likeliest candidate for this office. We didn’t start with much money or many endorsements. Our campaign was not hatched in the halls of Washington – it began in the backyards of Des Moines and the living rooms of Concord and the front porches of Charleston. It was built by working men and women who dug into what little savings they had to give five dollars and ten dollars and twenty dollars to this cause. It grew strength from the young people who rejected the myth of their generation’s apathy; who left their homes and their families for jobs that offered little pay and less sleep; from the not-so-young people who braved the bitter cold and scorching heat to knock on the doors of perfect strangers; from the millions of Americans who volunteered, and organized, and proved that more than two centuries later, a government of the people, by the people and for the people has not perished from this Earth. This is your victory. I know you didn’t do this just to win an election and I know you didn’t do it for me. You did it because you understand the enormity of the task that lies ahead. For even as we celebrate tonight, we know the challenges that tomorrow will bring are the greatest of our lifetime – two wars, a planet in peril, the worst financial crisis in a century. Even as we stand here tonight, we know there are brave Americans waking up in the deserts of Iraq and the mountains of Afghanistan to risk their lives for us. There are mothers and fathers who will lie awake after their children fall asleep and wonder how they’ll make the mortgage, or pay their doctor’s bills, or save enough for college. There is new energy to harness and new jobs to be created; new schools to build and threats to meet and alliances to repair. The road ahead will be long. Our climb will be steep. We may not get there in one year or even one term, but America – I have never been more hopeful than I am tonight that we will get there. I promise you – we as a people will get there. There will be setbacks and false starts. There are many who won’t agree with every decision or policy I make as President, and we know that government can’t solve every problem. But I will always be honest with you about the challenges we face. I will listen to you, especially when we disagree. And above all, I will ask you join in the work of remaking this nation the only way it’s been done in America for two-hundred and twenty-one years – block by block, brick by brick, calloused hand by calloused hand. What began twenty-one months ago in the depths of winter must not end on this autumn night. This victory alone is not the change we seek – it is only the chance for us to make that change. And that cannot happen if we go back to the way things were. It cannot happen without you. So let us summon a new spirit of patriotism; of service and responsibility where each of us resolves to pitch in and work harder and look after not only ourselves, but each other. Let us remember that if this financial crisis taught us anything, it’s that we cannot have a thriving Wall Street while Main Street suffers – in this country, we rise or fall as one nation; as one people. Let us resist the temptation to fall back on the same partisanship and pettiness and immaturity that has poisoned our politics for so long. Let us remember that it was a man from this state who first carried the banner of the Republican Party to the White House – a party founded on the values of self-reliance, individual liberty, and national unity. Those are values we all share, and while the Democratic Party has won a great victory tonight, we do so with a measure of humility and determination to heal the divides that have held back our progress. As Lincoln said to a nation far more divided than ours, “We are not enemies, but friends…though passion may have strained it must not break our bonds of affection.” And to those Americans whose support I have yet to earn – I may not have won your vote, but I hear your voices, I need your help, and I will be your President too. And to all those watching tonight from beyond our shores, from parliaments and palaces to those who are huddled around radios in the forgotten corners of our world – our stories are singular, but our destiny is shared, and a new dawn of American leadership is at hand. To those who would tear this world down – we will defeat you. To those who seek peace and security – we support you. And to all those who have wondered if America’s beacon still burns as bright – tonight we proved once more that the true strength of our nation comes not from our the might of our arms or the scale of our wealth, but from the enduring power of our ideals: democracy, liberty, opportunity, and unyielding hope. For that is the true genius of America – that America can change. Our union can be perfected. And what we have already achieved gives us hope for what we can and must achieve tomorrow. This election had many firsts and many stories that will be told for generations. But one that’s on my mind tonight is about a woman who cast her ballot in Atlanta. She’s a lot like the millions of others who stood in line to make their voice heard in this election except for one thing – Ann Nixon Cooper is 106 years old. She was born just a generation past slavery; a time when there were no cars on the road or planes in the sky; when someone like her couldn’t vote for two reasons – because she was a woman and because of the color of her skin. And tonight, I think about all that she’s seen throughout her century in America – the heartache and the hope; the struggle and the progress; the times we were told that we can’t, and the people who pressed on with that American creed: Yes we can. At a time when women’s voices were silenced and their hopes dismissed, she lived to see them stand up and speak out and reach for the ballot. Yes we can. When there was despair in the dust bowl and depression across the land, she saw a nation conquer fear itself with a New Deal, new jobs and a new sense of common purpose. Yes we can. When the bombs fell on our harbor and tyranny threatened the world, she was there to witness a generation rise to greatness and a democracy was saved. Yes we can. She was there for the buses in Montgomery, the hoses in Birmingham, a bridge in Selma, and a preacher from Atlanta who told a people that “We Shall Overcome.” Yes we can. A man touched down on the moon, a wall came down in Berlin, a world was connected by our own science and imagination. And this year, in this election, she touched her finger to a screen, and cast her vote, because after 106 years in America, through the best of times and the darkest of hours, she knows how America can change. Yes we can. America, we have come so far. We have seen so much. But there is so much more to do. So tonight, let us ask ourselves – if our children should live to see the next century; if my daughters should be so lucky to live as long as Ann Nixon Cooper, what change will they see? What progress will we have made? This is our chance to answer that call. This is our moment. This is our time – to put our people back to work and open doors of opportunity for our kids; to restore prosperity and promote the cause of peace; to reclaim the American Dream and reaffirm that fundamental truth – that out of many, we are one; that while we breathe, we hope, and where we are met with cynicism, and doubt, and those who tell us that we can’t, we will respond with that timeless creed that sums up the spirit of a people: Yes We Can. Thank you, God bless you, and may God Bless the United States of America. &lt;a href=&quot;http://voxterra.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Photography/Travel Blog&lt;/a&gt;~&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/vox_efx/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;~&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/voxefx&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;" id="3002776434" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="15" rank="11" tags="ivoted nov4 2008 canon election maryland sticker vote voxefx bokehrama bokehlicious g9" title="I Voted!" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3038/3002776434_643d076694_b.jpg" username="Vox Efx" views="8702" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-06 14:37:16" description="Company C, 10th Kansas Infantry From his son's biography in: From volume 4, pages 1980-1981 of A Standard History of Kansas and Kansans, written and compiled by William E. Connelley, Secretary of the Kansas State Historical Society, Topeka. Chicago: Lewis Publishing Company, copyright 1918 WILLIAM WALLACE BROWN, general attorney at Parsons for the Missouri, Kansas &amp;amp; Texas Railway and a director in that railway company, is one of Kansas' prominent lawyers with many well earned distinctions in the profession. The secret of his success has been hard work. He began practice only after a thorough preliminary training of self reliance and after getting his professional education through his own earnings and efforts. A native of Kansas, he represents a pioneer family. Mr. Brown was born in Coffey County July 29, 1868. He is of English ancestry. His grandfather Robert Brown was born in England, brought his family to America in 1845, and became a contractor and builder in the State of Iowa. While still at work in his business he was struck by a beam and that caused his death about 1857. He died in Iowa. Charles Brown, father of W. W. Brown, was born at Beverly, Yorkshire, England, November 14, 1832. He was thirteen years of age when he came to America and he grew up at Maquoketa, Iowa. After finishing his education he became a farmer. In 1857 at the age of twenty-five he moved from Maquoketa, Iowa, to Kansas, and was one of the early settlers in the territory. His permanent home was on a farm along the line between Anderson and Coffey counties. A few years after coming to Kansas he enlisted in the Tenth Kansas Regiment of Infantry, and was in active service during the war, principally in Missouri, Arkansas and Indian Territory. He was in the battle of Prairie Grove, Arkansas, and served with the Kansas troops in repelling Price's raid. After the war he homesteaded eighty acres and was married in 1865. He then settled down to farming and proved a man of unusual energy and success in that business. He was both a farmer and stock raiser and eventually he had fully 400 acres of land in his possession. In the early days he was actively identified with the Grange or Patrons of Husbandry, but in later years became somewhat dissatisfied with its management and methods. In his home community he was always active and influential. He served seven years as county commissioner and held all the township offices. He was a prominent republican, and a member of the Methodist Episcopal Church. After a life filled with usefulness he died at his home in Coffey County February 10, 1915, in his eighty-third year. Charles Brown married Miss Mary Isabelle Hinde. She was born in Cattaraugus County, New York, in 1842 and her death occurred on the homestead farm in Coffey County, Kansas, in 1892. Mr. W. W. Brown was the oldest of their four children. The next younger, Louie Grace died in Coffey County in 1895 as the wife of William Sharp, who is now living in Los Angeles, California. Maggie Amanda married H. A. Striegel, and they now live on their farm forty miles west of Wichita near Murdock, Kansas. Fred E., the youngest of the family, now occupies the old homestead in Coffey County. Though reared on a farm the ambitions of William Wallace Brown early pointed to a professional career. He attended the district schools of Coffey County, the high school at Burlington, and then entered the University of Kansas where he completed the classical course and received the degree A. B. in 1892. The following two years were spent in a schoolroom as teacher, and he was principal of the high school at Abilene, Kansas. Mr. Brown devoted several attentive years to the study of law in a law office at Burlington, Kansas, and in 1896, gained the coveted goal of admission to the bar. The twenty years since his admission have been years of growing experience and increasing ability in his profession. He practiced at Burlington until 1902, then at Emporia until April, 1905, and came to Parsons as assistant general attorney of the Missouri, Kansas &amp;amp; Texas Railroad Company. In July, 1913, he was advanced to the position of general attorney, and now fills one of the most prized positions in the legal profession in the state. He is widely known as a railroad lawyer throughout the west. His offices are in the General Office Building of the Missouri, Kansas &amp;amp; Texas Railroad at Parsons. Besides his position as legal adviser to the company he is also one of the directors. Mr. Brown is a successful business man. He owns considerable real estate in Parsons, has a fine farm of 160 acres on the Neosho River near Burlington, and is president of the Burlington Lumber Company. He is a member of the Presbyterian Church, is past master of Emporia Lodge No. 12, Ancient Free and Accepted Masons, and a member of Emporia Chapter No. 12, Royal Arch Masons, Parsons Council, Royal and Select Masters. He is also identified with the Parsons Chamber of Commerce and belongs to the Labette County, the State and the American Bar associations. In 1906 at Emporia he married Miss Frances Evans. She is a daughter of Judge E. N. Evans, a prominent attorney of Emporia, who has filled the positions of both probate and district judge there." id="1032658180" latitude="38.187263" license="6" longitude="-95.489516" nbComments="0" rank="12" tags="hobby civilwarveteran tombstonephoto cherrymoundcemetery westphaliakansas charlesbrown companyc10thkansasinfantry kansas union" title="Charles Brown" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1206/1032658180_d6253ce3b3_b.jpg" username="jajacks62" views="660" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-11-21 12:57:18" description="From my set entitled “Our Home, Streetsville” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/21861018@N00/sets/72157600265395738/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/21861018@N00/sets/72157600265395738/&lt;/a&gt; In my collection entitled “Places” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/21861018@N00/collections/72157600747479639/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/21861018@N00/collections/7215760074...&lt;/a&gt; In my photostream &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/21861018@N00/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/21861018@N00/&lt;/a&gt; I’ve always lived close to railway lines. When I was growing up in Orangeville, Ontario, I lived near the main station. Both the Canadian National Railway (CNR) and the Canadian Pacific Railway (CPR) passed through town. When my sister and I moved to a fifty acre farm in Dixie, Ontario (near Toronto) in 1960, the CPR bisected our land. For the twenty-two years Karen and I have lived at our current address in Streetsville, Ontario, the CPR has been our neighbour across the back fence. People ask us, “Don’t the trains bother you?” We answer that we don’t even hear them. We sit on the deck and view a lot of interesting stuff go by. One day I watched a trainload of tanks pass. Didn’t know Canada had so many tanks. We also see intriguing graffiti on the sides of tankers and boxcars. And there are cars from all over the U.S. and Canada. This is the first shot of the trains I have taken from the deck, but there will be more. It’s best to take such pictures after the leaves have dropped, since it’s hard to see the trains through the summer foliage. Reproduced from Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canadian_Pacific_Railway&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canadian_Pacific_Railway&lt;/a&gt; The Canadian Pacific Railway (CPR; AAR reporting marks CP, CPAA, CPI), known as CP Rail between 1968 and 1996, is a Canadian Class I railway operated by Canadian Pacific Railway Limited. Its rail network stretches from Vancouver to Montreal, and also serves major cities in the United States such as Minneapolis, Chicago, and New York City. Its headquarters are in Calgary, Alberta. The railway was originally built between eastern Canada and British Columbia between 1881 and 1885 (connecting with Ottawa Valley and Georgian Bay area lines built earlier), fulfilling a promise extended to British Columbia when it entered Confederation in 1871. It was Canada's first transcontinental railway. Now primarily a freight railway, the CPR was for decades the only practical means of long distance passenger transport in most regions of Canada, and was instrumental in the settlement and development of Western Canada. The CP company became one of the largest and most powerful in Canada, a position it held as late as 1975.[1] Its primary passenger services were eliminated in 1986 after being assumed by VIA Rail Canada in 1978. A beaver was chosen as the railway's logo because it is one of the national symbols of Canada and represents the hardworking character of the company. The object of both praise and condemnation for over 120 years, the CPR remains an indisputable icon of Canadian nationalism. The Canadian Pacific Railway is a public company with over 15,000 employees and market capitalization of 7 billion USD in 2008.[2] Canada's very existence depended on the successful completion of the major civil engineering project, the creation of a transcontinental railway. Creation of the Canadian Pacific Railway was a task originally undertaken for a combination of reasons by the Conservative government of Prime Minister Sir John A. Macdonald. British Columbia had insisted upon a transport link to the east as a condition for joining the Confederation of Canada (initially requesting a wagon road). The government however, proposed to build a railway linking the Pacific province to the eastern provinces within ten years of July 20, 1871. Macdonald also saw it as essential to the creation of a unified Canadian nation that would stretch across the continent. Moreover, manufacturing interests in Quebec and Ontario desired access to sources of raw materials and markets in Canada's west. The first obstacle to its construction was economic. The logical route went through the American Midwest and the city of Chicago, Illinois. In addition to the obvious difficulty of building a railroad through the Canadian Rockies, an entirely Canadian route would require crossing 1,600 km (1,000 miles) of rugged terrain of the barren Canadian Shield and muskeg of Northern Ontario. To ensure this routing, the government offered huge incentives including vast grants of land in Western Canada. In 1872, Sir John A. Macdonald and other high-ranking politicians, swayed by bribes in the so-called Pacific Scandal, granted federal contracts to Hugh Allan's &amp;quot;Canada Pacific Railway Company&amp;quot; (which was unrelated to the current company) and to the Inter-Ocean Railway Company. Because of this scandal, the Conservative party was removed from office in 1873. The new Liberal prime minister, Alexander Mackenzie, began construction of segments of the railway as a public enterprise under the supervision of the Department of Public Works. The Thunder Bay branch linking Lake Superior to Winnipeg was commenced in 1875. Progress was discouragingly slow because of the lack of public money. With Sir John A. Macdonald's return to power on October 16, 1878, a more aggressive construction policy was adopted. Macdonald confirmed that Port Moody would be the terminus of the transcontinental railway, and announced that the railway would follow the Fraser and Thompson rivers between Port Moody and Kamloops. In 1879, the federal government floated bonds in London and called for tenders to construct the 206 km (128 mile) section of the railway from Yale, British Columbia to Savona's Ferry on Kamloops Lake. The contract was awarded to Andrew Onderdonk, whose men started work on May 15, 1880. After the completion of that section, Onderdonk received contracts to build between Yale and Port Moody, and between Savona's Ferry and Eagle Pass. On October 21, 1880, a new syndicate, unrelated to Hugh Allan's, signed a contract with the Macdonald government. They agreed to build the railway in exchange for $25,000,000 (approximately $625,000,000 in modern Canadian dollars) in credit from the Canadian government and a grant of 25,000,000 acres (100,000 km²) of land. The government transferred to the new company those sections of the railway it had constructed under government ownership. The government also defrayed surveying costs and exempted the railway from property taxes for 20 years. The Montreal-based syndicate officially comprised five men: George Stephen, James J. Hill, Duncan McIntyre, Richard B. Angus, and John Stewart Kennedy. Donald A. Smith and Norman Kittson were unofficial silent partners with a significant financial interest. On February 15, 1881, legislation confirming the contract received royal assent, and the Canadian Pacific Railway Company was formally incorporated the next day. The CPR started its westward expansion from Bonfield, Ontario (previously called Callander Station) where the first spike was driven into a sunken railway tie. Bonfield, Ontario was inducted into Canadian Railway Hall of Fame in 2002 as the CPR First Spike location. That was the point where the Canada Central Railway extension ended. The CCR was owned by Duncan McIntyre who amalgamated it with the CPR and became one of the handful of officers of the newly formed CPR. The CCR started in Brockville and extended to Pembroke. It then followed a westward route along the Ottawa River passing through places like Cobden, Deux-Rivières, and eventually to Mattawa at the confluence of the Mattawa and Ottawa Rivers. It then proceeded cross-country towards its final destination Bonfield (previously called Callander Station). Duncan McIntyre and his contractor James Worthington piloted the CCR expansion. Worthington continued on as the construction superintendent for the CPR past Bonfield. He remained with the CPR for about a year until he left the company. McIntyre was uncle to John Ferguson who staked out future North Bay after getting assurance from his uncle and Worthington that it would be the divisional and a location of some importance. It was assumed that the railway would travel through the rich &amp;quot;Fertile Belt&amp;quot; of the North Saskatchewan River valley and cross the Rocky Mountains via the Yellowhead Pass, a route suggested by Sir Sandford Fleming based on a decade of work. However, the CPR quickly discarded this plan in favour of a more southerly route across the arid Palliser's Triangle in Saskatchewan and through Kicking Horse Pass over the Field Hill. This route was more direct and closer to the American border, making it easier for the CPR to keep American railways from encroaching on the Canadian market. However, this route also had several disadvantages. One consequence was that the CPR would need to find a route through the Selkirk Mountains, as at the time it was not known whether a route even existed. The job of finding a pass was assigned to a surveyor named Major Albert Bowman Rogers. The CPR promised him a cheque for $5,000 and that the pass would be named in his honour. Rogers became obsessed with finding the pass that would immortalize his name. He found the pass on May 29, 1881, and true to its word, the CPR named the pass &amp;quot;Rogers Pass&amp;quot; and gave him the cheque. This however, he at first refused to cash, preferring to frame it, and saying he did not do it for the money. He later agreed to cash it with the promise of an engraved watch. Another obstacle was that the proposed route crossed land controlled by the Blackfoot First Nation. This difficulty was overcome when a missionary priest, Albert Lacombe, persuaded the Blackfoot chief Crowfoot that construction of the railway was inevitable. In return for his assent, Crowfoot was famously rewarded with a lifetime pass to ride the CPR. A more lasting consequence of the choice of route was that, unlike the one proposed by Fleming, the land surrounding the railway often proved too arid for successful agriculture. The CPR may have placed too much reliance on a report from naturalist John Macoun, who had crossed the prairies at a time of very high rainfall and had reported that the area was fertile. The greatest disadvantage of the route was in Kicking Horse Pass. In the first 6 km (3.7 miles) west of the 1,625 metre (5,330 ft) high summit, the Kicking Horse River drops 350 metres (1,150 ft). The steep drop would force the cash-strapped CPR to build a 7 km (4.5 mile) long stretch of track with a very steep 4.5% gradient once it reached the pass in 1884. This was over four times the maximum gradient recommended for railways of this era, and even modern railways rarely exceed a 2% gradient. However, this route was far more direct than one through the Yellowhead Pass, and saved hours for both passengers and freight. This section of track was the CPR's Big Hill. Safety switches were installed at several points, the speed limit for descending trains was set at 10 km per hour (6 mph), and special locomotives were ordered. Despite these measures, several serious runaways still occurred. CPR officials insisted that this was a temporary expediency, but this state of affairs would last for 25 years until the completion of the Spiral Tunnels in the early 20th century. In 1881 construction progressed at a pace too slow for the railway's officials, who in 1882 hired the renowned railway executive William Cornelius Van Horne, to oversee construction with the inducement of a generous salary and the intriguing challenge of handling such a difficult railway project. Van Horne stated that he would have 800 km (500 miles) of main line built in 1882. Floods delayed the start of the construction season, but over 672 km (417 miles) of main line, as well as various sidings and branch lines, were built that year. The Thunder Bay branch (west from Fort William) was completed in June 1882 by the Department of Railways and Canals and turned over to the company in May 1883, permitting all-Canadian lake and rail traffic from eastern Canada to Winnipeg for the first time in Canada's history. By the end of 1883, the railway had reached the Rocky Mountains, just eight km (5 miles) east of Kicking Horse Pass. The construction seasons of 1884 and 1885 would be spent in the mountains of British Columbia and on the north shore of Lake Superior. Many thousands of navvies worked on the railway. Many were European immigrants. In British Columbia, the CPR hired workers from China, nicknamed coolies. A navvy received between $1 and $2.50 per day, but had to pay for his own food, clothing, transportation to the job site, mail, and medical care. After two and a half months of back-breaking labour, they could net as little as $16. Chinese navvies in British Columbia made only between $0.75 and $1.25 a day, not including expenses, leaving barely anything to send home. They did the most dangerous construction jobs, such as working with explosives. The families of the Chinese who were killed received no compensation, or even notification of loss of life. Many of the men who survived did not have enough money to return to their families in China. Many spent years in lonely, sad and often poor conditions. Yet the Chinese were hard working and played a key role in building the western stretch of the railway; even some boys as young as 12 years old served as tea-boys. By 1883, railway construction was progressing rapidly, but the CPR was in danger of running out of funds. In response, on January 31, 1884, the government passed the Railway Relief Bill, providing a further $22,500,000 in loans to the CPR. The bill received royal assent on March 6, 1884. In March 1885, the North-West Rebellion broke out in the District of Saskatchewan. Van Horne, in Ottawa at the time, suggested to the government that the CPR could transport troops to Qu'Appelle, Assiniboia, in eleven days. Some sections of track were incomplete or had not been used before, but the trip to Winnipeg was made in nine days and the rebellion was quickly put down. Perhaps because the government was grateful for this service, they subsequently re-organized the CPR's debt and provided a further $5,000,000 loan. This money was desperately needed by the CPR. On November 7, 1885 the Last Spike was driven at Craigellachie, British Columbia, making good on the original promise. Four days earlier, the last spike of the Lake Superior section was driven in just west of Jackfish, Ontario. While the railway was completed four years after the original 1881 deadline, it was completed more than five years ahead of the new date of 1891 that Macdonald gave in 1881. The successful construction of such a massive project, although troubled by delays and scandal, was considered an impressive feat of engineering and political will for a country with such a small population, limited capital, and difficult terrain. It was by far the longest railway ever constructed at the time. It had taken 12,000 men, 5,000 horses, and 300 dog-sled teams to build the railway. Meanwhile, in Eastern Canada, the CPR had created a network of lines reaching from Quebec City to St. Thomas, Ontario by 1885, and had launched a fleet of Great Lakes ships to link its terminals. The CPR had effected purchases and long-term leases of several railways through an associated railway company, the Ontario and Quebec Railway (O&amp;amp;Q). The O&amp;amp;Q built a line between Perth, Ontario, and Toronto (completed on May 5, 1884) to connect these acquisitions. The CPR obtained a 999-year lease on the O&amp;amp;Q on January 4, 1884. Later, in 1895, it acquired a minority interest in the Toronto, Hamilton and Buffalo Railway, giving it a link to New York and the northeast US. So many cost-cutting shortcuts were taken in constructing the railway that regular transcontinental service could not start for another seven months while work was done to improve the railway's condition. However, had these shortcuts not been taken, it is conceivable that the CPR might have had to default financially, leaving the railway unfinished. The first transcontinental passenger train departed from Montreal's Dalhousie Station, located at Berri Street and Notre Dame Street on June 28, 1886 at 8:00 p.m. and arrived at Port Moody on July 4, 1886 at noon. This train consisted of two baggage cars, a mail car, one second-class coach, two immigrant sleepers, two first-class coaches, two sleeping cars, and a diner. By that time, however, the CPR had decided to move its western terminus from Port Moody to Gastown, which was renamed &amp;quot;Vancouver&amp;quot; later that year. The first official train destined for Vancouver arrived on May 23, 1887, although the line had already been in use for three months. The CPR quickly became profitable, and all loans from the Federal government were repaid years ahead of time. In 1888, a branch line was opened between Sudbury and Sault Ste. Marie where the CPR connected with the American railway system and its own steamships. That same year, work was started on a line from London, Ontario to the American border at Windsor, Ontario. That line opened on June 12, 1890. The CPR also leased the New Brunswick Railway for 999 years and built the International Railway of Maine, connecting Montreal with Saint John, New Brunswick in 1889. The connection with Saint John on the Atlantic coast made the CPR the first truly transcontinental railway company and permitted trans-Atlantic cargo and passenger services to continue year-round when sea ice in the Gulf of St. Lawrence closed the port of Montreal during the winter months. By 1896, competition with the Great Northern Railway for traffic in southern British Columbia forced the CPR to construct a second line across the province, south of the original line. Van Horne, now president of the CPR, asked for government aid, and the government agreed to provide around $3.6 million to construct a railway from Lethbridge, Alberta through Crowsnest Pass to the south shore of Kootenay Lake, in exchange for the CPR agreeing to reduce freight rates in perpetuity for key commodities shipped in Western Canada. The controversial Crowsnest Pass Agreement effectively locked the eastbound rate on grain products and westbound rates on certain &amp;quot;settlers' effects&amp;quot; at the 1897 level. Although temporarily suspended during World War I, it was not until 1983 that the &amp;quot;Crow Rate&amp;quot; was permanently replaced by the Western Grain Transportation Act which allowed for the gradual increase of grain shipping prices. The Crowsnest Pass line opened on June 18, 1899. Practically speaking, the CPR had built a railway that operated mostly in the wilderness. The usefulness of the Prairies was questionable in the minds of many. The thinking prevailed that the Prairies had great potential. Under the initial contract with the Canadian Government to build the railway, the CPR was granted 25,000,000 acres (100,000 km²). Proving already to be a very resourceful organization, Canadian Pacific began an intense campaign to bring immigrants to Canada. Canadian Pacific agents operated in many overseas locations. Immigrants were often sold a package that included passage on a CP ship, travel on a CP train, and land sold by the CP railway. Land was priced at $2.50 an acre and up. Immigrants paid very little for a seven-day journey to the West. They rode in Colonist cars that had sleeping facilities and a small kitchen at one end of the car. Children were not allowed off the train, lest they wander off and be left behind. The directors of the CPR knew that not only were they creating a nation, but also a long-term source of revenue for their company. During the first decade of the twentieth century, the CPR continued to build more lines. In 1908 the CPR opened a line connecting Toronto with Sudbury. Previously, westbound traffic originating in southern Ontario took a circuitous route through eastern Ontario. Several operational improvements were also made to the railway in western Canada. In 1909 the CPR completed two significant engineering accomplishments. The most significant was the replacement of the Big Hill, which had become a major bottleneck in the CPR's main line, with the Spiral Tunnels, reducing the grade to 2.2% from 4.5%. The Spiral Tunnels opened in August. On November 3, 1909, the Lethbridge Viaduct over the Oldman River valley at Lethbridge, Alberta was opened. It is 1,624 metres (5,327 ft) long and, at its maximum, 96 metres (314 ft) high, making it the longest railway bridge in Canada. In 1916 the CPR replaced its line through Rogers Pass, which was prone to avalanches, with the Connaught Tunnel, an eight km (5 mile) long tunnel under Mount Macdonald that was, at the time of its opening, the longest railway tunnel in the Western Hemisphere. The CPR acquired several smaller railways via long-term leases in 1912. On January 3, 1912, the CPR acquired the Dominion Atlantic Railway, a railway that ran in western Nova Scotia. This acquisition gave the CPR a connection to Halifax, a significant port on the Atlantic Ocean. The Dominion Atlantic was isolated from the rest of the CPR network and used the CNR to facilitate interchange; the DAR also operated ferry services across the Bay of Fundy for passengers and cargo (but not rail cars) from the port of Digby, Nova Scotia to the CPR at Saint John, New Brunswick. DAR steamships also provided connections for passengers and cargo between Yarmouth, Boston and New York. On July 1, 1912, the CPR acquired the Esquimalt and Nanaimo Railway, a railway on Vancouver Island that connected to the CPR using a railcar ferry. The CPR also acquired the Quebec Central Railway on December 14, 1912. During the late 19th century, the railway undertook an ambitious program of hotel construction, building the Château Frontenac in Quebec City, the Royal York Hotel in Toronto, the Banff Springs Hotel, and several other major Canadian landmarks. By then, the CPR had competition from three other transcontinental lines, all of them money-losers. In 1919, these lines were consolidated, along with the track of the old Intercolonial Railway and its spurs, into the government-owned Canadian National Railways. When World War I broke out in 1914, the CPR devoted resources to the war effort, and managed to stay profitable while its competitors struggled to remain solvent. After the war, the Federal government created Canadian National Railways (CNR, later CN) out of several bankrupt railways that fell into government hands during and after the war. CNR would become the main competitor to the CPR in Canada. The Great Depression, which lasted from 1929 until 1939, hit many companies heavily. While the CPR was affected, it was not affected to the extent of its rival CNR because it, unlike the CNR, was debt-free. The CPR scaled back on some of its passenger and freight services, and stopped issuing dividends to its shareholders after 1932. One highlight of the 1930s, both for the railway and for Canada, was the visit of King George VI and Queen Elizabeth to Canada in 1939, the first time that the reigning monarch had visited the country. The CPR and the CNR shared the honours of pulling the royal train across the country, with the CPR undertaking the westbound journey from Quebec City to Vancouver. Later that year, World War II began. As it had done in World War I, the CPR devoted much of its resources to the war effort. It retooled its Angus Shops in Montreal to produce Valentine tanks, and transported troops and resources across the country. As well, 22 of the CPR's ships went to warfare, 12 of which were sunk. After World War II, the transportation industry in Canada changed. Where railways had previously provided almost universal freight and passenger services, cars, trucks, and airplanes started to take traffic away from railways. This naturally helped the CPR's air and trucking operations, and the railway's freight operations continued to thrive hauling resource traffic and bulk commodities. However, passenger trains quickly became unprofitable. During the 1950s, the railway introduced new innovations in passenger service, and in 1955 introduced The Canadian, a new luxury transcontinental train. However, starting in the 1960s the company started to pull out of passenger services, ending services on many of its branch lines. It also discontinued its transcontinental train The Dominion in 1966, and in 1970 unsuccessfully applied to discontinue The Canadian. For the next eight years, it continued to apply to discontinue the service, and service on The Canadian declined markedly. On October 29, 1978, CP Rail transferred its passenger services to VIA Rail, a new federal Crown corporation that is responsible for managing all intercity passenger service formerly handled by both CP Rail and CN. VIA eventually took almost all of its passenger trains, including The Canadian, off CP's lines. In 1968, as part of a corporate re-organization, each of the CPR's major operations, including its rail operations, were organized as separate subsidiaries. The name of the railway was changed to CP Rail, and the parent company changed its name to Canadian Pacific Limited in 1971. Its express, telecommunications, hotel and real estate holdings were spun off, and ownership of all of the companies transferred to Canadian Pacific Investments. The company discarded its beaver logo, adopting the new Multimark logo that could be used for each of its operations. In 1984 CP Rail commenced construction of the Mount Macdonald Tunnel to augment the Connaught Tunnel under the Selkirk Mountains. The first revenue train passed through the tunnel in 1988. At 14.7 km (9 miles), it is the longest tunnel in the Americas. During the 1980s, the Soo Line, in which CP Rail still owned a controlling interest, underwent several changes. It acquired the Minneapolis, Northfield and Southern Railway in 1982. Then on February 21, 1985, the Soo Line obtained a controlling interest in the Milwaukee Road, merging it into its system on January 1, 1986. Also in 1980 Canadian Pacific bought out the controlling interests of the Toronto, Hamilton and Buffalo Railway (TH&amp;amp;B) from Conrail and molded it into the Canadian Pacific System, dissolving the TH&amp;amp;B's name from the books in 1985. In 1987 most of CPR's trackage in the Great Lakes region, including much of the original Soo Line, were spun off into a new railway, the Wisconsin Central, which was subsequently purchased by CN. Influenced by the Canada-U.S. Free Trade Agreement of 1989 which liberalized trade between the two nations, the CPR's expansion continued during the early 1990s: CP Rail gained full control of the Soo Line in 1990, and bought the Delaware and Hudson Railway in 1991. These two acquisitions gave CP Rail routes to the major American cities of Chicago (via the Soo Line) and New York City (via the D&amp;amp;H). During the next few years CP Rail downsized its route, and several Canadian branch lines were either sold to short lines or abandoned. This included all of its lines east of Montreal, with the routes operating across Maine and New Brunswick to the port of Saint John (operating as the Canadian Atlantic Railway) being sold or abandoned, severing CPR's transcontinental status (in Canada); the opening of the St. Lawrence Seaway in the late 1950s, coupled with subsidized icebreaking services, made Saint John surplus to CPR's requirements. During the 1990s, both CP Rail and CN attempted unsuccessfully to buy out the eastern assets of the other, so as to permit further rationalization. As well, it closed divisional and regional offices, drastically reduced white collar staff, and consolidated its Canadian traffic control system in Calgary, Alberta. Finally, in 1996, reflecting the increased importance of western traffic to the railway, CP Rail moved its head office to Calgary from Montreal and changed its name back to Canadian Pacific Railway. A new subsidiary company, the St. Lawrence and Hudson Railway, was created to operate its money-losing lines in eastern North America, covering Quebec, Southern and Eastern Ontario, trackage rights to Chicago, Illinois, as well as the Delaware and Hudson Railway in the U.S. Northeast. However, the new subsidiary, threatened with being sold off and free to innovate, quickly spun off losing track to short lines, instituted scheduled freight service, and produced an unexpected turn-around in profitability. After only four years, CPR revised its opinion and the StL&amp;amp;H formally re-amalgamated with its parent on January 1, 2001. In 2001, the CPR's parent company, Canadian Pacific Limited, spun off its five subsidiaries, including the CPR, into independent companies. Canadian Pacific Railway formally (but, not legally) shortened its name to Canadian Pacific in early 2007, dropping the word &amp;quot;railway&amp;quot; in order to reflect more operational flexibility. Shortly after the name revision, Canadian Pacific announced that it had committed to becoming a major sponsor and logistics provider to the 2010 Olympic Winter Games in Vancouver, British Columbia. On September 4, 2007, CPR announced it was acquiring the Dakota, Minnesota and Eastern Railroad from its present owners, London-based Electra Private Equity.[3] The transaction is an &amp;quot;end-to-end&amp;quot; consolidation,[4][5] and will give CPR access to U.S. shippers of agricultural products, ethanol, and coal. CPR has stated its intention to use this purchase to gain access to the rich coal fields of Wyoming's Powder River Basin. The purchase price is US$1.48 billion, and future payments of over US$1.0 billion contingent on commencement of construction on the smaller railroad's Powder River extension and specified volumes of coal shipments from the Powder River basin.[4] The transaction was subject to approval of the U.S. Surface Transportation Board (STB), which was expected to take a year.[4] On October 4, 2007, CPR announced it has completed the financial transactions required for the acquisition, placing the DM&amp;amp;E and IC&amp;amp;E in a voting trust with Richard Hamlin appointed as the trustee. CPR planned to integrate the railroads' operations once the STB approves the acquisition.[6] The merger was completed as of October 31, 2008.[7] Post Processing; Topaz: vibrance PhotoShop Elements 5: crop, multiply, posterization, ink outlines, sandstone texture" id="3046860680" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="76" rank="13" tags="bbarber bbarber1 billbarber wdwbarber streetsville ontario canada peel region mississauga canonxti photoshopelements canadianpacificrailway cpr crosscountry rail west settlement class1 intermodal transportation confederation transcontinental privatecompany georgeétiennecartier hughallan sirjohnamacdonald pacificscandal alexandermackenzie publicworks construction train red engine track equipment profit progress entrepreneur geography nitroglycerin casualties syndicate williamcorneliusvanhorne mulberry tree fence yard logo rockymountaineer royalcanadianpacific freight passenger locomotive choochoo ironhorse cp cprail railroad" title="CPR / My Neighbour to the West" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3273/3046860680_07b52637e2_b.jpg" username="bill barber" views="12476" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-17 15:51:17" description="Carter Godwin Woodson (b. December 19, 1875, New Canton, Buckingham County, Virginia — d. April 3, 1950, Washington, D.C.) was an African American historian, author, journalist and the founder of Black History Month. He is considered the first to conduct a scholarly effort to popularize the value of Black History. He recognized and acted upon the importance of a people having an awareness and knowledge of their contributions to humanity and left behind an impressive legacy. He was a member of the first black fraternity Sigma Pi Phi and a member of Omega Psi Phi as well. Early life Woodson was the son of former slaves James and Eliza Riddle Woodson. His father had helped the Union soldiers during the Civil War, and afterwards moved his family to West Virginia when he heard they were building a high school for blacks in Huntington. Coming from a large, poor family, Carter could not regularly attend such schools, but through self-instruction he was able to master the fundamentals of common school subjects by the time he was 17. Ambitious for more education Woodson went to Fayette County to earn a living as a miner in the coal fields, but was only able to devote a few months each year to his schooling. In 1895 at the age of twenty, Carter entered Douglass High School where he received his diploma in less than two years. From 1897 to 1900, Carter G. Woodson began teaching in Fayette County. In 1900, he became the principal of Douglass High School. Woodson finally received his Bachelor of Literature degree from Berea College in Kentucky. From 1903 to 1907 he was a school supervisor in the Philippines. He then attended the University of Chicago where he received his M.A. in 1908, and in 1912 he received his Ph.D. in history from Harvard University. In 1915, Woodson and Jesse E. Moorland co-founded the Association for the Study of African American Life and History. By this time convinced that the role of his own people in American history and in the history of other cultures was being either ignored or misrepresented among scholars, Woodson realized the need for special research into the neglected past of the Negro. The Association for the Study of Negro Life and History, founded September 9, 1915, in Chicago, was the result of this conviction. In the same year appeared one of his most scholarly books, The Education of the Negro Prior to 1861. Other books followed: A Century of Negro Migration (1918), The History of the Negro Church (1927), and The Negro in Our History, the last in numerous editions and revised by Charles H. Wesley after Woodson's death in 1950. In January 1916 Woodson began the publication of the scholarly Journal of Negro History, which, despite depressions, loss of support from foundations and two World Wars, has never missed an issue. In 2002 it was renamed the Journal of African-American History, and continues to be published by the Association for the Study of African American History (ASAAH). The NAACP During this time Woodson became affiliated with the recently organized Washington, D.C. branch of the NAACP, and its Chairman, Archibald Grimke. On January 28, 1915, he wrote a letter to Grimke expressing his dissatisfaction with the way things were going. Woodson made two proposals in this letter: That the branch secure an office for a center to which persons may report whatever concerns the Negro race may have, and from which the Association may extend its operations into every part of the city; That a canvasser be appointed to enlist members and obtain subscriptions for The Crisis, the NAACP publication edited by W.E.B. DuBois. Dr. Woodson then added the daring proposal of &amp;quot;diverting patronage from business establishments which do not treat races alike.&amp;quot; He wrote that he would cooperate as one of the twenty-five effective canvassers, adding that he would pay the rent for the office for one month. The NAACP did not welcome Dr. Woodson's ideas. In a letter dated March 18, 1915, in response to a letter from Grimke regarding his proposals, Woodson wrote, I am not afraid of being sued by white businessmen. In fact, I should welcome such a law suit. It would do the cause much good. Let us banish fear. We have been in this mental state for three centuries. I am a radical. I am ready to act, if I can find brave men to help me. Apparently, this difference of opinion with Grimke contributed to the termination of Woodson's short-lived affiliation with the NAACP. On September 9, 1915, Dr. Woodson met in Chicago with Alexander L. Jackson, Executive Secretary of the new Negro YMCA branch. In addition to Woodson and Jackson, three other men were present: George C. Hall, W. B. Hargrove, and J. E. Stamps. At this meeting they formed the Association for the Study of Negro Life and History, and appointed Dr. Woodson Executive Director, a post he held until his death. The early years of the Association were difficult times, but it did not deter Woodson because on January 1, 1916, he alone began to publish the Journal of Negro History, a quarterly publication. He distributed the first edition on his own initiative. The publishing of the Journal coincided with the year of the arrival of Marcus Garvey. In 1926, Woodson single-handedly pioneered the celebration of &amp;quot;Negro History Week&amp;quot;, the second week in February, which has since been extended to the entire month of February. Because of Woodson's belief in self-reliance and racial respect, it is only natural that the paths of Dr. Woodson and the Hon. Marcus Garvey would cross; their views were very similar. Woodson became a regular columnist for Garvey's weekly Negro World. Dr. Woodson's political activism placed him at the center of activity and was in contact with many black intellectuals and activists between the 1920s and 1940s. He corresponded with individuals such as W.E.B. DuBois, John E. Bruce, Arturo Alfonso Schomburg, Hubert H. Harrison, and T. Thomas Fortune among others. Even with the monumental duties connected with the Association, Woodson still found time to write extensive and scholarly works such as The History of the Negro Church (1922), The Mis-Education of the Negro (1933), and many other books which continue to have wide readership today. He was never one to shy away from a controversial subject, &amp;amp; utilized the pages of Negro World to contribute to various fashionable debates. One of these debates was on West Indian-African American relations. Woodson summarized that &amp;quot;the West Indian Negro is free.&amp;quot; He felt that West Indian societies had been more successful at properly dedicating the necessary amounts of time &amp;amp; resources needed to realisticly educate and genuinely emancipate people. These opinions were the result of observing and approving of the efforts on the part of the West Indians to inject Black materials into their school curricula. Woodson was often ostracized by many African-American educators and intellectuals of the time because of his insistence on inviting special attention to one's race. At the time, these educators felt that it was wrong to teach or understand African-American history as in any way separate from a general (usually Eurocentric) view of American history. According to these educators, &amp;quot;Negroes&amp;quot; were simply Americans, darker skinned, but with no history a part from that of any other. Thus Woodson's efforts to get Black culture and history into the curricula of institutions (even Historically Black ones) were often unsuccessful. Woodson's legacy Woodson remained focused on his work throughout his life, never being deterred by the efforts of others. Many see him as a man of vision and understanding. Although Dr. Woodson was among the ranks of the educated few, he did not feel particularly sentimental to elite educational institutions. The Association which he started in 1915 remains today, with the Journal of African American History still published as a quarterly journal. Dr. Woodson's other far-reaching activities includes the organization in 1920 of the Associated Publishers, the oldest African American publishing company in the United States, which made possible the publication of books concerning blacks which were not at that time acceptable to many publishers; the establishment of Negro History Week in 1926 (now known as Black History Month); and the initial publication of the Negro History Bulletin, published continuously by the Association since 1937, and originally created for teachers in elementary and high school grades. Woodson also influenced the direction and subsidizing of research in African American history by the Association, and wrote numerous articles, monographs and books on Blacks. The Negro in Our History reached its eleventh edition in 1966, when it had sold more than 90,000 copies. Dr. Woodson's most cherished ambition, a six-volume Encyclopedia Africana, lay incomplete at the time of his death on April 3, 1950 at the age of 74. He is buried at Lincoln Memorial Cemetery in Suitland-Silver Hill, Maryland. In 1992, the Library of Congress held an exhibition entitled &amp;quot;Moving Back Barriers: The Legacy of Carter G. Woodson&amp;quot;. Woodson donated 5,000 items from the 18th, 19th, and 20th centuries to the Library. Dorothy Porter Wesley stated that &amp;quot;Woodson would wrap up his publications, take them to the post office and have dinner at the YMCA&amp;quot;. He would teasingly decline her dinner invitations saying, &amp;quot;No, you are trying to marry me off. I am married to my work&amp;quot;. His Washington, D.C. home has been preserved as the Carter G. Woodson Home National Historic Site." id="1604345594" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="14" tags="" title="Carter G. Woodson" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2287/1604345594_8e8e87aa24_b.jpg" username="dbking" views="4084" />
<photo  date_taken="1895-01-01 00:00:00" description="&lt;b&gt;Collection&lt;/b&gt;: A. D. White Architectural Photographs, Cornell University Library Accession Number: 15/5/3090.00153 &lt;b&gt;Title&lt;/b&gt;: Reliance Building, Chicago Architect: Burnham &amp;amp; Atwood (1891-1895) Photograph date: ca. 1895 Building Date: 1894-1895 &lt;b&gt;Location&lt;/b&gt;: North and Central America: United States; Illinois, Chicago &lt;b&gt;Materials&lt;/b&gt;: albumen print Image: 9.25 x 7.2835 in.; 23.495 x 18.5 cm &lt;b&gt;Provenance&lt;/b&gt;: Transfer from the College of Architecture, Art and Planning &lt;b&gt;Persistent URI&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hdl.handle.net/1813.001/5s9q&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/1813.001/5s9q&lt;/a&gt; There are no known U.S. copyright restrictions on this image. The digital file is owned by the Cornell University Library which is making it freely available with the request that, when possible, the Library be credited as its source. We had some help with the geocoding from &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.yahoo.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Web Services by Yahoo!&lt;/a&gt;" id="3678978130" latitude="41.88415" license="7" longitude="-87.632409" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="cornelluniversitylibrary architecture skyscrapers cityviews urbanviews reliancebuildingchicagoillinois pedestrians officebuildings culidentifier:value=155309000153 culidentifier:lunafield=accessionnumber" title="Reliance Building, Chicago" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3626/3678978130_991723d18d_b.jpg" username="Cornell University Library" views="1218" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-29 15:25:32" description="The Reliance Building in Chicago, completed in 1895, is considered the first skyscraper to have large glass windows make up the majority of its walls. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&lt;/a&gt;" id="3869926372" latitude="41.883093" license="4" longitude="-87.627843" nbComments="0" rank="16" tags="chicago reliance building" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2646/3869926372_1ddb4a1087_b.jpg" username="Marit &amp; Toomas Hinnosaar" views="198" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-29 15:23:13" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&lt;/a&gt;" id="3869144097" latitude="41.883217" license="4" longitude="-87.627843" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="chicago reliance building" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2661/3869144097_9146469e59_b.jpg" username="Marit &amp; Toomas Hinnosaar" views="82" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-08-29 15:24:32" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&lt;/a&gt;" id="3869926150" latitude="41.883093" license="4" longitude="-87.627843" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="chicago reliance building" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2636/3869926150_afc4c5663b_b.jpg" username="Marit &amp; Toomas Hinnosaar" views="126" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-04 19:54:30" description="" id="2129147073" latitude="41.880888" license="5" longitude="-87.625815" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="chicago reliancebuilding statestreet downtown illinois usa architecture skyscraper building hotelburnham historic urban commerce" title="Chicago - Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2163/2129147073_858964a3bc_b.jpg" username="Harshil.Shah" views="132" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-20 12:29:02" description="Used by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.schmap.com/chicago/hotelburnham/#r=none&amp;amp;mapview=Map&amp;amp;tab=Places&amp;amp;p=44629&amp;amp;topleft=41.96677,-87.68515&amp;amp;bottomright=41.83337,-87.58867&amp;amp;i=44629_2.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Schmap&lt;/a&gt;." id="1446369924" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="chicago reliancebuilding hotelburnham daniel burnham" title="Reliance Building daytime" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1391/1446369924_581a970ae6_b.jpg" username="bluebike" views="44" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-24 11:54:53" description="This is about 1/3 of a 4x5 negative. It's pretty difficult to shoot this building, as there is so much development around it (but not quite as hard as the Monadnock). Another of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/urbanoasis/240724550/&quot;&gt;Burnham's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/urbanoasis/140364432/&quot;&gt;famous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/urbanoasis/532689516/&quot;&gt;skyscrapers.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/urbanoasis/316191777/&quot;&gt;This one in 1963.&lt;/a&gt;" id="1433027503" latitude="41.883077" license="2" longitude="-87.628422" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="burnham reliancebuilding chicago architecture skyscraper 4x5 kodaktrix320 film" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1220/1433027503_9c26a92034_b.jpg" username="urbanoasis" views="235" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-19 14:10:23" description="A view of the Reliance Building, Chicago, IL" id="3585890333" latitude="41.883099" license="3" longitude="-87.628138" nbComments="2" rank="22" tags="architecture chicago dioramasky illinois" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3651/3585890333_99025a7129_b.jpg" username="Diorama Sky" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-17 17:24:26" description="" id="6207405542" latitude="41.883317" license="3" longitude="-87.62633" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="nikon d90 18200 usa america chicago illinois reliance building skyscraper" title="Reliance Building Chicago-1" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6016/6207405542_7e024783d5_b.jpg" username="Gouldy99" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-25 15:09:45" description="The Reliance Building in Chicago, a national landmark (1895). John Root developed an innovating floating raft system, which allowed tall buildings to be built in the soft soil of Chicago. Root died before the building was completed, and only the first floors reflect his design. Daniel Burnham recruited Boston architect Charles B. Atwood to complete the building. It is considered a proto-modernist building due to the abnormally large amount of natural light that the building allowed through its many windows. Today, the Reliance Building is a famous example of the good that can come out of landmark restoration. Badly dilapidated by the 1980s, it seemed destined for destruction after the recent demolition of the nearby McCarthy Building. A deal was finally stuck to convert the building into a luxury hotel." id="7187043031" latitude="41.883069" license="5" longitude="-87.628117" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="chicagoschool johnroot burnhamroot charlesbatwood chicago theloop illinois cookcounty 1890s" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5279/7187043031_c1d139b2e4_b.jpg" username="Teemu008" views="71" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-12-06 18:42:48" description="" id="2129155097" latitude="41.880888" license="5" longitude="-87.625815" nbComments="2" rank="25" tags="chicago subway lrt metro usa el loop downtown transport reliancebuilding urban street" title="Chicago - 'L' train &amp; Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2092/2129155097_d217d98fbf_b.jpg" username="Harshil.Shah" views="1165" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-26 18:08:17" description="" id="1446370392" latitude="0" license="6" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="chicago reliancebuilding hotelburnham daniel burnham" title="Reliance Building at Dusk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1050/1446370392_1fa27737a2_b.jpg" username="bluebike" views="63" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-06-11 22:46:02" description="Daniel Burnham designed this dynamic structure." id="4692604756" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="chicago reliancebuilding burnham" title="The Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4046/4692604756_feb30bca81_b.jpg" username="Timmy Caldwell" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-01-01 00:05:36" description="" id="5209408619" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="28" tags="reliancebuilding burnhamroot johnroot charlesatwood atwood burnham root danielburnham chicago illinois modernarchitecture architecture" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5167/5209408619_c344642601_b.jpg" username="pov_steve" views="870" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-04-15 12:33:50" description="Here you can really get an idea of how significant the windows are to this design. Apparently the use of this much window space was very advanced for its time." id="460344438" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="chicago" title="D.H. Burnham and Company / Reliance Building / Chicago, Illinois / 1895" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/173/460344438_b204696a26_b.jpg" username="Nate Hofer" views="128" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-04-15 12:36:24" description="This was the precursor to today's glass skyscraper. Curtain walls held up by a steel skeleton allowed for larger than normal windows allowing the most light in. 16 whopping stories." id="460348346" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="chicago" title="D.H. Burnham and Company / Reliance Building / Chicago, Illinois / 1895" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/236/460348346_e6a494879e_b.jpg" username="Nate Hofer" views="85" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:13" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the Reliance building taken by C. William Brubaker in 1962. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_o.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036987836" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4151/5036987836_233951aa24_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="939" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:10" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the Reliance building taken by C. William Brubaker in 1977. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_m.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036987614" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4154/5036987614_3c730af174_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="792" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:09" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the Reliance building taken by C. William Brubaker in 1980. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_h.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036368735" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4124/5036368735_9a55a2a7a4_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="796" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:07" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the upper part of the Reliance building taken in 1962 by C. William Brubaker. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_g.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036368609" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4091/5036368609_8f04d403c9_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="808" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:12" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the lower part of the Reliance building facade taken by C. William Brubaker in 1977. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_n.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036368943" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4091/5036368943_9094f8a1d1_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="875" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:05" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the Reliance building taken by C. William Brubaker in 1995, showing the building's restoration in progress. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_c.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036987006" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings historicpreservation" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4145/5036987006_a52bb202e6_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="837" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:05" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the Reliance building taken by C. William Brubaker in 1995, showing the building's restoration in progress. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William , 1964. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_b.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036368273" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings historicpreservation" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4132/5036368273_3063df0edd_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="814" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-29 13:11:04" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Photograph of the Reliance building taken by C. William Brubaker in 1995, showing the building's restoration in progress. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William , 1964. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_06_a.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5036368167" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="buildings chicago commercialbuildings officebuildings historicpreservation" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4106/5036368167_18cb389890_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="842" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-23 19:49:52" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; Sketch of the Reliance building by C. William Brubaker, with caption: &amp;quot;Reliance at 32 N. State St. (1890 - Burnham &amp;amp; Root) The finest pioneer skyscraper.&amp;quot; One of Brubaker's group of &amp;quot;early skyscrapers&amp;quot;. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William , 1960s. &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1890-1895 &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru001_01_pF.jpg For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library's survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="5018660675" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="highrisebuildings commercialbuildings officebuildings sketches drawing architecture chicago" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4111/5018660675_ac098219ea_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="1039" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-05-12 18:05:23" description="Today. This is the lobby of Hotel Burnham in the Reliance Building in Chicago by request. The hotel itself opened in 2006, but it was designed to keep in tact the original architecture and interior decoration of the Reliance Building. This was the first skyscraper to have large plate glass windows make up the majority of its surface area. From the photoblog at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shutterrunner.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.shutterrunner.com&lt;/a&gt;." id="4603282929" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="7" rank="40" tags="chicago hdr reliancebuilding hotel burnham lobby" title="175/365" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1041/4603282929_b2825f0334_b.jpg" username="ShutterRunner" views="423" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-26 14:53:42" description="Chicago School design by &lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.archinform.net/arch/3164.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Charles B. Atwood&lt;/a&gt; (1849-1896) of Chicago's &lt;a href=&quot;http://thearchimediaworkshop.org/taxonomy/term/17&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;D.H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/a&gt; • first skyscraper with plate glass windows a majority of building's surface area now houses &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burnhamhotel.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hotel Burnham&lt;/a&gt; • after years of neglect, deteriorating building rescued by City of Chicago and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suite101.com/article.cfm/historic_preservation/40272&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;renovated&lt;/a&gt;, 1994 • Atwood &lt;a href=&quot;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F00C10F83E5A16738DDDA80894D9405B8685F0D3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;obituary&lt;/a&gt;, NYT, 01/01/1896 • &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; • Designated Chicago Landmark, 1995 • Designated National Historic Landmark, 1976 • National Register #70000237, 1970" id="5812977050" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="chicago cookcounty illinois il usa unitedstates northamerica midwest architecture buildings commercial residential hotel officebuilding modern chicagoschool 1890s 19thcentury sminor lumierefl" title="Reliance Building (1895), front, 32 North State Street, Chicago, Illinois" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2267/5812977050_5a53320372_b.jpg" username="lumierefl" views="269" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-03-01 13:10:16" description="Reliance Building, world's first skyscraper" id="2653964339" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="chicago downtown reliance building" title="chicago-007972" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3053/2653964339_fcfe88c13b_b.jpg" username="suvarn" views="61" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-03-01 13:15:04" description="Reliance Building, world's first skyscraper" id="2653968575" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="chicago downtown reliance building" title="chicago-007978" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3201/2653968575_2dc4cac642_b.jpg" username="suvarn" views="48" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-30 16:42:02" description="Chicago School design by &lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.archinform.net/arch/3164.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Charles B. Atwood&lt;/a&gt; (1849-1896) of Chicago's &lt;a href=&quot;http://thearchimediaworkshop.org/taxonomy/term/17&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;D.H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/a&gt; • first skyscraper with plate glass windows a majority of building's surface area now houses &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burnhamhotel.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hotel Burnham&lt;/a&gt; • after years of neglect, deteriorating building rescued by City of Chicago and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suite101.com/article.cfm/historic_preservation/40272&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;renovated&lt;/a&gt;, 1994 • Atwood &lt;a href=&quot;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F00C10F83E5A16738DDDA80894D9405B8685F0D3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;obituary&lt;/a&gt;, NYT, 01/01/1896 • &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; • Designated Chicago Landmark, 1995 • Designated National Historic Landmark, 1976 • National Register #70000237, 1970" id="5805546959" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="chicago cookcounty illinois il usa unitedstates northamerica midwest architecture buildings commercial residential hotel officebuilding modern chicagoschool 1890s 19thcentury sminor lumierefl" title="Reliance Building (1895), 3/4 view, 32 North State Street, Chicago, Illinois" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5038/5805546959_ff74f4ecbd_b.jpg" username="lumierefl" views="333" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-22 21:56:39" description="Creator: Burnham and Root, firm 1871-1891, Chicago Date: 1889-1891; 1894-1895 Current location: Chicago, Illinois, U.S.A. Description of work: Corner view, tinted photo, from an old postcard of the Reliance Building, Chicago, IL. Work type: Architecture and Landscape Culture: American Materials/Techniques: stone Source: Society of Architectural Historians, Image Exchange (http://www.sah.org/imagex.html) Resource type: image File format: JPG Image size: 480x350 pixels Permitted uses: This image is posted publicly for non-profit educational uses, excluding printed publication. Other uses are not permitted. &lt;a href=&quot;http://alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightssah.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightssah.htm&lt;/a&gt; Collection: Worldwide Building and Landscape Pictures Record ID: WB7444" id="6071850498" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6072/6071850498_d983215fc0_b.jpg" username="Penn State Libraries Pictures Collection" views="39" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-03-02 17:27:47" description="I LOVE how Burnham put the name of the building above the door in this and the Wyandotte (and probably others). I think it takes the steam out of the interpretation of Venturi's Guild House, where he did the same." id="139182087" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="46" tags="chicago architecture burnham arborupdate" title="Reliance Building entrance" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/50/139182087_8d30d8e96e_b.jpg" username="urbanoasis" views="247" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-03-27 12:21:24" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliance_Building&lt;/a&gt;" id="5566696626" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="illinois chicago reliancebuilding hotelburnham" title="IMG_0189" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5061/5566696626_80c555b5c8_b.jpg" username="clare_and_ben" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-09-12 07:47:27" description="Exposure: ¹⁄₁₂₅ sec at f/13, ISO: 800, Lens: EF17-40mm f/4L USM, Focal Length: 17 mm. This photo is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Noncomercial-Share Alike license. Please link back to this page if you repost this photo on another website. For more info see &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to use this photo under conditions different from those described above, please contact me via Flickr Mail. Thanks." id="5020765849" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="48" tags="atwood chicago2010 reliancebuilding theburnhamhotel architecture" title="7688" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4106/5020765849_b4b955202c_b.jpg" username="engnr_chik" views="701" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-11 10:49:22" description="Burnham and Root, 1891. Restored in the late 1990s." id="389718415" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="4" rank="49" tags="architecture chicago building us il reliance burnham 1891 restored swanksalot sethanderson" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/124/389718415_9d8de9e260_b.jpg" username="swanksalot" views="238" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-27 16:40:17" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burnhamhotel.com/&quot;&gt;Hotel Burnham&lt;/a&gt; in the old &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burnhamhotel.com/bur_history.html&quot;&gt;Reliance Building&lt;/a&gt;." id="1431873474" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="chicago illinois hotelburnham reliancebuilding hotel buildingreuse historicpreservation" title="DSC07036.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1410/1431873474_ca2b6c569e_b.jpg" username="iwantamonkey" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-03-02 17:20:33" description="Daniel Burnham/Charles Atwood. Completed in 1895. Compare to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/30211583@N00/139162547/&quot;&gt;Wyandotte Building&lt;/a&gt; in Columbus, OH." id="108203580" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="chicago architecture burnham arborupdate" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/40/108203580_02561b90a5_b.jpg" username="urbanoasis" views="308" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-19 13:48:05" description="&lt;b&gt;Title:&lt;/b&gt; Reliance Building &lt;b&gt;Creator:&lt;/b&gt; D.H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co. &lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt; View looking up at the east (State Street) facade of the Reliance Building (36 North State Street) during a facade restoration project in 1995. After further extensive restoration, the building reopened in 1999 as the Hotel Burnham. The top corner of 24 North State Street is visible at the lower left. &lt;b&gt;Photograph credit:&lt;/b&gt; Brubaker, C. William, 1995 &lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; 1895 (Reliance Building) &lt;b&gt;Geographic coverage:&lt;/b&gt; Loop (Chicago, Ill.) &lt;b&gt;Collection:&lt;/b&gt; C. William Brubaker Collection (University of Illinois at Chicago) &lt;b&gt;Repository:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago. Library. [Visual Resources]. &lt;b&gt;Credit Line:&lt;/b&gt; Cite as [creator]. [title]. [file name]. [collection]. &lt;b&gt;Rights:&lt;/b&gt; University of Illinois at Chicago College of Architecture and the Arts holds reproduction and licensing rights. &lt;b&gt;File Name:&lt;/b&gt; bru010_09_lF For more images from the collection, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CISOROOT=/uic_bru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collections.carli.illinois.edu/cdm4/index_uic_bru.php?CIS...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MMGHMKK”&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Click here to take the Library’s survey on its Flickr collections.&lt;/a&gt;" id="7094200857" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="highrisebuildings highrises officebuildings commercialbuildings architecture exteriorview" title="Reliance Building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5456/7094200857_776284069b_b.jpg" username="UIC Digital Collections" views="54" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-02-20 13:56:17" description="" id="377878333" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="chicago illinois reliancebuilding" title="02-20-2004 Berghoff and downtown chicago 0019" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/182/377878333_7f0def28c3_b.jpg" username="clare_and_ben" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-02-20 14:03:54" description="" id="377878514" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="chicago illinois reliancebuilding" title="02-20-2004 Berghoff and downtown chicago 0020" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/154/377878514_6037ac3954_b.jpg" username="clare_and_ben" views="62" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-10 17:15:07" description="" id="1111879144" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="" title="Hotel Burnham, former Reliance Building, Chicago" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1207/1111879144_a220f6d6d0_b.jpg" username="yuzu" views="85" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-03-18 13:30:25" description="Charles B. Atwood (Burnham and Root). 1890-1895. Chicago, Illinois" id="5622398544" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="chicago illinois burnham root charlesbatwood" title="Reliance Building detail" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5064/5622398544_5d3c71266b_b.jpg" username="jonathan rieke" views="136" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-02-22 19:17:29" description="" id="5476794714" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="chicago" title="Reliance building" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5296/5476794714_d63d7632ce_b.jpg" username="artq55" views="735" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-04-22 13:45:01" description="Two great buildings in one. The Reliance Building, considered the world's first glass skyscraper (shown above the street lamp) is reflected in the windows of Louis Sullivan's Carson, Pirie, Scott and Company Store looking north on State Street near Madison. The Reliance, designed by Charles B. Atwood of D.H. Burnham &amp;amp; Co., is now the Hotel Burnham. A modern building that mimics or pays homage to the Reliance (take your pick) is seen near the bottom left side of the photograph. That is a dormitory for the Art Institute of Chicago, designed more than a century later. Taken April 21, 2011, in Chicago." id="5647629178" latitude="41.881839" license="2" longitude="-87.627631" nbComments="2" rank="58" tags="reliancebuilding carsonpiriescottandcompanystore louissullivan charlesbatwood danielburnham" title="Twofer" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5301/5647629178_9b39136846_b.jpg" username="wordsnpix" views="101" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-10-29 23:12:06" description="Reliance Building (Hotel Burnham) Architect: D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Company (and) Antunovich Associates Date: 1895 Style: Chicago School Address: 32 North State Street Height: 202 ft. (15 floors) Program: hotel, restaurant The Reliance Building, designed by Burnham and Root, was built in 1895, later restored in 1995 by Antunovich Associates and finally reopened in 1999 as the Hotel Burnham. It was one of the first skyscrapers to use large plate glass windows to make up the majority of its surface area and became a sort of foreshadowing for skyscrapers in the 20th century. In 1970 it was listed on the National Register of Historic Places and in 1975 became a National Historic Landmark." id="8400319001" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="" title="Reliance Building - Exterior 3" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8095/8400319001_c1e53ee77f_b.jpg" username="Chicago Architecture Today" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-10-29 23:12:14" description="Reliance Building (Hotel Burnham) Architect: D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Company (and) Antunovich Associates Date: 1895 Style: Chicago School Address: 32 North State Street Height: 202 ft. (15 floors) Program: hotel, restaurant The Reliance Building, designed by Burnham and Root, was built in 1895, later restored in 1995 by Antunovich Associates and finally reopened in 1999 as the Hotel Burnham. It was one of the first skyscrapers to use large plate glass windows to make up the majority of its surface area and became a sort of foreshadowing for skyscrapers in the 20th century. In 1970 it was listed on the National Register of Historic Places and in 1975 became a National Historic Landmark." id="8401405170" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="" title="Reliance Building - Exterior 2" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8088/8401405170_8621743197_b.jpg" username="Chicago Architecture Today" views="31" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-10-29 23:11:45" description="Reliance Building (Hotel Burnham) Architect: D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Company (and) Antunovich Associates Date: 1895 Style: Chicago School Address: 32 North State Street Height: 202 ft. (15 floors) Program: hotel, restaurant The Reliance Building, designed by Burnham and Root, was built in 1895, later restored in 1995 by Antunovich Associates and finally reopened in 1999 as the Hotel Burnham. It was one of the first skyscrapers to use large plate glass windows to make up the majority of its surface area and became a sort of foreshadowing for skyscrapers in the 20th century. In 1970 it was listed on the National Register of Historic Places and in 1975 became a National Historic Landmark." id="8400319759" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="" title="Reliance Building - Exterior 4" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8223/8400319759_29aa3eddf4_b.jpg" username="Chicago Architecture Today" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-10-29 23:14:09" description="Reliance Building (Hotel Burnham) Architect: D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Company (and) Antunovich Associates Date: 1895 Style: Chicago School Address: 32 North State Street Height: 202 ft. (15 floors) Program: hotel, restaurant The Reliance Building, designed by Burnham and Root, was built in 1895, later restored in 1995 by Antunovich Associates and finally reopened in 1999 as the Hotel Burnham. It was one of the first skyscrapers to use large plate glass windows to make up the majority of its surface area and became a sort of foreshadowing for skyscrapers in the 20th century. In 1970 it was listed on the National Register of Historic Places and in 1975 became a National Historic Landmark." id="8401406172" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="" title="Reliance Building - Exterior 1" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8188/8401406172_276ba0b814_b.jpg" username="Chicago Architecture Today" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-10-29 23:11:35" description="Reliance Building (Hotel Burnham) Architect: D. H. Burnham &amp;amp; Company (and) Antunovich Associates Date: 1895 Style: Chicago School Address: 32 North State Street Height: 202 ft. (15 floors) Program: hotel, restaurant The Reliance Building, designed by Burnham and Root, was built in 1895, later restored in 1995 by Antunovich Associates and finally reopened in 1999 as the Hotel Burnham. It was one of the first skyscrapers to use large plate glass windows to make up the majority of its surface area and became a sort of foreshadowing for skyscrapers in the 20th century. In 1970 it was listed on the National Register of Historic Places and in 1975 became a National Historic Landmark." id="8401404140" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="" title="Reliance Building - Exterior 5" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8222/8401404140_2080c555a5_b.jpg" username="Chicago Architecture Today" views="33" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-11-08 15:04:25" description="the gorgeous old mosaic on the floor of the reliance building in chicago" id="3018925870" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="chicagoillinoisilunited statesusaloop chicago" title="200811 reliance mosaic" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3001/3018925870_884f34f1dc_b.jpg" username="iambents" views="67" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-04-15 11:29:58" description="" id="460254631" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="chicago" title="Reliance-Building.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/199/460254631_650bc95799_b.jpg" username="Nate Hofer" views="10" />
</photos>
