<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Royal Palace of Turin">

<photo  date_taken="2012-04-07 11:47:05" description="Royal Palace of Turin or Palazzo Reale, is a palace in Turin, northern Italy. It was the royal palace of the House of Savoy. It was modernised greatly by the French born Madama Reale Christine Marie of France (1606–1663) in the 17th century." id="8062072145" latitude="45.077187" license="4" longitude="7.684035" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="italy2012 royalpalaceofturin italy turin torino houseofsavoy" title="Royal Palace of Turin" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8175/8062072145_c42205f77e_b.jpg" username="Peter Broster" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="1890-01-01 00:00:00" description="[Castle Place with Royal and Madama Palaces, Turin, Italy] [between ca. 1890 and ca. 1900]. 1 photomechanical print : photochrom, color. &lt;b&gt;Notes: &lt;/b&gt; Title from the Detroit Publishing Co., Catalogue J--foreign section, Detroit, Mich. : Detroit Publishing Company, 1905. Print no. &amp;quot;8531&amp;quot;. Forms part of: Views of architecture and other sites in Italy in the Photochrom print collection. &lt;b&gt;Subjects: &lt;/b&gt; Italy--Turin. &lt;b&gt;Format: &lt;/b&gt; Photochrom prints--Color--1890-1900. &lt;b&gt;Rights Info: &lt;/b&gt; No known restrictions on reproduction. &lt;b&gt;Repository: &lt;/b&gt; Library of Congress, Prints and Photographs Division, Washington, D.C. 20540 USA, &lt;a href=&quot;http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/pp.print&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/pp.print&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Part Of: &lt;/b&gt; Views of architecture and other sites in Italy (DLC) 2001700650 More information about the Photochrom Print Collection is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/pp.pgz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/pp.pgz&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Persistent URL: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/ppmsc.06637&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/ppmsc.06637&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Call Number: &lt;/b&gt; LOT 13434, no. 209 [item]" id="4755205628" latitude="0" license="7" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="2" tags="libraryofcongress dc:identifier=httphdllocgovlocpnpppmsc06637 xmlns:dc=httppurlorgdcelements11 turin piazza castello palazzo madama italy italia torino palazzoreale royalpalace" title="[Castle Place with Royal and Madama Palaces, Turin, Italy] (LOC)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4122/4755205628_a2ded0aef9_b.jpg" username="The Library of Congress" views="1106" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-28 14:44:26" description="&lt;b&gt;Palazzo Reale - Royal Palace of Turin&lt;/b&gt; Begun in 1646, for Cristina of France, was the residence of the Dukes of Savoy, the Kings of Sardinia and the first King of Italy until 1865. Both the 1th and 2nd &amp;quot;piano nobile&amp;quot; can be visited. The apartment of the King and the apartment of Madama Felicita are visitable too. The building is completed by the Royal Garden, built at the end of the 17th century and designed by André Le Nôtre, the most important European garden designer in the 17th century. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/residenze_sabaude/pal_reale.shtml&quot;&gt;Palazzo Reale&lt;/a&gt;" id="378522133" latitude="45.073262" license="3" longitude="7.686256" nbComments="3" rank="3" tags="italy piedmont turin italia piemonte torino palazzoreale royalpalace visitpiedmont d80 nikon" title="Palazzo Reale - Torino - 28.01.2007" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/148/378522133_7c135b4174_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="553" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-20 15:00:33" description="Il Palazzo Reale di Torino è collocato in piazza Castello al centro del capoluogo piemontese. È la più importante delle residenze sabaude, sede della governo del regno per oltre tre secoli. E’ stata riconosciuta dall'Unesco come patrimonio storico dell'umanità. Il palazzo destinato a residenza reale venne progettato tra la fine del Cinquecento e l'inizio del Seicento e realizzato durante il regno di Carlo Emanuele II dagli architetti Carlo e Amedeo di Castellamonte. Completato nel 1660, il complesso è stato la dimora della casata Savoia e dei re d’Italia fino al 1865. La severa facciata presenta ora una parte centrale affiancata da due ali più alte ma il palazzo è stato più volte rimaneggiato e ampliato. Gli stili che si sovrappongono nella lunga fase di completamento sono il barocco, il rococò e, nell’ottocento, il neoclassico. Turin - Royal Palace The Royal Palace is located in the center of Turin. It is the most important of Savoy’s residences, home of the government of the kingdom for over three centuries. It 'been recognized by Unesco as a World Heritage Site. The palace for royal residence was designed between the late sixteenth and the early seventeenth century and built during the reign of Carlo Emanuele II by architects Carlo and Amedeo di Castellamonte. Completed in 1660, the complex was home of the family of Savoy and king of Italy until 1865. The severe facade has now a central part flanked by two higher wings, but the building was remodeled and enlarged several times. The styles overlapping in the long process of completion are baroque, rococo, and in the nineteenth century, neoclassical." id="6210046931" latitude="45.072202" license="1" longitude="7.685478" nbComments="56" rank="4" tags="torino palazzoreale piemonte italia barocco rococò neoclassico dimora palazzo residenza piazzacastello unesco patrimoniodellumanità turin royalpalace baroque rococo neoclassical residence italy palace worldheritagesite" title="Torino - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6187/6210046931_0f84f0a628_b.jpg" username="giovanni_novara" views="521" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-03-10 02:36:07" description="On Sunday we went to the Royal Palace to see the exhibiton about the first king of united Italy: there were many important documents of our history and I could show the kids the Albertine Statute... which more or less represented our first form of constitution. Tomorrow Italy will celebrate 150 years of italian unification. Turin was the first italian capital so many things will happen &lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.italia150.it/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in the next 150 days (and even more). Ours is a country full of contradictions and not without its serious problems but I hope that these celebrations will help to create a true spirit of fraternity that will unite us in a moment so difficult for our republic. I made origami for the people at the entrance of royal palace by folding tricolor cranes. Model by Tomoko Fuse in Cranes Origami ISBN4-416-30205-3 Tricolor origami pattern are designed by me: see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mammaoca2008/sets/72157626271632262/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to get them. If you want to join italian origamists in folding tricolor origami see CDO site &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.origami-cdo.it/indexen.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;link text&lt;/a&gt;" id="5531648294" latitude="45.07158" license="2" longitude="7.687168" nbComments="2" rank="5" tags="italt italia 150 italia150 crane gru origami origamiforthepeople" title="Tricolor cranes at Turin Royal Palace" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5015/5531648294_f48a815104_b.jpg" username="Mammaoca2008" views="430" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-19 19:27:52" description="The two Knight Riders, in front of the Royal Palace, in one of the main plazas of Turin. I love the strong contrast of the 2 knight over the pale white of the palace behind. That's at last a shot like I wanted to do before taking it." id="3368407169" latitude="45.071035" license="1" longitude="7.685751" nbComments="2" rank="6" tags="palazzoreale 2009 torino turin night palace piazzacastello reale castello" title="Castore e Polluce" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3434/3368407169_3e82d21b57_b.jpg" username="Doc. Di0" views="135" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-19 19:06:25" description="I had to go, for working reasons, to the big city today (yay!!! Tons of shops there, life, tourists, monuments, museums, bars, restaurant!)... and because I was feeling to go green I took the bus... once seated I decided I wanted to try some bus folding (because I read origami_madness)... but it did not work very well... after the 50minutes trip I was all green (not only in spirit) and I had a terrible nausea.... maybe when I was younger (a century ago, when I was 20 I used to study on the bus)... in any way I could fold these two cranes that I decided to release in the wild for the group Origami for the People. This is not the only young thing I did today... because I was really late with a meeting, and I realised I could never make it walking, I called hubby, he came with a colleague's scooter (?)... so I made this trip in scooter with him... like when we were 14 years old, our green age. So I wish you this week to feel and be every day younger than the day before. Enjoy! PS. Beyond the cranes Turin's Royal Palace (protected by UNESCO), beautiful to visit for the rooms and the collections, here's a virtual tour &lt;a href=&quot;http://torino.arounder.com/palazzo_reale/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;torino.arounder.com/palazzo_reale/&lt;/a&gt; and information from Wikipedia &lt;a href=&quot;http://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palazzo_Reale_di_Torino&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palazzo_Reale_di_Torino&lt;/a&gt;" id="3947164721" latitude="45.071107" license="2" longitude="7.6847" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="origami paper carta crane cranes origamiforthepeople gru torino turin piemonte piedmont" title="Cranes in Turin - P.za Castello" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2559/3947164721_e03dd67121_b.jpg" username="Mammaoca2008" views="262" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-25 07:50:10" description="Reggia di Venaria Reale, maggio 2009" id="4135355499" latitude="45.135676" license="1" longitude="7.622108" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="venaria reggia reale savoia reggiadivenaria reggiadivenariareale savoy palaceofvenaria palace royal royalpalace royalhouse torino turin busto bust scultura sculptur egitto tesorisommersi tesori sommersi degitto egypt sunkentreasures egypts egyptssunkentreasures italia italy italiano italiani italiana italiane italian italians italianos italie italien italija 意大利 italya италия 이탈리아 イタリア איטליה إيطاليا 都灵 турин turim トリノ טורינו تورينو" title="Busto, mostra Tesori sommersi d'Egitto" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2754/4135355499_377b1ba40d_b.jpg" username="Michele Mariani" views="27" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-25 09:39:42" description="" id="4136119860" latitude="45.135676" license="1" longitude="7.622108" nbComments="0" rank="9" tags="venaria reggia reale savoia reggiadivenaria reggiadivenariareale savoy palaceofvenaria palace unesco patrimoniodellumanità heritagelist royal royalpalace royalhouse torino turin italia italy italiano italiani italiana italiane italian italians italianos italie italien italija 意大利 italya италия 이탈리아 イタリア איטליה إيطاليا 都灵 турин turim トリノ טורינו تورينو" title="Reggia di Venaria Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2531/4136119860_171ccd774a_b.jpg" username="Michele Mariani" views="49" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-22 16:57:42" description="Ruiny amfiteatru, Palazzo Reale, Piazza San Giovanni, Turyn, 22 sierpnia 2007 r. ** Ruins of an amphitheatre near the Royal Palace, Piazza San Giovanni, Turin, August 22, 2007" id="1419271006" latitude="45.073369" license="3" longitude="7.685043" nbComments="8" rank="10" tags="turyn turin torino włochy wlochy italia italy amfiteatr pałac palac ruiny amphitheater palace ruins piemont piemonte piedmont" title="Amfiteatr" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1085/1419271006_343d37694f_b.jpg" username="magro_kr" views="292" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-25 09:07:30" description="" id="4136117500" latitude="45.135676" license="1" longitude="7.622108" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="venaria reggia reale savoia reggiadivenaria reggiadivenariareale savoy palaceofvenaria palace unesco patrimoniodellumanità heritagelist royal royalpalace royalhouse galleria grande galleriagrande torino turin italia italy italiano italiani italiana italiane italian italians italianos humanidad patrimonio heritage list world mondiale mundial umanità italie italien italija 意大利 italya италия 이탈리아 イタリア איטליה إيطاليا 都灵 турин turim トリノ טורינו تورينو" title="Galleria Grande, Reggia di Venaria Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2638/4136117500_af9e007984_b.jpg" username="Michele Mariani" views="53" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-22 17:15:28" description="Widok spod Porta Palatina, Piazza Cesare Augusto, Turyn, 22 sierpnia 2007 r. ** Piazza San Giovanni seen from Porta Palatina, Piazza Cesare Augusto, Turin, August 22, 2007" id="1423047992" latitude="45.075043" license="3" longitude="7.684496" nbComments="2" rank="12" tags="turyn turin torino włochy wlochy italia italy pałac palac katedra kościół kosciol dzwonnica wieża wieza palace cathedral church tower belltower piemont piemonte piedmont" title="Piazza San Giovanni" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1296/1423047992_4299df1099_b.jpg" username="magro_kr" views="1017" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-20 15:12:05" description="La piazza Castello è il centro di Torino e comprende i principali monumenti della città. Ha rappresentato il punto di sviluppo urbano a partire dall’epoca romana a periodo sabaudo e risorgimentale. È stata progettata nel 1584 dall’architetto Vitozzi ed è completamente contornata da portici. Al centro è collocato Palazzo Madama, il castello medievale ricavato dalle vecchie porte romane e ristrutturato con l'aggiunta della imponente facciata settecentesca dello Juvarra. Dalla piazza si aprono le grandi direttrici viarie e si affacciano anche alcune fra le principali sedi amministrative: il Palazzo della Giunta Regionale, della Prefettura, delle Segreterie e l' Archivio di Stato. Dal 1998 la piazza dal lato del Palazzo Reale e di Via Garibaldi è diventata totalmente pedonale. Turin - Castle Square The Castle Square is the center of Turin and includes the main monuments of the city. It has been the starting point of urban development from the Roman period to the Savoy kingdom and the Risorgimento. It was designed by the architect Vitozzi in 1584 and it is completely surrounded by arcades. At the center it is located Palazzo Madama, the medieval castle built from the old Roman gates and renovated with the addition of the imposing facade of the eighteenth century. Large end open roads start from the square that is also facing by some of the main administrative buildings: the Palace of the Regional Council, the Prefecture, the Secretaries and the State archives. Since 1998 the square on the side of the Royal Palace and Garibaldi street has become totally pedestrian." id="6707199753" latitude="45.071505" license="1" longitude="7.684732" nbComments="58" rank="13" tags="torino piemonte italia regionepiemonte palazzo dimora piazza neoclassico architettura turin italy piedmont piedmon palace square neoclassic architecture" title="Torino - Piazza Castello" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7150/6707199753_da64e0366f_b.jpg" username="giovanni_novara" views="325" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:58:15" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Stork nests at the Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1795155544" latitude="44.787774" license="3" longitude="7.6688" nbComments="1" rank="14" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo margaria margherie cigogna nido stork nest heritagesite226" title="071027 - Racconigi - 51 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2075/1795155544_0f0b4a1007_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="137" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-07 16:07:02" description="Torino - Cancellata di Palazzo Reale, formella quadrata dorata recante l’effigie della Medusa. The monumental Royal Palace railings, gilt square panel bearing the figure of the Medusa." id="3093704804" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="6" rank="15" tags="palagipelagio torino turin cancellata railings medusa palazzoreale royalepalace" title="" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3268/3093704804_61f1a03fcb_b.jpg" username="bluestardrop - Andrea Mucelli" views="73" />
<photo  date_taken="2002-04-13 19:32:47" description="&lt;b&gt;Turin - Palazzo Madama&lt;/b&gt; The palace, already a towered castle belonging to the Acaja family, was enlarged and restructured mid-way through the 14th century and in 1420 when it was incorporated into the Roman Porta Pretoria. At the end of the 16th century, Ascanio Vittozzi carried out a series of interior modifications but, above all, conceived the monumental façade in a clearly late Renaissance style. The influential innovation, however, is by Filippo Juvarra who in 1718 added two elements: a Classical-Baroque pavilion characterized by a giant order of pilasters and fluted Corinthian columns and the marble balustrade with reliefs overhead, and the monumental staircase inside. The seat of the Museum of Ancient Art, Palazzo Madama, which owes its name to the royals Marie Christine of France and Maria Giovanna of Savoia Nemours who made the palace their home, maintains an important figurative art collection which came from the crown and from private inheritance. Having undergone a long period of restoration, it was reopened as the seat of the International Olympic Committee during the Winter Olympic Games in Turin 2006. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemontefeel.org/en/interesse/elemento-551.html&quot;&gt; Palazzo Madama&lt;/a&gt;" id="330887712" latitude="45.070967" license="3" longitude="7.685633" nbComments="3" rank="16" tags="torino palazzomadama piazzacastello turin italy italia piedmont piemonte oldcity nikon coolpix995 blu blue nightview night" title="Palazzo Madama - Torino - 12.04.2004" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/165/330887712_731e0a8c2f_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="361" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:56:29" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794169851" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="23" rank="17" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo visitpiedmont margaria margherie diamondclassphotographer oldcity italians abigfave blueribbonwinner superbmasterpiece archi arcs möbius geometrictonalvision heritagesite226 finestre winwods mattoni bricks" title="071027 - Racconigi - 47 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2124/1794169851_150af12b61_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="557" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 14:22:19" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1790055986" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="1" rank="18" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 03 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2321/1790055986_ddac21c414_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="91" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-08 20:45:03" description="Il Palazzo Madama è il compendio architettonico della storia di Torino. E' collocato nella centrale piazza Castello ed è stato nominato patrimonio mondiale dell'umanità Unesco. Raccoglie duemila anni di storia: costruito dai romani come porta pretoria verso il lato esposto al fiume Po, l'edificio diventò, prima, parte del sistema fortificato difensivo, castello nel medioevo e quindi nel Quattrocento palazzo vero e proprio, sede del duca di Savoia. Un nuovo impulso artistico avvenne con le &amp;quot;madame reali&amp;quot; Cristina di Francia, moglie di Vittorio Amedeo I reggente per il figlio dal 1637 e Maria Giovanna Battista di Nemours, seconda moglie di Carlo Emanuele II, reggente dal 1675, dalle quali il palazzo prese il nome. La riqualificazione fu progettata dal principale architetto di casa Savoia, Filippo Juvarra: è suo il disegno della grandiosa facciata barocca che domina la piazza. Nel maggio 1848 vi fu convocata la seduta inaugurale del Senato del Regno di Sardegna e successivamente, sino al 1864, fu sede di quello italiano. Turin – Madama Palace Madama Palace is the epitome of the architectural history of Turin. It's situated in the central Piazza Castello and it was named Unesco world heritage site. It collects two thousand years of history as a gate built by the Romans to side exposed to the river Po, then the building became the first part of the defensive system, castle in the Middle Ages and then in the fifteenth century a palazzo , home of the Duke of Savoy. A new artistic impetus occurred with the &amp;quot;Madame Royal&amp;quot; Christine of France, wife of Vittorio Amedeo I, regent for her son in 1637 and Maria Giovanna Battista of Nemours, second wife of Charles Emmanuel II, regent from 1675, from which the building took the name. The redevelopment was designed by leading architect of the House of Savoy, Filippo Juvarra like the design of grand Baroque facade overlooking the piazza. In may 1848 there was convened the inaugural session of the Senate of the Kingdom of Sardinia and later, until 1864, it was the seat of the Italian parliament." id="6175615627" latitude="45.07108" license="1" longitude="7.685301" nbComments="47" rank="19" tags="torino palazzomadama piemonte architettura barocco juvarra unesco palazzo italia turin senate piedmont baroque architecture palace italy" title="Torino - Palazzo Madama, il primo Parlamento dell'Unità d'Italia" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6169/6175615627_695a68dac6_b.jpg" username="giovanni_novara" views="561" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-08 17:50:49" description="Revisiting an &amp;quot;old&amp;quot; shot... It's a pretty lazy period for the DSLR, I am not going around too much... but I am really waiting for the Spring! This photo has been taken in Piazza Castello in Turin. This is one of the golden faces which are set into the railing just in front of the Palazzo Reale, the ancient royal palace in the center of the city." id="4398907731" latitude="45.071808" license="5" longitude="7.685773" nbComments="1" rank="20" tags="torino palazzoreale piazzacastello fullaperture bokeh fujifilmfinepixs5pro nikkoraf50mmf18n golden face railing tonight" title="Z79" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4042/4398907731_4d0609dfd9_b.jpg" username="flatpix" views="118" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-10-23 17:11:59" description="&lt;b&gt;Timeline of motoring history 1679 - 1939&lt;/b&gt; 1679 Practical French scientist Denis Papin invents the pressure-cooker or ‘digester’. 1690 Many before him have experimented with single charges of gunpowder as a means of moving a piston in a bore but, Denis Papin publishes his ideas for harnessing steam as an alternative, to achieve repeated cycles of movement. In doing so, he recognises the potential for a mechanical alternative to animals for mobilising carriages. He goes on to build the first steam engine, which is used to pump water to a canal running between Kassel and Karlshaven in Germany. 1698 English military engineer Thomas Savery uses Papin’s ‘Digester’ as the basis of a crude steam engine for pumping water out of flooded mine-shafts. 1712 Denis Papin, visiting London in the hope of finding patronage, writes to a friend reporting his failure and asking for financial support to pay for his return to Germany. Never heard of again, it is likely that Papin died in London in abject poverty and complete anonymity. Thomas Newcomen, an &amp;quot;ironmonger&amp;quot; and blacksmith of Dartmouth, England, patents the &amp;quot;Atmospheric Steam Engine&amp;quot; and, together with John Calley starts to build and sell engines for pumping water out of mines. 1765 James Watt, while engaged in repairing a Newcomen engine, comes up with several improvements which substantially change its method of operation and increase its efficiency. In so doing he lays a firm foundation for the design of all steam engines yet to come. 1769 In Paris, Nicolas Joseph Cugnot, a military engineer, demonstrates a self propelled steam vehicle - the first on record. The French government requests Cugnot to design and build a larger vehicle, capable of moving large amounts of artillery. 1770 At the French government’s immense cost, Cugnot builds ‘Fardier’ a large three- wheeled artillery carriage and creates history’s first motor accident by knocking down part of a wall. 1787 Oliver Evans of Maryland patents a steam engine for the use in powering carts and carriages. 1801 Richard Trevithick, an early pioneer of the Steam Railway, builds the first successful motor vehicle, and drives it through Camborne, Cornwall. Four days later it is destroyed by fire. 1803 Trevithick builds a second steam powered carriage, which makes several successful runs through the streets of London. Unfortunately it also frightens horses and kindles considerable public hostility. 1805 In 1804 Oliver Evans, builds the world's first amphibious vehicle, ‘Orukter Amphibolas’, a steam powered dredger on wheels, for the Philadelphia Health Service. In July of 1805 it makes a one and a half mile journey from Central-Square to the banks of the Schuykill. It weighs 20 tons and is powered by a 5 HP twin cylinder beam engine driving both the paddle and 2 wheels. With no method of steering on land, the vehicle is much more successful as a boat. 1807 In Switzerland, Francois Isaac de Rivaz builds, and demonstrates the first working internal combustion engine. It is fuelled by a mixture of hydrogen and oxygen and reliant on a foot-operated exhaust valve. Mounted on small trolley, travels just a few metres. 1816 Concerned about the number of people being killed by exploding steam engines Reverend Robert Stirling invents and patents an alternative which is not only safer but also much more efficient. It runs on hot air and rotation is caused by heat differentials as it passes between various parts of the engine. It can use a number of alternative fuels to heat the air and, in spite of its improved safety and superior efficiency, it remains largely ignored for use in vehicles. 1826 Samuel Brown patents and builds his &amp;quot;gas-and-vacuum&amp;quot; engine. It has two cylinders linked by a rocking beam, with a capacity of 8,800cc and an output of just 4hp. The engine powering a carriage successfully drives up Shooters Hill at Blackheath, on the outskirts of London. 1829 Goldsworthy Gurney, having built his ‘London and Bath’ steam coach, sets out on the world’s first long distance coach service, a round trip from London to Bath and back. While the outward journey is marked by many breakdowns the return journey is accomplished in ten hours at an average speed of 8.4 miles per hour. Gurney is later to be the inventor of the theatrical ‘Limelight’. 1830 A regular steam omnibus service is established between Stratford, East London, and Paddington, West London by Walter Hancock. Using ‘Infant’, his second steam carriage. 1831 Sir Charles Dance sets up the world's first scheduled passenger service by automobiles between Gloucester and Cheltenham, using three Gurney steam carriages. It operates for just a few months. 1834 In London, Walter Hancock sets up a chain of garages to service his passenger carrying steam omnibuses en route between their destinations. 1845 Robert William Thomson of Stonehaven, Scotland patents the world’s first vulcanized rubber pneumatic tyre. It is well received on trials in London but does not reach production for fear of its cost. 1859 Belgian J. J. Etienne Lenoir builds the worlds first practicable internal combustion engine running on a mixture of coal gas and air and using a ‘jumping-spark’ ignition system. A company is formed in Paris to develop the engine further. 1860 Le Monde Illustre. Devotes an article to J. J. Etienne Lenoir's first gas- engined carriage. First oil well in USA is drilled in Titusville, Pennsylvania. 1862 French engineer Alphonse Beau de Rochas, patents the four-stroke cycle used in most modern internal combustion engines. 1863 Lenoir demonstrates a second carriage, powered by a 1.5hp ‘liquid hydrocarbon' engine. Several six-mile journeys are successfully completed between Paris and Vincennes. 1864 Alexander II Tsar of Russia buys one of Lenoir’s carriages making it the first export sale of a car in history. 1865 Britain’s government introduces the 'Locomotives on Highways Act' more widely known as the 'Red Flag Act'. This requires that all mechanically powered road vehicles must have three drivers, must be limited to 4 mph on the open road and 2 mph in town and, must be preceded by a man on foot waving a red flag, to warn the public. 1866 In Germany Nikolaus August Otto patents a &amp;quot;free-piston&amp;quot; atmospheric engine. 1868 First steam driven vehicle ‘Cornubia’, exported to India. 1872 Nikolaus Otto and Eugen Langen form N.A. Otto &amp;amp; Cie to produce the ‘free-piston’ engine. 1877 The smooth-running &amp;quot;Otto silent&amp;quot; engine is patented in Germany as employees, Gottlieb Daimler and Wilhelm Maybach prepare it for production. 1879 An initial ‘master patent' for the automobile is filed in the United States by engineer and Patents Lawyer George B. Selden. He extends his application period for many years, by filing many amendments to delay its issue. Meanwhile he struggles to establish his own production capability. 1885 A petroleum (gasoline) powered four stroke engine is used to adapt a horse carriage by Gottlieb Daimler and Wilhelm Maybach. French inventor Ferdinand Forest, builds an opposed-piston engine with low tension magneto ignition and a spray carburettor. 1886 Nicolaus Otto fails to obtain a patent covering his four-stroke engine because of Alphonse Beau de Rochas’ 1862 patent in France. Nevertheless we still refer to the four-stroke principle as the Otto cycle Carl Benz's three wheeler, makes its first successful runs. This is the first petroleum powered car to be designed from scratch, rather than adapted from a horse-drawn carriage. 1888 John Boyd Dunlop a Scottish Veterinary Surgeon living in Belfast, re-invents and re-patents the pneumatic tyre without knowledge of the previous work and patent of fellow Scott Robert William Thomson. In the UK, Brighton inventor Magnus Volk begins production of electric carriages. His electric Railway still runs along the coast today. Karl Benz starts to produce three wheeled, petroleum powered cars; sales are slow. 1889 Daimler sells rights for France to a new V configured twin cylinder engine to Panhard &amp;amp; Levassor 1890 With no thought of manufacturing cars, Panhard &amp;amp; Levassor licence the Peugeot ironmongery business to use the engine in automotive applications. Daimler Motoren Gesellschaft set up by Gottleib Daimler and Wilhelm Maybach in Bad Cannstatt, Germany. 1891 M. Levassor decides to build cars after all, designing and building a rear engined car. Frederick R. Simms acquires Daimler rights in the UK, with the intention of using the engines to power motor launches. Ferdinand Forest produces the world's first four cylinder petrol engine with mechanical valve operation for use in boats and goes on to build the world's first six cylinder engine for the same purpose. The marine application ensures that his contribution to motoring history is ignored. 1892 Levassor introduces a new design of motor car which is to become the template for the vast majority of designs for many years to come. Four wheels, front mounted engine, sliding gear transmission and rear wheel drive. At first this configuration is known as Systeme Panhard. 1893 Brothers Charles Edgar Duryea and James Frank Duryea of Springfield, Massachussetts build their first motor buggy, Charles having an established background in the cycle trade. They are credited with being the first in America to build a practicable automobile. Karl Benz introduces the &amp;quot;Viktoria&amp;quot;, powered by a 3hp petroleum (gasoline) engine with a top speed of 11mph. Forty-five cars are in this year. 1894 After many years of financial difficulty, Karl Benz begins 'mass production' of two models, the Velo and the Viktoria. Henry G. Morris and Pedro Salom of Philadelphia open America's first car factory to build Electrobat electric cars. The Apperson brothers and Elwood Haynes of Kokomo, Indiana collaborate to build an automobile. 1895 Karl Benz sells 135 motor vehicles in the year. Sir David Salomans organises Britain's first exhibition of motor vehicles in the open air in October at Tunbridge Wells, Kent. In November, the first indoor exhibition of cars in Britain takes place, at the Stanley Cycle Show. Selden's master patent is finally granted in the USA, after years of revision. First petrol engine produced by De Dion and Bouton. The Autocar magazine founded by J. J. Henry Sturmey. Frederick, Frank and George Lanchester build the first all-British, four-wheel, petrol driven car featuring many technical innovations. Lanchester will go on to rival Rolls Royce in their reputation for excellence, but fail to achieve long-term commercial success. A Peugeot L'Eclair becomes the first car to run on Michelin pneumatic tyres. 1896 The British Motor Industry is born when Harry J. Lawson launches the Daimler Motor Company in Coventry. British Parliament repeals the Red Flag Act and raises the speed limit to l4mph; Lawson organises the first Run from London to Brighton to commemorate ‘Emancipation Day’. Duryea brings two cars over to Europe for the Emancipation Day event. American pioneers Henry Ford, Charles Brady King, Ransome Eli Olds and Alexander Winton all complete and test their first cars. The first car to be sold with pneumatic tyres as standard is Leon Bollee's Voiturette. Harry J. Lawson forms the Great Horseless Carriage Company (later the Motor Manufacturing Company) to acquire the rights to all important Continental patents, in an effort to gain control of the British motor industry. 1897 Emil Jellinek, financier, international diplomat and racing enthusiast, orders the first four cylinder Daimler. The first commercially available steam cars are manufactured by twin brothers Francis and Freelan Stanley. Alexander Winton a bicycle manufacturer of Cleveland, Ohio incorporates the Winton Motor Carriage Co. The Pope Manufacturing Company of Hartford, Connecticut, at the time the USA’s largest cycle manufacturer, begin their attempt to build cars in large quantities. A British-built Daimler is driven from John O’Groats to Lands End by Henry Sturmey, at the time a journalist with ‘The Autocar’ magazine. The Automobile Club of Great Britain and Ireland is founded by F.R.Simms. Emile Levassor dies. R.E. Olds and a group of Lansing businessmen invest $50,000 to create The Olds Motor Vehicle Company. Leon Serpollet builds his first steam car. 1898 James Ward Packard of Warren, Ohio, becomes one of the earliest buyers of a Winton and, immediately unsatisfied with it’s reliability and performance begins literally, to ‘pick it to pieces’. Rudolf Diesel is granted a patent for an internal combustion engine where extremely high compression of the fuel/air mixture causes self-ignition, rather than a spark. Using a De Dion engine and axle, Louise Renault builds his first car. Panhard-Levassor adopt the steering wheel instead of the tiller. De Dion Bouton introduce the Voiturette. Coventry-Daimler release their first four cylinder model. The first Napier power unit is built. 1899 FIAT, Sunbeam, Wolseley, Albion and Isotta Fraschini begin production. In the USA, the Olds Motor Vehicle Company also begins Production. 1900 Gottlieb Daimler dies at the age of 66. One week later Emil Jellinek secures an exclusivity agreement with Wilhelm Maybach. The cars in which he has been involved and will be marketing, will now be named after his favourite daughter, Mercedes. The Thousand Miles Trial is organised by the Automobile Club of Great Britain and Ireland to demonstrate the reliability and efficiency of the motor vehicle to the British public. Many people will see a car for the first time in their lives. American manufacturers produce a total of 4192 cars, each selling at an average price of $1000.00. 1901 With an exclusive sales agreement and some technical input from Emile Jellinek , Daimler at Bad-Cannstatt introduces the new ‘Mercedes’. Jellinek will both race these cars with great success and sell them to a personally selected clientele. Ettore Bugatti wins the Milan Grand Prix in his Type 2 and exhibits it at the Milan International Motorcar Exhibition. He is approached by de-Dietrich of Niederbronn in the Alsace region and offered a licensing deal to design cars for them. Since he is still legally a minor, his father Carlo signs the contract. The Olsmobile ‘Curved Dash’ model becomes the world’s first mass-produced petroleum (gas) powered car. John Starley dies, without seeing a Rover car go into production. 1902 Packard patents and introduces the &amp;quot;H&amp;quot; gearshift pattern so familiar today. Dr E C Lehwess sets out on the first attempt to drive around the world in a specially adapted Panhard Levassor bus named &amp;quot;Passe Partout&amp;quot; (&amp;quot;Anything Goes&amp;quot;). With no time-limit his intended route runs from London, through Europe to Asia, from where the bus will be shipped to California to cross the USA and return to England by ship across the Atlantic Ocean. He gets as far as Nizhni Novgorod in Eastern Russia, where &amp;quot;Passe Partout&amp;quot; and the attempt, have to be abandoned in deep snow. The Society of Motor Manufacturers and Traders is founded by Frederick R. Simms. 1903 The British Parliament passes the Motor Car Act, raising the speed limit from 12 to 20mph, introducing driving licences and establishing the registration and numbering of cars. 17,000 vehicles are now registered in Britain. Henry Ford finally succeeds in raising $28,000.00 to found the Ford Motor Company and begin production and sales of his Model A runabout. In Detroit, the Cadillac Motor Car Company is founded by precision engineer Henry Martyn Leland. In London, The Vauxhall Iron Works builds its first car. Marcel Renault is one of 10 drivers killed in that year’s Paris-Madrid race. Administration of George B. Selden’s ‘master patent for the automobile’ is taken over by the newly formed Association of Licensed Automobile Manufacturers, with the intention of pursuing numerous manufacturers for infringement, to gain compensation and future royalties. The Society of Motor Manufacturers and Traders hosts its first motor show at the Crystal Palace, in South London. The first completely new Benz, the front engined ‘Parsifal 12/18’, is designed by Marius Barbarou and introduced to compete with the very successful Mercedes Simplex. A six cylinder, four wheel drive racing car is introduced by Dutch manufacturer Spyker. The first six cylinder production car is introduced by Napier. James H. Whiting, co-founder of the Flint Wagon Works, persuades his partners to buy the Buick Motor Car Company, at that time a very small car manufacturer. Whiting becomes President and David Buick is General Manager. Mary Anderson is granted a patent for a handle-operated windshield wiper, originally intended to help the streetcar drivers of New York. 1904 On January 1st, The Motor Car Act becomes law in Great Britain. Having built his first motor car Henry Royce meets Charles Stewart Rolls, already successful in the sales of quality cars in London and Royce agrees to manufacture a range of cars exclusively for sale by CS Rolls &amp;amp; Co. They are to be known by the name Rolls-Royce. The Sturtevant brothers of Boston, Massachusetts invent the first automatic gearbox. With two forward speeds it is dependent on rotation by the engine, of centrifugal weights which, all too often disintegrate. The unit may not be a complete success but at least it points the way for future developments. Ford begins to export cars to Britain. Having invented the modern bicycle 18 years earlier, Rover embarks on the manufacture of cars. De Launay Belleville is founded in Saint Denis sur Seine, central France, with Marius Barbarou as engineer. William Crapo Durant, Co-owner of Durant-Dort Carriage Company, the USA’s largest carriage makers, is approached by James Whiting to promote his Buick automobiles. Durant becomes Buick's General Manager. Having refused to pay royalties to the Association of Licensed Automotive Manufacturers for infringement of George B Selden’s master patent, Henry Ford is taken to court. Key to Ford’s defence is that Selden has never even built a car and the validity of the patent is therefore questionable. The judge orders Selden to build a car in accordance with his patent. 1905 Herbert Austin, resigns as general manager of Wolseley to set up his own company at Longbridge, Birmingham. The American the market for cars is enlarged by the introduction of installment finance plans. The Automobile Association is set up to represent the interests of British motorists finding themselves easy targets for Police officers keen to gain promotion based on the numbers of speeding motorists caught and convicted! 1906 The Royal Automobile Club (RAC) introduce a horsepower formula, largely based on the Cylinder bore of an engine. The successful commercial collaboration between Henry Royce and C S Rolls results in the formation of the Rolls-Royce company and the launch of the 40/50hp six-cylinder ‘Silver Ghost’, soon to be hailed as 'the best car in the world'. Ford introduces the Model N at the New York Auto Show. Selling initially at $500, The American car industry produces 33,500 cars. Former Fiat test-driver Vincenzo Lancia sets up his own company in Turin with his friend and colleague Claudio Fogolin. Britain exports a total of two cars per month to France while importing a total of 400 cars per month from France. Otto Zachow and William Besserdich of Clintonville, Wisconsin, built the first successful 4-wheel-drive car. 1907 A year after its announcement, the price of Ford’s Model N had already risen to $600. King Edward VII awards the Automobile Club the Royal accolade. Willys-Overland is formed following the purchase of the Overland Company of Indianapilolis by John Willys. Over 60,000 Cars are now registered in Britain. A Rolls-Royce ‘Silver Ghost’ completes a 15000 miles test under supervision of the RAC, with just one enforced stop. Also completing a 15,000 mile test is a 45hp Hotchkiss, wearing out 46 tyres in the process. Otto Zachow and William Besserdich begin a company called the Four Wheel Drive Auto Co. 1908 Ford build the first Model T. This year’s production totals 8000. Based on a previous, failed attempt to bring together America’s top four car manufacturers William Crapo Durant incorporates General Motors of New Jersey (GM) with a capital of $2,000. Within 12 days the company has raised $12,000,000 cash, enough to buy Buick and Oldsmobile in quick succession. In London The Royal Automobile Club awards Cadillac the Dewar Trophy following the dismantling, mixing and re-assembly of components from three ‘Model K’ runabouts. 1909 The General Motors Company acquires Cadillac and Oakland. William Durant fails to raise the $9.5 million needed to buy Ford. Louis Chevrolet drives a Buick to victory in the fifth &amp;quot;Indy car&amp;quot; race at Crown Point, Indianapolis. Fernand Renault is dies after a long illness. Now alone at the helm, Louis Renault changes the company’s name to Les Automobiles Renault. While still engaged by de Deutz, Ettore Bugatti and good friend Felix Kortz build the ‘Type 10’ in the cellar of his house, probably as an expression of his imminent intention to establish his own production. Joseph Sankey &amp;amp; Sons of Bilston, near Woverhampton, specialists in steel pressings, commence production of stamped body panels for Arrol-Johnston cars. Joseph Sankey &amp;amp; Sons develop the first detachable pressed-steel artillery wheel, a considerable improvement over the wooden carriage wheels which most vehicles had used previously. Louis Coatalen is appointed as chief engineer at Sunbeam and starts to design cars capable of achieving records at Brooklands race track in Surrey. H.F.S. Morgan builds his first car, a three-wheeler with a twin cylinder 8hp engine, seating for one, tiller steering and patented ‘sliding pillar’ independent front suspension. Charles Franklin Kettering, having already invented, designed and developed the electric cash register, bank accounting machines and a superior ignition system for cars while working for NCR, sets up Dayton Engineering Laboratories Company (Delco). 8000 ignition systems are supplied to Cadillac in his first year of production. 1910 De Dion-Bouton introduces the first &amp;quot;mass-produced&amp;quot; V8 engine in the world. Automobile production in the Untied States reaches 181,000. The proposal to place a tax on petrol is rejected by the British Parliament. Charles Stewart Rolls is killed at the age of 33, when his biplane crashes during a flying competition in Bournemouth. The RAC devises the horsepower ratings by which cars in Britain are taxed. Wireless radio is installed in a car with considerable effect although the equipment is very bulky. Having spent the past 9 years designing cars for deDeutz and Mathis-Hermès, Ettore Bugatti sets up his own factory at Molsheim in the Alsace region (German territory until 1919, French thereafter) and starts production of his ‘Type 11’. Crossley, Arrol Johnston, Argyll and Isotta Fraschini offer four wheel braking. 1911 Burley Swiss racing driver and talented engineer Louis Chevrolet drives a Buick for Willam Durant in the first Indianapolis 500. A broken camshaft forces early retirement. Louis’s brothers, Arthur and Gaston, are also keen racing drivers. Having been ousted from General Motors William Durrant hires Louis Chevrolet as a consultant to develop a high quality car and forms the Chevrolet Motor Company. Ford opens its first factory outside the USA at Trafford Park, Manchester, UK. With an annual output of 3000 Model Ts, Ford soon becomes Britain's biggest car maker. Cadillac 20/30hp model comes with ignition, electric lighting and electric self-starting developed by Charles F. Kettering’s Dayton Engineering Laboratories Company (Delco). The Selden Patent Case finally ends in victory for Henry Ford when the car built to Selden’s patent is a technical failure. The patent is found to be 'valid but not infringed' releasing Americas car manufacturers to sell their products without further interference from Selden. 1912 Prominent figure S. F. Edge resigns from the Napier company following a dispute. He agrees to stay out of the motor industry for 7 years in exchange for a £160,000.00 pay-off. Instead he turns to pig farming, cattle breeding and film production, all with considerable success. Delco electric self-starters and electric lighting come as standard on all Cadillac models. The first Chevrolet, the big, powerful and very expensive Classic Six, reaches production but its price places it well out of reach of the mass market which Durant needs to attract to build his new business. Sunbeam causes a sensation by simultaneously entering two team of 3 litre cars in French races running at the same time. They come in 1st, 2nd and 3rd in Coupe de l'Auto for touring cars at Dieppe and 3rd, 4th, and 5th in the French Grand Prix against cars with engines of vastly greater cubic capacity. As a result, the virtually identical touring models sell very well. Brothers W O and H M Bentley buy the London agency for French DFP cars from their employers and call their new business Bentley and Bentley. 1913 Packard achieves a significant step in the development of the differential by introducing the spiral-bevel ring and pinion set. This cuts noise levels dramatically. Henry Ford trials moving conveyor belt techniques for magneto production. Ford’s sales rise to 182,809 vehicles. The Royal Automobile Club awards the Dewar Trophy to Cadillac for a second time, in recognition of the introduction of the electric self-starter and electric lighting. William Morris introduces his I0hp Morris Oxford light car. Congress is lobbied by the Lincoln Highway Association who want a transcontinental highway to be constructed across America. Mechanical direction indicators begin to appear on some models. Fiat builds 3251cars. Renault build 9338 cars. Louis Chevrolet falls out with William Durant, wanting his name to be associated with prestigious cars and resigns. By selling his stock Chevrolet has thrown away the opportunity to become a multi millionaire. Durant continues to grow Chevrolet sales by moving the range downmarket. W O Bentley develops the aluminium-alloy piston for use in automotive engines and achieves a class record at Brooklands in an alloy-pistoned DFP. 1914 De Dion-Bouton’s V8 engine is now available in 3.5 litre, 4.6 litre and 7.8 litre capacities. Ford introduces conveyor assembly line techniques to chassis production reducing unit production times from 12½ to 1½ hours. Ford raises the daily pay of its production workers to an industry record of $5. Ettore Bugatti designs and manufactures the world’s first series-produced 16-valve 4 cylinder engine. British buyers can now choose between 200 makes of car. The German Army’s advance on Paris is repulsed by troops ferried to the front line in Renault taxis. W O Bentley is commissioned into the navy to develop aero-engines for the Royal Naval Air Service. The BR1 and BR2 radial engines, built at the Humber factory, prove extremely effective and Bentley passes his knowledge of alloy piston technology on to Ernest Hives who is also developing aero-engines at Rolls-Royce. Lionel Martin and Robert Bamford set up a small sports-car manufacturing business in West London. Bamford’s early departure leaves Martin with the need for a new name. Success achieved at the Aston-Clinton Hill Climb course in the prototype car provides the ideal name. Aston-Martin is born! 1915 British Chancellor of the Exchequer Reginald McKenna introduces a ‘temporary’ 33.33 % levy on luxury imports to contribute to the cost of the war. Commercial vehicles are excluded, as they are needed for the war effort. This levy becomes known as the &amp;quot;McKenna Duties&amp;quot;. Catillac introduces the first successful V8 engine in the United States. Inspired by Sunbeam aero-engine designs, Packard introduce the Vl2 Twin Six. Banker Nicola Romeo takes over Anonima Lombardo Fabbrica Automobili of Milan to create Alfa Romeo. Ford give a $50.00 refund to every Model T customer in recognition of annual sales exceeding their target. The British Admiralty Landships Committee, charged with development of an armoured fighting vehicle capable of crossing trenches and barbed wire to attack an enemy, appoint a Lincoln agricultural machinery manufacturers William Foster &amp;amp; Co. Ltd, to design and develop it. For the sake of secrecy the factory workers are told to refer to the project as ‘a water carrier for Mesopotamia’. Their nick-name for the project is still with us today - ‘The tank’. 1916 Windscreen wipers powered by vacuum from the engine’s inlet manifold begin to replace the manual version originally patented by Mary Anderson in 1903. Because inlet manifold vacuum varies with engine speed so does wiper speed. C F Kettering’s Delco is sold to United Motors Corporation for $9,000,000.00. 1917 Herbert Austin receives a knighthood. Having founded Cadillac and stayed at the helm since the 1909 sale to General Motors, Henry Martyn Leland resigns and leaves with his son Wilfred C Leland, to found the Lincoln Motor Company and build Liberty aero-engines for use in WW1 fighter planes. Engineer William Rootes is demobilised from the British Armed to set up a new plant at Maidstone, Kent to repair aeroplane engines instead of scrapping them. The war ends before the plant is fully operational. 1918 Emil Jellinek dies. Car registrations in America exceed five million for the first time. The Thomas B Jeffery Company is bought by Charles Nash and renamed Nash Motors. United Motors Corporation is acquired by General Motors. As a result, C F Kettering is invited to organise direct General Motors Research Corporation and insists that its headquarters are established in Dayton. 1919 Andre Citroen, having decided the future lies in simple reliable cars for the mass market, begins production of his Model A. Henry Ford pays out $l00 million to buy-out all the other stockholders in the Ford Motor Company. S. F. Edge returns to the British motor industry by taking over AC cars. The first straight eight production engine is introduced by Isotta Fraschini. Walter P. Chrysler resigns his position as vice president of General Motors. New aero influenced post war models introduced by Hispano Suiza, Guy, Enfield Allday. WO Bentley, awarded an £8,000 gratuity for his wartime work on the design of aero-engines, uses it to establish Bentley Motors Ltd and develop his first sports-car. Charles F Kettering’s Dayton Metal Products Co. is absorbed into General Motors, forming the core of GM's new research division. William and Reginal Rootes re-establish the family car sales business, Rootes Ltd. in Maidstone Kent. Enzo Ferrari finishes ninth at the Targa Florio bringing him to the notice of Alfa Romeo. 1920 Half of all the motor vehicles in the world are Model T Fords. The American car industry is hit hard by a sudden post-war sales slump - Most companies struggle, many go out of business and some are absorbed into the larger corporate conglomerates. The merger of Sunbeam and Talbot-Darracq creates the STD group. The new organisation will fail to rationalise development programmes and share components, missing out on financial opportunities, building cars which compete with each other for market share. William Durant is ousted from his position at the head of General Motors for a second and final time, when DuPont/Morgan banking interests gain a controlling interest. Alfred P. Sloan is placed in charge of the group's affairs. Duesenberg introduce the first production car with a straight eight engine and four-wheel hydraulic brakes. Work starts on Britain's first bypass roads, The Great West Road from Chiswick, West London and The Purley Way near Croydon. 350 French companies manufacture cars. Louis Chevrolet’s Monroe racer wins the Indianapolis 500 with his brother Gaston at the wheel. Gaston Chevrolet is killed in a racing accident on a boardwalk raceway in Beverly Hills, California. C F Kettering, inventor and outstanding engineer and head of General Motors Research Corporation becomes a vice-president and GM board member. Driving a modified Alfa Romeo production car in the Targa Florio, Enzo Ferrari finishes in second place. 1921 Ferodo introduces a dry-plate clutch using asbestos friction materials that do not burn out every few hundred miles. The Motor Car Act taxes cars in Britain at £I per RAC horsepower. Because of the RAC formula this favours small-bore, long stroke engines used by British manufacturers. Sales of cheaper American imports which tend to use large-bore, short stroke engines are crippled. A Morris Cowley, rated at 11.9hp costs just £12 to tax, whereas a Model T is rated at 22.5hp and costs £23 per year. One variation is that pre 1914 cars pay only half the horsepower. One oddity is a complete exemption for cars used solely for taking servants to church or voters to the polling station! Bentley Motors Ltd start production of the new Bentley 3 litre sports car at a factory in Cricklewood, London and the three racing Bentleys entered in the Tourist Trophy Race win the team prize. Lincoln introduce theirV8. To counteract a drop in sales Morris cuts prices by up to £I00. The ploy works effectively, with sales increasing from 1932 cars in 1920 to 3077 cars this year. William Durant establishes Durant Motors, having raised $7 million in loans. Tommy Milton drives a straight-eight Frontenac, designed and built by Louis Chevrolet, to victory at Indianapolis. Two different Louis Chevrolet-developed machines have now won at Indianapolis in consecutive years. 1922 Ford buys financially troubled Lincoln. In Britain Herbert Austin introduces the Seven. Clyno begin car production in Wolverhampton. Marconi begin experiments with wireless receivers in Daimler cars. Ford produce over one million Model Ts. Inspired by the strength of a ship’s hull in a storm Vincenzo Lancia devises the first car to feature a sheet metal unitary body structure. The Lancia Lambda also featured a V4 engine with twin overhead camshafts, independent front suspension and brakes on all four wheels. Trico (USA) introduce electric windscreen wipers as a more speed-consistent alternative to vacuum-driven wipers. Leslie Hounsfield's Trojan Ltd of Croydon Licence production of his low-cost 2 stroke, four cylinder car to Leyland Motors. Charles F. Kettering, (previously responsible for the electric starter) and his assistant T. H. Midgley develop tetraethyl leaded petrol to improve the quality of fuels available in the USA. This alone encourages the development of more powerful and efficient high-compression engines. 21 year old Motor Cycle enthusiast William Lyons meets motorcycle sidecar maker William Walmsley in Blackpool, England. Together they set up the Swallow Sidecar Company. 1923 De Dion-Bouton cease production of their V8 engine range. Cecil Kimber builds his first MG, a Morris Cowley with flattened springs, a sports body and a rebuilt engine. Coventry bicycle manufacturer Triumph, builds their first car, the 10/20hp. Over 2,000,000 Model Ts leave Ford’s production lines. Sunbeams came 1st, 2nd and 4th in the French Grand Prix. While racing at the Circuit of Sivocci at Ravenna Enzo Ferrari is approached by Count Enrico and Countess Paolina Baracca, parents of deceased national hero Francesco Baracca. They give Ferrari Francesco’s squadron badge, a prancing horse on a yellow shield. 1924 Former General Motors Vice President, Walter P Chrysler, begins production of his own cars. Car production times are cut dramatically when DuPont develop quick-drying enamels. Napier give up the production of cars and concentrate on aero-engines. The &amp;quot;McKenna Duties&amp;quot; on luxury imports are removed. Sunbeam win the Spanish Grand Prix. No other British car will win a Grand Prix in the first half of the 20th century. Twin cam OHV engines become standard on the 3 litre Super Sports models. Malcolm Campbell achieves an official Land Speed Record d 146mph in an 18 litre 12 cyl Sunbeam developing 350hp. A Bentley Sport, driven by Sammy Davis and John Benjafield, wins the Le Mans 24 Hours endurance race for the first time. 1925 The &amp;quot;McKenna Duties&amp;quot; on luxury imports are reinstated and extended to include commercial vehicles. Morris production of ‘Bullnose’ Oxfords and Cowleys hits 54,131. Vauxhall Motors at Luton becomes a part of General Motors. The 250,000th Ford Model T rolls out of Ford’s British factory and begins a celebratory tour. Rolls Royce introduce the Phantom 1, their first new model since the introduction of the 1906 Silver Ghost. The Triumph 13/30 becomes Britain’s first family car with hydraulic braking on all four wheels. Malcolm Campbell raises the official Land Speed Record to 150mph, again in a Sunbeam car. Sunbeam enters their new 3 litre Super Sports car for the Grand Prix d'Endurance (24 hours) at Le Mans. It is the only British car to finish, winning 2nd place overall and coming first in the 3 litre class. The parent company (The STD Group) takes out a large loan. General Motors Research Corporation and its boss C F Kettering, move to Detroit. 1926 Cadillac introduce shatter-resistant glass. Long retired from racing, Louis Chevrolet drives the official pace car for his last laps of Indianapolis Speedway. As a driver he has achieved 10 career Indy car wins and won over 27 major events, making him the most successful of the three racing Chevrolet brothers. Following a trip to America William Morris is convinced that the future of the car revolves around all-steel construction and works with Edward G Budd to set up the Pressed Steel Company. In Germany, Daimler Benz AG is formed by the long-planned (since 1911) merger between Benz and Daimler companies. A 7136cc V12 sleeve valve engine is the main feature of the Coventry Daimler Company’s new Double Six model. In London, the General Strike and resultant marches bring traffic to a halt. London's motorists see electric traffic lights for the first time. Production of 300 cars a week makes Clyno of Wolverhampton Britain’s third largest car manufacturer. Packard further refines the differential by introducing hypoid gears, virtually eliminating rear axle whine. Major Henry Segrave sets a new Land Speed Record of 152mph in a 4 litre 12 cyl Sunbeam. The Swallow Sidecar Company starts to build special bodies for the Austin Seven and changes its name to the Swallow Sidecar and Coachbuilding Company. Beyond the Austin seven it also offers coach-built bodies on chassis by Morris, Fiat, Standard, Swift and others. William and Reginald Rootes move their business from Kent to offices and showrooms at Devonshire House, Picadilly, in the heart of London's West End. Within a matter of months they have built a network of branches across the UK, in the process, becoming Europe’s largest motor distributing company. 1927 Ford’s Model T comes to the end of the road after 19 years and fifteen million vehicles. The first British all-steel body is produced by the Pressed Steel Company for the Morris Isis Six, a medium sized saloon. William Morris acquires the failed Wolseley company. Chevrolet becomes the top selling manufacturer in America as Ford reorganizes its production facilities for the Model A. Chromium plating is pioneered by Studebaker and Oldsmobile. Stanley brings production of its steam cars to an end. Major Henry Segrave, sets a new World Land Speed Record of over 200mph driving a twin-engined 1000 hp Sunbeam. 1928 By now Britain’s largest car distributors, William and Reginald Rootes begin to acquire manufacturers, starting with Humber, Hillman and Commer. Dodge is acquired by Chrysler for $I75,000,000. In the face of fierce price competition from William Moris, Clyno introduce a £I00 8hp model and ‘hits the rocks’. Cadillac introduces the synchromesh gearbox. Britain's first front wheel drive production car is introduced by Alvis. A Bentley wins the Le Mans 24 Hours driven by Woolf Barnato and Bernard Rubin. As a result of slumping sales many UK companies are become vulnerable The Rootes brothers acquire a substantial interest in The Hillman Car Company and then take over Humber Ltd and it’s commercial vehicle brand, Commer. 1929 Karl Benz dies, aged 85. David Dunbar Buick dies. US car production reaches 5,337,087, a record that will stand until the I950s. 26.5 million cars are now registered in the USA. Clyno ceases trading and its assets liquidated. Armstrong Siddeley offer a Wilson pre-selector gearbox as an option. Sir Dennistoun Burney, the man behind the development of R100 airship, applies his aerodynamic expertise to car design and starts to make his Burney ‘Streamlines’ at his factory in Maidenhead. Each car features teardrop styling, space-frame construction, rear engine, all-round independent suspension and hydraulic brakes. Bentley win the Le Mans 24 Hours for the second year in succession with a Speed Six driven by Woolf Barnato and Henry Birkin. While continuing to work for Alfa Romeo, Enzo Ferrari forms the Scuderia Ferrari, a club/team for gentlemen-racers with the aim of organizing racing for members. 1930 Daimler fit fluid flywheels in conjunction with pre-selector gearboxes to produce semi automatic transmission. Cadillac introduces a 7.4 litre VI6. Economic depression causes a fall in car sales. Henry Royce receives a knighthood. In the bar of the Old Ship Hotel in Brighton following the annual ‘London to Brighton Run’, three participants decide to form the Veteran Car Club to help its members preserve the veteran and Edwardian cars which form a record motoring’s early history. The 20mph speed limit, which has been ignored by motorists and police alike for many years, is abolished by the British Parliament. In Britain, third party insurance becomes compulsory. Larger Morris cars come with hydraulic brakes. Walter Wilson introduces the Wilson Preselector gearbox based on a planetary manual transmission system like that used in the Ford Model T. Bentley wins the Le Mans 24 Hours for the fourth year in succession with a Speed Six driven by Woolf Barnato and Glen Kidston. 1931 The Vauxhall Cadet 2 litre six, is the first car in Europe to feature a synchromesh gearbox. Bentley Motors goes into liquidation. Napier are interested in buying, but are outbid by Rolls Royce who form Bentley Motors (1931) Limited. Daimler acquire Lanchester Britain’s oldest motor manufacturer. The Swallow Sidecar and Coachbuilding Company introduces its first cars, the SS1 and SS2. The larger SS1 is based on a modified Standard chassis and Standard six-cylinder engine. The smaller SS2 has a four-cylinder engine. As the first fruit of the Rootes Group acquisition, Hillman introduces the Wizard with a choice of either 2.1 or 2.8 litre engines. It is not a great sales success. 1932 After years of struggling to survive De Dion-Bouton goes out of business. Oldsmobile and Packard models feature automatic chokes. Ford of Britain moves it’s plant and machinery from Trafford Park, Manchester to its new factory at Dagenham on the Eastern outskirts of London over one weekend without losing any production. Ford design their first car for the European market, the 8hp model Y, in Dearborn. Ford facelift the Model A and offer it with a mass-produced V8 engine. Sales in the first year exceed 300,000. Hillman introduces the Minx, small family saloon, which proves to be extremely popular. 1933 William Lyons Changes the name of the Swallow Sidecar and Coachbuilding Company to SS Cars Limited, taking on the role of managing director. Ford looses its grip on the American market, dropping to third place behind General Motors and the Chrysler Corporation. 1934 REO introduce the Reo Self-Shifter, actually two transmissions connected in series. The first shifts automatically due to the engagement of a multi-disc centrifugal clutch mechanism. The second transmission is shifted manually to engage a lower gear. Under both the Chrysler and DeSoto brands Chrysler introduces the revolutionary ‘Airflow’ ‘streamline’ family saloons with aerodynamic unitary sheet-steel body construction and an automatic overdrive. In Britain a 30mph limit is imposed in built-up areas by Transport Minister Leslie Hore Belisha, pedestrian (Zebra) crossings are introduced, illuminated by a flashing orange (Belisha) beacon and new drivers are required to pass a test. Morris Motors’ first conveyor assembly line is installed at Cowley and Sir William Morris becomes Baron Nuffield. General Motors put the successful racecar designer and financial failure, Louis Chevrolet on their payroll in recognition of their use of his name. Ferdinand Porshe approaches the German Reich government with proposals for a car for the German masses – a Volkswagen. Massive government investment follows. Construction of the German Autobahn system commences, conceived by Adolph Hitler as a productive way of harnessing the unemployed masses. British cars are now available with Metallic finishes. Andre Citroen’s ambition gets the better of him as development of the ‘traction avant’ becomes so expensive that the company is virtually bankrupted. Michelin step in to prop up the business and Citroen looses control. At SS Cars Limited, William Lyons boosts his company’s technical capabilities with the arrival of renowned engine specialist Harry Weslake. Soon after his arrival overhead valve cylinder heads become available. 1935 The depression of the 1930s means STD Motors are unable to sustain repayments of the large loan taken out in 1925 and are forced into receivership. The Rootes brothers outbid the smaller SS Cars Limited and the proud Sunbeam and Talbot names are destined to become up-market badge-engineered versions of Hillmans. Ford of Britain introduces a cut price version of the 8hp Model Y saloon to sell at £I00.00. There are now 35 million motor vehicles on the world’s roads according to an international census. Triumph offer a screen wash system. William Heynes joins SS Cars Ltd as chief engineer and the SS Jaguar is announced. 1936 Morgan, specialists in economical three-wheelers since 1909 introduce their first four wheeler, thanks to changes in tax and market readiness for ‘a fourth wheel’. Fiat introduce the budget-priced 500A, featuring an aerodynamic shape, a ‘570cc engine and a full length sunroof. Its appearance earns it the nick-name ‘Topolino’ (Mickey Mouse) while a 55mph top speed and 55mpg economy makes it very popular, particularly in its home country. Ferdinand Porsche begins development and construction of prototype ‘Volkswagens’ to demonstrate his concept to Adolf Hitler. The declared intention is that they will sell for £50.00 on a special finance plan. At SS Cars Limited, William Lyons buys out William Walmsley and anounces the SS 100 and SS Jaguar models. There are still 45 British car manufacturers. Fifty-four percent of families in the United States now own a car. 1937 The first London Motor Exhibition is held at Earls Court, rather than Olympia, where it has been since 1905. Buick and Oldsmobile introduce the Automatic Safety Transmission, using a conventional clutch for engaging forward or reverse and shifting automatically once underway. 800 miles of autobahn have been built in Germany at a cost of £56,000 a mile. Chrysler perfects the fluid coupling, a major advance towards the fully automatic gearbox, but does nothing with it for the moment. 1938 The Volkswagen goes into production in Nazi Germany. The British government raises the petrol tax from 8d to 9d per gallon and horsepower tax to £1.25d per hp. The first small British saloon to feature independent front suspension is the Standard Flying Eight. Riley is taken over by The Nuffield Group. Morris launches the Series E 8hp Saloon at £128, the cheapest car in Britain. As another War begins to look inevitable British car manufacturers are requested to set up Shadow Factories next to small-scale specialists who’s products, in much larger quantities, would be crucial to any war effort. GM offer the Hydra-Matic hydraulically operated gearbox. SS Cars Ltd, like many other British manufacturers turns production over to the war effort. 1939 Britain, France, Australia and New Zealand declare war on Germany on September 3rd. The British Government introduces petrol rationing. Petrol is exchanged for coupons allowing each motorist about 200 miles of motoring per month. There are now two million cars on Britain's roads. The customized Lincoln Continental and the lower priced Mercury are introduced by Ford. Triumph has to cease trading and is put into receivership. &lt;b&gt;See Timeline 1940 - 2008&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5107286715/&quot;&gt;www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/5107286715/&lt;/a&gt;" id="5107883856" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="5" rank="21" tags="motoringhistory transport car motorcar auto automobile inventionofthemotorcar denispapin mechanical firststeamengine thomassavery thomasnewcomen lincolncontinental fordmercury sscars gm shadowfactories britishcarmanufacturers morriscars standardflyingeight volkswagen chrysler buick oldsmobile williamlyons williamwalmsley jaguarcar porsche morgancars williamheynes triumphcars sunbeam talbot hillman harryweslake andrecitroen michelin louischevrolet morrismotors cowley sirwilliammorris lesliehorebelisha desoto reo swallowsidecar hillmanminx modela modelt dearborn traffordpark dagenham packard dedionbouton rootesgroup hillmanwizard daimler lanchester bentleymotors rollsroyce vauxhallcadet walterwilson cadillac alfaromeo ferrari scuderiaferrari sirdennistounburney armstrongsiddeley clyno daviddunbarbuick commer alvis dodge humberhawk majorhenrysegrave stanleysteamcars" title="Oh the joys of the open road!" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1126/5107883856_a56dba8de9_b.jpg" username="brizzle born and bred" views="11343" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-12-21 16:57:32" description="La reggia di Venaria è la maggiore residenza sabauda in Piemonte. Fu progettata e costruita in pochi anni fra il 1658 e il 1679 su progetto degli architetti Amedeo di Castellamonte e Michelangelo Garove su commissione del duca Carlo Emanuele II che intendeva farne la base per le battute di caccia nella brughiera collinare torinese. Lo stesso nome in lingua latina della reggia, “Venatio Regia”, viene fatto derivare dall'arte venatoria. L'insieme dei corpi di fabbrica che costituiscono il complesso di enorme l'estensione (80.000 mq. di piano calpestabile) include il parco ed il borgo storico omonimo costruiti in modo da formare una sorta di collare che rievoca direttamente la Santissima Annunziata, simbolo della casa sabauda. E' paragonabile per quanto riguarda la struttura architettonica alla reggia francese di Versailles che fu in realtà costruita tenendo a confronto il progetto della dimora reale torinese. L'enorme complesso includeva originariamente il parco ed il borgo storico di Venaria. Successivamente al borgo si unirono molte case dei della casa regnante e palazzi della corte fino a far diventare Venaria Reale un comune autonomo della provincia di Torino Nel 1997 le Residenze Sabaude del Piemonte sono state inserite nella lista dei Patrimoni dell'Umanità UNESCO The palace of Venaria is the largest Savoy residence in Piedmont. It was designed and built in a few years between 1658 and 1679 by the architects Amedeo Castellamonte and Michelangelo Garove and commissioned by Duke Carlo Emanuele II who wanted to make it the basis for the hunt on the moor hills of Turin. The name in latin of the palace, &amp;quot;Venatio Regia&amp;quot; is inferred from the art of hunting. The set of buildings that make up the complex of great extension (80,000 square meters calpestabile plan) includes the park and the historic village of the same name built in order to form a sort of collar that directly recalls the Santissima Annunziata, a symbol of house of Savoy. It is comparable to the architectural structure of the French palace of Versailles which was built to compare the project of royal residence in Turin. The huge complex originally included the park and the historic village of Venaria. Then the village joined many houses and palaces of the royal house of the court to make Venaria a separate municipality in the province of Turin In 1997 the Savoy Residences of Piedmont were included in the list of UNESCO World Heritage Sites." id="5324338497" latitude="45.134162" license="1" longitude="7.623825" nbComments="17" rank="22" tags="venariareale reggia reggiasabauda piemonte provinciaditorino italia savoia residenzasabauda unesco patrimoniodellumanità ohhh" title="Venaria Reale (Torino) - Reggia sabauda" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5284/5324338497_1f0ea1798c_b.jpg" username="giovanni_novara" views="381" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-07 10:11:13" description="Hua Lamphong (Thai: หัวลำโพง) is the main railway station in Bangkok. The building opened on 25 June 1916, after six years' construction. During World War II the Allies tried to bomb the station but hit a nearby hotel instead. The station was built in an Italian Renaissance style, with decorated wooden roofs and stained glass windows. The architecture is attributed to Turin-born Mario Tamagno, who, with countryman Annibale Rigotti (1870–1968), made a mark on early 20th century public building in Bangkok. The pair also designed Bang Khun Prom Palace (1906), Ananda Samakhom Throne Hall in The Royal Plaza (1907-15) and Suan Kularb Residential Hall and Throne Hall in Dusit Garden, among other buildings. There are 14 platforms, 26 ticket booths and two electric display boards. Hualamphong serves over 130 trains and approximately 60,000 passengers each day. The station is a terminus of the Eastern &amp;amp; Orient Express. Since 2004 the station has been connected to the MRT subway system in Bangkok. Source: Wikipedia.com" id="5473615645" latitude="13.75333" license="6" longitude="100.504821" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="070707 thaiflickrmeetup thailand unicef hualamphongtrainstationbangkok fiveflickrfavs thaiflickrmeet" title="Hua Lamphong Train Station Bangkok on 07-07-07" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5251/5473615645_a67c5d888d_b.jpg" username="Y-Not ?" views="83" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-06 11:01:40" description="Royal Palace of Turin or Palazzo Reale, is a palace in Turin, northern Italy. It was the royal palace of the House of Savoy. It was modernised greatly by the French born Madama Reale Christine Marie of France (1606–1663) in the 17th century." id="8062076802" latitude="45.077369" license="4" longitude="7.684121" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="italy2012 royalpalaceofturin italy turin torino houseofsavoy" title="Royal Palace of Turin" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8314/8062076802_9a7f8047a3_b.jpg" username="Peter Broster" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-06 11:02:50" description="Royal Palace of Turin or Palazzo Reale, is a palace in Turin, northern Italy. It was the royal palace of the House of Savoy. It was modernised greatly by the French born Madama Reale Christine Marie of France (1606–1663) in the 17th century." id="8062073121" latitude="45.075399" license="4" longitude="7.683563" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="italy2012 royalpalaceofturin italy turin torino houseofsavoy" title="Royal Palace of Turin" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8454/8062073121_615a8e3d60_b.jpg" username="Peter Broster" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-11-03 18:53:47" description="&lt;b&gt;Palazzo Reale - Royal Palace of Turin&lt;/b&gt; Begun in 1646, for Cristina of France, was the residence of the Dukes of Savoy, the Kings of Sardinia and the first King of Italy until 1865. Both the 1th and 2nd &amp;quot;piano nobile&amp;quot; can be visited. The apartment of the King and the apartment of Madama Felicita are visitable too. The building is completed by the Royal Garden, built at the end of the 17th century and designed by André Le Nôtre, the most important European garden designer in the 17th century. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/residenze_sabaude/pal_reale.shtml&quot;&gt;Palazzo Reale&lt;/a&gt;" id="1952331677" latitude="45.072641" license="3" longitude="7.686084" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont torino turin d80 nikon photowalk notte night" title="Palazzo Reale - Royal Palace of Turin - 03.11.07" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2180/1952331677_2021e21202_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="273" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-28 17:29:51" description="&lt;b&gt;Palazzo Reale - Royal Palace of Turin&lt;/b&gt; Begun in 1646, for Cristina of France, was the residence of the Dukes of Savoy, the Kings of Sardinia and the first King of Italy until 1865. Both the 1th and 2nd &amp;quot;piano nobile&amp;quot; can be visited. The apartment of the King and the apartment of Madama Felicita are visitable too. The building is completed by the Royal Garden, built at the end of the 17th century and designed by André Le Nôtre, the most important European garden designer in the 17th century. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/residenze_sabaude/pal_reale.shtml&quot;&gt;Palazzo Reale&lt;/a&gt;" id="342897047" latitude="45.073262" license="3" longitude="7.686256" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="turin torino palazzoreale italy italia piedmont piemonte royalpalace d80 notte night" title="Palazzo Reale - Torino - 28.12.2006" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/165/342897047_06608efa24_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="252" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-26 12:04:50" description="September 26, 2008 - As long as we were staying in Genoa, we figured a day-trip to Turin was in order." id="3120711446" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="turin italy palazzoreale royalpalaceofturin" title="Turin, Italy 06" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3283/3120711446_ceb3043437_b.jpg" username="DennisSylvesterHurd" views="103" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-09-26 11:58:06" description="September 26, 2008 - As long as we were staying in Genoa, we figured a day-trip to Turin was in order." id="3119884425" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="turin italy palazzoreale royalpalaceofturin" title="Turin, Italy 05" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3258/3119884425_4be8f562cd_b.jpg" username="DennisSylvesterHurd" views="73" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-09-25 15:10:48" description="fountains of Venaria royal palace" id="6186387944" latitude="45.134344" license="1" longitude="7.629661" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="fontana fontane gocce goccia acqua drop drops splash splashes fountain fountains water reggiadivenaria venaria royalpalace torino turin piemonte piedmont" title="fontane della reggia di Venaria" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6155/6186387944_2e6d5221eb_b.jpg" username="ميكيلا michela" views="21" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-03-04 16:27:13" description="&lt;b&gt;Particolare della Cancellata del Palazzo Reale. Detail of the Royal Palace of Turin gate.&lt;/b&gt; Begun in 1646, for Cristina of France, was the residence of the Dukes of Savoy, the Kings of Sardinia and the first King of Italy until 1865. Both the 1th and 2nd &amp;quot;piano nobile&amp;quot; can be visited. The apartment of the King and the apartment of Madama Felicita are visitable too. The building is completed by the Royal Garden, built at the end of the 17th century and designed by André Le Nôtre, the most important European garden designer in the 17th century. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/residenze_sabaude/pal_reale.shtml&quot;&gt;Palazzo Reale&lt;/a&gt;" id="412911608" latitude="45.073262" license="3" longitude="7.686256" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="italia italy piedmont piemonte palazzoreale royalpalace cancellata gate d80 nikon visitpiedmont" title="Palazzo Reale - Torino - 04.03.2007" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/185/412911608_154b3ac377_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="129" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-22 13:12:34" description="Decorations on the gate of the Royal Palace (Palazzo Reale) in Turin" id="4206895092" latitude="45.067701" license="5" longitude="7.672576" nbComments="1" rank="32" tags="torino turin palace palazzo palazzoreale royalpalace savoia gold golden decoration gate cancello decorazione oro piemonte piedmont" title="Golden face" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2535/4206895092_f14856abb6_b.jpg" username="nastia (New Flickr Account - see profile)" views="31" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-16 11:00:53" description="The statue of Pollux." id="6564305841" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="italia italy italien italie torino turin statua equestre polluce dioscuri palazzo reale piazza castello" title="Torino - Royal Palace" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7165/6564305841_26a9de2468_b.jpg" username="marcohilo" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-03-06 19:14:46" description="Palazzina di Caccia di Stupinigi - Stupinigi hunting palace (by night). The Stupinigi hunting palace is one of the Residences of the Royal House of Savoy, part of the UNESCO World Heritage Sites list. Built as a royal hunting lodge in the early eighteenth century, it is located in Stupinigi, a suburb of the town of Nichelino, 10 km southwest of Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palazzina_di_Stupinigi&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palazzina_di_Stupinigi&lt;/a&gt;" id="326480807" latitude="44.996368" license="3" longitude="7.604341" nbComments="75" rank="34" tags="torino italy stupinigi piemonte piedmont italia visitpiedmont night coolpix995 anawesomeshot italians blueribbonwinner mastino70 explore photoexplore dna abigfave savoy savoia residenzareale palazzinadicaccia hunting palace royal diamondclassphotographer flickrdiamond goldstaraward golddragon villeegiardini heritagesite220 heritagesite225 flickraward flickraward5 flickrawardgallery" title="Stupinigi Palazzina di Caccia - 06.03.2006" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/144/326480807_e45e02d34c_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="2032" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-06-08 19:04:23" description="Sunday I was lucky enough to find an original collection of souvenir cards of the Turin Exhibition of 1911. I invite you to visit with me through these images, taking a slide show it is suggested… there are 22 images. THEME Industry and Labor No PARTICIPATING COUNTRIES 37 No VISITORS 7 million No 3000 workers PARTICIPATING COUNTRIES FRANCE GERMANY GREAT BRITAIN HUNGARY SWITZERLAND AUSTRIA NETHERLANDS BELGIUM RUSSIA TURKEY REP OF ARGENTINA AND BRAZIL JAPAN SIAM SERBIA URUGUAY U.S.A. REP.DELL 'EQUATOR CHINA SPAIN GREECE MEXICO NORWAY PERU BOLIVIA BULGARIA CHILE COLUMBIA DENMARK NICARAGUA ATTRACTIONS Palaces of fashion, manufacturing, agriculture, aviation and automobile shows, exhibition of public works, eastern festival, Somali village, monumental bridge, Alpine village, Eritrean village, roller coaster, treadmills, incubator, aquarium, conveyor air, boats on the Po, electrical evenings. Planned expenditure - capital subscribed 6.376.400 The international exhibition of industry and labor, was held in Turin, in 1911, during the celebrations for the fiftieth anniversary of the unification of Italy. As if by magic, a new city was built on the banks of the Po, which already held the previous two exhibitions (1898 and 1902). It predominated a neoclassical style with baroque tips with the exception of the halls of Serbia, Turkey and Siam inspired to the architecture of the respective places of origin. The Expo celebrated modernity, technology and science in the service to industry. All the halls are a profusion of lights and moving machinery. 70,000 people attende the inauguration that took place at the “Stadium”, one of the first structures of this kind in the world. The stadium had elliptical shape 361/204 mt., with an area of 15,000 sqm., 24,000 seats, with other 47,000 square meters of galleries with place for other 40,000 people. Among the pavilions triumphed Ballroom HALL OF FRANCE ALPINE VILLAGE: huge success for the whole village with thousands of visitors to the shop with crafts of the Alps. The windows were decorated with giant slides with images of the best known and most difficult peaks PAVILION IN HUNGARY: pearl exposure, very modern building, square and dry &amp;quot;is almost a challenge to the surrounding buildings.&amp;quot; The work of architects Toery Pogany and attracts attention of the world. Retrieved from: &lt;a href=&quot;http://museoauto.it/mambo/index2.php?option=content&amp;amp;do_pdf=1&amp;amp;id=200&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;museoauto.it/mambo/index2.php?option=content&amp;amp;do_pdf=1...&lt;/a&gt;" id="4682321707" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="torino turin esposizione1911 expo 1911" title="Royal manifacture of Tobacco" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4072/4682321707_7bc4abec68_b.jpg" username="Mammaoca2008" views="134" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-04-21 13:55:35" description="Turin has a Gothic Revival train station! It's one end of a VERY grand axis (gosh those Savoyards did well off Italy) with the Royal Palace. The interior is under intensive renovation at the moment - I didn't see a BIT of Gothic Revival until I got outside, dropped off my bags at the hotel, and went for a walk." id="3465141546" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="torino turin gothicrevival 19thcenturyarchitecture kingdomofitaly" title="Torino Stazione Porta Nuova" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3643/3465141546_2258fb2951_b.jpg" username="Michael Tinkler" views="137" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-04-21 13:55:05" description="Turin has a Gothic Revival train station! It's one end of a VERY grand axis (gosh those Savoyards did well off Italy) with the Royal Palace. The interior is under intensive renovation at the moment - I didn't see a BIT of Gothic Revival until I got outside, dropped off my bags at the hotel, and went for a walk." id="3465141198" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="torino turin gothicrevival 19thcenturyarchitecture kingdomofitaly" title="Torino Stazione Porta Nuova" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3507/3465141198_b4a78e8370_b.jpg" username="Michael Tinkler" views="137" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-08-22 12:39:28" description="Widok na Ogrody Królewskie (Giardini Reali), Mole Antonelliana, Via Montebello, Turyn, 22 sierpnia 2007 r. ** View of the Royal Gardens (Giardini Reali) from the Mole Antonelliana, Via Montebello, Turin, August 22, 2007" id="1404026006" latitude="45.06908" license="3" longitude="7.69324" nbComments="1" rank="38" tags="turyn turin torino włochy wlochy italia italy widok krajobraz miasto ogród ogrod park view landscape city garden piemont piemonte piedmont" title="Mole Antonelliana" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1013/1404026006_27a98d4a6f_b.jpg" username="magro_kr" views="376" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-17 05:20:11" description="Built in the seventeenth century, this was the palace for Madama Reale Christine Marie of France, and was occupied by the royal family from 1645, when Torino was the capitol of united Italy. In front there, you can see another crowd of students; an extension of the street protest I ran into on the Via Po." id="3635646777" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="palazzoreale architecture italy palace torino travel piedmont piemonte turin work" title="Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3314/3635646777_33bb207494_b.jpg" username="singingbeagle" views="138" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-04-07 13:03:51" description="The Cathedral of St. John the Baptist is in the centre of the city and houses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shroud_of_Turin&quot;&gt;Shroud of Turin&lt;/a&gt;. The Cathedral adjoins the Royal Palace." id="458495683" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="italy turin cathedral stjohnthebaptist church" title="Cattedrale di San Giovanni Battista" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/247/458495683_caf5cb46e4_b.jpg" username="*tamara*" views="239" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-12-19 14:16:21" description="Tricolore su palazzo reale (Torino)::::Italian flag on the top of royal palace (Turin)" id="5276452317" latitude="45.07149" license="1" longitude="7.68588" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="torino turin piemonte tricolore bandiera flag palazzorealeitalia italy europa europe" title="Always on the top" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5124/5276452317_6e31773971_b.jpg" username="torenet82" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 17:52:40" description="Residence of Savoia Royal family, Hunting palace, part of UNESCO heritage. Stupinigi, Nichelino (Turin) - Italy." id="1781479491" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="42" tags="stupinigi torino caccia residenze sabaude architettura juvarra unesco" title="Hunting palace, Stupinigi - Italy" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2198/1781479491_8cc452c292_b.jpg" username="Claudio71" views="60" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:58:10" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1795105328" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="1" rank="43" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo visitpiedmont margaria margherie oldcity" title="071027 - Racconigi - 50 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2007/1795105328_a30c81a963_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="277" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:45:31" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794776452" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="2" rank="44" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo margaria margherie villeegiardiniitaliani villeegiardini heritagesite220 heritagesite226" title="071027 - Racconigi - 41 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2133/1794776452_9639fb7097_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="342" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 14:29:44" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789457221" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="3" rank="45" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo italians visitpiedmont oldcity villeegiardini" title="071027 - Racconigi - 06 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2127/1789457221_9ca887ec41_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="576" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 17:41:11" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1795430490" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="1" rank="46" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo villeegiardini" title="071027 - Racconigi - 65 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2014/1795430490_e810dd1787_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="235" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:45:18" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1790971980" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="1" rank="47" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo villeegiardini" title="071027 - Racconigi - 14 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2176/1790971980_7833df5fb9_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="268" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 17:03:54" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1795329002" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo margaria margherie" title="071027 - Racconigi - 57 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2169/1795329002_75056703e6_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="93" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:58:35" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1795202860" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo margaria margherie" title="071027 - Racconigi - 53 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2076/1795202860_7d82ff43b8_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="81" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:55:10" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794120923" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo margaria margherie" title="071027 - Racconigi - 45 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2048/1794120923_9c917d6794_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="236" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:53:22" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Margherie&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794011293" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="1" rank="51" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo margaria margherie" title="071027 - Racconigi - 43 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2165/1794011293_ce4c3d20da_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="105" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 17:29:10" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi: sluice in the park&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794526539" latitude="44.776412" license="3" longitude="7.671718" nbComments="1" rank="52" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo sluice chiusa ruscello brook" title="071027 - Racconigi - 61 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2187/1794526539_4f69fce350_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="161" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:43:19" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794702472" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="1" rank="53" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo heritagesite226" title="071027 - Racconigi - 40 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2234/1794702472_576fd67e32_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="171" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 14:30:18" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789632101" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="1" rank="54" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo heritagesite226" title="071027 - Racconigi - 08 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2092/1789632101_daa1ddb6fd_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="104" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:40:32" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1790809348" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo oldcity" title="071027 - Racconigi - 12 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2341/1790809348_9c586ef9c2_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="92" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:29:26" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794399536" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo visitpiedmont" title="071027 - Racconigi - 33 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2339/1794399536_c20b42c375_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="64" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:31:07" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi The Park&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1793628615" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="5" rank="57" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo visitpiedmont lago lake blueribbonwinner naturesfinest heritagesite226" title="071027 - Racconigi - 34 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2230/1793628615_c29d1c357e_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="211" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:45:32" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1791062618" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 15 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2184/1791062618_e97a08b695_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="54" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:17:07" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1793318153" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 31 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2393/1793318153_4e2099d4e8_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="98" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:15:02" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1793910760" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 29 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2153/1793910760_8df28be9d0_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="87" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 17:40:08" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794561225" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 62 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2147/1794561225_241694db97_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="115" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 14:23:57" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789368511" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 05 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2129/1789368511_1e749c637d_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="74" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:40:05" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789784685" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 10 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2021/1789784685_bf1d92673f_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="93" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:01:08" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1792791643" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 23 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2028/1792791643_32f09171d3_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="64" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:22:12" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794266652" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 32 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2362/1794266652_f2e29c9380_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="376" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:31:31" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794537674" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="66" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 35 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2241/1794537674_ab2b93fd41_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="84" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:56:05" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1793407788" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="67" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 17 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2215/1793407788_8b5d05e932_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="48" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:58:45" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1792678907" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="68" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 20 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2020/1792678907_c6f6ceefb1_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="70" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:40:01" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794598046" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 37 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2386/1794598046_02a564bf0e_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="271" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:40:12" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789871425" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="70" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 11 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2224/1789871425_f3700e3670_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="57" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 14:21:29" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789894980" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="71" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 01 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2192/1789894980_c5d115e517_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="331" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:50:06" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789811718" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="72" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 16 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2309/1789811718_68ada69ac8_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="100" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:16:01" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1793194691" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="73" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 30 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2375/1793194691_b69c06da40_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="113" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 14:29:53" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1789540821" latitude="44.769116" license="3" longitude="7.675645" nbComments="0" rank="74" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 07 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2386/1789540821_2591e3e494_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="70" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:02:11" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1792929505" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="75" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon savoia cuneo" title="071027 - Racconigi - 24 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2056/1792929505_7a3d89f1de_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="115" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 15:58:18" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1793421486" latitude="44.7769" license="3" longitude="7.674894" nbComments="0" rank="76" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon" title="071027 - Racconigi - 19 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2353/1793421486_be8c9e0a68_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="76" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-27 16:49:18" description="&lt;b&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle - Castello Reale di Racconigi&lt;/b&gt; Old stronghold transformed into a castle by the Marquises of Saluzzo and acquired by the Savoy Dynasty in 1605. The Prince Emanuele Filiberto entrusted the enlargement and transformation into an aristocratic villa to Guarino Guarini in 1676. Inside there are many halls decorated and furnished with works of art and furniture from the 17th to the 20th century. Behind the castle there is a large, magnificent park, in which the greenhouses and the &amp;quot;Margherie&amp;quot; complex are found, made of various rooms related to hunting. Nowaday the Castle and the Park may be visited paying two separated tickes: in the Palace you can enter by guided tours (one each hour) while in the park you can make wonderful walks through the gardens or take the inner train or rent a lovely calash too. Racconigi is 39 km far from Turin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilcastellodiracconigi.it&quot;&gt;Racconigi Royal Castle Official website&lt;/a&gt;" id="1794785366" latitude="44.786343" license="3" longitude="7.668972" nbComments="0" rank="77" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont racconigi castello reale royal castle d80 nikon" title="071027 - Racconigi - 42 - Castello Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2394/1794785366_5e8b417f78_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="71" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 12:36:00" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1568755060" latitude="45.080733" license="3" longitude="7.767596" nbComments="3" rank="78" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa nikon d80 torino scalaachiocciola scala chiocciola spiralstaircase staircase church visitpiedmont" title="Basilica di Superga - 15 - 06.10.07" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2115/1568755060_6eba81aae1_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="458" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 13:02:06" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1568555442" latitude="45.08046" license="3" longitude="7.766835" nbComments="3" rank="79" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa church nikon d80 torino visitpiedmont cupola dome oldcity" title="071006 - Superga - 04 - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2135/1568555442_5e2e491c6c_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="391" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 13:02:46" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1567708329" latitude="45.08046" license="3" longitude="7.766835" nbComments="2" rank="80" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa church nikon d80 torino visitpiedmont cupola dome goldstaraward" title="071006 - Superga - 05 - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2098/1567708329_200d48c9ab_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="438" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 12:45:08" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1567927551" latitude="45.080733" license="3" longitude="7.767596" nbComments="7" rank="81" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa nikon d80 torino church dome cupola goldstaraward anawesomeshot blueribbonwinner worldbest ysplix" title="071006 - Superga - 17 - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2207/1567927551_93e8ff0759_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="334" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 12:46:19" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1568638216" latitude="45.080896" license="3" longitude="7.767199" nbComments="0" rank="82" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa church nikon d80 torino visitpiedmont" title="071006 - Superga - 06 - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2082/1568638216_0aeb0b6b5d_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="209" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 12:27:48" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1567789825" latitude="45.080733" license="3" longitude="7.767596" nbComments="0" rank="83" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa church nikon d80 torino" title="071006 - Superga - 07 - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2155/1567789825_e84c8516b2_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="181" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 12:33:06" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1568706514" latitude="45.080733" license="3" longitude="7.767596" nbComments="0" rank="84" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa nikon d80 torino church" title="071006 - Superga - 13 - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2026/1568706514_85e674e228_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="169" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 12:50:01" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga: organ&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1568572933" latitude="45.080733" license="3" longitude="7.767596" nbComments="1" rank="85" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa church nikon d80 hdr organo organ photomatix" title="071006 - Superga - 19 - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2286/1568572933_aed0915432_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="323" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-10-06 12:46:00" description="&lt;b&gt;Basilica di Superga: the dome (HDR)&lt;/b&gt; The building was designed by Filippo Juvarra between 1717 and 1731 and commissioned by Vittorio Amedeo II to keep a vow he made following the siege of Turin in 1706. The basilica is positioned at the junction of the Rivoli road and Turin Royal Palace. The entrance to the Savoy Tombs, covered with marble and gilt stuccoes, is found to the left of the basilica. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.piemonte-emozioni.it/cultura/eng/edifici_religiosi/edifici_culto/superga.shtml&quot;&gt;Basilica di Superga&lt;/a&gt;" id="1568872436" latitude="45.080733" license="3" longitude="7.767596" nbComments="5" rank="86" tags="italia italy piemonte piedmont superga basilica chiesa church nikon d80 hdr cupola dome visitpiedmont diamondclassphotographer flickrdiamond oldcity photomatix" title="071006 - Superga - 17hdr - Basilica" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2211/1568872436_5738f5a5b8_b.jpg" username="mastino70" views="585" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-27 14:11:54" description="Un particolare della cancellata del Palazzo Reale di Torino A particular of the gate of the Royal Palace of Turin" id="2215938323" latitude="45.071868" license="1" longitude="7.685456" nbComments="0" rank="87" tags="piazzacastello torino cancellata palazzoreale httpgalimbertineteu" title="Cancellata del Palazzo Reale di Torino" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2271/2215938323_7b25c3852d_b.jpg" username="dgali" views="252" />
</photos>
