<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Town Hall of Bremen">

<photo  date_taken="2009-05-02 17:01:35" description="The well preserved Town Hall of this Hanseatic city, constructed in 14th century with a Renaissance style facade added in 17th century is now along with the Roland Statue, a UNESCO World Heritage site." id="3496733568" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="bremen hanseaticcity hanseatic port portcity riverwaser waser northsea nordsee freiehansestadtbremen freiehansestadt schnoorquarter altstadt roland swordofjustice diestadtmusikanten townmusicians böttcherstrase harbour werderbremen nikon d60 nikond60 abhijeet rane abhijeetrane germany europe vivaeuropa vaterland" title="Bremen Town Hall and Roland Statue" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3417/3496733568_13557c235c_b.jpg" username="AbhijeetRane" views="238" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-19 16:46:39" description="Original from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edmondsun.com/arts/local_story_324171721.html/resources_printstory&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Edmond Sun&lt;/a&gt;. PHOTO PROVIDED | Susan Scott. Edmond actors starring in the Fine Art Institute's production of The Bremen Town Musicians include, top, Chloe Singleton, Katie Cheap, Greysen Ernst, Anna Elizabeth Hall, Carter Methvin, Peter Beierle and Luke Miller; bottom, Dalton Tatum, Adam Morey, Ellie Howell, Sarah Fryer and Emma Baird." id="4131480804" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="2" tags="play edmond oklahoma bremen" title="Bremen Town Musicians" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2741/4131480804_9d6142ba9b_b.jpg" username="Wesley Fryer" views="730" />
<photo  date_taken="2013-02-07 19:33:56" description="This is a 7-exposure HDR of Bremens town hall from 1409. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&lt;/a&gt; The extreme 10mm wide angle also shows the Cathedral as well as parts of the Parliament." id="8453115265" latitude="53.074829" license="3" longitude="8.808764" nbComments="5" rank="3" tags="" title="Townhall Bremen (Rathaus) - HDR" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8252/8453115265_def40b26b2_b.jpg" username="Peter Gorges" views="666" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-10-23 16:19:14" description="Sir William Bruce of Kinross, 1st Baronet (circa 1630 – 1 January 1710) was a Scottish gentleman-architect, &amp;quot;the effective founder of classical architecture in Scotland,&amp;quot; as Howard Colvin observes.[1] As a key figure in introducing the Palladian style into Scotland, he has been compared to the pioneering English architects Inigo Jones and Christopher Wren,[2] and to the contemporaneous introducers of French style in English domestic architecture, Hugh May and Sir Roger Pratt.[1] Bruce was a merchant in Rotterdam during the 1650s, and played a role in the Restoration of Charles II in 1659. He carried messages between the exiled king and General Monck, and his loyalty to the king was rewarded with lucrative official appointments, including that of Surveyor General of the King's Works in Scotland, effectively the &amp;quot;king's architect&amp;quot;. His patrons included John Maitland, 1st Duke of Lauderdale, the most powerful man in Scotland at the time, and Bruce rose to become a member of Parliament, and briefly sat on the Scottish Privy Council. Despite his lack of technical expertise, Bruce became the most prominent architect of his time in Scotland. He worked with competent masons and professional builders, to whom he imparted a classical vocabulary; thus his influence was carried far beyond his own aristocratic circle. Beginning in the 1660s he built and remodelled a number of country houses, including Thirlestane Castle for the Duke of Lauderdale, and Hopetoun House. Among his most significant work was his own Palladian mansion at Kinross, built on the Loch Leven estate which he had purchased in 1675. As the king's architect he undertook the rebuilding of the Royal Palace of Holyroodhouse in the 1670s, which gave the palace its present appearance. After the death of Charles II Bruce lost political favour, and later, following the accession of William and Mary, he was imprisoned more than once as a suspected Jacobite. However, he managed to continue his architectural work, often providing his services to others with Jacobite sympathies. Little is known of Bruce's youth, and his date of birth is unrecorded. He was probably born at Blairhall in western Fife, in around 1630, the second son of Robert Bruce of Blairhall and Katherine Preston. He may have attended St Andrews University in 1637-1638, which would suggest that his birth date was as early as 1625.[3] The Bruces were a well-connected Episcopalian family, strongly loyal to the king, and descended from Thomas Bruce a cousin of King Robert II, who had been granted lands in Clackmannan and Fife.[4] Bruce's first cousin Edward Bruce was created Earl of Kincardine in 1643. Letters in the Earl of Kincardine's papers show that William Bruce was in exile in Rotterdam during the 1650s with his cousin, Alexander Bruce, brother of the Earl of Kincardine. As Episcopalians, William and Alexander would have sought refuge from the Puritan Commonwealth established by Oliver Cromwell. In Rotterdam, they were in contact with Sir Robert Moray, a soldier and natural philosopher close to Charles II, who then resided at Maastricht. William Bruce was a merchant, based in the Scottish community in Rotterdam, but travelling widely. He owned a ship with Alexander Bruce and John Hamilton of Grange, and was involved in the trade of wine, coal and timber between Norway, France, England, Scotland and the Low Countries. He is recorded as having a house and a mistress in La Rochelle. In 1658, William and Alexander travelled together from Bremen overland to Maastricht to meet Moray. Alexander Bruce and Moray were founder members of the Royal Society in 1660, and it is likely that architecture featured in their discussions, particularly the new town hall in Maastricht that Moray had recently advised on. In 1659 Bruce acted as a messenger between General Monck, Cromwell's commander-in-chief in Scotland and the exiled King Charles II. A passport survives, issued to Bruce by Monck in September 1659, and giving him permission to remain in Scotland until his &amp;quot;returne to Holland,&amp;quot;[6] and it appears that the messages he brought from Charles persuaded Monck to march his army to London, a decisive event in the Restoration.[7] The nature of their communications is not known, although it would appear that Moray selected him for the task.[5] Sir Robert Douglas stated that Bruce &amp;quot;painted the distress and distractions&amp;quot; of Scotland before the General, and suggested to him &amp;quot;the glory that would be acquired in restoring the royal family.&amp;quot; Following the restoration, William Bruce was appointed Clerk to the Bills in 1660,[9] and Clerk of Supply to the Lords in Council in 1665. Both were lucrative positions, involving collection of fees, from Parliament in the first case, and from petitioners to the Court of Session in the latter. Meanwhile, Sir Robert Moray had established himself as a courtier and scientist at Whitehall, London, and employed Bruce as a trusted messenger between Whitehall and the Duke of Lauderdale, Secretary for Scotland.[5] Moray later served on the Treasury Commission for Scotland, as did Alexander Bruce, now Earl of Kincardine. Bruce reported to this Commission as a revenue collector, and benefited from the patronage of its members.[5] The Commission had responsibility for the King's Works, and in 1667 Bruce was appointed Superintendent and Overseer of the Royal Palaces in Scotland. Four years later he was made Surveyor General of the King's Works in Scotland, with a salary of £3600 Scots (£300 Sterling), for the purpose of rebuilding Holyroodhouse.[1] In March 1671, Bruce was part of a syndicate which bought the rights to collect taxes over a five-year period, paying £26,000 Sterling for the privilege. As such, it would appear that Bruce was not only the architect of Holyroodhouse, but one of the principal financiers of the £21,000 project.[5] As a key figure of the Restoration administration, he became close to other Stuart loyalists, who included such powerful patrons as the Duke of Lauderdale, Lord Haltoun, and the Earl of Rothes.[10] In 1667 he undertook his first building work for Lord Rothes, overseeing the extensions to Leslie House, and later worked on several of Lauderdale's properties, concurrently with Holyroodhouse.[5] In 1668 he was created a Baronet of Nova Scotia.[1] From 1669 to 1674 Bruce sat in the Scottish Parliament as shire commissioner for Fife, and from 1681 to 1682 as a shire commissioner for Kinross.[11] From April 1685 to May 1686 he reached the peak of his political career, as a member of the Privy Council of Scotland.[11] But, in 1674, he became embroiled in factional rivalry between his patron Lauderdale, and his rivals the Duke of Hamilton and the Earl of Tweeddale. His actions, which apparently included passing information to Hamilton, invoked the fury of the Duchess of Lauderdale, who tried to persuade her husband to deprive Bruce of his offices. Bruce survived, although his relationship with his patron was damaged.[5] Lauderdale described him as &amp;quot;the bitterest factionalist partie man of his quality in all Scotland&amp;quot;.[12] This breakdown resulted in Bruce's eventual dismissal as Surveyor General of the King's Works, on the false pretext that Holyroodhouse was finished.[5] Bruce's earnings from his offices had made him a wealthy man, even by the standards of his patrons.[13] This wealth allowed him to purchase the Balcaskie estate in 1665, and to extend the house and gardens. In 1675 he purchased the larger estate of Loch Leven, Kinross, from the Earl of Morton, which brought him the hereditary sheriffdom of Kinross-shire.[11] In the late 1670s Bruce took on his first architectural projects for entirely new houses.[5] Following the accession of James VII in 1685, Bruce gradually fell from favour, and was distrusted by the new regime.[1] After the Revolution of 1688, and the accession of William of Orange as King, he was once again at odds with his Protestant rulers, and he refused to take up his seat in Parliament. As a staunch Episcopalian, Bruce was considered a potential Jacobite threat.[14] In 1693 he was briefly imprisoned in Stirling Castle for refusing to appear before the Privy Council. He was incarcerated again at Stirling in 1694, and from 1696 in Edinburgh Castle.[15] Bruce was expelled from parliament in 1702, his seat passing to his son John Bruce. Despite these imprisonments, he continued his architectural work, indeed the 1690s and 1700s were his most prolific years.[3] Bruce was imprisoned at Edinburgh Castle again in 1708 and was only released a short time before his death, at the beginning of 1710.[15] He was buried in the family plot at Kinross Kirk, the ruins of which still stand beside Kinross House.[1] Bruce's surviving account books show purchases of books on music, painting and horticulture, as well as numerous foreign-language works, suggesting that Bruce was a learned man. He studied horticulture extensively, and applied his knowledge of the subject in his own gardens at Kinross. He was a friend of James Sutherland of the Edinburgh Botanic Garden, and may have known John Evelyn and other English horticulturalists. Around 1660 William Bruce married Mary Halkett, daughter of Sir James Halkett of Pitfirrane, Bt. They had two surviving children: * Sir John Bruce, 2nd Baronet of Kinross, (before 1671 – 19 March 1710) married Christian Leslie, widow of the Marquess of Montrose and daughter of the Duke of Rothes. He left no issue. * Anne, upon whom Sir William had entailed his estates if her brother failed to leave issue. She married twice, with issue to both husbands.[16] After the death of his first wife, Sir William Bruce married Magdalen Scott, widow of an Edinburgh merchant called George Clerk, in 1700. They had no issue. Magdalen lived until 1752, and gained a reputation as a Jacobite, establishing a Jacobite cell at her home in Leith Citadel." id="4038208440" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="4" tags="" title="Sir William Bruce of Kinross, 1st Baronet Bruce" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2433/4038208440_a8d037ccbf_b.jpg" username="lisby1" views="977" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-01-17 09:51:59" description="The New Town Hall, Domshof, Bremen. Built between 909 and 1913, and designed by the Munich architect Gabriel von Seidl in the style of the Neo-Renaissance" id="5371036222" latitude="53.076112" license="4" longitude="8.808664" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="bremen" title="The New Town Hall" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5010/5371036222_e8eaed210d_b.jpg" username="Reading Tom" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-07-25 21:02:36" description="one of these five Bremen pics is not photoshopped. The first correct guess has a wish free..." id="2701280487" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="5" rank="6" tags="bremen weser europe germany blackforrest light me fuji finepix flickrolf miracles trip travel now time space day color colour farbe couleur soe onlythebestare smörgåsbord worldtrekker" title="Bremen town hall" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3087/2701280487_764bea9105_b.jpg" username="flickrolf" views="142" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-26 18:39:30" description="Rathaus/Town hall Bremen's Market Square is regarded as one of the most beautiful in Europe. Its ensemble of historic buildings is unique. The Town Hall, dating from 1405, the statue of Roland, the symbol of the city's freedom, erected in 1404." id="334176564" latitude="53.076038" license="3" longitude="8.807655" nbComments="21" rank="7" tags="bremen germany architecture explore night nightshot" title="Bremen at night" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/155/334176564_ad891a1352_b.jpg" username="The guenni" views="1402" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-29 07:02:00" description="The &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bremen Rathaus&lt;/a&gt;, also on the market square. A UNESCO World Heritage Site, for the following criteria: &lt;i&gt;Criterion (iii):&lt;/i&gt; the Bremen Town Hall and Roland bear an exceptional testimony to the civic autonomy and sovereignty, as these developed in the Holy Roman Empire. &lt;i&gt;Criterion (iv):&lt;/i&gt; The Bremen Town Hall and Roland are an outstanding ensemble representing civic autonomy and market freedom. The town hall represents the medieval Saalgeschossbau-type of hall construction, as well as being an outstanding example of the so-called Weser Renaissance in Northern Germany. The Bremen Roland is the most representative and one of the oldest of Roland statues erected as a symbol of market rights and freedom. &lt;i&gt;Criterion (vi):&lt;/i&gt; the ensemble of the town hall and Roland of Bremen with its symbolism is directly associated with the development of the ideas of civic autonomy and market freedom in the Holy Roman Empire. The Bremen Roland is referred to a historical figure, paladin of Charlemagne, who became the source for the French ‘chanson de geste’ and other medieval and Renaissance epic poetry." id="43636956" latitude="53.076702" license="2" longitude="8.807601" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="bremen rathaus germany unescoworldheritagesite" title="Bremen Rathaus" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/24/43636956_70fa53c6c8_b.jpg" username="Fotomoe" views="51" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-15 12:52:50" description="The street-lamp before the town hall at Bremen" id="367358939" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="7" rank="9" tags="bremen germany deutschland" title="The street-lamp of Bremen" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/118/367358939_1037fda57d_b.jpg" username="The guenni" views="198" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-07-03 16:29:07" description="One of the pedestrianised streets in the city centre, leading to the Market Place, Old Town Hall and Dom. Es regnet." id="717093618" latitude="0" license="5" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="10" tags="tram rain dom cathedral street bremen germany deutschland jim champion jimchampion treehouse1977" title="Bremen" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1340/717093618_0abae2fb81_b.jpg" username="treehouse1977" views="156" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-05 15:30:44" description="Town hall of Bremen Map it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robogeo.com/Flickr2Map/&quot;&gt;Google Earth&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robogeo.com/Flickr2Map/?type=map&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Street&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robogeo.com/Flickr2Map/?type=map&amp;amp;view=satellite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Satellite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robogeo.com/Flickr2Map/?type=map&amp;amp;view=hybrid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hybrid&lt;/a&gt; |" id="142049786" latitude="53.075666" license="2" longitude="8.807" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="bremen weser map20060505 weserradweg meivakantie2006 geotagged geo:lat=530756666666667 geo:lon=8807" title="IMG_4062.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/45/142049786_0fe638589f_b.jpg" username="duimdog" views="169" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-23 12:09:25" description="After visiting our friends in Hamburg, Kate and I headed up to Bremen for a day. I took this picture of one the trams zooming by the Tall Hall of Bremen as we set up on the ground in the market square of the historic town centre." id="3980628607" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="5" rank="12" tags="bremen germany eurotrip2009 travel deutschland tram markt city centre town hall market square 2009 fall autumn september europe eurotrip" title="We Will Become Silhouettes" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2526/3980628607_c7c82b74d3_b.jpg" username="clint mcmahon" views="94" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-03-09 22:00:39" description="The Town Hall and St.Peter Cathedral. The closer statue is the Roland." id="116662420" latitude="53.120128" license="2" longitude="8.7363" nbComments="2" rank="13" tags="bremen germany rathaus" title="Main square of Bremen" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/45/116662420_db4fd3b09c_b.jpg" username="Bogdan Morar" views="357" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-01-04 03:11:17" description="This building is one of the most important examples of Brick Gothic architecture in Europe. Walking around at night during winter time was not a great experience, but I was just cannot help the beauty of the buildings at nightfall." id="4580829467" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="21" rank="14" tags="" title="Bremen Town hall" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4035/4580829467_20dbbcf08b_b.jpg" username="motiqua" views="167" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-05 08:22:22" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&lt;/a&gt;" id="4768741437" latitude="0" license="4" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="" title="Bremen townhall" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4100/4768741437_de6dcb0c01_b.jpg" username="storebukkebruse" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="1960-10-24 00:00:00" description="This sculpture of the &amp;quot;Bremen Town Musicians,&amp;quot; based on the Grimm fairy tale, was created in 1953. It is on the west side of the Rathaus (city hall), near the Ratskeller entrance. The donkey, dog, cat, and rooster are depicted. There is a horse-drawn beer wagon in front of the Ratsstuben. It is a tavern which has a connection with the Rathaus." id="3007357432" latitude="53.075909" license="5" longitude="8.807736" nbComments="0" rank="16" tags="stadtmusikanten rathaus rathskeller brementownmusicians bremen germany deutschland 1960 hansa hanse hansestadt beer beerwagon bier horse" title="Bremen - &quot;Stadtmusikanten&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3224/3007357432_6cc09945c8_b.jpg" username="roger4336" views="302" />
<photo  date_taken="2004-02-16 21:03:24" description="The town hall of Bremen. Photographed by night." id="405220863" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="17" tags="townhall rathaus bremen nachtaufnahme nightshot beleuchtung architecture achitektur gothic gotik unesco weltkulturerbe world heritage site altstadt marktplatz cityhall germany german nacht" title="Das Bremer Rathaus" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/124/405220863_83ed3c15dd_b.jpg" username="dirk@bremen" views="471" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-23 12:51:48" description="Town Hall and Roland on the Marketplace of Bremen, Germany." id="3129387831" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="1" rank="18" tags="worldheritage" title="DE2003 Bremen" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3264/3129387831_960aaa040a_b.jpg" username="S.K. LO" views="65" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-22 21:27:48" description="Town Hall and Roland on the Marketplace of Bremen, Germany." id="3128266052" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="19" tags="worldheritage" title="DE2002 Bremen" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3273/3128266052_8b717691cd_b.jpg" username="S.K. LO" views="30" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-22 19:04:44" description="" id="229119491" latitude="53.0757" license="5" longitude="8.8071" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="germany bremen geo:lon=88071 geo:lat=530757 geotagged stadtkreisbremen europe eu centraleurope wikipedia:en=townhallofbremen" title="DSCF0324" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/70/229119491_dad20d2c83_b.jpg" username="Matthew Black" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-08-22 15:12:16" description="" id="229118936" latitude="53.0755" license="5" longitude="8.8071" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="germany bremen rathaus bremerrathaus geo:lon=88071 geo:lat=530755 geotagged stadtkreisbremen europe eu centraleurope wikipedia:en=townhallofbremen" title="Bremer Rathaus" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/77/229118936_aa33d6cb6b_b.jpg" username="Matthew Black" views="118" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-07-24 20:39:10" description="Current location: Berlin, Berlin, Germany Description of work: The Roland statue is in the foreground with multi-storied brick and masonry builds in the background. &amp;quot;Bremen's Market Square is regarded as one of the most beautiful in Europe. Its ensemble of historic buildings is unique and consists of the Town Hall, dating from 1405, St Peter's Cathedral, begun in 1042, the &amp;quot;Schutting&amp;quot;, Bremen's historic Chamber of Commerce built in 1537, the merchants' houses that date back to the Weser Renaissance era around 1600, and the statue of Roland, the symbol of the city's freedom, erected in 1404. The modern &amp;quot;Haus der Burgerschaft&amp;quot;, Bremen's state parliament building, was built in 1966 and forms a sensitive counterpoint to the rest of the square.&amp;quot; (http://www.bremen.de/) Style of work: Medieval Culture: German Source: Copyright Gary Catchen; Photographer: Gary Catchen (2003-2004) Resource type: image File format: jpeg Image size: 962 x 1200 pixels Permitted uses: This image is posted publicly for non-profit educational uses, excluding printed publication. Other uses are not permitted. For additional details see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&lt;/a&gt; Collection: Worldwide Building and Landscape Pictures Filename: WB2005-016 Bremen Marktplatz.jpg Record ID: WB2005-016 Sub collection: marketplaces" id="5540647272" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="marketplaces" title="Bremen Marktplatz" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5053/5540647272_420bf9eda7_b.jpg" username="Penn State Libraries Pictures Collection" views="31" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-02-08 14:54:53" description="on top of the bremen town hall." id="3266674835" latitude="53.075826" license="5" longitude="8.807784" nbComments="2" rank="23" tags="bremen fz30 townhall rathaus roof dach statue warrior green grün" title="warrior" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1314/3266674835_974ff352a8_b.jpg" username="fihu" views="77" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-07-24 20:40:09" description="Current location: Berlin, Berlin, Germany Description of work: This section of the marktplatz shows more modern buildings with a multi-storied glass facade building topped by an almost gabled roof. The city's history goes back over 1, 200 years. And you will encounter it everywhere. In the baroque and Renaissance backdrop of the Market Square, for example, with the Town Hall and the statue of Roland, patricians' houses, and the &amp;quot;Schutting&amp;quot;, Bremen's historic Chamber of Commerce. All of them are emblems of Hanseatic republican consciousness - civic pride expressed in stone, bricks and mortar. (http://www.bremen.de/) Style of work: Modern Culture: German Source: Copyright Gary Catchen; Photographer: Gary Catchen (2003-2004) Resource type: image File format: jpeg Image size: 915 x 1200 pixels Permitted uses: This image is posted publicly for non-profit educational uses, excluding printed publication. Other uses are not permitted. For additional details see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&lt;/a&gt; Collection: Worldwide Building and Landscape Pictures Filename: WB2005-017 Bremen Marktplatz.jpg Record ID: WB2005-017 Sub collection: marketplaces" id="5540066231" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="2" rank="24" tags="marketplaces" title="Bremen Marktplatz" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5256/5540066231_b1b2f37168_b.jpg" username="Penn State Libraries Pictures Collection" views="31" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-07-24 20:43:59" description="Other title: Bremen Town Musicians Creator: Marcks, Gerhard 1889-1981 Date: 1953 Current location: Berlin, Berlin, Germany Description of work: The Brothers Grimm tell their story in a fairy tale, and Bremen has erected a monument to them: the Bremen Town Musicians, four animals who were threatened with death at home and hoped to survive in freedom in Bremen. Their sculpture, taking the form of the donkey, the dog, the cat and the rooster standing on each others' backs, stands on the West side of the Town Hall and was created by the sculptor, Gerhard Marcks in 1953. You will find other interpretations of the Town Musicians theme in Bottcherstrasse and in the Schnoor quarter. (http://www.bremen.de/) Culture: German Materials/Techniques: metal Source: Copyright Gary Catchen; Photographer: Gary Catchen (2003-2004) Resource type: image File format: jpeg Image size: 2018 x 1200 pixels Permitted uses: This image is posted publicly for non-profit educational uses, excluding printed publication. Other uses are not permitted. For additional details see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&lt;/a&gt; Collection: Worldwide Building and Landscape Pictures Filename: WB2005-019 Stadtmusikanten Town Musicians.jpg Record ID: WB2005-019" id="5540104635" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="" title="Stadtmusikanten (Town Musicians)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5052/5540104635_5714fd3e61_b.jpg" username="Penn State Libraries Pictures Collection" views="33" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-07-24 20:38:30" description="Current location: Berlin, Berlin, Germany Description of work: The stone statue of Roland sits on the right of the picture. The square is framed by several brick and masonry buildings that are several stories high and topped with steeply pitched roofs. &amp;quot;In the 15th century the Marktplatz, the civic focus of the town, was completely surrounded by buidings. To the north, between the market and Unsere Lieben Frauenkirche, the Late Gothic town hall (1405–10) was added. The two-storey brick building has a three-aisled, flat-roofed hall above a vaulted Ratskeller (town hall cellar), and on the first floor there is a flat-roofed chamber. The facade is decorated with life-size sandstone statues of the emperor with the seven electors and Prophets. The stone figure of Roland (1404) on the Marktplatz is part of the same iconographic scheme. When the town hall was altered (1608–15), the facade in particular was enhanced by the addition of a large number of sandstone reliefs that together provide an allegorical picture of the world. Shortly afterwards, the Güldenkammer, decorated with carvings and oil paintings, was created on the first floor as a new council chamber (see Germany, §V, 1). To the south, the Marktplatz is closed off by the Schütting (see fig.), the premises of the merchants' guild. The present sandstone building (1537–9), by the Antwerp architect Johann de Buschener ( fl 1536–9), replaces one dating from 1425; in 1565 a new east gable was added, and in 1594 a new facade was built (see Bentheim, luder von), both the work of local masons.&amp;quot; (Dictionary of Art, Albrecht, Steven) Style of work: Medieval Culture: German Source: Copyright Gary Catchen; Photographer: Gary Catchen (2003-2004) Resource type: image File format: jpeg Image size: 897 x 1200 pixels Permitted uses: This image is posted publicly for non-profit educational uses, excluding printed publication. Other uses are not permitted. For additional details see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&lt;/a&gt; Collection: Worldwide Building and Landscape Pictures Filename: WB2005-015 Bremen Marktplatz.jpg Record ID: WB2005-015 Sub collection: marketplaces" id="5540647250" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="marketplaces" title="Bremen Marktplatz" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5020/5540647250_688c6cd452_b.jpg" username="Penn State Libraries Pictures Collection" views="54" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-22 21:27:53" description="Town Hall and Roland on the Marketplace of Bremen, Germany." id="3128266528" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="3" rank="27" tags="worldheritage" title="DE2001 Roland" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3289/3128266528_2c8a683b1b_b.jpg" username="S.K. LO" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-07-24 20:47:38" description="Other title: Bremer Rathaus Date: 1404-1408 Current location: Berlin, Berlin, Germany Description of work: The much visited Bremen Town Hall was erected in 1405-1408. It is the only European town hall of the late Middle Ages that has never been destroyed. Since its construction, the town hall has undergone permanent repair and maintenance - a condition to be inscribed as a World Heritage site. The UNESCO World Heritage Committee with its decision also recognizes the authenticity of the building. The Bremen Town Hall is considered to have preserved its authenticity - from the very first Gothic construction, a so-called Saalgeschossbau (i.e. a multi-storey construction built to contain a large hall) in the beginning of the 15th century, the comprehensive restorations two centuries later and up to the construction of the new town hall in the early 20th century. Numerous German town halls were destroyed during the Second World War, and many have been modified. The Bremen Town Hall, however, has been fully preserved in its original state. UNESCO also sees the special importance of the Bremen Town Hall in its artistic and stylistic values: today its main facade represents the so-called Weser Renaissance and is considered a highly representative example of this style. The medieval attributes of this building - such as the emblematic sculptural decoration in sandstone - remained at their original position. It is also to be underlined that the Bremen Town Hall reflects European-wide trends at the end of the 16th and early 17th centuries. (http://www.rathaus-bremen.de/en/Kap1/Kap1_2_e.htm) Style of work: Medieval: Gothic Culture: German Materials/Techniques: brick Source: Copyright Gary Catchen; Photographer: Gary Catchen (2003-2004) Resource type: image File format: jpeg Image size: 895 x 1200 pixels Permitted uses: This image is posted publicly for non-profit educational uses, excluding printed publication. Other uses are not permitted. For additional details see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;alias.libraries.psu.edu/vius/copyright/publicrightsarch.htm&lt;/a&gt; Collection: Worldwide Building and Landscape Pictures Filename: WB2005-020 Rathaus.jpg Record ID: WB2005-020 Sub collection: government office buildings" id="5540686060" latitude="0" license="2" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="governmentofficebuildings" title="Rathaus" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5011/5540686060_8243ca267a_b.jpg" username="Penn State Libraries Pictures Collection" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-02 08:52:09" description="7/6 Bremen &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&lt;/a&gt; Town Hall &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&lt;/a&gt;" id="3682063768" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="europe germany worldheritage" title="P1010021" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2647/3682063768_c6dd021745_b.jpg" username="YuKengShih" views="23" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-02 08:52:56" description="7/6 Bremen &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&lt;/a&gt; Town Hall &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&lt;/a&gt;" id="3681250641" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="europe germany worldheritage" title="P1010020" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2594/3681250641_cc3a9158ce_b.jpg" username="YuKengShih" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-02 08:51:27" description="7/6 Bremen &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&lt;/a&gt; Town Hall &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&lt;/a&gt;" id="3681247723" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="europe germany worldheritage" title="P1010022" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3590/3681247723_b191c33b43_b.jpg" username="YuKengShih" views="29" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-02 08:50:36" description="7/6 Bremen &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bremen&lt;/a&gt; Town Hall &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_Hall_of_Bremen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;whc.unesco.org/en/list/1087&lt;/a&gt;" id="3681245993" latitude="0" license="1" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="europe germany worldheritage" title="P1010023" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2427/3681245993_353e977b63_b.jpg" username="YuKengShih" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-04-16 15:03:14" description="The original statues of the swine herder and his swine were erected in the northern part of Bremen at the end of a shopping area called the Sogestrasse. The street is lined with many shops selling imported goods and nothing was in place apart from the town name to remind people that this port town was once a pig pasture. Now the statues stand as that reminder.  The reproduction at Gluck's is between the cafe and the town hall." id="10040067" latitude="0" license="3" longitude="0" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="japan glucks" title="The &quot;Statue of a Swineherd&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8/10040067_73ca1dd8c6_b.jpg" username="kuckibaboo" views="67" />
</photos>
